UFOs are a Swiss Army knife for intelligence.
They can use them for anything.
He was seeing lights, like, out somewhere on the base,
like, lifting up off the ground
and then flying over a mountain and going down,
and they were just glowing orbs.
And he said that he could look through binoculars
and sometimes see, like, Air Force people
or somebody walking around them before they took off.
He built, apparently, a setup and started listening
to transmissions coming from the base.
He said there were dinosaurs and, like,
old, like, Roman battles and stuff.
The Air Force had taken him in a helicopter,
flown him up to northwestern New Mexico
and showed him stuff, saying,
look, we think there's something going on here.
And they actually put jeeps and, like, water tanks
and all kind of stuff in this place as props.
And then he starts to kind of lose his mind?
Is that right?
Yeah, as things get worse,
he went there with a camera and took pictures.
Bennewitz was there with, like, a rifle and a pistol
and he said, you know, they're coming.
You have to come in the house right now.
The idea that UFOs are a cover
for just prosaic technology is totally wrong.
In fact, it's the opposite.
Prosaic technology is often used as a cover for UFOs.
It's an interesting discussion.
Yeah, probably both.
In fact, it's demonstrably both.
Imagine the Bennewitz operation as a 24-hour long stage play.
And Bennewitz is five minutes in one scene.
Not even five minutes.
I'm here with Greg Bishop, who is the excellent author of Project Beta and, most recently,
It Defies Language.
And I know you to be a very hardheaded UFO journalist, investigator,
who sometimes reports on things that fly in the face of what the believers of everything want.
And the first kind of great example of that is in Project Beta where you documented this guy named Paul Bennewitz,
who's this earnest industry man in aerospace.
And he is driven kind of crazy by the Air Force Office of Special Investigation,
specifically this counterintelligence agent named Rick Doty.
And it makes for an amazing kind of dramatic thriller.
I'm excited to get into the weeds with you.
Thank you for being here.
Thanks.
Thanks for inviting me.
Bennewitz wasn't involved in aerospace and he was already kind of unstable to begin with.
It's just the Air Force, AFOSI and other people just encouraged it and made it worse.
There you go.
Which is no excuse.
Everybody says, oh, he was perfectly okay.
No, he was kind of heading down that road.
It's just when somebody in power tells you something.
Yeah.
It's like, oh, well, that must be right.
So you just keep, you know.
Well, didn't he have a company that sold components to aerospace?
They still do.
Yeah.
His sons still run it, at least one of them.
And Thunder Scientific.
Yeah.
Temperature and humidity instruments.
Okay.
I think it's humidifiers and things to monitor temperature and humidity
in like highly, you know, corrosive or wetter environments like on submarines or on aircraft
or whatever.
So that's, he actually had, as far as I know, contracts with the military for these things,
along with a bunch of, you know, scientific organizations and stuff.
And he both lives and his office is near Kirtland Air Force Base, like basically across the street
or what's the.
His house is in the Four Hills area of Albuquerque, which is on the border of the north side of
Kirtland Air Force Base.
Okay.
And his office was near the Wyoming gate of Kirtland Air Force Base.
So at work or at home, he was always like right next to the base.
Uh-huh.
So, and the company's still there.
If you go there, there's a big sign, a little sign that says Thunder Scientific.
Uh-huh.
And I think his son, one of his sons is still the president.
And I'm not sure if his wife is still alive. Cindy, I think her name is or was.
But yeah, that's on, like I said, it's just, you could walk out his front door and down
a street like two minutes and you're at the fence that says, you know, government facility,
do not trespass, all that stuff.
So this is the late 70s.
Mm-hmm.
Paul Benowitz is living and working around Kirtland Air Force Base.
What's he like as a person?
The people I do know that knew him, such as Bill Moore, Doty, and Gabe Valdez, those are
three people I talked to who knew him.
And mostly because I was talking about that period, they talk about him getting more and
more frightened about stuff.
I've seen pictures of him before all this started happening.
Mm-hmm.
And he, he's got this mischievous look on his face.
He looks like a, he looks like a grown up kid.
There's a, I've seen a picture of his, um, application to APRO, Aerial Phenomena Research
Organization.
And he's just kind of standing there like kind of, it's just, it's kind of like, wow, that
doesn't look like Paul Benowitz.
I think of him as like this scared, paranoid person.
But, um, you know, in the picture, which is just a snippet of somebody, he, he looks actually
pretty, pretty happy and funny.
There's a, um, picture of him in the Albuquerque Journal or Tribune, one of the two, uh, in 1981
or two, he looks way different.
He has long hair and a big beard and he's kind of sitting there and he looks very serious.
Mm.
And it was just a, uh, profile of him and his business.
But, um.
Anything about his childhood or is he, was he a generally credulous person who believed
in other sort of, you know, crazy lore growing up?
I don't think so.
The only thing I knew about, and I can't remember who I found this out from as he liked
to read Wild West novels.
Okay.
You know?
Um, also he was a private pilot.
Uh, he had a, he had a, uh, pilot's license also.
I think he did aerobatic flying, which made me feel closer to him cause I have a pilot's
license too.
Uh huh.
He did aerobatic flying.
Um, but it's just, you know, there's not a lot on his background.
People actually said, well, why didn't you get into his background?
And what was just your question?
And I said, well, nobody that was close to him wanted to talk to me for obvious reasons.
Yeah.
Cause it's like, we don't want to dig that up again.
So he's living and working near Kirtland Air Force Base.
Kirtland Air Force Base has an interesting history in just UFO lore.
I believe it was managed back in the day by the Sandia offshoot of the Atomic Energy Commission.
Oh, okay. Okay.
And, and so, um, a couple of places where it shows up in UFO lore just to kind of set the,
set the scene for people, maybe take this with a grain of salt, but you have, uh, Bill Steinman,
who is a UFO researcher who writes about the Aztec crash, which is a very controversial crash.
Yeah.
I have his book.
I talked to him on the phone once.
Oh, wow.
I want to hear about that.
Cause he seemed like a very interesting guy.
He was actually, people don't know this.
He was a skunk works employee and he was pushed out of that.
I didn't know because he was so interested in this topic.
Huh?
And then he could never really get a job in aerospace again.
But he, uh, writes about Kirtland Air Force Base, uh, with respect to a guy named Eric Henry
Wing, cause he was interested actually in the Kingman crash, which is associated with Operation
Upshot Knothole, this nuclear test in 1953 in Nevada at the Nevada test range.
And you have this Arthur Stancil, this guy who's on the re definitely worked at Wright
Airfield at the time.
Yeah.
And, um, he sees his name in the records cause he was this witness of this crash.
He sees a body like a, you know, four foot body mortared or whatever in Kingman.
And he Steinman looks him up, sees his name in the record next to a guy named Eric Henry
Wang.
Yeah.
Eric Henry Wang, uh, was head of special studies at, uh, you know, Wright Airfield.
He was German.
German studied with Victor Schauberger actually.
Yeah.
Okay.
That I didn't know.
Yeah.
And people say, well, why is his name Wang?
And I found out, and I think this is true because of the, uh, because of, um, uh, monk,
uh, East Asian, you know, uh, barbarians came through Germany.
Fascinating.
And so he had this Asian name.
He wasn't, he was German, but he had this Asian name because of, you know, something that
happened in what the third, I mean, sorry, like the third century or fourth century or
something.
Yeah.
There were, there were people named Wang that came through there and just kind of.
Attila the Hun.
Yeah.
I'm not sure, not sure he made it to Rome, but.
Um, yeah.
So, okay.
Mongol hordes did, but apparently that's where his name came from.
That's.
Go ahead.
No, no, no.
Amazing.
I love it.
I love the historical detours.
So, um, his name, he's apparently moved from, um, Wright Patterson or Wright Airfield
to Kirtland air force base.
And, uh, I believe there's even, uh, some sort of complex near Los Alamos.
That's like named after him.
And, but that's it.
Like he's kind of scrubbed from the internet.
Otherwise.
Yeah.
Steinman.
Um, like most people that do that kind of work.
Yeah.
Bill Steinman gets in touch with his wife, uh, Maria wing.
And she says, oh yeah, he worked at Kirtland air force base.
He worked on some, you know, secret UFO related stuff.
They came and also came and, uh, took a bunch of stuff out of his house when he died.
Interesting.
Kind of like that, that Tesla story where the Navy goes in, in New York and pulls all the
stuff out of storage.
Yeah.
But the same thing I believe.
Well, that's interesting.
That's definitely factual in the case of Tesla.
So, um, yeah.
And then John Trump Trump's Donald Trump's uncle actually looks at the Tesla files, uh,
to see if they can confirm.
I think I've read that.
Yeah.
Uh huh.
Crazy history, but okay.
So they, yeah.
Raid wing's house.
Um, Steinman speaks to Maria wing.
She says, yes, he's working on all sorts of spooky stuff.
And, uh, he was managed by Henry a Kissinger.
So that's pretty crazy.
And then Henry Kissinger is actually on record meeting, doing these like kind of, um, meetings.
This guy, Don Cotter, uh, who was head of advanced research at Kirtland air force base,
uh, in 1962 is convening these interdisciplinary groups to talk about UFO.
No, not talk, not talk about UFOs.
Talk about, we don't know.
Yeah.
Um, you know, kind of, you know, national defense security and geopolitics.
And, um, and Kissinger is on record being there.
So that's the backdrop.
Um, otherwise, all we know is Kirtland is working on probably advanced aerospace.
And at what point does Benowitz start to think that he is picking up some sort of alien signal
or, you know, he's, he's detecting UFOs.
I think it's 77 or eight.
He was seeing lights fly as, and, uh, Chris Lambright describes this in his book too.
Um, he was seeing lights like out, out somewhere on the base, like lifting up, up off the ground
and flying over a mountain and going down, but they were, they were glowing orbs.
Hmm.
And he said that he could look through binoculars and sometimes see like air force people or
somebody walking around them before they took off.
Hmm.
Then they'd go straight up, go over the mountain, go down.
And it's not clear as to whether they were doing things that were unconventional or just
kind of doing this.
Cause if they went zip and then went like, you know, then you kind of like, Whoa.
So he saw that for a while and then he started filming it with eight millimeter cameras and
then later video, early video.
And because of that, and also because, um, the, uh, he was, um, doing hypnosis with this
woman, Myrna Hanson, that said she was abducted or something had happened to her.
You know, at that point, but Hopkins book hadn't even come out.
Hmm.
So one of the few people that knew about this kind of thing was, um, Leo Sprinkle and also
James Harder, there were two psychologists and they both worked with APRO.
And as I said, um, Benowitz was a member of APRO area phenomena research organization.
Okay.
This is a UFO research group.
Yeah.
They're in Arizona.
It was run by Jim and Coral Lawrence and who had split off from the Midwest UFO network,
which is now the mutual UFO network.
Move on.
Yeah.
So, um, they'd started their own, uh, group, which they said, I think was more scientific.
Anyway, Paul joined them.
I've, I've seen his application.
It's kind of cool to just see what he was saying about himself.
Anything interesting that he said?
Um, they said, what are your, what was it?
He just said, I can help with some of the technical aspects.
Okay.
He had a master's I think in electrical engineering.
That's right.
Yeah.
And he said that he can help with some of the technical aspects of, you know, if they
wanted to, you know, if they had any kind of equipment they wanted to use to start,
you know, doing what people now do now, which is to detect UFOs.
And it's been going on for years, but we just gotten to the point in the last 20 years where
you can actually have an automatic system.
That's pretty accurate.
Um, so he said that about, um, his expertise, but he also, the other thing I thought was kind
of fascinating.
They said, what's your favorite UFO book?
And he said books by Hynek.
That's all he said.
Okay.
Which is funny.
Cause later Hynek apparently visited his house.
Yeah.
Um, and that's how he got in touch with, um, at first Leo Sprinkle and Sprinkle came out,
um, to interview, to help him regress this woman and figure out what had happened to
her.
And Sprinkle after being there, I think the second time he came, he said, Bennett was
there with like a, like a rifle and a pistol.
And he said, you know, they're coming.
You have to come in the house right now.
And this was before he even contacted the air force.
I think.
Wow.
So he was already exhibiting signs of paranoia.
Yeah.
Okay.
Crazy.
I'm always diving into the edge of science and consciousness on this show.
Lately.
I've been thinking a lot about aging, not just in terms of years, but in how it actually
feels in the body.
Slow recovery, lower energy, that middle aged fog that sneaks up on you.
I feel like I can barely go out and drink alcohol anymore.
That's why I started using something called qualia senolytic.
And it's been a major shift for me.
Let me explain.
As we age, our bodies accumulate what scientists call senescent cells, also known as zombie cells.
These are worn out cells that stop dividing, but don't die.
They hang around in your body, draining your energy, clogging up your recovery and generally
making you feel older than you are.
Qualia senolytic is a first of its kind supplement formulated with nine plant based compounds designed
to help your body naturally eliminate these zombie cells.
It's not something you take every day, just two days a month.
But it supports your body in aging better at the cellular level.
Since I've started taking it, I've felt sharper, lighter, and like my body's resilience has come back online.
It's vegan, non-GMO, and grounded in serious research.
Experience the science of feeling younger.
Go to qualialife.com slash jesse for up to 50% off your purchase.
And use code JESSE, again that's J-E-S-S-E, for an additional 15% off.
That's Q-U-A-L-I-A-L-I-F-E dot com slash jesse, J-E-S-S-E, for an extra 15% off your purchase.
Thanks so much to Qualia for sponsoring this episode.
So he does, he sees these sort of orb like things going over a mountain right next to Kirtland.
Yeah.
And then does he detect anything else? Like any sort of like signals?
He wasn't at that point. As things progressed, he started putting up equipment to detect signals
because he thought maybe I can hear what the aliens are talking about.
Because he called the Air Force and said, look, there's, there's stuff flying over the base.
Uh huh.
And I think it's aliens and I want to tell you about it and I've got films and so they're, you know,
the base was like, he's not supposed to be watching this stuff.
So instead of telling him, no, no, I get out of here, you know, that that's nothing.
Um, it's national defense or whatever, security.
They said, well, we'll come on down here and show us what you got.
Cause they wanted to see what it was.
You know, is it something we're working on that he's not supposed to see?
Obviously it's something we're working on cause he's pointing the camera at the base.
So I talked to, um, a guy at the NSA who was not there.
Um, his name was Tom Dooley.
I actually talk about him in the book.
Um, but he had a colleague that was at that meeting.
Uh, the first meeting with Benowitz where they had all the security people.
And like I, maybe the commander of the base, I'm not sure, but it's certainly all the security people and some of the military and civilian people, I guess, in charge of different projects at the base.
Cause they wanted to see what he's looking at.
And he told me by the end of the meeting, everybody started leaving.
And by the end of the meeting, there was like three or four people left.
Cause they're like, oh, that's not ours.
Well, that's not ours.
So they didn't care about it.
But the people that were concerned stayed there.
And the only one I know of is the guy that was a head of AFOSI at the time, I think.
And he said, Hey Paul, this is interesting.
Why don't you keep telling us what's going on?
Cause I wanted to see, you know, exactly what he's saying when he's seeing it.
And then eventually convinced him that he was working with them.
So he trusted them.
So they could basically tell him whatever they wanted and keep, keep an eye on him.
And people keep asking.
It's like, well, what did they do that for?
And I said, it was far more valuable to them to find out what he was seeing, how he was seeing it.
Um, if anybody else could do this, even though he was an electronics genius and, uh, who he was talking to.
Like anybody could just write him and say, I'm a UFO researcher.
What are you doing?
And then they, you know, they could check up on the person.
Maybe he's, maybe he's a Russian or Chinese or otherwise asset.
So it's basically so they could get a handle into what do these people, you know, who does he know?
Well, what is he telling them?
What does he thinks going on?
And of course he tells somebody from, you know, another country from a, from an adversary,
and they'll get clues as to what's being worked on.
And they can, they can, uh, um, you know, concatenate that with other information they're getting from other sources.
So it's another source of information.
So I want to make sure he wasn't some sort of security leak inadvertently because they didn't think he was an enemy agent or anything like that.
They just thought he was kind of a, you know, outlaw, crazy scientist guy, which he kind of was.
And, um, in keeping in touch with them, they could keep a lid on that stuff.
And that, I think that's why they contacted bill more.
It's like, well, you're a UFO guy.
If you, you know, if you cooperate with us, we'll give you some secrets, we'll give you some documents.
Hmm.
And they did, but.
So explain that.
Just about all of them turned out to be crap.
So let's explain that.
So, so Bill Moore is a UFO researcher.
Yeah.
Who's kind of, uh, starting to reach peak prominence at that time, I think in 79 or 80.
Cause he had, he had just written, um, co-written the Roswell incident.
Roswell incident.
The first book about the Roswell crash.
Which really put it on the map before that.
It was not, you know, before him and Stan Friedman, 79 to 80.
Stan kind of discovered what was going on and then he helped, he was like Bill's research.
That's right.
Yeah.
Nobody mentions bill at the Roswell, uh, uh, uh, festival.
He's why they're doing all this.
Right.
Him and Stan actually.
Yeah.
Well, it might be because of his, his, you know, the souring event of events, which we'll
talk about, which we'll talk about, but he was kind of, you know, really starting to ascend
in UFO world as a good researcher.
He'd written also the Philadelphia experiment.
And he was on the board of APRO on APRO too.
Okay.
That was the other connection.
So he is ascending.
And then what happens?
Does he get sort of co-opted by, um, counterintelligence or.
Yeah.
Basically he got a letter that was sent to APRO and APRO looked at it and said, well,
why don't you check this out?
It was just basically from this guy who said they were on patrol somewhere.
And it might've been New Mexico.
I can't remember, but he said, we're on patrol.
We saw this UFO is really weird.
Everybody got freaked out.
And I just wanted to write somebody.
Bill checked it out.
And he, uh, told the APRO people it's BS.
This is just, this is somebody's fake letter.
It was supposedly a military person that wanted to get this information out.
Hmm.
And bill checked out and the guy didn't exist.
He did find out the incident may have happened, but not in the way the guy said.
Hmm.
So he just said, we'll ignore this.
It's BS.
Um, and a few months after that, he was on tour doing radio shows for, um, Roswell incident.
He was at one radio station that they said, there's a call for you.
He thought that it was a prank call and he just basically hung up on him.
Hmm.
So he goes to Albuquerque the next stop on his book tour.
He goes into the radio station.
Same thing happens, same voice.
And he's like, okay, this is a lot, a lot of effort to put in for just a hoax.
So he started talking to the guy and they said, um, you know, if you're interested, come
and meet, you know, at this certain time.
And so that's when he met, uh, I think the first meeting he had was with Doty and the
guy known as he called Falcon, um, which was apparently was a old, a retired CIA, um,
agent called Harry Rositsky, who has since passed away.
Um, and I think it was like, do we know anything about him?
Rositsky?
Yeah.
You go look him up and you will know more than I do because a lot of stuff has come out about
him since I first, um, what's come out?
Um, who he was, uh, what he worked on.
His specialty was Soviet operations.
He had, he had, he'd come out of, um, OSS.
Okay.
And World War II.
And, um, I think he'd worked with Reinhard Galen and some of the Nazis afterwards to, to
set up intelligence networks in Europe because, because of the Russians.
And he'd also, you know, he'd also been in Afghanistan, I think.
And it was, um, uh, monitoring Soviet radio transmissions there.
He did a lot.
He was basically was there one of their Soviet experts.
And so in the late seventies, early eighties, when this, when, uh, the period we're talking
about, they pulled him out of retirement to help run this unofficial operation against
the Russians and Chinese or whoever else.
Hmm.
And, um, they needed somebody from the UFO like research community as kind of a contact.
So they approached, I think a bunch of different people.
And a few of them said yes.
And bill was one of them.
Do we have any sense of what Doty had?
So Doty is obviously going to play this sort of villain role in this whole story.
Uh, you know, he's the main kind of, you know, air force office of special investigations
agent who enters Benowitz's life and.
You know, plants all sorts of BS and, and, and kind of screws with him mentally.
Um, do we know anything about his history up until that point?
Who Doty's?
Yeah.
I don't know too much about it.
All I know is what he said.
And it's like, what am I going to do with what he said?
He said he was a guard at area 51.
I have no idea.
It's hard to take that at face value.
Yeah.
Well, I, he also said, I think his father worked at area 51.
Are you familiar with that history?
Dolan told me that Richard Dolan.
Yeah, I think maybe.
Yeah.
Well, Dolan will probably know.
Um, another, I don't think he ever mentioned that, but you know, he could, he would probably
take stories like that and kind of, you know, mix and match them.
Another interesting data point on Doty.
I know very little about him before the Benowitz story, but he shows up at Mario Woods's case.
So Mario Woods is at Ellsworth Air Force Base in South Dakota in 1977.
Uh, he's a missile security officer and he not only sees a craft.
I see this light off to my east.
He claims that these beings walked up to him.
He then gets a hypnotic regression and he discusses being inside of a craft, wakes up 10 miles away.
Uh, you know, and it's, I think it's, it's, it's dawn.
So like our, it was like the whole night had elapsed.
Yeah.
And his, his partner, Michael Johnson's in a catatonic state.
I even tried pulling his hand off that steering wheel.
And, uh, he has no idea what's happened to him.
And he then is debriefed by, you know, a slew of official, you know, people at Ellsworth Air Force Base.
And one of the guys is Rick Doty.
Next to him was this new OSI guy named Rick Doty.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Because the first time I saw him was on ancient aliens.
And I said, I know that guy.
He was at my debrief.
Hmm.
So that's kind of interesting as well.
What year was that?
77.
Okay.
A year or two before.
Yeah.
Well, maybe if, if true, that's probably why Doty was tracked into this.
Right.
Because I think he has an interest in the UFO subject.
Cause I just like, just like we all do.
It's just that his job was to mess with people concerning it.
Totally.
Which he enjoyed.
The weird part is, is like there's Mario's is one of the.
Strongest cases.
You know, I'm, I'm like you.
I think a lot of UFO stuff is bullshit, but Mario's to me, I've spent a lot of time with
the guy.
It just pattern matches to one of these nuclear cases where like clearly there is an overwhelming
nuclear pattern that goes above and beyond, in my opinion, the ability for humans to coordinate.
Hmm.
So it's interesting that Doty was probably part of a debrief around a real case.
Yeah.
He's also involved in this sort of.
It makes sense.
He's inserting himself as, you know, a counter Intel guy in this other case.
Yeah.
Well, maybe when that stuff came up there, like, well, you know, either he said something
or this guy knows, you know, this is just speculation.
Yeah.
And Rositzky apparently handpicked all these people to be part of this operation.
I asked, uh, more about it once and he said, well, think of it as a giant.
Cause what he said was the Benowitz thing was one cog in a giant wheel connected to a
bunch of other giant wheels that you would never notice.
And the only reason it's noticed is because it's UFO.
People have kind of made it into, uh, uh, a big, uh, big story.
Not that it isn't, but you know, there are a lot of other parts of this counter Intel
that was going on in the late seventies, early eighties before the Berlin wall fell
and all that, that, um, people don't know about.
And the only reason this came out is because it had to do with UFOs.
So people are interested in that subject, obviously.
But, um, what he said, the other thing he said to me later was imagine the Benowitz operation
as a 24 hour long stage play.
Hmm.
Yeah.
It's like you and Benowitz is five minutes in one scene, not even five minutes.
That's how much of the entire, cause, uh, when people, UFO people, uh, and researchers,
et cetera, hear about this, they're like, Oh my God, it's so important.
It's like, it was a tiny little piece in a big wheel that was working with a lot of other
things to like, here's one more way we can, you know, uh, uh, mess with and, and, uh, um,
vet out, um, Soviet, uh, assets.
Mm-hmm.
And that's what he was using it for.
I don't think Rosicki gave less of a crap about UFOs.
All he cared about is what he could do with it.
It's another thing I had put on a t-shirt.
What, um, UFOs are, are a Swiss army knife for intelligence.
They can use them for anything.
Yeah. We were just talking earlier that they're sort of a Rorschach test.
Yeah.
And you could insert UFO, like, I find this interesting with like the JFK assassination.
If you were a counterintelligent, you would say that the JFK assassination was only, you
know, it was like only UFOs.
Like say you wanted to detract from the fact that it was, you know, nuclear, you know, that,
that JFK wanted to defang the American nuclear arsenal or that, you know, get rid of the CIA.
Yeah.
Get rid of the CIA.
And so they were retaliating or whatever.
Yeah.
You throw people down the trail with this thing, UFOs, and then it's, you can track the people
that talk about it with respect to UFOs.
UFOs are sort of a proxy for somebody's kind of irreverence towards, you know, earthly authorities
or something and open-mindedness generally, you know, you can track Soviet spies or traitors
or whatever.
Take something that people have a really strong emotional attachment to, but no way to prove
any of it.
And that's a big ass wrench in the, in the, in the toolbox.
Totally.
Because if you're emotionally attached to something, you can be led around by the nose.
So, um, sometimes when people get excited, I was like, detach your, your, your emotions
from this, because you're not going to see the bigger picture if you just, if you're just
looking at this thing.
Well, not only that, you're making yourself susceptible to counterintelligence.
Yeah, exactly.
I mean, it just, it just, it snowballs, you know?
Totally.
This episode is sponsored by one of my new favorite products, Odoo.
This is one of the coolest internet products I've seen lately.
It allows you to start a full scale business from your laptop.
It's not just a website builder or a CRM.
It's a full suite of tools that all seamlessly integrate and speak to one another.
Odoo gives you everything in one connected platform, sales, inventory, accounting, e-commerce,
whatever you need, it works together out of the box.
So whether you're selling a physical product, launching a media company like me, running
a nonprofit or scaling a startup, it's all you need in one simple system.
What I like is their philosophy.
Unity makes creative strength.
It's true in systems and it's true in teams.
Odoo helps simplify the chaos of running something complex.
So your creative focus stays sharp.
It's really a beautiful and simple product.
So act on the idea you have.
Don't keep putting it off.
You can start with just one app and it's literally free to try.
There's no downside.
If you want to upgrade later, the service will scale with your needs.
Head to odoo.com to get started.
That's O-D-O-O pronounced Odoo.
And follow at odoo.official on Instagram or at odoo on TikTok.
Now back to today's episode.
So, okay.
Before we get into the kind of the meta analysis of how these mechanics work, let's talk about
the details.
So Moore is basically his ascendancy is being used against him.
We're going to give you secret info if you comply with us.
Yeah.
And then at what point does Moore interact with Benowitz?
And at what point does Doty directly interact with Benowitz?
I think, oh, Moore interacted with him just through APRO.
And it was very soon, I think, after he was contacted because he said that, oh, there's
another part of the story.
The reason they met with him after that phone call is he was one of the few, because they
sent that letter out to different people.
That supposed letter from somebody in the military that had seen a UFO at close range.
And he was one of the few that said, this is BS.
Before he met with Rosicki and Doty, they gave him one more test.
They gave him a memo showing that there was some sort of a UFO sighting, I guess, in central
or southern New Mexico in the late forties or early fifties.
And it was, I believe it was called, it was part of a project called Silver Sky, because
the memo was called the Silver Sky memo.
He went and checked it out and found out that was BS too.
So he's like, when they finally talked to him, they said, you're the only person that
just, you actually went out and found out that this stuff was false.
Yeah.
And they kind of, for some reason, they wanted somebody who was, had an investigative mind,
like could kind of dig out whether something was BS or not, or with a false flag or not,
or whatever you want to call it.
And that's why they picked him.
I think Bill Moore was a pretty decent UFO investigator.
Like if you read the Philadelphia experiment, you know, I don't know.
I don't know.
It's, I haven't corroborated whether all of the details that he discusses are right.
And I have reason to believe there's a lot of counterintelligence around the Philadelphia
experiment.
This is again, this case.
Oh yeah.
In the, uh, 1942, uh, where, you know, a ship was rumored to be zapped from a Philadelphia
Navy port to Norfolk, Virginia.
Yeah.
Time travel, uh, whatever.
Time travel.
Thomas Townsend Brown.
There's a movie made of it.
There's a movie made about it.
I think Charlton Heston was in it.
And there are rumors that the, the sailors in the ship were, were, were fused to the
hull and you had all these screams.
And then you have this guy coming out later saying he was a time traveler as a result
of it.
Yeah.
Carlos Allende.
Carlos Allende is the, um, guy who leaked the story to Morris Jessup, who was a pseudonym.
The real guy's name was Carl Allen, who was a sea, a merchant Marine, a Navy merchant
Marine.
Yeah.
Carlos Allende.
And Bill Moore writes about this whole story in like, I think a pretty, you know, hardheaded,
you know, maybe you get some things wrong, but like, he's a great, he's a good researcher.
He's not, I don't think he's a bad researcher.
So, but he, he seems to lend a lot of credibility to the fact that Rosicki and, uh, Doty can give
him secret information.
So he's going to comply.
Or, well, at least somebody that Rosicki knows is going to hand him dossiers of stuff.
He had to go to one time.
He was told in the middle of this, he said, go to this hotel room in upstate New York.
There'll be somebody there to meet you.
And they just gave him an envelope with all these old documents in it and said, you got
20 minutes.
Yep.
Cause what can I do?
And they said, anything you want, you just can't keep the documents.
Wow.
So he had a 35 millimeter camera.
He just currently took pictures of all of them.
Whoa.
Um, and he, this happened more than once in, in various forms.
Yep.
And I, and that was the exchange for keeping tabs on people and saying what this person
doing, what are they thinking?
Um, as he told me later and actually he told other people, none of them ever really amounted
to anything.
Yeah.
The MJ 12 stuff, the Eisenhower briefing memo.
When he first released the report on them in this book called the MJ 12 papers, the thing
actually said compelling, but not conclusive.
That's all it said.
And then after a few years, he said, I don't think, I don't think almost anything I was given
was actually true.
100% UFO information.
Yeah.
It was all either around it or completely made up.
And he said, he kind of felt, he kind of felt used and cheated.
Sure.
Does Moore and Doty proceed to trick Benowitz into believing he is detecting more than he
is when it comes to alien signals and UFOs?
Yeah.
People are going to argue with me, but as I recall it and I wrote Benowitz was his own worst
enemy.
The only problem was he had people around him, not contradicting him and encouraging him.
And then occasionally saying something.
The only thing I know that Bill Moore did was he was told to give Benowitz a document
called the Aquarius document or memo or something like that.
And it said it was, there was a little different pieces of UFO, like examinations of, of footage.
It's like, this looks good.
This doesn't apparently from some government source.
And one of Benowitz's or two of Benowitz's films are mentioned in that.
I know that because you look at it and you go, oh, that's the, it says, I think Albuquerque
or Kirtland or something like that.
But their analysis, analyses of his films in part, and they were encouraging.
It's like, well, this is unidentified.
We don't know what it is.
Um, but, uh, he was more was told to give that to Benowitz.
He said, hand him this document as far as I know.
And he, or he never admitted it to me.
He never actually went to Paul and Paul Benowitz and said, look into this.
This is important.
This was leaked to me.
He was basically there just kind of monitor him as far as I know.
But Paul Benowitz was so excited about what he was seeing and so convinced of whatever
he thought became reality that it was really easy just to mislead him with a little push
here and there.
Well, that sounds interesting.
Paul, why don't you look into that a little further instead of, don't worry about that.
That's not part of anything.
That everything was encouraged as long as it pushed him away from any secret, um, um,
um, projects or information.
And you see Benowitz start to get more and more fervent in his interest and he's doing
flights around Archuleta Mesa where he thinks maybe there's some underground activity.
They took him up there and showed it to him.
Uh huh.
Because they wanted him to pay attention to that rather than to Kirtland anymore.
It's like, let's just draw his attention away from there and to in furtherance of that.
And, you know, Doty told me this, I think Moore told me this.
And then a few people around the area, around the Hickory Apache, um, area.
Yeah.
Paul was very excited when he told him that the Air Force had taken him in a helicopter
from Kirtland, flown, flown him up to Northwestern New Mexico, um, to the Archuleta Mesa, which
is on the Hickory Apache reservation and showed him stuff saying, look, we think there's something
going on here.
They actually put Jeeps and like water tanks and all kinds of stuff in this place as props.
So he would be concentrating on that.
The funny thing is that apparently there was some sort of crash up there within that period
after that.
So there was a stealth fighter or maybe it was a drone or something that definitely crashed
there, but he did.
He never took pictures of it close enough where you could tell what it was.
Oh no, he got up there after they'd cleaned it up.
So you see like this burned area and Gabe said they went up there and found, you know, broken
up brush and evidence that something had been picked up and a pen that said US government
property on it.
So something happened there that was very important.
And maybe they just thought, you know what, this is even better because now he's really
going to concentrate up there.
And he made drawings of what he thought he saw.
And I included those in the book and they kind of morphed depending on what he was thinking
at the time.
He had like one version of it and then he said it was a craft that the aliens had given
to the United States government and the government was flying and they didn't know how to do it
and it crashed.
And so it just, it gets more and more Byzantine and complicated and, you know, and his paranoia
builds.
And is there a good prosaic explanation for the orbs that he initially saw going over that
mountain next to Kirtland or?
The only thing I can think of and based on what I was heard and on Chris Lambright's
book, X descending, it was some sort of project either with drones or some sort of unconventional
flying objects that, that had some sort of glow to them.
Whether you can ascribe that to having like a lighter than air with a light in it or, you
know, Chinese lantern type thing or some kind of weird energy or something like that.
I don't know, but they seemed, apparently they seem solid and they didn't move like airplanes
and they, they tested them at night.
So how was he detecting any sort of signals to begin with coming out of the base?
Because he was an electronics engineer and he built things to pick up, um, uh, I guess
a wide range of, uh, uh, um, radio signals probably centered on the military bands of signals,
not just, you know, like FM or AM or shortwave or anything.
And he built an antenna array.
He had all these machines for, uh, for, uh, analyzing the signal and he built all this
from scratch.
Nobody had any of this stuff or he jury rigged some of the stuff from his lab, but he built
apparently a setup and started listening to transmissions coming from the base, which is
a huge problem.
If you're trying to be a security person at Kirtland, you know, people shouldn't even
be listening to this much less inventing machines and, and equipment to listen to it in the first
place.
Cause if he's doing it, other people can do it.
So that's what they were worried about.
But he thought he could pick up.
He thought he could pick up, as far as I remember, he thought he could pick up transmissions, um,
that aliens were, were, were beaming either to each other or to the military or something.
And why did he think whatever he was picking up was alien?
Because it didn't comport with anything he could, could, uh, conceptualize.
So just the fact that it was kind of anomalous, there was no like actual message.
It might've been from what I've heard and what I've assumed, which might be wrong as it
was, uh, it was a telemetry for a missile guidance or something like that.
It was microbursts.
Okay.
So, you know, they sounded like, and he would slow them down.
Sure.
And he thought he was hearing patterns in it and saying, these are the aliens doing this.
And, um, he was using this, uh, this setup and Gabe told me about it.
He said he saw that setup, but he also saw the setup apparently after jail and Hynek showed up.
So what bill told me, and of course everybody's like, well, he's telling you this cause it's
disinformation.
Hynek wouldn't do such a thing.
Um, sometime, I believe in the early eight 81 or so, maybe even earlier, 80, 81, something
like that.
Jay Allen Hynek showed up at Paul's door with a computer and entirely built already made
computer and said, this will help you with the signals.
And bill told me that, uh, since Hynek knew that bill was doing some of this spy stuff somehow.
Yeah.
They went to, or he told them enough that Hynek kind of got it.
Cause you know, Hynek had been employed by the airport air force since the 1960s.
And apparently in the early eighties, he was still on the payroll.
He just wasn't doing very much.
Yeah.
It sounds like he was complicit in this whole thing where.
But I think that he didn't know what was on the computer.
Otherwise he might, he had a conscience.
He might've said, I don't want to do this.
Okay.
So, okay.
So they give him the computer.
Benowitz then starts to pick up even more on this computer.
So at some point, somebody at the base or at one, you know, any number of, uh, intelligence agencies
that were based, that had presence there to, um, make sure that the security was tight.
Um, decided why don't we just give him a computer with stuff on it and let him pick it up and
then have it, you know, because he thought the air force was cooperating with him.
Like he was bringing the information they needed.
He was, but not the kind that he thought.
So he thought he was doing sort of vital work, security work to decipher these alien signals.
They said, you know, we're interested in what you're doing, Paul, please keep talking to us.
Tell us what you're doing.
It's important for national security or whatever.
And he's like, Oh, okay.
But I think even more explicitly, he picks up certain messages that he interprets as like,
we've given the U S eight crafts or something like specific.
Yeah.
He starts decoding things and the decodings are basically based on his pareidolia about what
should be coming out of those messages.
Pareidolia, by the way, for the audience is seeing a pattern where it doesn't exist,
which is a human tendency.
Yeah.
It's, it's an evolutionary thing.
You gotta see patterns so you can survive.
Yes.
So, but it does us a disservice when it's things like this because you can make patterns
out of stuff that don't exist.
So that's what he was doing.
As you know, I'm always on the hunt for things that helped me stay sharp, focused,
and full of energy while I'm diving into life's mysteries and making this show happen.
And I've got to say mud water has completely transformed my mornings.
Back in the day, I used to struggle with that post coffee crash and let's not even get into
the caffeine jitters.
Mud water gave me the smooth, steady energy I was missing.
It's packed with functional mushrooms like lion's mane, chaga, and reishi, plus turmeric
and cacao all working together to keep me focused, calm, and grounded.
Honestly, it's like coffee went on a yoga retreat and came back zen.
What I love most is that it's not just about replacing coffee.
It's a whole new ritual.
It's a simple, nourishing way to start the day.
And I actually look forward to it every morning.
Every ingredient is USDA certified organic, vegan, non-GMO, and there's zero sugar.
It's energy that doesn't mess with your sleep or make you question your life choices at 3am.
Ready to make the switch to cleaner energy?
Head to mudwater.com, that's M-U-D-W-T-R dot com, and grab your starter kit today.
Right now, our listeners get an exclusive deal up to 43% off your entire order, plus
free shipping and a free rechargeable frother when you use code JESSE.
That's right, up to 43% off with code JESSE at M-U-D-W-T-R dot com.
After your purchase, they'll ask you how you found them.
Please show your support and let them know we sent you.
Keep your energy natural and refreshing all year long with mudwater.
Because life's too short for anything less than clean, delicious energy.
Did he get any other messages?
So something about possibly eight crafts that the US had retrieved?
I'm not sure if the stuff that I put in there, in the book, his deciphered code.
Okay.
I'm not sure if that's before or after the computer.
It might be after because it seems really detailed.
Okay.
So what else did he receive generally?
Just that there were aliens from another planet.
They were here.
They were trying to establish a base.
They needed Earth women or something.
It sounds like a science fiction movie.
Yeah.
To propagate their race.
Their planet was dying.
Wow.
All this stuff.
And that they were at some point going to take over.
And so that's what really scared him.
And I think he was saying that before.
And this computer just basically said, okay, let's take what he's saying and just crank it up.
And across the street, there maybe are some NSA officials.
Yes.
Maybe that happened.
I mean, that's, I, the person that told me that was, was, was Bill.
Okay.
And since he's my friend, I trust him.
The people say this about Bill's like, well, why do you trust him?
It was like, I've never found him to be lying to me ever.
I've known him for what?
35 years or more.
Well, if never lied to me once.
If anything, his ability to off himself at MUFON and say that he was complicit in wrongdoing
is probably a, maybe some sort of indicator that you should trust him.
Also, I don't know why he would make that up.
I mean, that seems, if, if you were to, you know, incept signals into a mainframe computer,
the NSA would be the ones to, to, to do that.
I mean, that, that their signals intelligence, that's what they do.
Yeah, exactly.
So somebody programmed it for him.
Heineck brought it to the door.
He hooked it up and then started immediately seeing these messages.
He also saw pictures.
Hmm.
He thought he, he thought he was looking into the alien planet, into the future and past
of the earth.
He, he had a little oscilloscope or at least at CRT.
Oh my God.
Analog CRT with, you know, with the scans.
And.
What is CRT?
Uh, cathode ray tube.
Okay.
Like old TV screens.
Yeah.
Got it.
Um, and somebody had just put this video in there for him.
Gabe told him he went over there and saw some of it.
He said there were dinosaurs and like old, like Roman battles and stuff, but they were
probably from old movies.
Hmm.
Um, but they were all garbled and weird and Gabe said he saw this.
So somebody was beaming this junk at him.
Oh man.
And apparently they set up across the street and to, um, send these signals into the computer
that would be decoded in the way the computer was designed to decode them.
And he thought it was coming from inside the base.
Cause I think they probably just sent him at the same frequency.
And then he starts to kind of lose his mind.
Is that, is that right?
Or.
Yeah.
Um, he starts losing sleep.
He thinks there's going to be some sort of alien invasion.
The woman, Myrna Hanson, that she, he had coming to his house in the eighties, talking
about, she was talking about being abducted and going to this underground facility, which
really that stuff is, I don't know if it's true or not, but it's formed so much of the
UFO or afterward.
Um, so a lot of stuff happening at the time that Paul was dealing with just became part
of the UFO lore.
Yes.
There's independent people that have said that this happened to them.
I don't know where they get that information.
Maybe it's been, you know, disinfo beamed at them, you know, said to them too.
I don't know.
Yeah.
But a lot of the, a lot of the tropes kind of started back then.
He said there, you know, there was an alien base underground at the Archuleta Mesa.
He went there with a camera and took pictures.
Whoa.
He said of things going in and out of the mountain, but they basically, they're just like blurs.
And it could be something, but it'd also be camera, you know, artifacts.
Who knows?
Nothing I've seen of the pictures he took up of the Archuleta Mesa area really amount to.
There's no like clear, like Billy Meyer looking picture.
Um, but you know, a couple of the things he, videos he took in at Kirtland show, there's
one of them that looks like a saucer kind of like this.
And there's a, there's a, there's a PSA Pacific Southwest airlines plane flying behind it.
So who knows what that thing was, but as nobody came in and said, Paul, stop, you know, Jesus.
Um, Bill said he tried.
Hmm.
He did give him that Aquarius document.
And it actually mentions access only to MJ 12, which is the first time anybody said anything
about MJ 12.
That's interesting.
Was in this fake doc in the Aquarius doc.
Wow.
And it says quote MJ hyphen T W E L V E unquote.
Whoa.
Yeah.
So somebody was trying to plant that in the, in the culture then too.
Like it's, you know, 1981 or whenever he got this, um, um, document, but bill was told
to give him this, this, the only documented thing that document, at least by bill where
he said, they told me to do this.
And they told me if I didn't give him that thing, that the deal was off and he read it.
He knew what it was.
He's like, this is being asked.
Um, so he went to Paul's office and he was trained.
They gave him spy training bill.
They had him doing other stuff too.
They had him like, you know, passing mail through and doing, you know, stuff with Soviet spies
on our side spies in the Soviet union.
They would send postcards and you'd have to like read them on a telephone call exactly.
And then take them to another post office and mail it from that post office to the next
post office spy stuff.
Um, but he said that, um, he, they finally, cause he hesitated.
It's like, I, I don't, I don't know if I want to do this.
He said, it was like, you know, you're a kid.
They tell the mafia says, why don't you stand on the corner and look, tell me if this car
comes by.
And then the next week you're burying bodies, you know, kind of thing.
Yeah.
It wasn't that bad, but he's like kind of, he kind of just gets wormed into this.
Yep.
This, uh, uh, structure, this, this, this intelligence structure.
So he said that he took the, the, finally he said, okay, you know, I'm going to give
it to Paul.
He goes down to his office, tells, you know, meet me at your office at a certain time.
And he takes some, he says, get a radio and they go in the, the, the supply closet.
He said, and he turned the radio up and he gave him the thing and said, I was told to
give this to you.
Take it with a grain of salt.
Um, and he said, as far as he knew, Paul never said anything about it.
And he just put it in his, in his safe at work.
Hmm.
So he did this with Paul.
Paul took it.
Didn't say anything about it, but it certainly affected his mindset and his thinking.
It's like, oh my God, I'm, I'm important.
They're paying attention to me.
Yeah.
I'm getting the secret information.
What happened was his family got worried about him.
They're like, geez, you know, he's not doing his work.
He's staying up all the time.
He's chain smoking.
Like he'd smoke a whole pack of cigarettes over lunch while Bill talked to him.
He's like, Paul.
It's like, yeah, you know, everybody was telling him to calm down while knowing what was causing,
what was going on.
They're like, you know, Dodie said he even told him.
Yeah.
But, um, he couldn't, he couldn't control, you know, I don't know if you've ever been
in a paranoid state where just everything makes sense.
Everything that's is arrayed against you.
Every conversation you hear.
William Burroughs talks about this.
It was a great lecture.
He talked about this, but yeah, I think, um, in UFO world, you can get into this sort
of solipsistic mindset where you go, Oh, this is all an illusion or whatever.
And if there are other beings and I'm in community, it becomes this, you're living
in the Da Vinci code or something.
Yeah, exactly.
And he, and he couldn't get out of that loop.
And his family's just like, Oh my God.
So they actually put him in a mental health facility for like a month or so.
Cause there's these, I've heard people still say he died in a mental institution or he
killed himself.
Like, no, his family was worried about it.
And they put him in a mental, like a mental health facility for like a month or two till
he calmed down.
And when he came out of it, he was still interested in the stuff, but it wasn't running his life.
That's good.
And then I think he realized probably from talking to his family and maybe even bill, like just,
you know, if you want, don't want to go to an early grave, please relax.
Yep.
And Dodie then comes out and admits, I befriended Paul that was tasked to do that.
Uh, and I sent him down the wrong path and I would continuously feed him passage material.
Passage material is classic kind of spook, you know, uh,
I don't know if he did or not, but I wouldn't put it past him.
I don't, I don't know if bill was privy to that or anybody I talked to was.
And Dodie didn't tell me that.
Uh huh.
Maybe because he didn't want to say that.
I just mean passage material, not in terms of documentation.
I just mean like wrong information.
Oh yeah.
He could have done that anytime.
Paul said, like I said before, Paul would say this is happening.
Don't we think, yeah, you know what?
I have indication that that's happening.
Maybe you should check it out.
Right.
I mean that kind of thing.
And it just kind of builds on itself.
Yeah.
And, and John Lear, who's obviously implicated in the Bob Lazar story and sort of, you know,
says all sorts of insane things around this time.
Yeah.
He worked for air America and all this stuff.
So I think John Lear was like Benowitz part two because he communicated with Benowitz after this.
Right.
So yeah, that's the interesting thing is in some ways John Lear seems like he was fed maybe a ton of disinformation, but he also meets with Benowitz.
Are you familiar with this?
Yes.
Did you know that?
Yeah.
And then Benowitz.
Multiple times until Benowitz got mad at him and said he didn't want to talk to him.
Right.
Yeah.
I don't remember what the breakup was about, but yeah, Ben, uh, he met with Benowitz a few times.
I just like asked him questions and.
Do you think John Lear was subject to the same disinfo as Benowitz or do you think he was tasked with.
Both.
Okay.
Not because I could sit here and say that's what happened, but the indications to me is, is, uh, from his actions and what he, you know, what I was told that, uh, when I was told he was met with Benowitz and how is, and how Bennett's reacted to him.
And also the fact that, um, I think somebody asked, uh, Lear at one point about something, uh, about, uh, God, I wish I knew exactly what it was.
I know who told me so I can ask them, but he said, well, John, what about, you know, all this stuff up at, you know, the underground base up at Archuleta Mesa and the Hickory Apache and this, you know, this big firefight and all that.
And I don't know if it was that story, but Lear said, oh yeah, I made that up.
Right.
He actually said this.
He literally says I made that up.
Yeah.
To in confidence or at least privately to this one guy right before one of those first congressional hearings about UFO stuff in the, I think it was in the early nineties or something like that.
It was, it might've been one of the ones that Greer set up.
I'm not sure.
Yeah.
But yeah, I mean, Lear admitted this and because of his, you know, uh, previous background flying for air America, which he touted a lot saying I was one of the, you know, he's got an intelligence background.
So CIA cargo pilot.
Yeah.
So he, you know, he very well may have been tasked to check up on Benowitz and feed him more stuff after the fact.
But you're giving Jalen Hynek the benefit of the doubt.
Only because what I know of him is that if he knew that's what it was, I don't think he'd have done it.
I'm not so sure.
Well, I don't know.
Uh, you know, I don't have, I don't have a ton of reason to believe that.
It's just a guess.
That my only, you know, I think of that, you know, a documentary UFOs past, present and future.
Emenegger's.
Yes.
Robert Emenegger and Rod Serling's doing the, you know, um, narration.
Yeah.
I interviewed Bob a couple of times on my show.
Interesting.
Yeah.
I'd love to talk to him.
He's a cool guy.
I liked him.
Seems like a cool guy.
Well, he, it seems like he was maybe one of the first examples of this, you know, using
UFOs as a strategy to sort of lure people in because he is in communications with Norton
Air Force Base.
And I believe he goes there and everybody there is talking to him about UFOs and they're telling
him that they are going to give him, uh, you know.
The Holloman landing.
Exactly.
Al Mugordo, uh, earlier, um, I think in the, in the, um, in the sixties.
And so he gets all excited and they say they're going to give him footage and they keep saying
they're going to give him footage.
They're going to give him footage.
And then the footage never really appears.
And he's, he's actually, he is shown a little, he says.
I think he was, or his, um, his, like one of his partners, Bob Shardle or think something,
uh, saw it.
Yeah.
Alan Sandler, another guy.
What did you see on the film?
Was it color?
Was it black and white?
It was black and white.
Yeah.
It wasn't beautiful.
Like my friend, but it was nothing other than what we ended up in the book.
We see this thing, this round thing.
And it wasn't that stable.
Funny part.
And it landed and the door opened and guys come up looking like they were outer space guys.
Yeah.
It was Sandler.
One of them actually said they saw it.
I think even Emenegger says he saw it briefly or something.
And then you have this video that ends up, you have mostly like this animation rendition
and you have those past, present and future that they have to do because they don't have
the real footage.
Yeah.
But there's also a little bit of footage and that footage has now been debunked as an F4
and an F, the F4 came out, I think in like 59 or something.
So it was like, right.
Like it was probably like not, you know, well known at the time.
Yeah.
And it was definitely flying, you know, around Holloman.
Mm-hmm.
And so I almost feel like the first kind of, you know, Rorschach test, you know, throwing
people off the trail was that documentary and J. Allen Hynek is obviously a big part
of the documentary.
So was J. Allen Hynek used in that documentary as well?
I don't know.
Probably because he was through this whole thing.
He was still getting a check from the Air Force.
Well, that's what I'm saying.
That's what I'm saying.
So I don't know.
But does that mean you know what you're doing?
Does that mean somebody tells you everything that's going on when you're getting a check?
I don't know.
But one other data point about J. Allen Hynek is, you know, Jacques Vallée was like his
kind of understudy, his assistant.
Yeah.
Jacques Vallée finds this pentacle memo in the Blue Book files.
And he goes to J. Allen Hynek and he's like, what the fuck?
Because the pentacle memo is like this whole, you know, Battelle Memorial Institute secret
UFO research program that is looking at, you know, these hot aerial hotspots, presumably
around nuclear.
If you look at what was happening at the time.
And J. Allen Hynek is like, wait, what's going on?
You're not allowed to, apparently you weren't allowed to mention the pentacle.
You know, this is written by a guy named Howard C. Cross.
You weren't allowed to mention that program in the Robertson memo or Robertson panel, which
creates a Robertson memo, which is basically the constitution of Blue Book.
It creates the mandate for Blue Book to kind of explain away and rationalize, you know,
this stuff.
Yeah.
And then J. Allen Hynek or Vallée comes out saying, you know, I was convinced that J. Allen
Hynek actually, you know, didn't know about the pentacle memo and this other thing.
But like, I don't know.
There are all these cases where J. Allen Hynek has to like play dumb.
And I'm like, I don't know, dude.
I think you might've known a thing or two because he seems like a smart guy.
Yeah.
So.
Oh, no, I don't think he was dumb, but not being told something doesn't mean you're dumb.
It just means you don't know it.
No, I know.
But it's like, you know, maybe three times where he could be complicit in.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
And I'm like, how many other times?
You know, those are just three times that I know.
I'm pretty sure he showed up at the computer.
I'm pretty sure he gave it to Bedowitz.
I don't know.
Yeah.
The crux is.
Does he, did he know what was on the computer?
Did he know?
When did, when did, what did he know?
And when did he know it?
Yeah.
So I don't know.
There's no way to find that out.
I asked Q foes when I was writing the book, do you have any, any correspondence with Heineck
during this time?
And they said they'd helped me like three times.
I never responded.
They probably just thought I was a crazy person.
Yeah.
Well, far be it from I to try to off, you know, a UFO legend in jail and hiding.
Like he's, he's definitely contributed.
I don't know.
I, I, I'm going to err on the, on the side of like what I'd like to think, which is basically
my whole MO because unless something convinces me that something's one way, I'm going to,
I'm going to think the thing that makes me feel better until I get contravening.
Because you know, if I don't, cause if I don't, I go down the paranoid path.
Yeah.
But I view the thrust of your work as, um, inconvenient truths that you are laying out before people.
And I like that.
I mean, that's an interesting way of thinking.
Well, I checked up on the stuff myself.
That's why I believe it.
If I hadn't checked up on it, if I hadn't written project beta.
Yeah.
I would probably doubt it more.
I, but because you know, I, I didn't experience, I wouldn't be an experienced what I experienced.
I talked to the people I talked to.
Yes.
I don't know if I was lied to with Doty.
I know was lied to a few times.
So like 95% or more 97% of what we told, he told me it's not in the book.
Cause there's no way to tell.
And the stuff where I just got it from him, it was relevant to the story.
I said, Doty's the only person that told me this.
One other interesting data point is in 1982, Rick Doty gets in touch with another UFO researcher, Linda Moulton Howe.
And she's shown a bunch of documents around presidential, you know, knowledge of UFOs and aliens, as well as Project Garnett, which involves accelerated evolution of humanity with alien intervention.
Is that right?
That I don't remember.
Okay.
See, a lot of stuff I wrote about.
Yeah.
More stuff has come out since then.
Some of which is accurate.
Some of which isn't.
Yeah.
And you may very well be right.
I do not know what was in those documents.
I thought it had something to do partially with some of the cattle millilation stuff she was doing, but it was a bunch of different.
Yeah, no.
Well, I believe it had both, but this is based partially.
She was very excited.
I actually talked to Tom Adams.
Uh huh.
I think afterwards, who was a cattle millilation researcher.
And she went up and visited them right.
Like a couple of days after that.
And she was like over the moon.
She's like, Oh my God, I saw all this great stuff.
It's so important.
Right.
So she, she, she took the bait at the time.
I don't know what she thinks about it now.
Yeah.
Well, she was later, um, interviewed in a, in a documentary and she was like, I just don't want you to paint this, that the whole UFO thing is BS.
I was tricked in this one instance, but the idea that UFOs are a cover for just prosaic technology is totally wrong.
In fact, it's the opposite prosaic technology is often used as a cover for UFO.
It's an interesting discussion.
Yeah.
Um, it's probably both.
In fact, it's demonstrably both.
Well, there you go.
Yeah.
Sort of, you know, but that's, yeah, it's separate from the UFO issue itself, which, you know, I, people think that after I wrote that book, you think it's all like military.
It's like, no.
Yeah.
There's no way that the entire UFO phenomenon is, is military or intelligence connected.
So you just used some of the UFO stuff is genuinely anomalous.
And by genuinely anomalous, I mean, not explained by prosaic atmospheric conditions.
Oh, definitely.
And not explained by a military tech advancement.
Definitely.
Yeah.
I mean, there's, there's so many hundreds of thousands of things that have no connection.
There's no connection than military anything.
I agree with that too.
And I, I find it frustrating that this case that you write about so, so well, uh, needs to be contended with as a, uh, modality of how UFOs are used from a counterintelligence perspective.
Yeah.
And you need to have those, that sets of goggles on when viewing everything in the UFO world.
But, uh, you can't throw the baby out with the bathwater.
Yeah.
In some ways that's maybe even the goal that like you, you're losing if you think the whole thing is fake.
Well, that's, there's that belief thing.
Again, if you believe something so strongly, that's all you ever going to see.
Hmm.
And so there's people, there's all kinds of opinions about it, whatever people's beliefs are.
But, um, the, the, the project beta, I mean, I, I wrote it because, well, because I made the proposal and the publisher said, let's do this one.
Yeah.
You know, um, Patrick Quij and, and Simon and Schuster said, let's do this one.
I said, okay.
Um, but so many different weird accusations I've had about, it's like, oh, you're cooperating with the government.
It's like, no, I was trying to tell a story.
That's like saying that some, that's like saying that, uh, Vincent Bugliosi cooperated with Manson.
He's just writing a story about it.
Yeah.
A very opinionated story.
But that's a weird analogy.
Cause I think Bugliosi, who was the lead prosecutor of the case and wrote helter skelter about Manson.
Okay.
Got a lot wrong.
Gerardo Rivera was, was, was, uh, cooperating with Manson.
There you go.
Okay.
They had that weird interview online.
That's fine.
On TV.
Yeah.
The whole thing.
Oh, he wrote it.
Did he write a, he wrote a book about the Kennedy assassination that said that Oswald did it
and there's no way around that.
And that's right.
Yeah.
So for your sake, I want, I just want you to be clear, no ulterior motives for you.
Okay.
What am I saying?
It's a, if you report on anything, it means that you agree with it or disagree that it's
like, no, I don't agree or disagree with what I put in the book.
I think, I think a lot of stuff that happened was absolutely morally wrong and shouldn't have
happened.
Yeah.
Of course you're documented, but I'm not going to put that in the book or say anything about
it.
I've, I've had people like a convention of when I first started doing this and lecturing about
it, like, why don't you tell, you know, why didn't you just say how wrong it was?
It's like, what am I supposed to do?
Tell you what your, what I was moral and is not.
Yeah.
I think you got a better sense of what's right and wrong than, you know, I would give you,
I could, that I would be assuming.
It's also, I didn't, I mean, I'm just, you should know as much of the facts as you can
and you make up your own decisions based on that.
I think you're also in UFO world.
You're kind of setting yourself up for failure.
If you polemicize everything, because you're setting yourself up as the arbiter of right
and wrong and truth and untruth.
And then you're going to get stuff wrong.
You're, you're dealing with the most speculative stuff.
So there were times where I've, I've been tempted to make videos like the most steel manning
I've done or like, you know, it's like I did this piece on Harold Malmgren and I'm probably
going to come up with like a rebuttal on, you know, certain.
Oh yeah.
Cause there was that big D D Johnson thing about it, which I'm happy to address now.
Um, uh, I think it's excruciatingly obvious that Harold Malmgren was CIA.
Yeah.
Uh, and you know, he says my agency a bunch of times and his daughter goes the state department.
And he's holding Paul Mellon's walking stick, which he didn't buy at a yard sale.
Yeah.
And you know, uh, uh, so Paul Mellon is one of the founders of the CIA.
He says, Tom Farmer is his best friend, the general counsel of the CIA.
Yeah.
Uh, he's this like spooky trade representative in all these cases.
Uh, he's, he, he was helping formulate the presidential daily briefing.
Yeah.
So the guy was CIA.
You can a lot of debunking is based on the most likely thing, especially with UFOs.
Let's the most likely thing is a prosaic explanation.
So that's the explanation.
And we're going to do anything we can.
Well, you literally work yourself towards that prosaic explanation because that that's
the, you work from a point of view rather than from a, well, I've seen which UFO people
are completely guilty of.
I've seen his diary and I don't think it's a fake diary.
Yeah.
Richard Bissell is all over it.
Richard Bissell is the founder of area 51 and the guy who he claimed to get briefed on other
world technologies from, and he's, you know, even, uh, D Dean Johnson admits that he's in
his phone book or whatever.
So there there's connectivity there.
He says in a 2024 interview before me, I was at the IDA, but that was a cover for my real
work for the joint chiefs and the Pentagon.
Yeah.
So all I'm saying is we, everybody in the audience believes that, you know, probably the CIA
killed JFK.
And if you really connect the dots, who, who called the shots?
There was Alan Dulles at the Brown brothers Harriman.
So you're talking about this time where you can't just do a FOIA from the FBI and know
that if the person who, you know, uh, uh, got their queue clearance through the CIA, you,
you have no idea if they have their queue clearance.
It's ridiculous.
Yeah.
So I just think that plus like a few anecdotes about, you know, certain people not being
aware of him or whatever is insane as a, as a sort of like a whole debunk.
And then there were a lot of, I thought it felt like.
From what I know of it, it sounds like the, the D he did the, I think he and a few other
people try it.
No, it wasn't him, but the Travis Walton case.
Yeah.
And there, and they talk about this fire tower and it's like, it was right next to the road.
It's like, no, it's not.
Yeah.
It's over a hill.
You think they're so stupid.
They don't know what a fire tower is.
Yeah.
Just stuff like that.
Not, I'm not saying the whole story is true because of that.
I'm not either.
The debunk is so ridiculous on the face of it.
Yes.
I got, I, one of my friends stopped talking to me because I said, get better evidence
if you're going to debunk.
No, it's true.
Like I, I actually, I like debunks.
I like skepticism.
It's, it's not like a.
Oh, I don't, I don't not want to see a debunk.
No.
I want to see a.
A good debunk.
Well done one.
I agree.
Which takes as much as, you know, not everything, but takes as much into account as you can
and, and answers all the different data points.
I agree.
No, it's like, um, Kendrick and Drake, you know, dis, disses back and forth.
Yeah.
Except it's great.
If you do the debunk and then I'll do the debunk of the debunk and we'll get better and
we'll get to the truth.
And if you win fantastic.
Cause we're getting close to the truth.
So I think it's all, it's all good.
And it's all love, but, um, yeah, it's a bad, it's not a good debunk in this case.
It's just not.
Um, and then there, there are issues with the, uh, you know, bluegill triple prime.
I think according to Jeffrey Cruikshank, who I'm in touch with, um, who's analyzed this stuff really
deeply, apparently Johnson's actually kind of really scared.
He realized he got a lot wrong when it came to that the booster trajectory could not have,
you know, it wasn't at all near the plume.
Right.
And then it's funny.
You have disagreements between the debunkers.
Now, um, where my buddy Merrick von Randenkamp, who I think is, is great, but I think he's
wrong in this case, said it was the instrumentation pod.
And DD and Johnson's like, no, it's not the instrumentation pod.
It's the booster.
And then Jeff Cruikshank shows that it's not the booster or the instrumentation pod.
Yeah.
So I think they're sort of running on a thing like a dog with a bone until, you know, it's
until it's obvious that it's, they don't have it anymore.
That's right.
So anyways, all of that's to say, I could be wrong.
I am not, you know, I'm not the arbiter of truth.
I'm covering things.
I do feel a little more inclined to defend a guy who just died.
Who's 89 years old, who to me, you know, this is probably the softest, most qualitative
point I'll make, but just pattern matches to a great statesman who really helped the
U S in an earnest way over decades and was kind of a quiet operator.
Yeah.
Uh, so, uh, that's, that's all I'll say on that.
But yeah, no, I see an analogy of how I feel about Bill Moore.
It's like, I know him, I know his motivations.
I know his, you know, political stance.
I know his moral code and all of it fits with what he said.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And it also fits with how, how upset he gets with people that get it all wrong.
And then haven't been through it.
Well, I empathize for that with that or sympathize.
I, you know, and I'll, I'll even say this now.
I would bet that I'm a horrible dupe.
No, for sure.
Well, I would say I'll, I'll bet.
I would bet that in the future, I will have to retract a thing.
That I cover.
Of course.
I mean, you are dealing with the most speculative topic on the planet.
I mean, so if you, you know, so it's like, I will get to be willing to be wrong.
I guarantee I will get stuff wrong.
That's the only guarantee.
And then like, if I get stuff right, then it's like the most important stuff ever because
it's like so uncorrelated with the consensus reality that, you know, you're contributing in this exciting way.
Yeah.
So I, I think that's the way you have to view everything.
You can't take yourself too seriously and attach your ego to any of this.
Oh, no.
Yeah. That's the problem.
I mean, it's really hard to detach your ego from whatever opinion or research you've done.
So, um, getting back to the cord story.
Okay.
So, so, so, so Rick Doty then comes out after this whole saga and he says that I am now on
the side of the truth.
And you see him on, you know, UFO Twitter or whatever, and you see him, you know, getting
interviewed on Gaia and, you know, saying we have this many alien races.
And these were these crashes that really happened.
They see these extraterrestrials, these four and a half foot tall, gray colored entities.
He even recently said that Lou Elizondo was part of Space Force disinformation or something.
And so he's going after some of the other, you know, whistleblowers, um, in UFO world.
What's up with Rick Doty now?
And is he at all trustworthy?
Rick Doty the first chapter of that book that I gave you, it defies language.
The title is the chat of the chapter is you play the game or you get nothing.
And I believe, and what that means is you can be paranoid that somebody is going to tell
you BS or disinfo or lead you down a path or whatever.
But if you're not in the game playing, you know, if you're not sitting at the table playing
cards with people that are just handing you bad cards all the time.
And occasionally a nice one, you'll never get anything.
So, and I think that applies to Doty, maybe a little less now than it used to, because
I think less of what he says is either true, relevant or whatever.
And I think that's mainly because he likes messing with people.
Um, that's his personality.
He's basically, he's, you know, he's a troll.
He likes it.
He likes messing.
I mean, as far as I can tell, he probably won't want to talk to me again after this.
He, he made a, he made a statement a few years ago.
He never wanted to talk to me again.
Wow.
Because I said something about the Serpo thing where apparently there was some exchange
with some other planet and some other star system.
Yeah.
And he was a document leak.
Uh, um, it was more like an info leak that was coming through a couple of sources
on the internet.
Uh huh.
And it involves like, um, hydrogen isotopes or something and exotic propulsion and some
spooky science.
And that I'm not sure of all I remember was it was basically was like the, the last scene
in close encounters where a bunch of people from the earth go to another planet.
And then some of the aliens come here.
So the Serpo thing was planet Serpo sent a bunch of aliens here.
And we sent a bunch of humans to their star system in an exchange in the 1970s.
Do you think, do you think any of this is, have you heard of cicada 3301?
No.
It's okay.
So it's this weird, like online scavenger hunt puzzle that involved complex mathematics
that was presented in 2014.
And I'm going to screw up some of the details, but like very high level, I think it involved
like you had to solve it.
You needed a serious math, you know, aptitude.
Yeah.
And a lot of people think that the whole puzzle was set up by the NSA or CIA.
And it was like a recruitment tool.
Right.
Yeah.
Do you think some of this stuff that's coming out through Doty or other people is some sort
of initiation path?
Or do you think it is all passage material to catch bad actors or Rorschach test to test
people's belief structures?
Or what do you think?
I don't think, I don't think it's so much that anymore.
It's more like when I first saw that article in 2017, the New York
Times article, the Kane Blumenthal thing.
Yeah.
With Elizondo in it.
The first thing I thought was, what new project are they trying to ingrain within the,
with the, trying to, what's it called, mix with the UFO subject?
And for what purpose?
So I didn't think it was a purpose.
Do you have a top candidate for what that project might be?
And do you think that the 2017 article was sort of, of the same variety as whatever happened
to Benowitz?
No, I don't think it was a Benowitz thing because we live in a different time where information
is disseminated in a completely different way than it was then.
But do you, do you think those, you don't think those three videos that came out?
I don't think they were faked.
I'm pretty sure they weren't faked.
Okay.
But I think, you know, Rorschach blot again, Swiss army knife again, get something that everybody's
interested in.
There's a lot of emotion around it.
There's no real idea about what it might be and then use it for whatever you need to
use it for either to deflect or direct attention.
And I think, and this is just me being dumb at the time.
And I think still, although in the last few months, it's probably messed up now.
I think there was a cold war going on with China and they're just trying to keep it from
going hot.
I have a friend that lives near Los Alamos.
This friend told me, you want a job?
And I said, what?
She said, Los Alamos is hiring.
I said, I don't, I don't have any of those skills.
It was a woman.
She said, you can, you can, you can write English competently.
Can't you?
It's like, yeah, you edit video.
They need those people.
I said, why, why does Los Alamos need those people?
She said, there's a huge nuclear arms race going on right now and they're building bombs
like mad.
Um, and, uh, and I just thought it sort of coincided with what all this big buildup with
the, and I don't know if it's directly related.
But I think the UFO subject right now is being used as a, as a fulcrum to figure out what
people think, where people's attention can be drawn.
I mean, it's just, I, I see it as this giant, like social experiment saying, you know, how
can we use this to our advantage?
Right.
Um, and on top of that, there's a technology advantage.
Um, there's a advantage where you have some technology that might look like that.
And that can be, you know, attention to be directed towards or away from that.
Um, and I, you know, I know that sounds vague, but I'm not privy to that information.
I mean, you probably had other people on here that probably know a lot more than I do about
that.
Um, but my suspicion is that it's being used for, um, uh, political gamesmanship, um, uh,
covering up, uh, uh, defense tech, black projects, all that stuff.
Well, it's definitely being allowed to be amplified at the very least.
Yeah.
And I look at some of the people.
And I think it's metastasized and, and, and that it's all over the place now.
Cause somebody probably thought, let's just do this little thing announces because I guess
the time has come and it's become this big thing.
Yeah.
The other thing I think, and I'll fit, I won't interrupt you, but the other thing I think
is it is crowdsourcing expertise around the subject.
So people would share people with the S with the training and the equipment and the, and the
motivation, but were scared to before are going to concentrate on the UFO subject and, and
put some expertise to bear on it, which was, um, uh, uh, was discouraged in the past.
It was, it was, you know, now that stigma has been lifted.
I think that that's right.
Like I think about this.
So that's a good, that's a good thing.
That's a total good thing.
I also think like one of the things that I got interested in through the UFO subject,
but in some ways, you know, is the most out of left field and uncorrelated with kind of
consensus UFOlogy, like really came out of left field was the Townsend Brown stuff around
like, you know, gravity manipulation experiments.
Oh yeah.
He said that he was really impressed with your, like digging into that Townsend Brown stuff.
You know, Bill Moore interviewed, interviewed T Townsend Brown.
I, that's why I want to talk to him because I know he did.
And I made that movie, the cosmic conspiracy about, I may have his notes from that.
I'll look for them for you.
Thank you, man.
That means a lot.
Yeah.
I'd appreciate that.
So, but with the Brown stuff, um, it's people don't know who he is.
Well, I'm also, I'm convinced that, you know, I've, I've signaled to no end that like, if I am doing anything that like seriously hurts, like American national security or like, you know, get, you know, then like I want to know.
Yeah.
But nobody, nobody said anything.
So it's like, it's just like, you know, sort of empty on the other end.
So at that point, somebody I imagine has made a call on high that like, we're going to allow some of that stuff to come out too, even though, you know, completely organically looked into it and kind of, I think corroborated a lot of his stuff.
Yeah.
And somebody probably made a call that like, you know, I'm not like extremely well versed in like some of the high level theoretical physics around it.
That at least saying this guy created this topological physics effect, you know, we're probably past the point of like that being okay.
Yeah.
Not okay.
The Bifield Brown.
Yeah.
So I, you could be right that like, there are these like surprising, but adjacent things that UFOs give you a framework for.
That like, you know,
Well, maybe whoever in the Navy or whatever was hoping for that.
Yeah.
They want like energy unlocks and they want more surface area.
And even if we don't know what UFOs are, it's going to push, but Hopkins of all, you have a whole secret science kind of initiation.
Having a recording of him from 1987 or something.
I videotaped him for a documentary and he said, UFOlogy or UFOs are, are dragging us kicking and screaming into the science of the 21st century.
And it's kind of happening now.
I agree.
Well, John Mack would talk about, you know, head of the Harvard psychiatry department, friends with Bud Hopkins.
Yeah.
You know, who would see all these, you know, abductees.
He would talk about how UFOs would inspire tech because it would look like, like you had the airships of the 1890s or whatever.
It would look like tech that was just about to come out.
And, you know, Bill Lear is quoted in 1956.
You know, he was the father of John Lear and invented the first, you know.
Lear jet.
Yeah.
The first private jet basically.
And he said, you know, I believe anti-gravity is possible because UFOs display them.
And so I, that to me is just this really important thing where it's like.
I've got kind of a chapter on anti-gravity and project beta actually.
Ah, yeah.
That's right.
About that memo from the British, whatever society of, of gravity research or something.
And it was released sometime.
The copy I saw was stamped Wright-Patterson Air Force base on it.
There you go.
And it missed about like five pages.
Like there's this big legend about the missing five pages.
Yeah.
Where it's like, it was achieved in the mid-century in and then it cuts off and then it like.
Well, we know that Wright-Airfield was sponsoring the Chapel Hill conference in 1957 at University of North Carolina with the top theoretical physicists in the world.
And at the same time, UNC Chapel Hill was sponsoring Townsend Brown's work on anti-gravity.
We know that Wright-Airfield had a dedicated team of people working on anti-gravity, which included Lewis Witten, father of Ed Witten, who was at Martin Corporation's RAS, their anti-gravity division.
And he says in an interview live that we have tape of, he goes, I was hired to do gravity by Wright-Airfield and that's what I did.
The reason there was a laboratory at Wright-Field was to find out what we were doing and to help us do it.
And I got a contract from Wright-Field to do it, to do gravity, which I did very happily.
And you have Josh Goldberg, who's a PhD from Syracuse, who's a top physicist also working on the theoretical underpinnings of anti-gravity.
Yeah.
So we know that this stuff was extremely in vogue in the 50s.
And who knows?
It may have been done or partially done.
I have a friend that was in the Air Force and he said that when they go, when the stealth fighter lands, people go in and pull panels out of it and put them in briefcases and go away.
And he said the rumor was that some of those were anti-gravity just to help it fly in a different way that, you know, not totally anti-gravity, but to help the avionics.
Yep.
That's a, that's a rumor.
That is possible.
I, I go back and forth on that with like the B2, for example, where I don't see a ton of hard evidence that the Paul-
No, there never is, but maybe that rumor was, was, was, uh, given to me just to see who would talk about it and where that would come from.
Yeah, I think that's right.
It's just one of those things where you pour dye down a, uh, like 50 pipes and you see where the dye comes out, you know?
Yeah.
Well, I track the Brown stuff pretty closely and I think his work did make it into the B2, but the part of the aspect of his work that made it into the B2 is electric fields and their ability to manage airflow over an airframe and confer a tactical advantage when it comes to reducing, uh,
the lift to drag ratio.
Right.
Okay.
So that's all I've ever found on a really first principles level.
And then there's a bunch of.
Yeah.
That might be it.
That might've been what the guy was talking about.
I think so.
But maybe it's mixed in with the Brown legend because of that.
Yeah.
Well, I, I, I, I know that I'm pretty sure 95% that Brown stuff made it into the B2 bomber.
In fact, Floyd Odlem, who is the majority owner of Northrop who funded Brown's work in the sixties paid Brown 4,000 bucks or I don't remember.
2,000 bucks, 4,000 bucks a month and his family, uh, the same amount, uh, until, until he died.
Yeah.
Until the eighties.
So I mean, that to me, Catalina or whatever.
Yeah, exactly.
Good, good memory.
Um, yeah.
So I dunno, it's fascinating.
Yeah.
UFOs really are.
You've, you've made this analogy to me on the phone before.
It's like, if you have a bunch of pipes and the pipes represent, you know, possible leaks in intelligence, you pour some dye in the pipes and you see where the dye goes.
Yeah.
And the UFOs I think are used as a tactic for that, where it's like, you sprinkle in a UFO here.
That's, you know, shouldn't be there.
Or a rumor about a UFO or some case or whatever.
And you see, it's like, don't talk about this.
Then you see who talks about it.
You see who tracks.
Yeah, exactly.
And then you see who's trustworthy.
It's funny.
A long time ago while I was working on this book and before that, from knowing Bill, if somebody tells you don't talk about this, I always think it's a test.
Me too.
I always think.
And I've, that's happened to me before.
It's happened to me on a thing that was later debunked publicly.
Yeah.
And I was like, I know what you're doing.
I know you're telling me this because you want to see if I'm going to leak it.
I was showing stuff about the Tic Tac incident and pilots whose names hadn't been released yet.
And I was told, don't talk about it.
You were, you were.
Yeah.
And then like six months later, bam, their names are out there.
And I think whoever told me.
So in your case, it was true.
Yeah, it was true.
So, so you were given like David Fravor's name before the Tic Tac incident or something?
I think Alex Dedrick and a couple others.
Whoa.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Interesting.
And I talked to Alex Dedrick later, but I didn't tell her that.
Can you say who gave you that information?
Nope.
There you go.
You passed the test to whoever did that.
That's wild.
Crazy.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Whoa.
And it doesn't mean I'm hooked into any like great network or anything, but that's, you
know, and it used to be a lot.
This would happen now about once or twice a year.
Somebody will tell me.
Yeah.
Lynn Buchanan, who I've known for a long time, the army remote viewer.
He told me like eight or nine years ago that he had met with an alien.
And he said, but don't talk about this to anybody.
He's like, why'd you meet with the alien?
He said, well, they wanted to see if I could communicate with it.
Cause I was one of the remote viewers said, but don't mention.
I was like, all right.
He said, then like five years later, he said it online somewhere.
So I can say it now.
Whoa.
Really?
Yeah.
So he's still on record claiming that he's met an alien.
The, the remote.
At least I hope it came up.
Cause I saw it later.
He had mentioned it in somebody's interview or on a podcast or something.
Where did he meet the alien?
I don't know.
He didn't tell me it was probably on a base somewhere.
At least he wanted me to think that.
Wow.
I don't know Lynn really well, but he's, I interviewed him in like 97 or something.
So I've kind of, he's, we've been meeting every once in a while since then.
And every once in a while he'll, he'll, that's the only thing he ever told me.
Don't say, don't mention it.
And I said, why'd you tell me?
He said, it's for your information.
Wow.
But there's so many little bits and pieces of information like that, that just float around.
And I think a lot of them are just kind of like throwaways of something that used to be important.
Yeah.
But it isn't anymore.
But then they become this lore in the UFO community and then they just stick and they grow.
And you know, it's, it's just, it's, you know, fertile ground for any weird rumor like this to grow.
Do you suspect like, um, Diana Pasolka came out with a quote where she, she was friends with Chris Bledsoe.
Who had all these UFO interactions.
I, by the way, I'm not in any of the drama.
I love Diana Pasolka and I love Chris Bledsoe.
I think they're both great.
I mean, I'm the same way.
So, uh, but Diana Pasolka came out and she said, I think Chris Bledsoe is a modern Paul Benowitz.
Um, Chris Bledsoe claimed to, you know, have an interaction with this goddess Hathor and see also an alien craft.
And a bunch of government people are very interested in him, which is I think pretty demonstrably true.
No, that is demonstrably true.
You know, he'll say like, I'm so kind of the same dynamic, I guess.
So do you, do you think it is the same dynamic?
Do you think they're just genuine friends or like, what do you think?
I think whoever is interested in the subject thinks he may be a key to the answer or part of it.
Hmm.
And when that happens, then they just become friendly until I've had this happen and you probably have too.
Somebody comes from the government and tells you something that nobody else knows or very few people know.
Hmm.
And then they say, you know, I'm telling you this for, not, Lynn didn't do this.
Cause we'd known each other for years, but just because they want you, they want to flatter your ego and get your confidence and find things out.
Yep.
I'm not saying that, you know, Sam Ivan or whoever, the people that are talking to him are like, you know, we're going to get all of his information and throw them down, you know, throw them, throw them out with the trash.
No, I think they're genuinely interested.
Yeah.
And they genuinely think something, some useful information can come from him.
And if they're friendly with him, they can get some of this information.
Yeah.
And they're really helpful either both for their own personal, uh, uh, quest and, and, uh, knowledge and also for whoever they might be working with or for.
Totally.
I don't think, you know, some of these.
Not to say that any of those people, that all those people are wonderful and moral, but.
Yeah.
But I don't think, I don't think you can immediately jump to the conclusion that they are modern Rick Doty's either.
I think.
No, no, no.
It's a different dynamic.
You can be in the government and earnestly want disclosure.
Yeah.
And usually if you're in the government, there are caveats to your earnest desire for disclosure that involve national security.
But I, I, yeah, I don't think.
I don't paint them with all of them with this evil brush.
I don't think you can.
Because that's not how the world works.
I don't think you can a priori impugn anybody's motives unless they prove to be really, you know, bad actors.
Yeah.
And if they do and they're working in intelligence, they're not always bad actors.
It's always something or other.
And that's why I, you know, I think, you know, for my, they'd said, what do you think of Richard Doty?
It's like, I don't hate him.
Yeah.
I don't think he's evil.
I just think he was doing his job and he likes messing with people and that's it.
Also.
And what he did, some of the things he did were morally wrong and he knows it.
Also, if we have, you know, take it face value that we had a remote viewing program for 23 years at the very least.
We probably have covert remote viewing programs now and take it face value that some of that remote viewing was effective.
You have a guy in North Carolina who is claiming these like remarkable stories around kind of a miracle healing that he's experienced.
And, you know, messages that he's getting involving prophecies.
If you take the first thing as a real intelligence modality that obviously needs to be corroborated by other intelligence modalities, you're going to take seriously this dude in North Carolina.
Yeah.
And you're going to be probably very interested in that.
You've got antenna up and you're correlating all kinds of different information, most of which might be BS.
Sure.
But the stuff that isn't is worth all the others combing through this stuff.
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
The thing I've found too, I don't know if you've found this, but sometimes people inside the government are more conspiratorial than people on the outside.
Like you assume that.
Because they've seen it.
That's right.
They see it all the time.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Once you're in this for anything where you get a little glimpse into how some famous person or some, you know, somebody that's not too many people know or a government operator.
When you see what's going on with them, just get a little glimpse of it.
Yeah.
You realize how much what we all see and in the news and all that has already been decided like months or years before.
But it's not like, you know, it's not some conspiracy.
It's just the way the world works.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're not, you and I are only privy to a certain amount of information and other people are privy to less and other are more, way more.
And there's, you know, it's kind of our, you know, you and I are interested in, it's like, what are those people above us doing?
What is coming down the road?
How is that going to affect us?
What does the past look like because of that?
What does the future look like because of that?
Who does it affect?
You know, should I be emotional about this?
Is there a moral issue with this?
I want to know all these things.
And so I've got antenna up just like these weirdo government people and I've learned things from them, too.
You know, just how to operate and how to think.
And part of that, like you said, is being a little bit paranoid, but only a little bit because I've been a lot paranoid for about a year and I didn't like it.
That's a lot paranoid is never good.
I made this documentary with David Grush in September of 2023.
After he testified before Congress, he said that he, you know, gave over like I think like hundreds of pages, maybe over a thousand pages to the, you know, intelligence community inspector general, you know, experienced reprisals based on his blowing the whistle.
And he brought forward 40 people directly to the ICIG who had, you know, worked on this stuff firsthand and we're still in this sort of liminal space, even though he did all that, which is kind of crazy.
I just wanted to put enough out there, touch on all the most sensitive parts, like the biologic side and like things that really need to come out.
Yeah.
But I don't want to overly disclose because it's not my job.
I don't know him well.
I don't even know if I know the details about, remember the details about what he was saying, except to, you know, shore up that the government is interested in the subject has been for a long time and a lot deeper than we think.
Yeah. Well, the substance of what he said is that we have non-human bodies, pilots, craft, we have, you know, craft in our possession that we have.
Okay. Yeah. Now I'm remembering.
Yeah. Crashes on record. He talks about the Magenta crash, 1933.
He even kind of talks about, you know, possible agreements, I believe, in the Ross Coulthard interview.
And then he says he has all these firsthand witnesses. And again, like I know him to have a very eidetic sort of memory and to be a very, you know, intense kind of, you know, as mild autism, you know, researcher.
So yeah, he does, you know, definitely not fit the pattern of some of these other really slick and smooth, savvy guys. So it's interesting.
Yeah. Well, the mistake I think people make with Grush and other people is that they want to know if they're telling the truth or not.
Like that's not the question. I think the question is, is what they're saying relevant and can connections be made with what they say to other things that things have been said and also documentation, if you can get it.
It's just kind of this, it's a, I keep using the word concatenation, but it's a concatenation of all this stuff together.
And when somebody says, well, I think that person's lying. It's like, why? Because he said this, it's like, he said like 500 things.
Yeah. So you're saying everything he said is a lie based on this one thing you think is a lie or have you proven as a lie or is wrong or inaccurate.
That's not how the world works. No, it's especially not how the UFO world works.
Yeah. I think it's tough being in that whistleblower position because the more you say, the more surface area exists on, you know, what you, yeah.
The more falsifiable, there's, there's more ways for people to get their hooks in and pull you apart. Yeah.
And it's going to happen. It's not like you're commenting on, you're not like a sports commentator on ESPN.
People are like, this is the truth. And if you said one wrong thing. Yeah. Well, that's different because I, I, I always had that analogy.
People look at that analogy. People made it with this was bought into a court of law. Then, you know, it'd be proven. It's like, no, it wouldn't because we know about murders and robberies and stuff.
This is dealing with something we can't bring in a lab and prove and not many people had experience with.
So it's a whole different thing. And it's throwing all these different definitions we have.
And, you know, I hate the word ontology, but throwing everybody's ontology into question.
Yeah. It's like, how much of this are you going to let into your life? How much of this is relevant to you?
You know, is it just like, you know, is it just like talking about movies and TV shows or something? Or does this mean more?
I think it means way more, but I also don't know how much of this stuff is going to much more of it.
It's going to come out because I think that every time the government says, Hey, let's look at UFOs for a while.
When the usefulness of looking at it and having it in the public is gone, bam, it's gone.
And then suddenly everybody's like, well, you were just going to tell us what it was.
And this has been the longest and the strongest I've ever seen it go on.
And so I don't know what the end game is, but I have a really strong feeling that as soon as whoever gets what they need to get or it's not useful anymore, that faucet's going to be turned off.
I hope I'm wrong because I'd like to see something.
Although the disclosure thing still kind of irritates because my one quote about it and I keep saying it and I've been saying it for years.
Disclosure is like asking the parent that always lies to you to tell you the truth just this one time.
And if they don't tell you what you want to hear, they're lying.
I love that.
Well, there are two vectors though.
There's like, is the government ever going to like let some of this stuff ultimately out in the way of like showing you a craft?
And what do they know?
And what do they actually know?
Yeah.
Like, do they actually know anything as far as like some metaphysical worldview that it's super concrete as opposed to, you know, maybe not.
Maybe it's.
Yeah.
I mean, it's too, too much to admit it because it's not explainable in terms that people would understand.
Yes.
What's the point?
And it's much more useful the way it is now, which is that that Swiss army knife that I was talking about.
Yeah.
But I do think so.
There are two different vectors.
There's the government vector.
I do think if we just followed up on some of David Grush's, you know, face value claims, that would be like really exciting if we could like corroborate, you know, some of those.
And it's crazy that it still exists in this liminal kind of, kind of, kind of space.
Well, the UFO exists in a liminal space.
So it drags everything else along with it.
Right.
Right, right, right, right, right.
I mean, that's the model it's coming from.
So it's going to be fighting that the whole time.
Yeah, right.
Sure.
Prove this liminality to me.
Break, you know, collapse the waveform.
I don't know if that's going to happen.
Well, that, yeah.
I mean, then you're getting into deeper stuff, which is so there's a government vector and then there's like a belief consensus reality vector.
And like most people believe there's aliens and exist and UFOs are real.
Most people believe that.
Yeah, no, it's like probably over 50% of America.
Yeah.
So if there's some other like version of reality that is egregoric in nature where like you are literally, you know, going to create the manifesting things in your purview, then the amount of momentum that I see now has to turn into something.
And I don't know what that turns into.
I don't know either.
I like that Whitley Strieber quote where he said the government was keeping it secret because if enough people believed in it, would it allow it in?
Fascinating.
I think he said that in Communion?
No, it wasn't in Communion.
It was in his Majestic.
It was his semi-fictional account of the Roswell crash and everything after it.
Right, right, right.
Really good.
A lot of metaphors in there which are still relevant and I still go back to.
I love it.
Well, I'll check that out.
Have you had Whitley on?
I have.
Yeah?
He's always a good, he's always a good interview.
And people, I was at Contact.
Uh huh.
I got to get up on, I got to speak at Contact.
I wasn't scheduled.
Amazing.
But I got up on stage because Dean Alioto showed his film Alien Perspective.
Uh huh.
And one of the first things I said when I was, they asked me for a statement.
I said, and I've said this before, you know why I believe, like people say, do you believe Whitley Strieber?
I said, I believe him in the way I believe, you know, the Beatles or the Foo Fighters or Van Gogh or, you know, Jackson Pollock.
He's a great artist.
He's a great artist telling you the truth of how he sees something that has affected him.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, I think that's the case of, you know, when it comes to a lot of experiences.
And then people say, well, then he just made it up.
It's like, no, art doesn't come from nothing.
It comes from, it comes from the artist's feelings.
It, his or her, um, life experience, everything.
And the way Whitley's explaining to us is the way an artist would explain the abduction phenomenon to us.
And it's in a way that nobody else talks about it like, like he does.
And I've, I've enjoyed it from the beginning.
Well, that's a beautiful note to end on Greg Bishop.
Thank you so much for coming on.
Thank you for your work.
Everybody go out and buy project beta as well as it defies language.
And, um, yeah, thank you, man.
Thanks a lot.
All right.
Thank you.