A few, uh, very bright particles or fragments or something that, uh, go drifting by as we maneuver.
I do understand.
There's a whole bunch of big ones on my window, then.
Just bright.
Looks like the 4th of July outruns, Wendell.
Yeah, and now you can see some of them in shape.
They're very, uh, jagged, angular fragments or tumbling.
Right, they look like fluid or something, sir?
Not to me, they look like pieces or something, uh.
Roger.
They're very bright.
Jack, we'd like Omni, Charlie.
Okay.
Thank you.
Well, you know, I don't know, there are a number of possibilities.
If you had some kind of a, I got the impression maybe they were curved a little bit, as if
they might be off the side of the S-4B, and that's a wild guess.
Okay, RCS logic is...
Ice chunks, possibly, and maybe there's paint coming off of it.
Roger, I noticed on one trip up the elevator last week, one of the flags, I thought it
was in the S-2, but it might be on the S-4, it looked like it was peeling.
Maybe that's what you got.
And the S-4B maneuver is complete.
One minute.
Okay, we'll set the o'clock.
Okay, and with the maneuver complete, the fragment field is essentially static, except for a
very slight tumbling within the fragment.
Roger, copy that.
Every once in a while, a fragment of considerably higher velocity than the others goes across
my window, but that's very rare.
Roger.
Okay, that's that field of view I saw on my...
Jack, do you see it now?
Yeah.
Bob, at least there's no apparent relative motion between fragments.
I do understand.
I'll take two pictures about a minute apart, if I can, and it'll be frame 70.
Okay, frame 70.
And, Bob, it's Gino, my impression is that they are flat, flake-like particles, some maybe
six inches across.
And, although there's no relative motion between the two, most of them seem to be twinkling.
And I think, for the most part, they're all moving away from us.
I focus on finishing up a minute apart, of different directions.
So you can say-
I don't know, but they can say thank you for the most part.
So you want to choose what we get here?
Okay.
I'm going to try to see it when seeing and then say I'm going to be 요즘 them.
So, I mean, it's too...
How you do what I do, folks?
So you got like a question.
So I'm going to say, if I'm going to be doingflake and maybe you Wu, and I can manage that.