Chevy Control here again.
Earlier in the flight, you'll recall, at the start of the Second Revolution,
we had a reference to several objects that the crew spotted.
This was in the area of Antigua.
Due to a mechanical breakdown, we did not have that portion of the tape available for you.
This was a line breakdown between Building 30 and our new center in Building 6.
Since then, we have dubbed the tape off the master tape here in the control center,
and we are now prepared to play it for you.
It contains references to sighting not only some particles,
but as well as an unidentified object,
plus the booster.
Here's that tape. We'll play it for you now.
Gemini 7 here, Houston on your 8.
Loud and clear. 7, go ahead.
Bogey at 10 o'clock high.
This is Houston. Say again, 7.
So we have a bogey at 10 o'clock high.
Roger.
Gemini 7, is that the booster, or is that an actual sighting?
Not working.
Say again, 7.
Roger.
We have several, looks like a three up there, actual sighting.
Do you have any more information, estimated distance or size?
Roger.
We also have the booster in sight.
Understand you also have the booster in sight.
Roger.
And we have very, very many, looks like hundreds of little particles going by from the west,
going by from the west, out about three to four miles.
Understand you have many small particles going by on the left, at what distance?
Four miles.
Roger.
Looks like a, perhaps a vehicle that's disintegrated.
Understand they're about three to four miles away.
They're past now.
They're going to pull a little bit.
Roger.
And understand they were about three to four miles away.
Gemini 7 Houston, were these particles in addition to the booster and the bogey at 10 o'clock
high?
Command.
Roger.
Uh, 7, this is, uh, Houston, this is 7.
Go ahead.
I have the, uh, booster on my side.
It's a brilliant body of the sun, just a back, uh, black background.
There's a brilliant particles around it.
Roger.
What direction is it from you?
It's about at my two o'clock position.
Does that mean it's ahead of you?
It's ahead of us, 2 o'clock, slowly doubling.
Roger.
4S-9-1.
5S-9-1.
7S-9-1.
Show me control here again.
The reference in that conversation to the third unidentified object, of course, was, or the third object was a bogie.
There were several references to the bogey. This is the unidentified object, in addition to particles which appear to be headed in a polar orbit, you heard Frank Borman say, plus Jim Lovell discussing the booster. It was Borman who reported sighting the bogey.
This is Germany Control in Houston at four hours, 24 minutes into the flight.
Thank you.