And now at one hour at this time, I now have one hour and 21 minutes, and I am observing John's fireflies drifting away from me.
I can observe them sort of a departing from the spacecraft and drifting out to the rear. I can see some of them a considerable distance out to the rear.
The sun is coming up behind me. I am beginning to get the glow on the clouds.
Fireflies appear to be white. Very whitish, almost a green like rail fireflies.
I think that's all we've been able to harvest at the graduate point which goes 1,000 by 2.7 million miles away from me.
More light updates have been.
Feedback gives me a lot of energy perspective.
Finance relations.
Clouds on the Earth below are changing color, are getting quite light.
I am now on the day side, the sun is not yet quite up, and I am in the middle of the day side.
And I am observing stars. The Earth is light below me, the sun is still behind me, the sky looks dark above me, and I can see stars very distinctly.