a little bit there uh listen we read this paragraph in here about these quotes coronal
discharges that you guys were seeing and and that that completely stops us tell tell us what how
this came about and who who talked to you about and what and what you saw he reported it on or
somebody reported on one of the earlier flights that uh some guy up like a letter his paperwork
somewhere they shipped it down to me at the cape about two things where the vhf radio noises which
could be discharged from some places and the other ones were i thought it was a neil flight he said
airport is seeing flashes on spacecraft it's nice with their eyes closed they noticed them when they
were awake at night the spacecraft was dark and they thought they were in the spacecraft but whoever
this guy was said no that's a perfectly known phenomenon you can get discharged across your
eye from gamma rays or something so he said what you think would we close our eyes and face the moon
you know when we were orbiting it because it would be more you get less discharges facing the moon and
away from them but you don't have to be anywhere near the moon or anywhere the first night happening
and if you keep your eyes closed and your weight down there and it's dark and you think about it
but it happens you can trade your hat because you can spin down and it's one eye it's not a discharges
you can see in both sides you really see it with one eye or the other eye and you can see what kind
it is we had two kinds i guess the particle either strike the eyeball perpendicular or or a discharges
parallel and we'd get either a flag like that or we'd get a streak and uh and i feel that i know
that they either got a flag or a streak and i for some reason got more with my left eye and my right
eye so i could tell which eye it was that i was concentrating on i'm trying to tell the reason he did
it's because his where he left was always on the left side of the spacecraft
they should have protected you dick they should have all they should have picked them all up
i remember their their conversation about it
charge they thought it was something you know penetrating the spacecraft
what pete described is the exact phenomenon of all three of us you see a light you know just a
plaque out there or sometimes there'll be a on the street and i saw them in both eyes either i and
i can't remember if there was one of the more predominant than the other but i agree with p is
a phenomenon that you're not seeing with both eyes it's not something external to you there's something
that's inside the target coming across is that one apparently they know that apparently they're
completely known known phenomenon well we've been looking for uh cosmic rays you know cosmic rays
strikes and uh uh heavy heavy particles heavy nuclei that go through you know we started at clearback
and mercury taking uh photographs of the retina to see if you could see his streaks across the
retina and stuff we never could find any in there and so we stopped that up early and uh well by the
end of the site your eye is what the fastest healer on your body and if it's doing anything you're never
going to see it by the time you get a guy back you know they're going to see it if you photograph it right
well probably what what it's doing anyway is probably hitting just a single cell and uh yeah that's all it
have to do particularly make this flash you know you hit a single spell i saw one night
looking at the mdp a handrail up above and one right right along i don't know where it went here you
know right straight along that handrail for about that that's just i just got to be looking at that
but now you could almost see in the wheel that's right where you just lie there you close your eyes
what if they don't want to see you on it you open one eye and you doesn't already see it you didn't
believe it at first that we thought it was right and uh hey i'm just being spring loaded from that
you know when we uh heard that i had to keep seeing them that got like they said remember the mission
you wake up at night and say well i think i don't see something you can close your eyes
uh let me ask you one more question about heart uh oh here were these random uh distribution
okay uh were these were these things random that or did they all seem to be in one direction like
were they always horizontal or were they at random they could be at any kind of angle
but the streets i saw were minus one i saw were horizontal i'm just going to say that's
interesting mine it seemed to me i had the impression that they were always roughly in the same
place and mine were horizontal the horizontal streets were always if i knew where i was looking it always
seemed like the horizontal street was a little bit above the center and it always seemed to me it went from
right to the left no matter which i was in the uh the uh discharges were more towards the center and it
would be just it was just like a pinpoint of light when they closed again like somebody was flashing a light at you
whatever whatever that's right yeah not too big or light it yeah it wasn't still your eye very small
yeah yeah
that about the same for both of you is that the same uh reaction you had dick and al the way he described it
what's that yeah i remember about 30 degrees of horizontal but they were coming see i didn't
know it was from the right or left that's pretty interesting yeah but about the same they seem to
appear about the same place no i know the ones the horizontal ones that i saw were generally above either
the same way yeah now i don't know that i can't include any other i can't remember i just don't
remember him being down on the lower part of the division well i think you see that dick's telling
you about seeing him with his eyes open and and other things that he centered his eye on the lights on the
instrument panel well i used to notice on the boat and one of us down there in a sleeping bag of us
pitch black down there in the hole and what makes you difference with my eyes were open or close
but i could lay there for if you kill a time that way you say for a half an hour and either open them
or close them and wait and sure enough after a while you get one and then i sit there for a while
and say okay there's a left eye or the right eye take you a while to sort it out and but you usually
figure out which eye it was in now you know what you're doing you're supposed to be sleeping
yeah there was a comment that