I have some pretty stars in sight, and also I have the little white objects that seem to come from the capsule itself, and drift off.
And if they are a yaw check, it's fantastic. I suspect that the star I see is...
...Octurus would be very interesting. It is neither. It is one of the white objects.
So I have two stars that are standing quite still. The white object actually looked like it came toward me, but it wasn't.
You can actually see the particle there, going off. As John described, there's a lathe shaving. It's a very good description of it.
My rates are now just about zero in all three axes.
I still have light in the periscope, of course. I'm looking straight up.
And yet, at this point, there's to be that my altitude is...
I guess the couch here, I really can't pick it too well. Yeah, I'm just about inverted at this point.
And that my nose is above the horizon.
As a result, I notice that these particles keep tending aft on me, relative to me, at any time.
The periscope is blocking out rather rapidly, at sunset.
It's almost blocked out completely at this point, and it's really not usable.
What's the pasti path?
I'm not afraid of exactly with the camera, but I'll try to keep it backwards at that point.
Getting a real burst of light in the window and I really don't know what it is.
At this point I should be coming up on a sunset, 5 hours and 15 minutes.
The telescope is dark. I must be just getting a last look at the horizon, yet I'm not down on it.