I have some more of the white particles in view below the capsule. They appear to be traveling exactly my speed. There is one drifting off. It's going faster than I am, as a matter of fact.
Roger. Understand. I haven't seen the great numbers of these particles, but I have seen a few of them. Their motion is random. They look exactly like snowflakes to me.
Roger. Have you tried returning? Negative. Let me get within scanner limits first.
Say yes. I must adjust my attitude to within scanner limits first.
Roger.
There were some more of those little particles. They definitely look like snowflakes this time.
Roger. I understand your particles look like definite snowflakes. However...
Mr. Scott? Roger.
Mr. Scott?