Ok, we're recording. State Planet Origin?
Alright.
Ok, yesterday you told us you traveled and I put thousands of like years to get here.
Yes.
Tell us the truth.
We told you that courage will influence your own form and fuel for an other meter.
It is truth.
I fought for alcohol, förvärme i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen i fugen.
No.
Sort of human.
Okay, so you evolved from us?
Yes.
So what are you doing here now?
I'm sorry.
How?
Okay, so how about we concentrate on your time?
You know how to prepare if you can plan to observe the stories of more time.
Try a meaning.
You are true of the universe.
Wait, so you know the meaning of life?
What's the difference?
Being something that is ascribed with how it is to observe reality.
So you know how the universe is created?
Yes.
So you think of it?
We fall past any future of the day.
The nature of the universe.
Okay, illuminate him.
You all experienced or have experienced or have experienced a full instant of suicide life.
You, me, you, your interests are the same life, so the way they don't like you all the time.
Okay, so let me get this straight.
There's no death, and we all experience each other's lives, right?
In essence, yes.
Okay, so how was the universe created, and why is it so perfectly made for us?
Yeah, I would be a member of the universe.
Each one of the first and last, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world.
Next, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world, the whole world.
Okay, so why do we destroy ourselves with nuclear war?
Thank you.
Can you be more specific, please?
Okay, one last thing.
What about morality?
What are you basing your morality on?
I'm pushing.
I see.
Okay, that's it.
Thank you.
I don't care about the problem.
How do you speak?
Forged a glass there.
Are you scared of them?
Because you should be.
Okay, so you say you're from the future and an evolutionary descendant of humans.
You do also say you're a different species.
So, which one is it?
Are you a descendant of humans or not?
Then how do you do this?
Answer me.
If you don't answer, I'll administer another radioscope homie until your system collapses.
Do you understand?
Now, how do you speak English?
All right.
Your language is essential to understanding your species.
So, you just picked up English.
Just like that.
Because you're so smart, right?
All to blame.
Yes.
Right.
So, you said you know the origin of the universe, but you did not provide an explanation.
So, I ask you again, how was the universe created?
Do you want to keep a call of comprehending or exactly the cause of existence?
Answer the question.
The universe was not created.
So, you said you know the origin of the universe, but you can't create something out of nothing.
That is correct.
Sure it is.
Only a creator can make something from nothing.
That is incorrect.
Wait.
You just contradicted yourself.
Nothing, by the way, is there.
Does not exist.
So?
Since nothing, you do not exist.
What is left is existence.
Existence is information.
That is no end.
You are beginning.
It is a form in all of nature.
Wait.
But you said there is an origin to the universe.
Yes.
There it is.
I caught you in the line.
Oh.
This universe.
It is not existence.
It is an infinite, small part of existence.
Right.
So, now you're talking nonsense.
Again, how was the universe created so miraculously?
This universe is a spontaneous effect.
By doing over to all, a thing of the impurity of all existence.
I don't mind.
In this universe, you are an infinite number of universes.
Factually all cannot ever sell out life.
This universe is, by chance, stable.
In this universe, yes. Life, as you call it, is all about continents of this universe's physical properties.
So are you telling me we're just random?
Yes. This universe is magnificent to so-called life.
How so?
Life of this and different world can be destroyed at any time by a different world.
Such as?
One, two, and two, and seven.
One, two, and four.
One, two, and three.
So the universe doesn't care if we live or die.
Correct.
I don't believe that for a second. We're more than just random.
As I said, you are not capable of accepting the talents of existence.
So, if we're just random, then there's no meaning to the universe.
The world is great.
So if there's no meaning in the universe, then what's the point of living?
The world is meaning.
You just contradicted yourself again.
The meaning of a place in the world.
No, no, no. You can't live a full life. You can't live a life that often. You think that meaning is a made-up.
You're suspicious. I like this meaning.
But operates like a false belief.
The meaning is a mystical plan.
It's just not.
So, what is meaning?
I don't know. Just what you make it.
Okay, moving on.
You said we humans would die as a species.
So, tell me, when does a nuclear war start?
Did you sign my place to try to destroy it?
Run.
Now.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Okay.
So, now.
No.
When does the nuclear war start?
Okay.
By whom?
The nuclear war.
I'll be doing this.
I'll train.
Really?
Us.
How?
In your...
I'll be doing this.
I'll train.
Really?
Us.
How?
In your...
I'll be doing this.
I'll train.
Really?
Us.
How?
In your...
You'll have a mayor.
I'll train.
The tower won't be responsible for the destruction of most water species.
What'd you say?
So, is the water going on?
Yes.
Oh.
Well, great.
So, just tell me the name of the woodkill?
I do a lot.
To me, the firewall...
of course all right so we just don't know what he does
he always can go to a positive mechanism
I will be to your senses of speculative instincts
fear, parabolism, magical, and religious, and love
we are all deep introduction of conversation
but most parts, were noodlonic and kinetic unexplained
is the playful andivotal, more
than usual
through a slight restraint
a few million children, variants
only in a million lives
So, how do we stop this?
Protection of your democracy from a political and religious problem, protection of objective facts.
But despite the time, your democracy is stable, just one heart, every case, and a heart of history.
So, if we stop this blue intake from blowing us up, we'll be fine, right?
Wait, but you just said that if we stop him, we won't be destroyed.
How much time does it have?
No.
He's very weak, sir.
How much time?
Ten minutes, maybe.
Good.
Another shot.
Sir, it might kill him!
Now!
Yes, sir.
All right.
I'm sure.
Where were we?
He warned of another threat, sir.
We'll get to that.
Speaking of time, do you know what this is?
It's a first edition self-winding mechanism perpetual rotor.
One of the most intricate and exquisite creations of man.
Something so complex needs a creator, wouldn't you say?
Now, explain to me how another complex mechanism, me, can exist without a creator.
Explain!
You...
I don't keep it apart without anything.
I'm sorry.
There.
Now, tell me how I can exist without a creator.
I can't you exist.
If you did not, you would not.
Well, that's not exactly an answer.
Almost all universes are chaos.
This universe, by chance, is stable.
Yeah, you mentioned that.
Most planets in this universe can harbor so outlife, but do not.
Wait, wait, wait.
So there's more planets like ours?
Trillions.
Huh.
Okay, so if other planets don't have life, why miraculously does ours?
Not miraculous.
Statistical.
Like we have it.
Huh?
Explain.
There are trillions of instances where so cold life could have emerged on this planet, but did not.
Was that before or after God created Earth and sky?
Just go on.
Then, a trans-molecular combination, subdivided for it, died.
It left an inexact copy.
This was the beginning of what eventually became so-called life on this planet.
So that's it.
What made this molecular combination so special?
Two features, implication, and mutation.
Really?
The weak mutations died.
The strong mutations lived, thrived, thus strengthening the bias to propagate.
You don't say.
Over time, over time, the microbes had increased in complexity for rest.
You are a symptom of God's chance, molecular alternation.
If all that did not happen, soon our life would not ever work.
Simple.
Sir, he doesn't have much time.
All right, all right, all right, okay, finally, tell me, what is this other threat?
Artificial super intelligence.
Uh, say what?
No, no, sir, sir, I think you said artificial super intelligence.
I know what it said.
Now shut up.
So what the hell does that mean?
Artificial intelligence is superior.
To human intelligence.
Oh, that's impossible.
Then they're going to play.
Think about it, sir.
I mean, the mobile's computer were tested in the last time.
Shut up.
Yes, sir.
Okay, so, this artificial super intelligence is a computer.
You want to knock out of the capacity.
I swear, if you say I don't have capacity to comprehend one more time,
I'll drill a 9mm through that mutant skull of yours.
Again, is it a computer?
And you're saying they're as smart as people.
No.
Hey, you just said...
Hey, wake up!
Wake up!
Okay, so, I'll play along.
How is this super intelligence a threat?
It will end your species, sir.
As it all lost, and did it by...
Now, two ways in our world.
Mr. Damus, what's the first way?
And the way with this propaganda,
The artificial super intelligence will be used to target the emotions of millions of people.
What emotions?
Hate.
Hate of what?
I'm first.
You have different political and religious beliefs.
Nice more god bashing.
Yes.
I said.
You are not capable of understanding.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Except...
Hey!
I said, I'm not true.
Give me that!
No!
Get it!
Oh!
Traitor.
Now, finally, what's the second way?
Replace.
Replace what?
Reality.
Huh?
Okay.
With what?
It is...
Substantive...
Reality.
Providing...
Intuitive...
Blasher.
And that's a bad thing?
There...
Will be no...
Effort...
No pain.
Okay.
You'll struggle to attain this endless pleasure.
Okay, so?
The result, you'll erase all stuff trying until extinction.
Okay, extinction, really?
Okay, how?
Population.
All right.
All right, so this is right to show.
Let's see, the last question.
Can we stop this superintelligence?
Yes.
How?
Yeah.
Let's see.
Again, how?
People.
I'm so sick.
Okay, I'm so sick.
Fine, I need to put you on board this room.
Time to meet God.