and if you looked at a particular place over secret mountain you would see this big orb
being escorted by helicopters rising from behind secret mountain and we watched at 1 30 in the
morning and sure enough up comes this beautiful golden orb gigantic it pulses it's plasmatic
and so where my mind might go with that is that this is some sort of global control system
but an object about a mile behind us and it's following us let's hope they're friendly one of
the first things that one of my sources in that georgetown pub back in probably 2018 told me was
it's all about consciousness you've probably met more people in and around these programs than
anybody else alive you are saying to the human race we are not alone we're definitely not alone
anyway he chuckled and i remember he just let something like yeah the americans wanted that
one shut down pretty quickly whoa it's a multi-minute long video of this thing flying in the air and
there are symbols around the top i showed photos of the symbols to mario woods and to randy anderson
and both of them freaked out we went to his home and saw this sphere apparently move under its own
power people have been murdered because i'm told that the briefing that the fbi gave in congress really
blue people away i have no doubt they think they're going to get away with it uh-huh
and you know what why they probably will
i'm here with ross colthart who um i have just so much gratitude to express first of all uh we've
been waiting to do this for a very long time i'm grateful you're in the us i haven't been avoiding you
i know you haven't um but i'm also i just want to express my gratitude because we were talking before
when the you know cameras weren't rolling i feel like i am aerodynamically drafting behind you i feel
like you uh have done so much leg work in getting all these amazing scoops and uh you know often i'll
do you know a follow-up interview where you know i have a lot of fun but it's really i just have so much
i i owe you a debt and i think humanity owes you a debt as well and so i'm grateful for you uh
sitting down it's a mutual admiration society jesse because i often say to my family how the hell does
he do it you seem like a jackrabbit everywhere i see i mean you have you just come back from
columbia or something you're doing a bugosphere story i was in yeah i was well i was in this is
what's crazy and i know you've experienced i'm sure all sorts of stories where like it starts a
certain way and then you have another story come up so i was investigating these peruvian mummies
these tridactyl you know three toad and fingered mummies from peru and then on the way back up to
the us i stop in mexico city to meet with jaime musan who's a big proponent of this and two days
before he happened to get this bugosphere sent to him or whatever and so i happened to be there um
i've got to know what's your preliminary assessment is it real it's so hard to say you know what do
you see what my friend roni verney posted on twitter repeat it for the audience a fuel tank
and so so there's a particular shape of fuel tank that is exactly nine liters and it's got similar
holes to the one that yaime is relying on and it does have the same seam running along the side it looks
like a direct visual match with a few changes if somebody's cosmetically altered it it's definitely
remarkable just the fact pattern so as you know very well whenever you take a stance a hard stance
in this world you get a ton of flack so i'll just give you my fact pattern of what i've experienced and
then people can sort of decide for themselves so jaime musan was given this thing it was taken in
buga colombia that's why it's called the bugosphere um it was given by a guy so this video was taken by this
guy who is um i guess he like does like uh mining and and metal detection underground and it's a it's
a very long it's a multi-minute long video of this thing flying in the air you've seen the video and
then he picks it up in the forest and there is a little gap in the video so that does beget a question
of like you know provenance and why is there a gap in the video and then he has it for a while in his
possession he ends up giving it to jaime musan and there are symbols around the top apparently
it's an aluminum alloy that's you know three times the hardness of what we generally use in
conventional aerospace and then maybe the most interesting fact i can give you uh that is new to
the audience as well is i showed photos of the symbols to mario woods and to randy anderson
mario woods 1977 ellsworth air force base experiencer and then randy anderson is this
guy who was taken underground you know at um crane naval surface warfare crane and was possibly
shown some off world technology and both of them freaked out because it was like that these were
the symbols that they had both seen mario inside the craft i want to give you something because i'm
not sure and again again i am not avowing that this is my opinion neither of us are endorsing the
boogie sphere we are just these are facts that we are endorsing nor debunking that's right um but i
did what i'm increasingly doing these days i took a photograph of the sphere and i uploaded it to ai
and i asked ai in this case i think it was groke and i said can you please decipher these symbols for
me and it came back very quickly and said the circuit and that i have to admit made me think it was a
hoax now i'm not saying it's a hoax okay but what i am saying is that came back when i put it through ai
but ai is often wrong but uh what i love about ai is that its ability to draw on symbology and
numerology and all of these ideas and it came back with this one phrase the circuit well if you look at
the top it looks like a little semiconductor or a chip yeah and then you have you know this begets all
these ontological questions of like you have i think his name is patrick jackson yes who has
you've done an amazing story everybody go watch ross's story with this and i have seen one of these
spheres in a different domain in the home of a beautiful man in texas who is a good soul and i can
tell you it may be the case that his sphere is now in the possession of brandon fugal and the skinwalker
ranch show is going to be paying to have that sphere properly investigated there's a scoop for
you that is i was going to run it on my show yeah so jim marlin is a former um rock promoter who worked
with willie nelson and uh he has a house in texas and uh we went to his home and saw this sphere
i have to be careful apparently move under its own power and i mean we were sitting with jim for hours
talking and he was in a home where the floor had just been fixed so it's perfectly level and we
verified that with a level and the ball is sitting stationary on the floor and then all of a sudden it
starts moving and there's a bar which has a pole coming down onto the floor it goes up to the bar
and from memory it might have even circled the pole and then come back again part of the way
and there was no movement we were all just sitting in a chair talking and then jim chortles and goes
and it moves yeah was there something that came up in the conversation was it aligned with anything
synchronous no and so when i ran that story on um channel 7 australia they as usual as tv networks
or want to do beat the living daylight side of it which is a journalistic term for flogging the story
until it bleeds and um it um you know there were all the promos were fancy and it made it look like we
we were saying for sure that it was an anomalous object we truly don't know for sure and the great
frustration for me for the past few years since i did that story in 2021 is every time i went to jim
and asked him could we take it to go and get it tested there was a lot of resistance and it made me
suspicious but then he agreed to go and let it get tested but the problem was when i was trying to
find an x-ray place that does industrial x-rays the first thing they want to know is well what's inside
it and i'm going well that's why we want to x-ray it and um and i i was expressing this dilemma only
very recently on a show somewhere and this gentleman rang me from chicago and said that he would x-ray
it in his industrial x-ray machine and he had some other type of machine um can't remember what it was
might have been a ct i'm not sure yeah and he would run it through that as well and it was for free and
i went to jim and i said to jim jim i finally found a place that can test the ball for you the sphere for
you because one of the things i get most a lot of the inquiries about from our audience is what happened
to the sphere you know why haven't you told us the story about the sphere and i was finally about
to announce that we've got somebody who will allow us to do the testing on the sphere because jim won't
let us to cut into it for obvious reasons and um he told me i'm sorry ross brandon fugles agreed
to fly up in his private jet to utah where he's going to have it tested in the lab and look frankly i'm
really happy if that's going to be the case for patrick who i know and um and for jim who's a
beautiful guy uh to finally get an answer and brandon i've spoken to brandon about it and i've
encouraged him to to do it and so hopefully it's all going to happen um fingers crossed yeah let's hope
that's amazing and i think patrick because you were talking about the chip and so where my mind might go
with that again i don't know if it's real is uh that this is some sort of like global control
system or something well patrick's theory is that these spheres are part of a global defense system
by some alien civilization to keep the bad guys out of earth right and i quite like patrick he's a very
clever man yeah he has an eclectic intelligence and he's fun uh i honestly don't know how he could know
that right so i mean a lot of it is speculation and he's got type one spheres and type two spheres and
often there'll be a photograph of a plane and you do you see these spheres around planes in uap events
so there's often a big let's call it object rather than a craft there's a big object that's clearly
anomalous sometimes beside an aircraft and then if you look really closely you'll see these dots that
are these metallic spheres and when i did that story i did that in 2021 for australian tv it just went
nuts it's been seen that particular story if you add the two iterations of the story because we
we had to take one down because of copyright issues with music um it's been seen over 43 million
times and so i was getting phone calls messages emails from people all over the world including i
remember a beautiful guy in africa who who told me that they were seeing these spheres and what i i can
report is whatever they are i do think i can say they're real they're a real phenomenon whatever they
are they're metal spheres with no visible means of propulsion dozens of people have told me that
they've seen them flying or moving under their own locomotive power there's no visible way in which
they're moving and i don't honestly know what to conclude about them because i mean i expressed the
enigma by telling the story but like so much of this whole story jesse i don't know about you but i
often feel like i've got my eyes closed and i'm kind of feeling in the dark and trying to get an idea
about what it is and then as soon as i've got the texture and the feel of what's been in front of
me here i realized there's a whole other room over here of stuff that i've never got my brain around
and it's it's it's mind-bogglingly complex whatever it is this episode is brought to you by my favorite
new product masa chips here's a quick history lesson before the 1990s all chips and fries were cooked in
beef tallow then the big food companies swapped this ingredient out for cheap highly processed seed
oils today seed oils make up 20 of the average american's calories and they're linked to all sorts
of bad things like chronic inflammation and metabolic issues masa decided to rewind the clock
they make tortilla chips with just three simple ingredients organic corn sea salt and a hundred percent
grass-fed beef tallow no seed oils no weird additives and honestly they taste way better too
masa chips are crunchier more flavorful and they don't disintegrate in guac like the usual ones but
the real difference is how you feel light satisfied no crash no bloat and no weird craving spiral an hour
later i've been snacking on them non-stop while working on these shows and they actually keep me sharp
masa chips are beloved by tens of thousands of customers and have been endorsed by
industry-leading health and nutrition experts like ben greenfield and gary brecca so ready to give masa
a try go to masa chips.com jesse michaels michaels with no a and use code jesse michaels for 25 off your
first order that's masa chips.com jesse michaels and use code jesse michaels for 25 off your first order
you're really helping the channel out when you use that code and this is a product i love and consume just
about every day part of what i want to do in this interview is so many people are used to seeing you
in the context of breaking these bombshell stories i want to get to know the man behind that because
you you are often the interviewer and so how did you were you know exposing corruption and stuff with
the surveillance state in australia right how did you get into ufos to begin with
like every kid i was obsessed with doctor who and i i i loved a show called ufo that was on tv
it was a british series um about malevolent aliens invading earth and there was this secret
organization called shadow that was defending earth but i'll be honest i always saw that as fiction
and i accepted it was fiction i never believed it was true and even when in new zealand where i was
living as a kid i um there was a really big ufo incident in 1978 when i was 16 years old in a place
called kaikura on the east coast of the south island of new zealand and there was a cargo aircraft flying
up that coastline in 1978 in the middle of the night and the pilot and the co-pilot had these objects
clearly in their view elliptical metallic disc shaped objects come right up to the cockpit window
glowing but clearly metallic and then go away again and um what was interesting was that it was
another kind of nimitz story because you had sensor systems i found the guy in wellington across cook
strait who was the radar operator on the night who'd seen these things on radar and as the two guys who
were the journalists on the aircraft were describing the objects say going to the west the radar operator
john cordy was seeing them go to the west i have a strong target uh at 12 o'clock to you at two zero miles
uh right do we have that one also and uh quite a quick uh visual display at the moment
showing light
so you had this contemporaneous real-time confirmation of solid objects moving or at least objects that
registered on radar moving in the directions that these witnesses were saying that they were seeing
these objects moving and they were seeing objects that were plasmatically glowing but at the same time
clearly solid structured in their words craft
you just heard from wellington radar that we've uh got an object about a mile behind us and it's
following us let's hope they're friendly
i see ralph reko uh the
strong target uh right in formation with you now uh could either be left or right but your target has
doubled its size and for each of those people it was a transformative moment but what was really
interesting for me as a journalist was i bought as a teenage boy the official government explanation
and i was doing my exams i was really focused on my studies there'd been the valentich story of a
young boy called frederick valentich who had disappeared in his cessna aircraft flying over bass
strait in australia just a few months before and as somebody who was really already very interested in
the media i kind of bought into the idea that this is all a big media beta because there's a big
problem in the december january period it's the christmas holiday period the news is pretty boring
and so this was obviously a story that the media had leapt onto and i just thought yeah this is just
a big media beat up what was interesting also was that the government had come out with an official
explanation very very quickly which said that these were squid boat lights and in new zealand
there are these big japanese fishing fleets that go off the coast with these gigantic lights and you
often saw them as a kid and they were glowing on the horizon and they looked spooky and so the theory
that was pushed by the new zealand air force was that these were squid boats lights and the captain
the co-pilot of one plane and the captain the co-pilot of another plane even though they were flying
at 14 000 feet they were mistaken and those objects were below them and it was some kind of refraction
in the air blah blah blah blah blah it all gave a reasonable tinge of explanation that made everybody
in new zealand think oh that was just a bullshit story during the christmas season it's all over
for me though it was interesting because much much later when i became a journalist
i was working for the new zealand herald newspaper and i met sir robert muldoon who was the former
new zealand prime minister and he used to do these convivial little chats at christmas time where
a young reporter me had to drive up and interview him and talk to the former prime minister about
whatever he wanted to talk about and i decided i don't know why i knew he'd been the prime minister at
the time i decided to ask him what about that kaikoura ufo thing that happened when i was 16 and
by that time i think i was about 19 or 20 i can't remember anyway he chuckled and i remember he just
let something like yeah the americans wanted that one shut down pretty quickly whoa and that because
i love espionage stories and i love as a young new zealander i was always focused on books about
espionage and as you referred to earlier one of the biggest stories i did in my time in australia was
i revealed the existence exclusively of the echelon communications surveillance system which is what
the five eyes operate to intercept communications and for the first time ever um i got from an
intelligence service in australia an official admission that there was a system called echelon and
it was involved in communications surveillance and spying and so i was switched on to that issue
all my life i've always been really interested in spies and espionage and so it twigged my interest
that sir robert moldurne was describing this admission that there'd been some kind of american
intervention but he wouldn't go any further and then much much later when i was writing my book
i discovered that there'd been this release of the new zealand archives in about 2011
and it essentially revealed the detail of what went on inside the air force in new zealand to try
and fix this problem as fast as possible and it was quite clear these air force officers had been told
find a fucking solution as fast as possible we want this off the front page and it was quite clear
enormous amounts of pressure was being put on the chief of air staff the head of the air force
by the prime minister's office to make this one go away and hence the squid boat explanation
and then when i was writing my book i met quentin fogarty who'd been one of the reporters on the
plane who by complete chance his son ben was one of the chief cameramen at 60 minutes where i was
working as a reporter and so ben said to me my dad was the guy who was on that plane that night so i got
to meet his father another weird serendipity and another one of the reporters was a political
correspondent called dennis grant of great renown later on in um australia and dennis confirmed all
the story and um he introduced me to bruce mccabee who was the um atmospheric physicist who sadly recently
died and all of a sudden i realized that the story that i'd bought as a young teenage kid
that basically told me this was bullshit was actually completely untrue and there'd been a
really elaborate cover-up and that fascinated me and it was one of the because i actually started out
writing my book in about 2018 when i left 60 minutes i thought i wanted to do a book debunking
ufos i was arrogant and i had this assumption that all ufos were nonsense and it was only a matter
of time i'd read nick cook's um hunt for zero point and you know he'd implied very strongly that there
was some sort of secret us aerospace program we obviously have all heard all the rumors about the
aurora which or the tr3b and i just assumed it was some kind of black world american technology and
that a bit of dutiful digging would no doubt reveal this and somehow for some inescapable reason
i would discover it and make my name by revealing that the whole ufo story was complete nonsense
but the more i got into the story because of that kaikoura story everywhere i went everybody was
telling me this is real and so i had sources from the original echelon investigation i'd done and
from people i've met in afghanistan and iraq when i covered the war who were in senior levels in
intelligence and um defense and they facilitated introductions for me to people who privately when
we sat over a table in a bar said ross this is real yeah and that only really happened for me
more recently you know while i was writing my book and probably the biggest breakthrough moment for me
where i went holy heck this is real is when the um the technique i'd used to try and investigate this
was because of my knowledge of echelon and how easy it is to intercept digital communications
i decided i wouldn't approach anybody that i thought might know something about this other
than by using analog communication techniques i wouldn't even use phones because of course
there's a metadata and we knew about that because of the um snowden revelations that there was this
metadata trail that essentially reveals that you can be tracked and and they might not know the contents
of the phone conversation but they can certainly track a lot about your habits and your movements and who
you're talking to by looking at the metadata and so i wrote letters wow so i wrote i think about 160
170 letters at last count and a lot of it involved doing things like uh i'm a lawyer by training and so
as a young trainee lawyer i'd learned that a lot of stinky stuff happens in the discovery process and legal
proceedings with documents that are maybe procured but not necessarily tended in a court case
and um they're often tangential to what you're trying to discover to prove the case that you're
mounting but there's some really juicy stuff in there and so i don't want to go into too much detail
but there were some very helpful lawyers and so i built up a name base of people that i thought might
be interesting who'd been involved in litigation at area 51 and in a layering and iterative process of
doing what i do which is basic investigative journalism where you you build up a chronology
and you think who might know something about advanced aerospace or who might have been working in
a security role or a support role at that time in this area that might know something
you build up a name base and so i wrote letters to people and one of the glorious things about america
is how ridiculously open every database is and i could procure the home addresses of everybody that
i wanted to write to including some of the most important scientists in america wow and what shocked me
was one of the letters i wrote was to a guy called nat kobitz and um he was the former head of science
technology development for the u.s navy and i'd written to him and as an act of brazen cheek to be
perfectly honest i honestly did not expect that somebody like him would respond what did kobitz say
he rang me and i didn't talk ufos with him for three months and i realized sadly one of the reasons he
wanted to talk to me was because he was a lonely elderly man who god bless him was dying slowly of
cancer and he was in his daughter's home and she was nursing him and he was bored and i was interested in
talking to him and he was talking to me about developing early drone technology and and how
one of their drones had crashed in george bush the president's ranch because the secret service had um
frequency blockers and you know they'd spent millions of dollars on building this drone and
the first time they flew it because they flew into the secret service envelope it crashed and he went
went there went a few million bucks you know and uh and he had this wonderful jewish brooklyn sense of
humor and i became very friendly with him and i loved i used to really enjoy talking to him there
were things like he'd been involved in developing things on the the lunar lander and i knew somebody
who'd worked on the lunar lander and they told me something about the lunar lander and because
nate knew about that we bounced off that and it just got more and more interesting and then
one day i rang him and he was getting really ill
and i could hear a kind of a um a change in his voice and i i felt really sad because it was obvious
he was ill and he went why don't you ask me the question no way he was the guy who suggested i ask
it oh wow he kind of knew you were oh yeah he knew he knew why i was there yeah i'd made no secret
that i was writing a book about ufos uh-huh you know how we're always diving into the edge of science
and consciousness on this show lately i've been thinking a lot about aging not just in terms of
years but in how it actually feels in the body slow recovery lower energy that middle-aged fog that
sneaks up on you i feel like i can barely go out and drink alcohol anymore that's why i started using
something called qualia senolytic and it's been a major shift for me let me explain as we age our bodies
accumulate what scientists call senescent cells also known as zombie cells these are worn out cells
that stop dividing but don't die they hang around in your body draining your energy clogging up your
recovery and generally making you feel older than you are qualia senolytic is a first-of-its-kind
supplement formulated with nine plant-based compounds designed to help your body naturally
eliminate these zombie cells it's not something you take every day just two days a month but it
supports your body and aging better at the cellular level since i've started taking it i've felt sharper
lighter and like my body's resilience has come back online it's vegan non-gmo and grounded in serious
research experience the science of feeling younger go to qualialife.com jesse for up to 50 off your
purchase and use code jesse again that's j-e-s-s-e for an additional 15 off that's q-u-a-l-i-a-l-i-f-e dot
com slash jesse j-e-s-s-e for an extra 15 off your purchase thanks so much to qualia for sponsoring this
episode why don't you ask me the question and i was nervous i was actually slightly nervous
and i've never released it but i've actually got a recording of this oh my god and he had
authorized me to record it of course um and i went i've been agonizing about how to ask you this question
and he went third time why don't you just ask me the question and so i went have you ever been
read in to any kind of program involving unidentified aerial phenomena alien technology
and before i finished answering the question he went yes wow and he obviously made a decision to
answer the question and i actually didn't hear him the first time he said it uh-huh i was expecting
him to go no i don't know it because everybody was saying no i don't know anything about what
you're talking about and you know well actually no that wasn't true i'd already had people confirm
the retrieval program but there was a kind of a beat one two and then i went what
and and i i i out of respect to nate and that and his family i'm not going to go into a lot of
detail of the remaining parts of the conversation because what he then did for me was incredible he
facilitated introductions to people and that was my big breakthrough wow and um will that conversation
ever come out i i think i'd want his family's okay about it sure you know because it's an emotional
thing i think for a family to hear a father's voice after he's been passed for so long yeah but um
he was a beautiful guy and and it was an act of courage on his part and i remember one of the
conversations i had with him was do you think there's any good reason because this is the thing
i wrestle with i know you do as well what's the dirty secret right why why can't we know this you
know if the us has recovered technology why can't we know and he hadn't been told that and and he had
that rigid doctrinaire thing about how he wasn't read into that part of it and um that was a
compartmentalized issue he wasn't entitled to know about what he told me was that he'd been told that
the united states had recovered multiple craft wow multiple craft and he implied very strongly that
roswell and another case i'm interested in aztec and kingman are all real incidents and that really
rocked my world view and um but what what happened was he also told me that he because oh there was
another time i asked him i said oh have you have actually seen evidence of alien technology and he went
no and kind of i was kind of disappointed because he's implied that he had yeah and then he gave me
this cheeky look and because we were talking on zoom and um and i said have you ever been given
anomalous technology that defied prosaic explanation uh-huh and he went like he had the first time yes
wow and he told me this amazing story about how he was an expert in a particular type of welding called
electron beam welding okay and apparently they his company had done the the nose wheel for the c47 one
of the big cargo planes these by the u.s military and they need really tough worlds and this is one of
the strongest worlds you can do of metals and he was like the world expert with his company in that type
of welding and it's an indistinguishable bead unlike i don't know if you've ever welded but it's it
welds leave a big bead this type of welding didn't and so he was contacted on his own admission by
wright patterson air force base and i think it was even whatever the technology division is known as now
i think it might be the foreign technology exploitation something and he um he was flown to wright pat yeah and
he did go underground i remember i giggled and i said did you go underground he went yo yeah
oh yeah it was obviously a long way down and he was taken into a room under heavy guard
and shown what he described to me as the piece of a bulkhead and he said it looked like it should
have been incredibly heavy but it was almost light almost lightweight you know like a feather yeah
and he said what blew him away was and he i don't know enough about metal metallurgy to know this but
he said there were two types of metal and he wouldn't tell me what types of metal they were
that had been bonded and he asked to look at it i think under an electron scanning microscope
mm-hmm and the scientist in him couldn't resist giving that sense of awe about what he saw that
he said it was bonded at the atomic level whoa whoever had built this had layered it atom by atom and he
said i i know for a fact that's not a technology certainly that i'm aware of and i would have thought
that i would have known yeah i think like semiconductors you can do little amounts of
atomic layer deposition but you can't fabricate at scale materials that are atomically you know where
you're deliberately placing atoms you just can't do that that's amazing so i think for me the the big
aha moment where i stopped being the skeptic and went oh fuck this is real i can't believe this
and i remember i actually spent days just going for walks because i was writing my book and it had
it had actually altered i had a conformational bias yeah i was writing a book to debunk all this nonsense
yeah and and this guy is telling me it's true is this in plain sight by the way that you were writing
at the time yeah and the great thing about it was um i was doing a lot of traveling for 60 minutes and
channel 7 to big networks in australia and i was often in america and as part of cost cutting they'd
often leave you in a hotel for a few days while you shared the crew with another reporter and so
you'd have done time when really all you wanted to do was be with your family and you're sitting in
a hotel in washington or new york and it sounds like fun i know and once you've tried on the fluffy
dressing gown and used the bath salts once you're just a bit bored yeah and so i would um
i'd research things and i was going to the national archives and reading a lot of the old archives on
ufos and then that organized for me to start meeting people and that was like
uap 101 and there was just this conga line of people coming through the apartment i rented
that were brave amazing people it's amazing well it's amazing how deeply embedded you became
because if i remember correctly grush had come out and you guys had had some mutual contacts before he
came out yeah that's true and with jake barber i believe you knew him for like a couple of years
before he came out i can't say how long i knew i have a man but okay it's just to protect them but
basically yeah i i learned about david grush from people in the program i just think that's
important for the audience to hear because you know they think it's some like choreographed thing
or whatever it's like you know people have always got this idea that all that happens is these people
come to you and you interview them and it's a really lazy job yeah and they have no idea honestly i
like i used to have a full head of hair and and the the the the job of
it's a bit like you i really admire the way you do your stuff because you actually know
a lot of science and a lot of physics and you do and i love the way you demonstrate that knowledge
in the shows that you do thank you whereas i honestly am not a scientist but what i do is i'm
really good and i learned this at law school at absorbing huge amounts of information complex
information and analyzing it and understanding it and and making sure i understand it because
at law school we had the socratic method where you were tested orally about your understanding
of something and you were put on the spot by the lecturer and questioned in front of 300 other
students and if you didn't know your stuff you were humiliated and vilified and i was never going
to let that happen and i was humiliated and vilified on constant occasions and um so you're
like pavlovian conditioned yeah yeah it's a great terror terror training yeah that's right and um
and so i learned subjects so that i could hold conversations with people and i'd read scientific
american articles and try and understand them and i for the life of me couldn't and i i'd get friendly
physicists or um neuroscientists to explain things to me and it's by demonstrating a knowledge or an
understanding or just enough to be able to have a conversation with somebody that increases the flow
and so sometimes i'd come out of a conversation and i'd go i think i've got what they're talking
about and there's a lot of ideas that people were discussing with me that frankly now that i'm into
consciousness and psionics and stuff like that i'm now only now beginning to understand and it's um
it's seven years since i had those conversations it's it's wild how much your kind of aperture
opens up getting i mean i'm curious as to like how you feel now because you've broken all these stories
you can't really argue with the substance of a lot of the stories you can't argue with the people's
backgrounds you know their credentials like you can't really do that and so i imagine you feel like
you're on this like remote island and then like you have you know i feel this at least you have
like mainstream media or news and they just it's like they can't even comprehend like where you are
you know it's funny i'm so glad you've led me into this path because i'm going to give you my rant
i think there will come a time in the not too distant future where there will be a bloody reckoning
with the failure of the mainstream media in the main to deal with the greatest disinformation
operation in human history yes yeah it has been the most effective psyop ever yeah yeah but you you
also realize when talking to a lot of these people the psyop maybe it's at the top like okay i'll tell
give you a crazy story sure a friend of mine was planning an op-ed with a former cabinet member
in the u.s the cabinet member wanted to know where they were they were expressing frustration about
their lack of access to ufo stuff i decided to help him out because he was having trouble with
the wall street journal getting this published which is just prima facie crazy if you take that claim
at face value even just the fact that the cabinet member is claiming it well look i mean what made
the new york times publish it in 2017 the mere fact that the pentagon was looking at ufos was a story
it's it's there you go which is that is a story right and so um and then you get into all these
questions of like why did the new york times reject the grush story it's crazy but in this case i'm
talking to this journalist at the wall street journal trying to help my friend out
and she's actually somewhat open-minded but like she just
you know it's one of these things where it's like it seems so beyond the pale and if you don't
understand the the deeper research and you haven't gone down the rabbit hole it's kind of like in one
ear at the other and she then says i don't know we have this um we have this like consultant that we
talked to about ufos here uh and his name is david spurgle and you know where i'm going with this
and david spurgle tells me that it's all uh space trash uh temperature inversions and light
reflections and in my head i'm thinking that's exactly what don menzel would say in the 50s to
throw people off the trail and david spurgle not only did the nasa uap review panel in 2023 but he
happens to run the simons foundation you know uh um and uh you know as a scientific advisor and is very
embedded in like you know doe research and that's where if you both if you know what we both know
that's where the bodies are buried absolutely no and it's it's funny i i one of the things in my line
of work is we have a vulgar expression which is always assume a fuck up before a conspiracy like
conspiracies happen so rarely and invariably it's the it's the screw-ups that that are the explanation
rather than active conspiracy in this case i have been led reluctantly to the conclusion
this is a conspiracy that there really is a group a cabal a leadership cabal that is actively
conniving to deceive the public why do why do you think that going back to your earlier question of
like what's the big deal why do you think they hide it i think they've convinced themselves because
i i actually asked somebody from lockheed martin this perfect what's up guys i want to tell you
about my new favorite boots these things are epic i've been wearing these everywhere they're called
brunt they're insanely comfortable and durable these things last for years and they're super
versatile i wear them for hiking for hanging out they look pretty swaggy if you're going out they
even look good in work meetings they feel incredibly comfortable there's no annoying break-in
period they just kind of form fit to your foot right off the bat they're lightweight you don't
have to lug them around but they're also super weather resistant waterproof and durable brunt is
committed to making sure you're 100 satisfied with your new gear with over 500 000 customers
already on board these boots are the best in the category take it from me brunt makes the most epic
durable and comfortable work boots for a limited time our listeners get ten dollars off at brunt
by using code jesse at checkout just head to bruntworkware.com and use code jesse and you're
all set even better brunt lets you try all their products on the job risk-free just go to bruntworkware.com
and use code jesse for ten dollars off again that's bruntworkware.com code jesse after you purchase
they will ask you where you heard about them please support our show and tell them that we sent you so
so somebody rang me out of the blue from lockheed martin i won't say who they are and convey who they
are but they were they were an executive a very senior executive and we were playing a delicate
dance they heard me say something and they were thanking me for not putting them in it and for
more accurately reflecting the true state of events about something and essentially it was an implicit
acknowledgement by that lockheed martin executive that they are holding alien technology
and i just blurted it out i said look can i ask you a question i said i promise you i'm not recording
you why yeah why not just come out and say it's not us yeah he said it's the agency interesting he said
we want to do it and then that's how i found out about the attempt by bigelow aerospace right there's
this bullshit story about metamaterials that god bless them leslie and ralph put in the new york
times story that was always nonsense it wasn't metamaterials it was a spacecraft right lockheed
martin was going to pass on control of an alien spacecraft to bigelow aerospace that's the real story
and you hear rumors that maybe it was the kingman craft and yeah three yeah and so the the
interesting thing is the um the cia intervened to stop that from happening or at least the office
of global access as it was once known and it was it was glenn gaffney right it was now it's
interesting i'm not a hundred percent sure it was glenn gaffney people have denied that from the inside
but i don't know if that's disinformation okay glenn gaffney's definitely been involved in the cover
up right yeah no for sure yeah and australia i remember when i first met you it was at the soul
foundation a couple years ago and australia has its own fascinating history that i remember
asking you about at the time you have this guy named harry turner i love harry turner tell us
about harry turner well good friend of mine bill chalker who's probably australia's preeminent
uap researcher he got to know harry really well while harry was alive and harry had been
in his youth as a young 20 something a young physicist recently qualified from melbourne university
and he expressed an interest in investigating ufos to the then government and they'd invited
him to come on board back in those more learned and insightful days when governments didn't try
and hide evidence of ufos they invited this young physicist in to analyze ufo sightings because they
were like the americans trying to investigate them and we were involved in a collaborative relationship
with america providing information to project blue book handing over some of the more interesting
new australian and new zealand sightings cases and there was a collaborative exchange of data and
information which there still is secretly but i won't get to that until later but the um the
interesting thing is harry turner somehow fell into the maralinga nuclear test program and when the
british were developing their nuclear weapon god bless the british they let their bombs off in the
middle of australia and uh i've been involved in doing stories about what a dreadful scandal that
was and how the woomera aboriginal people died in their droves from horrible cancers and so did the
servicemen who were involved in supervising the tests but there's two ranges there's the maralinga
range where the bombs were tested and there's the woomera range where they tested the icbms and woomera
is still very active it's where the americans have secretly been testing hypersonic missile technology
and there's a huge level of collaboration secretly between australia and the us where
a lot of your dirty aerospace gets brought out to australia and funnily enough it's neither here nor
there i've had many aboriginal communities that are often the only communities out there in these
remote parts of australia who've described black triangles flying over their communities silent black
triangles wow something is i'm sure being tested in the australian outback wow but harry
in the 19 whenever the nuclear tests started i think it was in the 1950s and into the 60s he was the
supervising physicist on the range at maralinga and he was invited to investigate multiple uap sightings
that took place at maralinga during the sightings and there are still reports in the archives of those
uap sightings and i put a lot of them in my book and there's a young fella who i've just put an article
of his up on a website in australia uh reese dalton moore and he's basically his grandfather ran
the woomera test range and it turns out he was secretly involved in investigating uh reese dalton
morgan i apologize and his grandfather was involved in secret investigations with the british government
in the late 1950s late 1940s in britain into ufos and so it turned out there's this whole area of
physicists including harry turner who were witness to ufo incidents in their droves in the maralinga
and woomera test range areas during the 50s and the 60s and so after he'd done that work harry went on
to work in the equivalent of the dia the defense intelligence agency in australia which at the time
was known as the joint intelligence organization jio and he in 1972 wrote an extraordinary paper
which lots of people keep on sending me going wow you must read this ross you wouldn't know about
this and i've blooming written chapters about it and talked about it for years i find it fascinating harry
wrote this definitive piece which basically was a report to the chief of jio recommending that the
defense department of australia set up a ufo flying squad to investigate ufos and it was under serious
active consideration you can see that they weren't going to dismiss their chief scientist in a hurry and
he made a very authoritative argument that the americans were essentially lying and i have a
strong suspicion because there was an enormous amount of liaison between physicists from america and
physicists from australia that there was a bit of cross pollination that harry had picked up stuff from
american nuclear physicists who were aware of the early stages of the american legacy program well you
told me one time that like some of the graybeards you've spoken to in the australian context talked
about robert sarbacher coming and visiting them and robert sarbacher was definitely involved in
liaison and the most interesting thing is a lot of the australian scientists including harry at one
stage went on um expeditions to the pacific tests because the americans were trying to suck up to us
for exploding bombs in our backyard by inviting us to be part of these tests and to be witnesses to them
and of course they were polluting vast parts of micronesia and spraying nuclear residue all over
huge parts of the marshall islands and johnson atoll huge numbers of communities and i've been out to
the marshall islands and johnson atoll briefly and it is really quite amazing to think that they were
exploding thermonuclear weapons in the open but i think there was a lot of cross-pollination there as
well between australian scientists and american scientists it's pretty obvious harry picked up a lot
of information and he wrote this absolutely candid analysis that the americans clearly have some kind
of retrieval program he talked about roswell he talked about other retrievals and he talked about
how the americans were clearly keeping this from us and look even in present day this is strategically
significant for us in australia because i was involved in 1994 that's how old i am in another story
about spies where i revealed that our intelligence service the equivalent of the cia asus in australia
did plausibly deniable favors for its allies america and the uk under the five eyes alliance and there were
amazing examples of plausibly deniable favors where for example australian technical operators people who did
bugging and tapping were borrowed by the brits and mi6 would ring the australians and say i say old chap
can i borrow one of your tech ops lads and we we spoke to some of these people who were involved in these
technical operations and they told us how one of them had flown to kuwait after the first gulf war
and there was a huge amount of money going for contracts for the rebuilding of kuwait multi-billion
dollar fat juicy cost plus contracts and there were australian construction companies involved in
bidding wars with british companies to win these incredibly lucrative contracts and so the brits
secretly borrowed one of the technical operators buggers from australia
to win a commercial advantage against australia by bugging the kuwaiti government offices on behalf
of british intelligence and it blew me away i verified this directly with some of the people involved in the
operation that australian spooks were used this way as plausibly deniable operatives to do things
that the british wanted to be entirely off the books and if they'd been caught doing it they would
have it would have been my government australian government that was compromised not the brits
and we've been doing this kind of dirty work for years in the five eyes alliance
that story was like incendiary inside the five eyes alliance i i know it upset a lot of people because
it revealed the dirty little secret that the kiwis and the aussies and to a lesser extent the canadians
they do the shit that the brits and the americans want to deny including spying on their allies
and bugging including in some cases their allies and i i've met this group of people who'd been
involved in these operations and that was always in the back of my mind when i was investigating the
ufo stuff so when i later on started investigating uap retrieval operations i knew people from special
forces in australia including retired special forces people who'd worked in a particular era when
i knew there were allegedly american retrieval operations involving ufos and they told me they'd
been involved in retrieval operations and the incredible thing was wow the australian government
was never briefed into these retrieval operations wow they were paid cash us dollars just to keep
their mouths shut they were asked to sign ndas and if you think about it it's perfect yeah there were
no u.s personnel involved in this operation right right and it's not even the australian government
didn't know and these guys walked away with fat checks and were kept very happy this is why the fact
of the canadian involvement in retrievals and um reverse engineering efforts has been kept so secret
for so long because canadian scientists have been and are involved in the legacy program
and it's been kept secret from the canadian people and um the only reason i'm aware of this stuff is
because i know to look for it because of the stories i've done previously about things like echelon and
the plausibly deniable favors of secret services exchanging each other's men to do dirty tricks
on each other and that woke me up i i knew to ask the question when i was questioning people in the
program and they'd say oh yeah i remember the aussies i remember that guy yeah and it's interesting
because people wanted to talk about it because when i really pushed the issue to come back to the
actual question you'd ask me there was no good reason for this to be kept secret and that blew
me away and harry turner was the very early proponent of the fact that australia was having
the wool pulled over its eyes yeah and i care about this issue because we're currently negotiating we've
actually agreed to buy 368 billion dollars worth of virginia class nuclear attack submarines
from your government in america because we supposedly need them as a strategic deterrence to deal with the
chinese and what it's really all about is helping you guys fight the next war that they think they're
going to have with china and maintaining american imperial hegemony and there are a lot of people
including in a former australian prime minister i know paul keating who've said publicly why are we
so slavishly doing these things for the american alliance and i think there's a fundamental deceit
that lies at the heart of this alliance and its uaps and i've raised this at a very high level with
our government and i've had people in our government say to me ross give me the evidence yeah well i'm
going to link that document at the bottom of the in the description of this video because it's an
amazing document it is talks about crash retrievals it confirms all these things that you have to kind
of do deep research in the u.s to even know which is blue book is fake blue book was this total pr you
know job to rationalize and it kept laying away ufo settings in the 50s and 60s and then it goes into the
fact that the real work around anti-gravity was going on and you had people like oppenheimer
wheeler uh freeman dyson are top scientists all investigating this stuff and it even lists the
outposts of the cia's office of scientific intelligence studying this and it talks about
university of north carolina chapel hill where we know that they were funding thomas towns and brown
and all sorts of other you know anti-gravity stuff so it's a it's a fascinating document speaking of the
marshall islands you before me actually broke this amazing story about bluegill triple prime oh yeah you
with uh jeffrey cruikshank who um uh is a really amazing researcher and also comes from the nuclear
world and what got you onto that story and now you know i want to talk about this with you because
there's a little bit of controversy around harold malmgren well i i know and i've seen um jeff's also
published a rebuttal to douglas dean johnson's hatchet job i will link that too yeah and and it's
interesting because i haven't had a chance to read his rebuttal yet i thought douglas raised some
legitimate points totally and i'm really interested to see uh the academic argument back from jeff i
just haven't had a chance to read it yet um but yeah i mean how did i get into that i was as a young
man i was living in new zealand when these tests were happening in some cases and it was i can tell you
a big issue that both the yanks and the french particularly the french at murray or atoll
were exploding thermonuclear weapons in our backyard and i can remember um as a much younger journalist i
learned how to use the archives and one of the early documents i found in the australian archives
were was evidence of secret testing of animals for radiation residue from those nuclear experiments that
were at the time kept from the australian and new zealand public and there were nucleotides
showing quite concerning levels of radioactive isotopes coming from weapons testing including
by the way maralinga and um and um other explosions that had taken place in islands off the coast of
australia that showed that contrary to what the public had been told there were radioactive elements
getting into the blood and the the bodies of human beings and more importantly there was a discernible
sigma move if you like showing a statistical lift in cancer rates and this was never revealed it was
never talked about and uh i i just i guess i grew up in that environment of deep skepticism i was also um
living in new zealand around the time of the attack by the french on the greenpeace boat in auckland
harbour where an environmental vessel that was being used by greenpeace to go and demonstrate
against the muoroa atoll nuclear tests was blown up by the deja essay french intelligence an
intelligence operation slap bang in the middle of auckland harbour i mean an incredible operation
i mean incredible french arrogance to think that they could do that and not get caught
and the stupid buggers if they just hadn't tried to get the deposit back on their rental car the french
would have got away with one of the most awful crimes of that time of recent history but um you know
there was this sordid period where the great imperial powers of the world were looking for rental for real
estate to explode their nuclear weapons and both the us and france used the south pacific
and or the pacific and um it was a big political issue for me as a young man in new zealand and much
later in australia as well people were concerned about this why the hell are we allowing the yanks to do
this and when maralinga came out very much in 1988 there was a huge court case by servicemen in the uk
where all of the dirty secrets of maralinga came out and all of these horrible revelations of toxic
radiation exposure were finally revealed and the maralinga royal commission remains i think one
of the most sensational public inquiries of that era because essentially it was crimes committed by the
state on the justification of national security exposing servicemen and women to high levels of
radiation that in some cases killed people yeah absolutely i mean that's that's the history and that's the
backdrop of uh you know some of these interesting ufo stories where we do have this well-documented
you know nuclear connection you've interviewed robert hastings i've interviewed robert hastings
and um i do think it's interesting with this with this malmgrim case i think there's a lot of
circumstantial evidence to to say that this this actually happened i don't know what you think
yeah i mean i i'm not prepared to stake my my hand to my heart and say i think harold was telling the
truth yeah i'm not prepared to say yet i think he was lying and part of this has driven my my deep
respect and admiration for pippa and i i do feel where the way douglas did it was quite heartless and
malicious well in the way that he did it that so soon after i agree the death of a man who the
family are still treasuring i think it could have been done in a more gentle way and i had the feeling
a little bit too much when i was reading harold's write-up not harold's douglas's write-up this is
douglas dean johnson who who wrote an analysis of the claims of harold momgren that substantiated the
the the allegation that there was a ufo retrieved in the triple blue girl triple prime blue girl tests
in the pacific and yes it is odd that there's no paperwork that substantiates this but is it possible
for example that because of the role that harold was playing of course there was no paperwork yes well
that is the history historiography of the time right we are talking to an audience that probably
believes that the cia had a hand in killing jfk then you ask people i have no doubt no doubt right
yeah they're all sure and then you ask okay so how'd that get coordinated who called the shots and like
oh it's it's alan dulles where was alan dulles at the time was he at the cia no he wasn't he was at
the brown brothers harriman where he had left the cia we're also talking to an audience that is taught
loves to talk about tim taylor this like really interesting character that inserts himself in
diana posolka's life says he's part of the secret space stuff and where was he working he was national
mission controller but he was also at a federally funded research and development center called
aerospace corporation so that is the backdrop that is the lens through which you have to understand that
this guy is working at the institute of defense analysis another federally federally funded which
research and development which i'm told by my intelligence friends is used as a front it is
used as a front he said in a 2024 interview with what robin laird i was the cover was that i was at
the idea but in fact uh i was actually helping the joint chiefs in the pentagon i know he couldn't say
this and and other people we both know can't reveal that they're cia as well but do you think it's
possible harold was cia i do and and i'm going to be coming out with a more extensive video
on this uh because i think it's important to say and i i actually wanted to say it as part of the
story but i wanted to respect his sort of gentlemanly desire to sort of keep it shut at
the end but you okay here a few a few fun facts if you watch that interview i did with him uh he says
oh i was best friends with tom farmer happened to be the gc the general counsel of the cia he says you
know oh i was living at nabikov's house and then pippa says yeah there's all these cia connections with
nabikov um he says he he helped create the presidential daily brief which is a cia thing
like over i was holding paul mellon's walking stick you think he bought that at a yard sale
paul mellon founded the cia so this is really important because a lot of the the douglas dean
johnson you know uh debunk is like i spoke to an archivist here i spoke to a person here and they
didn't know him but but but the the crux of it the heart of it is he didn't have a q clearance
if that q clearance came through him being part of the cia which he was part of the cia you wouldn't
be able to query it it wouldn't be in some fbi request down in a file and released to the public
absolutely not one of the things you can make a discretionary thing to do is to is to redact any
evidence that somebody held a q clearance absolutely because the fact of somebody holding a q clearance is
in and of itself potentially compromising a special access program yes totally and the
institute of defense analysis has been formally even on paper involved in every single missile
defense program after bluegill so strat x to thad and aegis now to you know star wars in the 80s
ida has its fingerprints over all of it not to mention you'd appreciate this you've
if you've spoken to bob jacobs ever 64 yeah yeah so yeah i'm sure you have some great content with
him um he's a really believable guy in my opinion he was deleted by the government and then you know
a mansman his major in the air force what a brave act by mansman to to go back so this is a guy just
to explain to our audience this is a guy bob jacobs who as a young captain in the u.s air force was asked
to photograph a fairly mundane launch of an icbm test prototype missile from edwards air force base
in the course of the launch of that missile they didn't know it at the time but when they reviewed
the film footage there is a ufo circling the warhead and shooting at it with a laser beam
and of course the usual suspects attacked him when he came public in omni magazine in the 70s and
basically said he'd seen this and said that's just a load of nonsense and to his great credit i love the
one of the things i i think we often we tend i certainly do in the media you tend to assume the
worst about all military and all intelligence but the thing i've learned especially from reporting from
war zones is there really is an honor in the american officer class and these men and women
are inculcated with a decency that is drilled into them it's a character thing to be truthful
and so the commanding officer of bob jacobs he'd been there when they'd watched this film
and bob asked him for support and he supported him and verified that that's exactly what happened
and that these two i think cia guys had basically told them to shut up about it that's exactly right
and so the the update here why bob jacobs is related at all the malmgren is people don't know this i have
footage of bob jacobs bob jacobs was stationed at johnson atoll but in 1963 so a year after
bluegill bob you had such an interesting experience at vandenberg in 64 i didn't realize you were
actually stationed at the marshall islands before that and that you were involved in the operation
fishbowl tests is that right first of all i was officer in charge of optical instrumentation at
vandenberg the 13th photo squadron as such we were charged with high-speed instant rotation
photography of every single missile missile launched down the western test range we had a
detachment at johnson island in the marshalls and i was sent down there for a period of time and
i believe it was november of 1963 not 62 the scuttled up the time by every single person on that island
when i got there this was engineers technicians um my airmen who had been down there before me
we were told that what happened is the the soviets have launched a nuke into orbit up above us
and jfk told khrushchev take that down khrushchev said i won't do it jfk said then we'll shoot it down
and khrushchev said you don't have the technology to do that we were down there according to the
common talk at the time to shoot down that nuclear missile that nuclear weapon in orbit i was told
that that that launch had happened and that several things had happened because of it first of all
something had fallen down toward the island from that explosion in sky explosion lit up the entire
south pacific and and caused all sorts of alarm and reports of ufos and so on
and something had been recovered i was never told what it was so that's fascinating i actually want
to be clear the incident that i'm referring to is the bluegill triple prime test which is at the end
of operation fishbowl in october of 1962 it's october 26 so it's during the cuban missile crisis
and so you're saying that the kind of rumors at the time you know at the bar sort of thing
uh were that uh soviet warhead was actually knocked out of the sky as a part of that operation is that
right that's what i understand yes but here's what's interesting we've never had nukes in space
no and i and not to my knowledge so unless there's some double story here where like you know we actually
did take out a nuke in space which i don't think we did it sounds like an ex post facto psyop
disinformation operation that's right but even then there were rumors widespread rumors of people
on the ground that there was a ufo shoot down that had that's taken place and the only alternative
is a nuke which obviously isn't true so i find that very interesting along with if uh there there
were um there was a FOIA request of the national uh nuclear security administration and it was for
everything you know all these ufo related acronyms and this was around starfish prime so a little
earlier and uh they basically say the responsive records you know we we can't give you any of the
responsive records showing that there are responsive records with those names in them um and it says
the subject matter expert we have to consult them on this topic or whatever so there are there's a lot
in my opinion of circumstantial evidence yeah i mean my i keep on coming back to the fact that if
there's a stinky dirty secret you don't write it down right and if if harold as he alleged was
working for example in the um the white house undercover um they wouldn't put his name in the uh
address book you know they i mean i i'm still keeping an open mind and i i think it's slightly
naive to think that everything would be written down well i've also seen his diaries which are now
in a safe place and they're backed up so don't mess with them and i have seen a lot of meetings
between harold malmgren and richard bissell oh wow in the diary richard bissell who founded area 51
mayor of area 51 and it was key to harold malmgren's claims that he was read into the existence of the
legacy uap retrieval program by richard bissell there you go yeah so who went on to become a deputy
director of the cia that's right he went on to become the number two at the cia so fascinating
what you know along the lines of what we were talking about earlier you've probably met more
people in and around these programs than anybody else alive in the from the outside please don't
say that too loudly you know it's funny when i came through on the weekend to come here um i was
actually nervous i've never been nervous coming into the u.s before but there's been a lot of
stories in the australian press about young people who were just turned away by border protection for
no good reason and harassed for no good reason and there's been a change of culture at the border
and uh i have to admit i had my computer on auto delete if it was opened yeah uh wow when i came
through customs wow and um i was ready to go live on national television if i was detained by border
protection wow which actually happened to me after i did the grush story really yeah i did the grush
story i was detained and held by cbp oh my god and um a mutual friend of ours made some inquiries and
confirmed that there'd been some kind of a flag put on my um on my file and unfortunately it was so
high level they couldn't access it but basically somebody i suspect from the agency had flagged we
want to know when cool tart comes through next and let's cause them some mischief and i have to admit
i um we have a euphemism in australia tearing somebody a new asshole i i just wasn't going to put
up with it and i i very i summoned my anger and basically yelled at border protection and said
i strongly advise that you get on the phone whoever it is that's flagged me contact them now
or tell them i will be going live on television in about 10 minutes to talk about the fact that i'm
being illegally held i have a valid visa you have no good reason to hold me if you want to fight you
can have one and i was let out good for you man well i think you're hopefully you're protected and
you're protected by the by the public because i think well it's funny i look i must confess i've
been quite humbled coming to where we are which is everybody here knows who you are i've been mobbed
yeah i believe it and and it's funny my my wife and children think it's hilarious that there is this
fandom uh there's even a guy god bless him in germany who's done a three-dimensional model of me
with far too much hair which is quite flattering it doesn't show the gut and it doesn't show the lack
of hair and um my wife and children just wanted to know whether it had a bobblehead like this so we
could stick it on the front of the car oh my god that's amazing that's hilarious but you know i'm
really touched by the fact that people care about this issue and and just to make it serious for a
moment um the issue is still ridiculed in much of the british style english language australasian press
you know i get mocked and ridiculed by my journalist colleagues because i take ufos seriously
you know and people will pejoratively sneer how's your ufo obsession ross or there's actually a national
broadcaster the abc in australia and one pompous twat on that broadcaster said oh ross cools out he's
been investigating ufos he's either completely crazy or he's the best journalist ever that's the best
but it was a snide it was deliberately snide because the clear inference was i was you can't
be the best i was a shithouse journalist and i was obviously going crazy but the thing i'm really
heartened by is the degree of interest that sparked me getting hired by news nation is incredible when
we did the david grush interview news nation admittedly not at the time a very high rating
news chat no you brought it on the map it escalated its ratings by 990 percent that was written up in
the industry press it's amazing and they still say to me that ufos ufos is the issue that saved the
network yeah and it's a really interesting issue because the audience no matter what the mainstream
media do to ignore this issue you know you've got the doctrinaire attitude of the new york times
we're not going to do ufo stories we're going to reject the david grush story you know the the jake
the jake barber story wouldn't fly in any of the national media sure i don't think it's had a
coverage anywhere i don't think it's had a coverage um yes and yet the public they make it clear they
really want this story that's right and they can smell another journalistic euphemism i'll give you
they can smell a smelly turd when they smell one and this story stinks to high heaven yeah and they
can smell bullshit and what fascinates me is particularly the younger generation i'm amazed
i've never had a story i've always been the kind of old fart of journalism you know and doing
investigative stories that not many people are really that interested in but they matter because
they're sort of interesting points of principle this one really captures the imagination of the
millennials and the x generation it's amplifying what i do on news nation and i don't know how to
use instagram or tiktok but there are kids that are making a living out of repackaging my stories
on instagram and tiktok and my daughters are constantly coming to me saying dad have a look at
this this guy's making a fortune over doing your stories on tiktok and i go look i don't know how to do it
i haven't got time to do it good luck to them you know it's great but what it's done is it's
generated this massive audience and i'm not trying not to sound boastful but you know we're routinely
getting millions of views for stories that frankly i'm genuinely surprised and excited and interested
that people are watching them well you're doing an amazing job and just a recent one which i i was
watching in preparation for this and i i was so fascinated by is you were um in sedona arizona
oh yeah and it was like if you watch watch this video it is the most mind-blowing video
let me tell you let me tell you i am in no doubt whatsoever jesse that there is a deep underground
military bunker that was built in the 1950s under secret mountain that's what it's called it's the
hilarious thing it's named secret joke it's called secret mountain unbelievable near sedona it's within
five seven kilometers of sedona and more importantly there's a place called secret canyon where there's
allegedly a portal some kind of interdimensional portal and i thought all of this was just crazy
nonsense but there are incredibly brave and super super interesting people jeremiah horstman and his
wife alexandra particularly who live in sedona and they've been doing some really clever on the ground
research and one of the things we did a lot of the stuff we got as so often happens you can't put it in
the story because you can't get these people to go on camera but there was a number of people who
would privately admit that they'd been walking in what is public land public parkland and they'd be
stopped by men with guns men in uniform with with automatic weapons clearly highly trained elite
soldiers probably tier one operatives from the way they moved and they would basically order people
go away or we will kill you no no mucking around and there are sightings numerous sightings of what we
saw i saw it with my own eyes i was told that the best time of night is around about 1 30 in the morning
and if you looked at a particular place over secret mountain you would see this big orb being escorted
by helicopters rising from behind secret mountain so i was skeptical but we went out with a local lady
melinda leslie who has some good quality military grade night vision goggles and we watched at 1 30 in
the morning and sure enough up comes this beautiful golden orb gigantic it pulses it's plasmatic
it slowly moves off and the way it moved you couldn't tell if it's because it got smaller or
it went so fast that it just disappeared so quickly but it just disappeared and they were they were being
escorted by military blackhawk helicopters dozens of them i mean the helicopter fuel bill alone for the
evening that we're watching them must have been somewhere between 50 to 100 000 somebody is paying
huge money to operate orbs with no visible means of propulsion over secret mountain in sedona
and it's funny because um one of the people told us that um if you want to hide something you hide it
in plain sight and that's the best way to describe what's going on in what i think is happening in
sedona and i think that's nhi non-human do you think it's i don't know made or i mean there are
allegations that that base is nhi i've had people who are psionic tell me that they have detected nhi
in that area sedona is also a strange place it's a place everybody says when you go weird stuff
happens yeah no it does and and i i never expected to see such overt displays of obviously anomalous
technology in company with obviously military style aircraft and you show footage it's which is amazing
and then you also show all these sort of logical fallacies of the cover story where it's like
i think there's like a contract between northern arizona university yeah but like none of the
professors ever show up and it's and it's funny because um what we're talking about is the bradshaw
ranch and there's allegedly a portal in the bradshaw ranch that was seen by the former owner of the
ranch linda bradshaw and she actually took photographs of it and um it opened up in a
particular area of the ground around that ranch which just so happens to be the area that's fenced
off and we noticed that there is a tower in the middle of that area this is supposedly a deserted ranch
there's nobody there there's no electrical power and there's solar panels on this post that has
a camera now if you're protecting the security of what is supposedly an academic research institution
you have the camera pointed out so that you can see people coming from the outside yeah but you know
where the camera is pointing where it's pointing exactly at the point where linda bradshaw says she
saw the portal and then the other thing we noticed when we were there and this was picked up by my
friend paul who's an australian ground penetrating radar operator he um he heard a humming and he kicks
a bush aside and there's this gigantic three-phase power power box with a cable definitely going into
the ground wow three-phase power and it's humming and then we walk a bit further around and there's
another one and there's massive amounts of electrical power going into the ground under bradshaw ranch and
we didn't put this in the um feature-length film that we put to air on primetime but it runs in the
full-length interview with paul my friend he did a ground penetrating radar check on the road around
bradshaw ranch and we found a 50 foot wide reinforced steel concrete highly visible on ground penetrating
radar literally just under the ground whoa i mean i'm in no doubt whatsoever it's there can you get
down there no i mean i was half tempted to get a shovel and start digging but the the interesting
thing is um the other thing we we learned about was there's an egress point into this whole secret
facility called the clarkdale cement plant and the weird thing about it is it's nowhere near secret
mountain it's halfway between two mountain ranges but it if you run a direct line between those two
mountain ranges and put it through bradshaw ranch where we know there's a tunnel or at least we picked
up the tunnel and if you match the walls of the tunnel with where it goes it goes directly wow to
the clarkdale cement plant and one of the things we heard about from locals was that 20 years ago
the drilling was so intense that things were shaking on their bookshelves and they were obviously
tunneling underneath the village at clarkdale where these people live and people were even compensated
for damage wow and you know i mean the i don't understand as a journalist i mean i've been taught
journalism to do the work on the ground and go and ask the question don't accept what you're told by
some defense pr flunky go and check and do the basic checking and i think the interesting thing is
that this is all coming out at a time in journalism where sadly investigative journalism is in serious
decline because even the great masthead newspapers like the new york times the wash post the la times the
boston globe the baltimore sun papers i grew up like i didn't have bay city rollers on my wall i used to
paste up big newspaper investigations that's what i always wanted to be and um it's sad because that
era of great big budget investigative journalism where they would deploy teams of people to go and
investigate stuff it's well and truly over and the big unspoken secret about the new york times is even
the new york times doesn't have the resources to do this kind of journalism but all you need to do if
i was the editor of a newspaper today i would put 10 days into deploying a couple of investigative
journalists to go up from phoenix and have a look at what i saw in sedona and you will find a deep
underground military facility that is highly protected has hydraulically operated doors in the side of
mountain sides and is secretly operating what i suspect is non-human technology it's amazing and
it corroborates uh you know uh larry saunders who wrote a book about deep underground military
richard saunders richard saunders sorry thank you and uh katherine austin fitz who talks about large
you know trillions of dollars missing from the the federal budget from the dod budget to to go towards
these these projects so uh and then nat kobitz's story another story randy anderson's story so
at what point though do i mean this is the thing i don't get i really don't get it it's almost like
there's a willful blindness in because why do we expect the mainstream media to follow this
because they should yeah but they know that they really should it's like the most interesting
important thing and it's if you talk about like an archimedes lever like the point of most leverage
i mean you can cover like local griffs right but why don't you cover like the trillions of dollars
missing from the from the dood's budget or why don't you you know this stuff no i love that quote
and it's a true quote i actually dug it out when i was writing my book that donald rumsfeld admitted
that there was something is it 23 trillion dollars missing from the budget i think he said 2.1 trillion
missing in an audit the day before 9 11 happened yeah the day before 9 11 trillions of dollars
are disappearing from the american defense budget documented that's actually one thing i really liked
about what doge was doing yeah yeah musk was basically saying why the hell do you not have
the acquittal numbering that allows you to reconcile what this money is for yeah with where it's being
spent well there was an amazing i think it was like babylon b like headline or something and it was
elon musk leaves job of making government more efficient for easier job of allowing humans to occupy more
which is like this guy doesn't give up on anything you know a successful car company hadn't been built
in the u.s since like the 1910s or something and you haven't built tesla you haven't single-handedly
resuscitate you know a version of nasa with spacex and and and he gives up with government efficiency
i had to interview elon in 2015 that's amazing i didn't know 60 minutes wow how was that well it
was funny because i honestly genuinely had the feeling that like one percent of his brain was
answering my questions and the other 99 was working on another problem but the thing i was really
impressed with was he he was excited to show me around the spacex factory in la because that was
where they were building the new rockets and a lot of the people in spacex but particularly in the
tesla factory right next door are aussies because the australians had laid off all of their car industry
we completely destroyed in an act of utter stupidity our entire car industry and so a lot of those
engineers went to work for elon and he loved aussie engineers but the thing i was really impressed with
was he knew more about every aspect of the production line than anybody that he was showing
us that day and it wasn't some big performance he really did know and he was asking about metal
tolerances and you know he really knew his stuff every aspect of that production line he knew intimately
and you could see he had everybody on his toes and frankly that's if you're going to be running a
rocket business or an electric car business that's exactly the kind of propriety you want yeah no
it's it's he's incredibly impressive he has a unique mind and ability to to make things happen
albeit albeit i'm sure he's probably highly annoying to live with i'm sure and probably hiding something
when it comes to the ufo issue because why i think he's been read in i think he has to i've been told
he's been read in uh yeah i i think so too um speaking of which speaking of high level people that
you've spoken to you were interviewed by don jr by the son of the sitting president before you broke
the jake barber story what was that like and did it give you any hope as far as american movement on
disclosure at the highest level if if don trump senior listens to his son don trump jr is very
engaged and interested in ufos and in a really well-informed way as well i mean uh he's been
briefed by a lot of people and there's been a lot of well not a lot but there's been multiple
secret briefings of the trump camp before they came into government and it's interesting because
i am persuaded not at the moment though i'm seeing any action but i am persuaded that people like
tulsi gabard nash patel and the fbi tulsi of course is the dni the director of national intelligence
um john ratcliffe at the cia these are all people who've previously expressed a strong desire
to get to the truth of the uap mystery and i don't think it's any coincidence that um representative
anna paulina luna when she was tweeting earlier this week about what a hopeless cause arrow is that's
the pentagon yeah ufo investigation office good for her she made the observation that they were
obviously a waste of money and should be defunded she implied that the money should go to someone
else and i think that's the fbi she's talking about yeah because i'm told that the briefing that
the fbi gave in congress really blew people away and watch that fbi ongoing investigation i've dealt
with some of the people on the investigation team yeah and i like g-men they're they're like dogs on a
phone yeah and they're looking at crimes yeah yeah because ultimately if what we're talking about
here is true david grush jake barber they have insinuated and alleged outright in jake's case that
people have been murdered that's right to protect this secret yeah it's a capital crime yeah there are
people who i suspect are very nervous right now in the legacy program because they are under active
fbi investigation yeah i wonder what the mentality uh is arrogance or yeah probably arrogance i have
no doubt they think they're going to get away with it uh-huh and you know what why they probably will
oh no don't say that no i'm pretty bleak i i i'm not i actually had an argument earlier on today
actually well not an argument but a free and frank exchange of views with a lawyer who's been liaising
with congress um and they were having a bit of go at me because i talked about how i'm talking to
legacy program whistleblowers who want to come forward yeah but they're wary of coming forward
and they took a swipe at me and basically said we've got all these protections in congress you should
bring them in and encourage them to come in and i said well hang on a bloody moment look at what
they've done with david grush's allegations that's right sweet fa yeah you know david gave them first
hand direct information from his sources of where to look where to find the spacecraft yes where to
literally go and open the door oh by the way there's a there's a spacecraft recovered from aztec yeah
open this door oh yeah that's the one from kingman that's right you know who's the person in charge
what's the title of the program what's the code name he gave them chapter and verse how many
subpoenas have been issued senate select committee for intelligence for any of that information
nada so crazy fucking nada and so i don't think congress is doing its job and frankly i do get
the impression that congressional staffers are captive to the defense establishment yeah i mean
that feels right i mean the last time around the uapda was killed by mike turner yeah like you know
his largest donors were all no but i mean it's funny because i mean a lot of the work is done
in this preliminary investigation of allegations made by people like david grush by people like
lou elizondo people like jake barber when they've gone in and given evidence in camera in skiffs as
they all have done to the congress the people that have been sitting there have been staffers
yeah and they're good people they're well-intentioned good people but one of the things jake
barber told me when he was um giving his direct evidence of the legacy program first person evidence
i mean people say where's the evidence yeah the first person evidence of jake barber was given
to the senate select committee for intelligence yes and um one of the staffers on that committee
was concerned for his own safety yep and asked jake are you able to help me get security because
somebody from the defense department is ordering helicopters to fly across and over my home they're
harassing my home and that's the kind of thing that the defense department was doing they were buzzing
a guy with black hawk helicopters just hovering over his home as an act of intimidation
a staffer working for the congress i know exactly who you're talking about and he was
providing a pipeline of legacy operators to uh basically uh talk to the senate the select
senate committee so i'm not blaming the staffers because these people are intimidated they have
families too yeah and i don't think the public realized that this is how the game is being played
you've got a vast national security state and it is truly a deep state protecting itself yeah it's
self-interest misusing the resources of the state your money your taxpayer dollars yeah to essentially
bully and intimidate and in some cases murder people yeah it's that's where i sort of go there are so many
times when i sit back in this story and i go hell's bells this is like a thriller it's like a john grisham
thriller truly but it's true yes and it's being ignored by the premier national security reporters of the
land i mean any sane rational editor who has an ounce of journalistic respect for himself and his bones
would deploy staff to at least go and check out the basic allegations see if the 170 odd q cleared
you know people seeing ufos around our most sensitive sites shutting them down in certain cases might be
somewhat credible like maybe maybe check that out yeah it's crazy but you know what i'm enjoying i'm
enjoying the tyranny of the internet the fact that you and i yeah are actually generating programs in
your case you're actually making a living by the looks of it yeah uh doing stories on this phenomenon
and reporting on it and it's interesting because that proves to me there is an audience there that
want this stuff oh yeah there there really is and i think it resonates deeply with what they intuit
about reality themselves which is that there's more and that uh you know there there have been
sort of secret programs around these things hidden from them for a very long time and and with ai and
with the internet you can vigilante corroborate and research a lot of this stuff yourself and so
i think people are waking up post pandemic as much as i share your uh pessimism around government
action on the topic i do think the the larger you know public is waking up to these broader realities and
that's exciting i'll tell you this if you accept psionics which of course the debunkers won't
yeah they're saying disclosure is coming interesting wow yeah well that it there's a perturbation in the
force luke yeah well hey i think the government itself accepts psionics as we know through their
remote viewing programs that yeah i mean that's the other double think you know we're told and there's a
whole movie made about it debunking the idea of telepathy and psychics and psionics yeah and yet
you've only got to read the cia gateway documents in the cia files and they show that that's actually
not true yes that that essentially everybody took it very very seriously and i've spoken to people who've
confirmed that there is still an ongoing psionic operation being run in the pentagon clearly well the
the um nominal reason for shutting it down in 1995 was there was only offense there was no defense why
would you shut a program down where there's still offense and it's still working absolutely makes no
sense yeah no i i just i mean i don't know why people buy this you know is it because they're so
distracted covering the ukraine war or um uh i mean i i don't get it i mean at what point did the lack
of curiosity begin i don't know well it's something i've found anecdotally that i wonder if this uh is
in accordance with with your experience meeting a lot of these guys with long government histories
and serious credentials they're often more conspiratorial than people in the public you expect
you you're a conspiracy theorist to be this tinfoil hat you know they live in their mom's basement or
something they're like they're watching crazy shit on the news but no this is these these people have
serious credentials their version of reality is way weirder than the average person in public's
reality yeah i mean it it's it's how i felt when i started getting into um psionics because one of
the first things that one of my sources in that georgetown pub back in probably 2018 told me was
it's all about consciousness yeah yeah and i had no idea what he was talking about right right it really
has taken me probably seven years to actually begin to understand and now i'm realizing more and more
it's all about consciousness yeah it really is i agree so much is downstream of that well uh ross this
has been an honor i have one final question before it for you before you go is there anything joe rogan
just talked about this everybody talks about this amazing bombshell thing that you reported on you know
i'm gonna say yeah this ufo possibly found in uh uh that that they needed to build a bunker around
that was like you know a mile plus long anything you can say about it i do not resile from saying what
i've said previously which is that there is a buried or at least built upon ufo that was too big to move
and that's it i i part of the reason it's actually i it's weird just how angry people get because i
can't reveal it and there seems to be this view in uap social commentary that i'm obliged to reveal
everything no and if i don't reveal everything then i'm being irresponsible and i'm not helping the
disclosure cause and one of the things that was steeped into me as a journalist i've been privy
because people started leaking to me things that they probably shouldn't have done to secrets where
including from america i should not have them and i've been shocked that i've had these things in my
hand and i've gone holy hell and in some cases i've burnt them wow but the worst one for me was when i
covered a um i was i was made aware that australia was deploying special forces troops into um the
iraq desert probably three weeks before the war started and a friendly special forces operator told
me that this was happening and i initially got really excited and i actually went and spoke to
an editor about it and said look i've i've got this story i mean they're deploying sas troops we're going
in you know we're going to be in the western desert and then we kind of looked at each other and went
nah and and i spoke later on i did a story with the australian sas about what they'd done in the
western desert and i asked one of the guys who'd been there if i'd revealed that what would have
happened and he said we would have been killed oh my god well there you go and and and so in the
case of the buried ufo i can't reveal because if i reveal why i say this it would compromise it
it's a very sensitive place that should be enough of a guide for you and to reveal the full extent of
what i know would compromise the lives of young men and women who are doing good things for america
completely separate from the uap program and they're probably oblivious to what's sitting downstairs
that's uh as valid a reason as ever and it also you know to to to argue on your behalf against the
the people that say that's bad for disclosure you're going to torpedo your relationships if you
you know are speaking to somebody they're never going to speak to you again if you reveal something
that you promise not to so because i actually take it as a journalistic responsibility not to reveal
something it's going to compromise the safety of your country or my country absolutely and and you
know we are really i i lie in bed at night worried about how dangerous things are at the moment i
wouldn't be surprised at all if israel launched a preemptive attack on iran in the next few weeks
i wouldn't either it's a it's a the world's in a freaky place and i think i don't know if you have
this kind of mind dialectic around the ufo issue but i think about that i'm like oh man maybe ufos
don't matter the world's going to blow up and i say well if the world's going to blow up if there
were ever a time to care about ufos and throw a hail mary yeah it would be now well one of the
things i asked somebody very recently was is there some kind of super weapon that we've got stashed
away because i've heard this rumor and look to be honest with you it's only rumor it's people who
probably wouldn't really know for sure but they've told me secondhand stuff suggesting that the u.s
has developed what are called scalar weapons well you heard the michael kratzian statement we are
capable of so much more our technologies permit us to manipulate time and space they leave distance
annihilated which you know he's in an official position and he said i know and trump keeps on
hinting that the u.s has a weapon a super weapon that's right that they haven't revealed yet but
notice putin has said exactly the same thing and i have been told that the russians have developed
extraordinary weaponry and i wouldn't be surprised at all if one of the primary reasons for the
secrecy is because each nation thinks that they have an advantage with scalar weapons but the reality
is none of them do right oh wow that's scary that there's some sub rosa manhattan project 2.0 going
on oh i'm sure there's a manhattan project 2.0 going well you have these rumors that you had
kammlerstab in nazi germany where they were doing kind of black world nuclear well i'll tell you one
thing i'm sorry we were trying to finish but i'll just give you this little tip we talk forever yeah
there's a there's a friend of mine who speaks to a lot of astronauts and to people who supervised
astronauts and um one story that came up was that in the early days of glasnost when russia
and america were kind of friends again russia imparted to america that it was in possession of
a crashed craft and there was an astronaut a known astronaut still alive deployed to go and actually
i don't know if he's still alive to go and assist in the retrieval and a lot has changed in the last
what 25 years 30 years since the end of the cold war 35 years and it's really interesting because i
suspect that there has been collaboration in the distant past between the americans and the and the
russians and that it's suited each side to keep quiet about the fact that there is this sub rosa
manhattan project going on where essentially there's a cold war there's a battle for possession of
and development of non-human technology and i'm in no doubt whatsoever that that's happening
well that's an amazing note to end on which is let's hope disclosure happens and these psionic
uh viewers are correct before the world blows up me too um ross this is an honor man is a long time
coming for me and uh it's amazing to to hear all your you know your vast knowledge and all this stuff
and uh pray for your continued productivity uh because you are you're really uh doing the lord's
work well vice versa jesse i love your show and there's plenty of room there for both of us
awesome all right thanks ross
so
you