You know, a lot of people I interview have had fleeting interactions in one-off instances.
You know, they've been abducted by a gray, or they've, you know, interacted with a tall white or a Nordic.
You've had years of interactions with all three, but mostly with the tall whites.
There was this giant white radioactive horse that floated around the ranges at night
and was fluorescent.
The extraterrestrials, when they come, even if they're your good friends,
there's always a tension because they always come heavily armed.
Today's amazing guest on American Alchemy has seen the inside of a UFO.
He's a first-hand witness to the collaboration between human beings and aliens from another world.
He's even made an alien laugh.
Charles Hall was in the Air Force.
He was also stationed at the notorious Area 51.
While stationed there, he was in regular contact with an alien race that he calls the Tall Whites for two years.
This conversation is absolutely wild.
There's a guy at NASA who has a deep interest in these sorts of things, experiencers.
His name is Timothy Taylor. Have you heard of him by any chance?
Did you say Timothy Taylor?
Yeah.
He's a good friend of ours.
We're going to be talking about aliens going to the bathroom,
what powers a UFO, and theories of subatomic physics that overturn Einstein.
Before we get into it, I want to introduce our guest, Charles Hall.
Hall enlisted in the U.S. Air Force in 1964 when he was just 19 years old.
He trained as a weather observer, measuring wind speeds, cloud cover, and visibility.
From 1965 to 1967, he was stationed at Nellis Air Force Base in Nevada.
His job included long, isolated tours at the Indian Springs gunnery ranges.
He was out in the desert doing routine weather observations when he started noticing strange figures.
Tall, pale, glowing shapes moving at a distance.
At first, he thought they were ghosts or maybe hallucinations brought on by solitude.
Other observers had similar experiences.
They called it the legend of Range 4 Harry, a ghostly radioactive horse roaming the desert.
One observer was even injured in an encounter with something and given a medical discharge.
Others flat out refused to return to the post.
But Hall was very different.
Something about who he was meant that he wasn't going to break like the others had.
And both his commanders and these tall white beings seemed to take notice.
In this isolated crucible, he began slowly interacting with the tall whites.
These beings would stalk him and test him, appear suddenly, and vanish, slowly gauging his reactions.
But he eventually learned this unwritten language.
And although there were some painful setbacks, he gradually developed a trust.
He saw family groups, parents, children, elders.
He would even end up referring to one of them as something like a brother.
Hall claims that the tall whites lived in underground facilities at the north end of Indian Springs Valley, complete with hangers for their craft.
A story bearing striking resemblance to that of Bob Lazar.
He learned about their different flying crafts.
And as you'll see in our conversation, what he saw comports with much of what we've learned about UAPs since 2017.
But the tall whites were not the only alien race described in this story.
Hall has talked about the grays.
The small, frail, large-headed humanoids that matched the classic Roswell image.
The tall white technology was better than the technology of the grays.
But the grays come from a planet that's closer than the planet the tall whites come from.
And the grays got here first.
And then there are the Nordics, what you'll hear Hall refer to as the Norwegians with the 24 teeth.
Hall described them as more patient, more diplomatic, even benevolent compared to the tall whites.
Some of them could pass among humans in the public, sometimes blending into crowds.
There is no end to the speculation about how these alien species, who Hall suggests have been here for thousands of years,
might have interacted with humanity's evolution or social development.
If all of this sounds crazy, well, yeah, I don't blame you.
And trust me, we've only scratched the surface here.
I personally don't even know what to make about this conversation.
There are things Charles Hall is about to say that feel beyond the pale to me.
So that's my primer for you.
Without further ado, please welcome this week's amazing American alchemist, Charles Hall.
Today's episode is sponsored by Incogni.
Before we dive into today's episode of American Alchemy, I want to give a quick shout out to our amazing sponsor, Incogni.
This is a service that I use to make all of my personal information vanish from the sketchiest corners of the internet.
Here's a fun but slightly terrifying experiment.
Google your full name plus your city.
What comes up?
Old addresses, family members, court records you didn't even know were public,
and maybe some bizarre risk profile that makes you sound like a bond villain.
That's all thanks to data brokers, companies you've never heard of,
quietly buying, selling, and reselling your personal information to advertisers, political campaigns, insurers, even scammers.
Incogni fights them for you.
They contact over 250 data brokers.
They demand your data to be deleted and follow up until it's actually gone.
And now they've launched something called custom removals, part of their unlimited plan.
Here's the upgrade.
If you find your information on any site, anywhere on the internet, even ones outside of their automated system,
you just paste the link into your dashboard, and Incogni's privacy team will personally get it taken down.
And you get unlimited requests.
Think sites like whitepages.com, trellis.law, or unicourt.com, places you'd never visit but where your data somehow lives rent-free.
I personally use it because I don't have the time, or quite frankly the patience,
to chase down every obscure website that's selling my address for $2.50.
And with Incogni, I don't have to.
So take your personal data back with Incogni.
Use code AmericanAlchemy or go to incogni.com slash AmericanAlchemy to get 60% off an annual plan.
Again, that is 60% off an annual plan.
That's over half the normal price off.
Online privacy isn't about paranoia.
It's about control.
And this is one of the easiest ways to get some of that control back.
So don't put it off.
Take care of your internet hygiene.
Now let's get back into this crazy episode.
I am here with Charles Hall.
It's an honor to have you.
It's been a long time coming.
You're the subject of an amazing documentary by Emil Marzak called Walking with the Tall Whites.
But you've also written a series of amazing books called Millennial Hospitality.
You have six volumes.
There's six volumes.
You have six volumes at this point.
And you've interacted with, you know, a lot of people I interview have had fleeting interactions in one-off instances.
You know, they've been abducted by a gray or they've, you know, interacted with a tall white or a Nordic.
You've had years of interactions with all three, but mostly with the tall whites.
And I really want to dive into that.
But first, I want to talk about your Hall photon theory.
You believe that Einstein is wrong and has limited physics, stagnated it for the last century.
And so let's get into that.
I'm quite certain Einstein was wrong.
And I've also written books entitled Beyond Relativity.
And I've done a rumble video entitled Mirage Galaxies and Edges in Space.
Edges is spelled with capital letters because it's a zone.
And I've also done a second film with Emil Marzak, which discusses that, called Walking with the Tall Whites Aftermath.
And that's all copyrighted Hall photon theory.
I first copyrighted Hall photon theory in 1997.
And I'm quite certain that there are many more particles, subatomic particles,
and many more types of force fields which exist in the real world.
And that's why relativity is not correct, because relativity doesn't take those into account.
And for context for the audience, you are extremely smart.
You have a master's degree in nuclear physics.
And you scored off the charts on one of these math tests before joining the Army.
I was in the Air Force, and what you say is correct.
I got one wrong out of 500 on the Air Force math ability test.
It was the one I was marking as I was marking the correct answer as the clock had sounded,
and they were ripping the answer sheet from my cold hands.
If they'd just given me 10 more seconds, I'd have got them all.
That's amazing.
But you told me off-air that what inspired this Hall photon theory was you actually seeing a craft
and realizing it could go faster than light.
So you were stationed at Area 51?
That's correct.
I was a weather observer in the U.S. Air Force,
and I was stationed at Nellis Air Force Base from March of 1965 until May of 1967.
And Nellis is in charge of the gunnery ranges at Indian Springs,
and I was a duty weather observer at Indian Springs.
Area 51 in 1965 was just the entry area to the areas,
and the areas went up to number 60, and I've been in all of them.
The areas were assembled into lands.
The most famous land was Dreamland.
Area 51 was not actually Dreamland itself.
It was merely Groom Lake.
Dreamland was Area 53 and 54,
which was the northern half of Indian Springs Valley,
and then the valley to the east, Dogbone Valley,
and part of the valley to the west, including French Peak.
The biggest shock was not that extraterrestrials were here on Earth
and had been ever since at least the Ice Age.
The biggest shock that I felt was discovering that Einstein was wrong about relativity.
The craft that the tall whites and the grays came in, the Roswell grays came in,
could easily exceed the speed of light by many times.
The tall white technology was better than the technology of the grays,
but the grays come from a planet that's closer than the planet the tall whites come from,
and the grays got here first.
So I would guess that 90% of the time that you see an actual extraterrestrial craft,
it's one of the gray craft.
And about 10% of the time, it's one of the tall white craft.
And the grays are much more numerous for that reason.
I remember the shock when I really, truly understood that Einstein was wrong about relativity.
I was out at Range 3 as the duty weather observer.
What year is this?
And this was in the mid-1960s.
This was like in 1965, the late summer.
And there was a six-week or two-month period where I was certain that the tall white individuals
who identified themselves as the teacher and Range 4 Harry and tour guide, who were my good friends,
that they had taken a vacation or a business trip somewhere and that they weren't on this planet
and that they had gone to some other inhabited planet orbiting some other star.
A reasonable guess would have been the star Arcturus or a star near Arcturus.
Then they came back.
I believe they'd been on a business trip-slash-vacation-type trip.
Now, Arcturus is 36 light-years away.
And the nearest star, Alpha Centauri, is almost four light-years away.
It's a group of three stars.
And to go anywhere and come back to another star,
the craft you were on had to travel quite a few times faster than the speed of light,
like 44 times or something minimum, just to go there and come back in two months.
I think a lot of people in the audience might hear that they're coming back and forth from,
you know, a star system that is 36 light-years away
and want to know some core details as to what you are seeing.
Do you see crafts coming in?
And what did the crafts look like?
On schedule, on the night of the full moon or a few days before or a few days after.
But their base at the north end of Indian Springs, they were using Dogbone Lake as their landing field.
What did the crafts look like?
Like tic-tacs.
Yeah, like eggs, like white eggs.
They were egg-shaped.
Are they of the kind of, you know, David Fravor, 2004, the Nimitz sighting, where you have a tic-tac?
Or was it like the egg that Jake Barber or, you know, Socorro, New Mexico, 64?
Or, you know, those are two different shapes, or both shapes.
When I first saw them, it reminded me the most of like a large version of the engine of a passenger train,
only with everything rounded like an egg.
There were no sharp edges, no sharp protrusions, just smooth and round like a round, it was ellipsoidal, okay?
Any hieroglyphics or symbols?
Not on the outside.
When you went on, their writing is hieroglyphics, more so.
Their writing, if you didn't know Egyptian hieroglyphics, a couple of the guys that were with me who had seen them
thought that they were ancient Egyptians who had somehow or another gotten into Indian Springs Valley and trapped there,
and were still using their own hieroglyphics.
Who thought that?
A couple of the other range men, yeah.
Interesting.
And they can stand right there in front of you. I speak from direct experience.
And if they feel like talking to each other using sounds too high for a human to hear, they'll do so.
And if you didn't know better, you'd think they were able to do telepathy.
Because they'll be sitting there in total silence, and one will laugh, and then they'll be going through a complete conversation.
And, of course, their electronics also are able to tell what a person is thinking and to put thoughts in the conscious part of their mind by electronic means.
Why do you think that?
From direct experience.
Okay.
Did they have a device that could implant thoughts?
Yeah.
Only it wasn't a big device that they had to carry in their hands.
It was one that they'd carry like on a helmet or whatever, you know?
No.
And what's the broader context here?
Are you sort of this rogue Air Force rangeman, or do the other range men and superiors, are they aware of this ET presence coexisting alongside you guys at this testing complex?
And is it sort of a, there's just this kind of awareness that there's this cohabitation there?
The Pentagon had a tiny handful of people that knew, that interacted with them.
The range maintenance men, a few knew they were there, but most of them just knew about the legend of Range 4 Harry.
The range, the legend of Range 4 Harry was that there was this giant white radioactive horse that floated around the ranges at night and was fluorescent.
And supposedly it was a horse that had gotten too close to the bomb blast at Yucca Platts.
And you'd see him on warm summer nights from a distance and you could stay, but you needed to stay away from him.
Hmm.
And he was called Range 4 Harry.
Now there was an actual tall white guy with the name, Range 4 Harry.
And the tall whites, when they were wearing their protective suits, could form up into a high-speed horse formation.
Like if there were a typical one as if there were two women, a couple, three kids, children, and two men, the two women would be in front and bend over at the waist and bend forward and put their arms out like that, some usually.
And they would be in front.
And they would be in front of the horse.
And then the three children, who remember their suits, the technology of them, allowed them to float 9 or 10 inches off the ground.
They could float a lot higher if they wanted to, but they had to balance themselves.
And the children would float, whose suits were a slightly different design, would float higher so that they were floating at about the waist level.
So you'd have the two women in front, then the three children.
Then at the back, you'd have the two men who had bigger suits and more powerful packs, and they would bend over the children.
So if you saw them when they were out in the desert, say a quarter mile away, when they all turned on their suits, the force fields from around those suits merged into one.
And I speak from direct experience, you would swear there was a giant white floating horse coming at you from out in the desert.
Now, that horse could, when they were in that formation, the reason I call it the high-speed horse formation is because when they, I personally watched them when they wanted to go somewhere with, when they were out hiking, say like, and they wanted to go somewhere fast.
They could form up into that formation, and they could reach speeds of 100 miles an hour over the desert by floating up above the ground and just going zoom.
I used to watch them play at the runways at Indian Springs Air Base on summer nights as the way tobogganists did, where they would pretend they were airplanes taking off.
And then when they got to the end, they would lift up and go over the fence around the runway and go out in the desert and turn around and pretend they were airplanes doing touch and goes.
Why do you think they were allowed to operate independently on kind of American military grounds?
So the superiors were kind of unaware?
The base for them was like a foreign embassy.
And they've been here since the ice age.
Do you think it was the nuclear testing that like created some sort of Wheeler tunnel or something that they traveled through?
Or like, why there? Why do you think they set up shop there?
I'm certain that the greys got here first, and they were here before the last ice age.
And that the tall whites got here second, and they were here by at least the middle of the last ice age.
And the Norwegians with 24 teeth got here towards the end of the last ice age.
The tall whites have the best technology.
The greys have really good technology.
The Norwegians are just barely able to travel in space and make it here.
When you look at the bases and where the tall whites and the greys are, you have to look at the way they were in the ice age.
There's a place out in the deserts that I was in.
It's out in one of the most desolate sections of the western deserts that you can imagine.
There's a L-shaped valley with desert mountains on both sides.
And then there's a valley on the northern side.
But in the southern side, the valley is an L-shaped valley, and there's a dry lake bed, a small dry lake bed on the southern side, and a huge amphitheater-type set of ground that the greys farmed during the ice age.
And in the mountain on the west, they'd cut 13 tunnels in the mountain on the west, and they used them as a granary.
And the first one on the north was larger than the others, and it was large enough for their deep spacecraft to come in and pick up grain.
And the 13th one overlooked the fields, and at the top of the L-shaped valley and at the bottom of the L-shaped valley, the mountains form a constriction.
So if you were a gray teenager with an appropriate weapon, and you were sitting there, you could monitor both entrances.
And so if any ice age animals came in to eat the grain, because they're plant eaters, the tall whites and the grays do not eat meat, they're only plant eaters, you could keep them out and protect, keep them from eating your food.
And when you asked, and when you looked at the valley on the west, you could see the ancient water lines from how high the lake had been during different stages of the ice age.
Now, central Nevada was never glaciated.
It was only, it was just that in the ice age, because the weather was different, it rained lots and lots, like it does in Kentucky.
And so those dry, those lake beds were not glacial lakes, they weren't glacial carved, they were paluvial lakes, the Latin word for rain.
And therefore, the bottom, those lake beds were flat, and the land leading into them were perfect places to farm.
And what you were looking at was a granary, a farm that the grays used during the ice age.
So it sounds like there are all these unique reasons as to why, as an extraterrestrial presence, you'd set up shop in that area.
This is a really interesting point.
Something I kept coming back to while preparing for this conversation was this strange possibility of what if Area 51's weirdness didn't start because it's a military base?
What if the base was put there because of a pre-existing weirdness in the region?
As Charles points out, the broader pattern is hard to ignore.
Many of the most restricted military ranges and test sites sit in the same kind of landscapes.
Remote deserts, mountain valleys, and high plains.
And sometimes, Native American burial grounds.
Sure, there are practical reasons for this when it comes to testing weapons and spy planes.
But often, these places were tied up in UFO sightings, cryptid creatures, electromagnetic anomalies, before military bases were even placed on them.
Many were even seen to be portals to other dimensions.
Maybe it isn't just a coincidence.
Maybe the military wasn't just picking up empty land, but claiming ground that was very unusual.
To put it bluntly, maybe military bases often like to co-locate themselves with very strange paranormal areas.
Skinwalker Ranch in Northeastern Utah is perhaps the most public example.
I've been there myself, and you've no doubt heard the stories.
It's probably the most scientifically studied paranormal hotspot in the world, at least on the civil side.
Multiple UFO sightings, glowing orbs, cattle mutilations, and even reports of orange portals opening up in the air.
But it also has its former military connections.
There was a U.S. Army outpost in the region in the 19th century.
And today, it sits not far from Dugway Proving Grounds.
In the 2000s, billionaire and government contractor Robert Bigelow received Pentagon funding through the OSAP program to research the ranch.
Why, you might ask?
Well, folklore from the Utah tribe had already marked the land as cursed, prowled by shapeshifters.
That was long before the Pentagon made it a research site.
And if you zoom out, the geography is interesting, too.
You can draw a rough triangle between Area 51, Skinwalker Ranch, and Roswell.
Other paranormal hotspots with co-located military activity exist all over the United States.
For example, Sedona, Arizona.
Local legends speak of tunnels and gateways hidden in the cliffs, where star people pass through shimmering portals.
The Bradshaw Ranch there became famous for UFO sightings investigated not long ago by Ross Coulthart.
Eventually, the site was taken over by the U.S. government, a move that raised some eyebrows.
Why seize a random rural property in Arizona unless there was something they felt needed securing?
To this day, locals still report black helicopters circling overhead and interference with drones near the area.
It fits the pattern.
Land fenced off not just for practical reasons, but because of whatever it is said to be in the land itself.
Land that seems full of electromagnetic anomalies.
And perhaps the same tunnels and land that are occupied by the tall whites.
And that brings us back to Nevada.
It's easy to forget that Area 51 isn't just one base.
It's part of a vast test range anchored by Nellis, swallowing up thousands of square miles of desert.
Charles gets into this in just a moment, but the history of how this whole area ended up getting claimed by the government doesn't quite add up.
Especially when it became a herd of desert sheep, suddenly becoming an issue of national security.
And it begs the very important question, how much of this pattern extends overseas?
Look at where the United States has planted some of its overseas bases.
Diego Garcia in the Indian Ocean, Pine Gap in Outback Australia, sprawling compounds in Iraq and Afghanistan.
Some of these sites already had their own unusual reputations amongst locals.
Or maybe some other uses to our alien visitors from out of town.
Do you think it's a coincidence then that you get Area 51 and some of the most top-secret advanced R&D when it comes to the American military co-located on that area?
I subscribe to the Marine Corps theory.
If it happened once, it would be random.
If it happened twice, it would be a coincidence.
But the third time you see it's there, somebody planned it.
Okay?
Yes.
Remember, what else is out there?
The Desert Game Range National Park.
Okay?
Now, the Desert Game Range was set up in the time of Franklin D. Roosevelt.
It was what I talk about in my book.
And it was like 1935 or 1937.
For some reason, FDR just got up all by himself.
And after talking with a single Army colonel, Army Air Force colonel, decided that the Desert Bighorn Sheep,
who live in the mountains like Sheep Peak, for which it's named, and the mountains to the east, must be an endangered species.
You say, wait a minute.
This is 1937.
I didn't realize we had endangered species until 1970 or something.
This was 1937.
And by executive order said, we've got to make that a protected area to protect the Desert Bighorn Sheep.
They're white.
And if you're out there hiking and you see something, in the words of the park rangers,
that looks like a human looking at you from over the sagebrush, which may be as tall as six feet,
don't look back, especially if it looks like a woman with children, because the bighorn sheep don't like that.
They'll attack you.
Just look away and walk away.
And in 1937, in order to protect the sheep, and we're talking before World War II,
Franklin Roosevelt and the Army Air Force decided that they would station a battalion of anti-aircraft guns with live ammo to protect it.
Okay.
In case it, so it wouldn't be subject to Japanese air attack.
And it was all that specific area.
In that specific area.
Wow.
Right.
And that was the Desert Bighorn.
Before there was an Area 51, before there was a Nellis Gunnery Range, before there was a Camp Mercury or anything, there was the Desert Southwest Game Range.
So that's the first time there.
And you say that, so the sheep are being protected by anti-aircraft crews that have live ammo, and they're open to fire at any airplane that goes across there in 1937.
And FDR just said, well, I want the sheep to be safe, and that's why it's called Sheep Peak.
Wow.
And you say, when you look at it, Sheep Peak seems like a pretty easy place to climb.
Why is it that the first time it is a matter of record that anyone climbed it was 1970?
Okay.
You say, well, we did Mount Everest before that, right?
Well, it sounds like, you know, protecting sheep with, you know, anti-aircraft technology, the most advanced at the time.
Yeah, well, it seems like if you'd fire a few live rounds, wouldn't you kind of scare them a little bit, right?
Right.
So based on your rule, if it's like, you know, fool me once, okay, fool me twice, fine, fool me three times, you know, that's sort of a, you know, that's not a coincidence anymore.
Yeah.
What's the second time? Is there a second time before Area 51, which gets set up in the 50s, that suspicious military or covert activity occurs in the region that might have to do with the ET presence?
Well, remember how good their technology is, the technology of the whites and the technology of the grays.
And I do not exaggerate, I speak from direct experience.
When you say, if they came here in the Ice Age, and in order to, and they're plant eaters,
and in order for, to get a little help with harvesting grain and doing manual labor and things like that,
there's nobody out in Nevada, where would they get that from?
Remember how good their technology is.
And I speak from direct experience.
If they wanted to use the scout craft, which is, oh, the tall white scout craft or the gray scout craft,
which I've, both of which I've personally seen.
And in the time I've been talking, if they wanted to, say, lift off from the backyard and go to the moon and circumnavigate the moon to check up on what's going on in the far side of the moon and return and land in the backyard right here, they would have already done so.
That's how good their technology is.
One of the things I personally watched them do from a distance, because if you get too close, the fields will burn you like a microwave.
But like from a distance of, say, like two and a half, three miles, was to lift, was to go onto the scout craft and sit down in the seats.
No seat belts or anything, just chairs like this, and lift, power up, and power up the, not the outer coils, but just the bottom and control coils.
And lift off until they were floating, perhaps as far off the desert or above the sagebrush as the height the camera is.
And then take a few seconds, like 30 seconds, to power up completely the outer coils.
It takes a few seconds to do so.
When they do so, before they do so, the craft looks the way you're expecting.
If you saw a helicopter out there, you'd see the actual metal of the helicopter.
But after they've powered up, they just look real fuzzy white, like a Tic Tac, because they're surrounded with force fields.
You no longer see the actual metal, you just see the force field and the way it's fuzzing over light and interacting with it.
Once they're powered up, they're ready for high-speed maneuvers.
Let's get into it.
If they choose to go straight down the line of sight, they can go seven miles at an average speed of 8,000 to 12,000 miles an hour, stop, power down, and set down.
And in the process, they would have taken more than 15,000 Gs starting and 15,000 Gs stopping, just sitting there in the room like this.
And in case you're wondering how much that is, 10,000 Gs will liquefy steel.
What's the speed of light is like 86,000 miles per hour?
186,000.
Okay.
Miles per second.
And they can do...
So, if they're going 8,000 to 10,000 miles per hour, there's still a massive difference between that and speed of light.
They're not even in low gear.
Yeah.
Not even in low gear.
Wow.
If they do that and they choose to go sideways, they'll go side.
They'll just seem to blink out.
You'll be looking there and they'll just seem to disappear before your eyes because they will have accelerated and moved to the side so fast your eyes can't follow.
I speak from direct experience.
And if you're looking up straight up Indian Springs Valley and they choose to pop over to Dogbone Valley and come down and then come in one of the northern passes to see what you're doing,
it'll look like they just blinked out there and magically reappeared over there.
This in a second or two later, if they were in the hands of a skilled pilot.
A lot of people who still believe in Einstein will mistakenly say they went to another dimension.
Really, they haven't.
If you were in the way, the craft would run into you.
There is no such thing as wormholes or warping space and time.
What you're warping isn't space and time.
You're interacting with other force fields that all matter has.
And, you know, the same way that you might have an electric field of different shapes or a magnetic field of different shapes.
But time never slows down.
Time never runs in reverse.
Time is just time.
It always goes forward.
Have you ever flown in a craft?
Yes.
Yeah.
A couple of times I did.
What was that like?
Well, I was in the cargo hold at the time, because there was, as I describe in my books, the day after I thought I'd broken my kneecap and then it healed up, there was the next morning when they came down to get me and take me up to their base, up at area 53, to see if I needed a surgery on my knee.
And was it the tall whites?
Yeah.
And when I got up there, the American generals and medical people were up there, too.
And I didn't.
I just bruised it.
But the tall whites had to prove to the Americans that they were telling them they're correct or wanted to prove that.
And so they came down and grabbed me and put me in the hold of the cargo shop.
And I still remember the trip up there and the trip back.
Where did they go?
Did you leave?
No, they just lifted off and we just went gently up the valley, perhaps 100 feet off the ground.
And I remember flying around range fours and made the turn around range four and then going up the valley to the, they were going to the scout craft, the back entrance to their scout craft hangar.
And the door was open and we went in there and then there was a whole bunch of them in there, but there were also American, an American general and some American medical people.
And the six sergeants, the chief master sergeants that were the human guards for the human generals and the teacher in range four, Harry.
And it was just like sitting here in a chair only in the cargo hold.
And they didn't do this.
They didn't totally power up because they didn't have to.
And it was, it was like sitting here in the chair and having the whole room just be lifted up and taken and come back.
And it was remarkably unremarkable.
Yeah.
The important part was that they thought they'd electronically hypnotize me, but their equipment doesn't work if you're sick or if you're angry or if you're really tired.
And since I was, even though my knee was not broken, I was still experiencing some pain, you know, it was still tender.
It meant that the way my thoughts, the blood flow in the brain was, was somewhat different than the way it would normally be.
And so, therefore, when you use the electronic hypnotism on me that would normally have worked when I was ordinary, if I was healthy and well rested, it didn't quite do the job.
It's almost like anesthesia that doesn't work during surgery or something.
Yeah.
So I got to remember it.
Uh, range four hearing knew that was the case, but that was all he could do.
Yeah.
Why do you think they chose you for all of this?
Why do you think you were sort of picked to be endowed with this knowledge?
One time I asked a different person who was one of the top, identified himself as one of the top three psychiatrists at the CIA.
One of the time I asked them why they chose me.
Okay.
Because I said I thought there were lots of men that were better at going out in the desert and surviving and doing fixing trucks and so on than myself.
A lot of weather observers with more experience and so on than me.
And he told me the following.
He said that, and he had like nine PhDs hanging on the wall for different facets of psychiatry.
And he was a very nice guy.
He was surprisingly young, like in his thirties.
He said that when he studied psychiatry, he was told that there was 105 different psychological defenses that humans might use.
The most famous is whistling in the dark.
Okay.
He said that most humans only use one or two at the most.
That one of the projects that he and the others usually did was trying to train colonels and generals on how to have more psychological defenses.
They were hoping to get generals to use three or they always want them to use three.
They were hoping they could get them to use four or five.
This is of the 105.
And he said that he had told his, the other guys that were with him, psychiatrists, that some of the, there were a couple of, there were some generals he was trying to train.
He thought he was going to get them to learn seven and he couldn't.
They were going to hang in there at three.
He said that the first time he met me, he was shocked because in the first 15 minutes, he saw me use the first 70 out of the 105.
And he was a certain I could use the other, the remainder of the 105.
And you can see it in my books.
He said the 41 men that went out before me, who all came back compromised and some of them burned.
He said the problem they had in his opinion was that they recognized what they were up against or something of what they were up against before they understood how they were going to, had decided how they were going to react.
Okay.
And he said that in, and therefore what happened was in just the first encounter, their psychological defenses got destroyed.
And he said that the reason they sent me, he said, if there ever was a person to send, it would be you.
He said it's because they'll never lay a glove on you.
Yeah.
They'll never, that, you know, that no matter what happens, you know, you have a defense for it.
Okay.
And they had evaluated that prior to sending you out.
Yeah.
To commune with the 18th.
They'll let, they have a, you know, and you can see it in there.
There was a time when I thought that the extraterrestrials, the extraterrestrial lady I was looking at, that I was hallucinating.
And I was kind of surprised because I was kind of thinking that if I was going to hallucinate, I was alone out in the desert, I was young and single, that if I was going to hallucinate, that it would be more like a Las Vegas showgirl.
And she wasn't, you know, and I thought, my God, how sick am I? I'm not even, you know, see.
And she was laughing because she could tell that I was thinking because of her electronic equipment, you see.
See, and there was a time when I was, there was a time when I thought that I must be short on vitamins when they would come into my barracks at Indian Springs and I would get up and I would see the children playing.
And I thought, golly, I knew I should have drank more milk. It's for supper. I must be short on vitamins and milk. And so I would take more vitamins and they would still keep coming. There was a time when I—
But you're also debriefing with generals who are admitting that this is a phenomena that they're aware of and that they're kind of working alongside these ETs. Is that right?
Well, I'm never debriefed.
You're never debriefed.
I'm never briefed. I'm never debriefed.
Are you talking to the generals about—
Not only—that's not an accident. My orders are, I can never be briefed. I can never be debriefed.
And the reason is very simple. Because the tall whites, like the teacher, can tell what a person is thinking, even if they're not talking.
Well, if you're debriefed and they're very touchy about their children, if a briefing person were to say, what kind of mother is the teacher?
You know, how does she treat her little girl? I mean, she was lost in the sagebrush and you saved her life. How did they let that happen?
See, then they wouldn't have to ask me to tell them about it. See, they could tell it by just reading my thoughts.
The next thing they would demand is that somebody, like that officer, be delivered to them out in the desert, and he wouldn't live another moment, okay?
Yeah. And I wouldn't have to say anything or do anything or say else, because she could just tell, oh yeah, I read Charlie and I see that happened.
So when I say that no one could ever ask me questions, I could never be debriefed. Nothing I would do would ever be classified.
I mean, they couldn't even inspect me. If they wanted to talk to me, they physically had to come out to the parking out of the chow hall at Indian Springs between noon and 1230.
And I would meet them there if I felt like meeting them, or if I didn't, then they would just, and before they went out, they would have to check in with the base commander at Nellis.
And when they came back, they had to go directly from checking on base to the base commander and say, yeah, I looked healthy and so on. And I could, and they couldn't come out and inspect my barracks or see anything.
Have you, you mentioned the CIA psychiatrist who said that you had all these psychological defenses and that sort of allowed you to enter into relations with the ETs and come back in time.
So it allowed me to protect my thoughts, the person I am, before admitting to myself, they are real and I know what I'm going to do.
Have you ever heard the name Kit Green? Is that familiar to you at all?
Hmm. It doesn't ring a bell, but I probably heard them. But see, like, see, like, like the first thing I agreed, the first agreement I made with them was after realizing they were real, that I asked them that whenever they came around me, that they talk between themselves, if they were talking between themselves or with me in a way that I could hear to speak English,
because it frightened me if they were talking between themselves. And it sometimes sounded like horse winnings or bird calls. And they agreed. And then the second one was that if I saw them out in the desert, like if I came over a rise and there was one sitting on a rock, I understood that it was easy for me to sneak up on them behind them and surprise them. And I didn't want to do that.
And I would just stop where I was and stand where I was and sing a song and let them know I was there. And then if they wanted to come closer, I would just stand there and they could walk up towards me and stop whenever they wanted to.
I wouldn't pursue, I wouldn't pursue, I wouldn't close the gap. And if they got too close to me so that it, I started feeling intimidated, I would start backing away and they would stop. And then when we had decided how far apart we were going to be physically, then we could communicate.
Your wife, Marie-Therese, mentioned that you actually were sent out initially.
Initially, I was supposed to go from, after doing my basic training at Lackland, then I was put in PAT standing. You know, that was airmen waiting their security clearance. Okay. And those airmen that were going to get a security clearance and be sent to San Angeles, Texas for security school 101, were supposed to wait there for like three weeks or so. Okay.
Now, the security clearance you're waiting for is whatever the government decides to give you, but it's supposed to be the top secret clearance. Okay.
Now, the security, the security training, the people who are sent to San Angeles, Texas are waiting to get their orders to San Angeles, Texas.
However, in my case, they've issued two sets of orders, the real ones to San Angeles, Texas, and the cover orders to the weather training school at Shunard Air Force Base, Illinois.
The idea is that the captain, who is in charge of those guys, who has a safe for classified material that's locked, this is 1965, times have all changed since then, he's the one that will give out my orders.
Yes. The day sergeant can give out all the rest of the orders. Okay. Yeah. Because the day sergeant, because my clearance is going to be a higher clearance than theirs.
Well, the Friday that they came in, the captain is off playing golf. Now, as a military officer, he's supposed to be on duty. He's off playing golf and left the sergeant in command.
The sergeant does not have the clearance to know about my orders. So, when the orders come in for everybody else, and we were all in the same class together at boot camp, I think a mistake has been made.
Okay. They get their orders. I go in with them. There's no orders. I say, well, because my cover orders are in a different location than their orders,
but they're not locked up, see? They're just in the temporary outbox. Well, I asked the sergeant, I got no orders. I go into weather school, too.
So, the sergeant goes and gets those orders and says, oh, yeah, here's your orders, and hands them to me to go to weather training school.
So, I go out and I get on the bus. You know, I got my stuff back. Now, my drill sergeant had made a very special point.
He said, anytime you do anything in the military, keep two copies of your orders because you can't trust your officers.
Right? Genius, right? I keep two copies, right? Okay. So, I get on the bus. I'm not in the travel mass, but I got orders.
So, what? So, they throw me on the airplane, and they send me to shoot at Air Force Base, Illinois.
If you can't shoot them, shinoot them, that place. Okay. Well, I'm in the base, and everybody else is getting paid,
and I'm at weather school, and I'm the best student in the class. And after, like, six weeks, I still haven't been paid.
And so, I go, and I ask the command, my immediate commander, can I go see, I'm not getting paid.
He sends me over to the base payroll offices, and they look at their records, and they're panicky.
You're on this base, and they send me back to weather school. I go back to weather school, and two MP air policemen and a dog come in and grab me
and march me over to the base commander's office.
I'm a little terrified, and the base commander says,
Airman Hall, if you have a copy of your orders showing you that you're supposed to be on this base,
then you're going to be a happy man, and whoever gave you the orders is not going to be very happy.
But if you don't have a copy of the orders, the man who gave them to you is going to be a happy man,
and you're not going to be a soldier. You're not going to be a very happy soldier,
because the generals tell me you're too valuable a man to be wasted at this school.
I had two copies in my hall. I said, thank you, Sergeant Matt, you're Sergeant Peoples.
I graced his hand. I said, you need another one. I can copy this, right?
I was a happy man. They said, well, we'll decide what to do, right?
So they'd been looking for me at St. Angels, Texas for six weeks.
The FBI had been looking for me at my house in London.
Nobody had found me. I go back, and the sergeant comes out and says,
You're going to Nellis, okay?
Wow.
Yeah. They gave me the usual wish list.
When you finish weather school, name three places you'd like to go.
I said, Germany, England, and March Air Force Base, Los Angeles.
And I said, no, you're going to Nellis.
How soon after you're stationed at Nellis do you encounter this abandoned weather station
and meet your first tall white?
Well, the first time that I heard tell of the tall whites at Nellis
was that my very first duty session had Nellis with another airman,
which I describe in my book, okay?
He was the airman that had been on leave for several weeks
because he claimed the Nellis weather station was haunted.
And it's not the one you see there today.
It was the old one that was the northeast end of the base operations building.
The base operations building was a very nice building for its day,
as was the weather station.
I describe it in my book.
And it had something very important.
It was the military version of an airport terminal.
It had clean restrooms.
The next clean restroom was a mile away in a group of barracks they were still building.
To get to another clean restroom, you had to go a mile and a half away, okay?
He claimed that when he was working NYCHA graveyard,
and he had been in its military, he was on his fourth year,
the previous swimmer that he thought ghosts,
you and I would say a group of five tall white aliens,
had come in off the runway, off the tarmac,
unlocking the glass doors between the base operations,
the interior of the base operations building, the tarmac,
because one of the force fields will make every piece of material
repel every other piece of material and just pop every lock open.
And that when he came in, there was one waiting outside, standing guard,
one holding the door open,
and then that's two men,
and then three women, one holding open the door to the bathroom,
another one inside,
helping them hold open the door to the bathroom,
while the third one was using the ladies' restroom,
and that they were rotating so that they'd come in to use the restroom.
He didn't, he, although he described them doing that,
he didn't appreciate what he was describing.
He thought they were ghosts.
He panicked immediately and started screaming,
locked himself in the doorway,
and called the base air police,
only to discover that the Nellis base commander said,
no, the air police cannot come beyond the road junction a mile away.
He's on his own.
Okay?
Now, I know from firsthand experience that he was telling the truth,
because there came a day when I had worked,
I was working graveyard,
actually a whole bunch of days on Sunday night when everything was empty,
when that would happen.
And the reason that they came is because they're just like us.
The bathroom that was a mile down,
which the mechanics down in that hangar,
airport hangar, thought was haunted,
was occasionally visited by tall white men
who had to go to the bathroom,
and it was a mess, never cleaned.
And if you were out with two men and three women
who wanted a clean bathroom,
and the one a mile and a half down was too far
and wasn't suitable,
and you said, where do we want to go to the bathroom,
you'd say, I know just the place.
It's the one in the base ops,
and on Sunday night there's nobody around.
There's the weather observer,
and he's usually sleeping at night like he should.
Okay?
He's not supposed to, but usually they did.
Actually, that was a great place to sleep.
I myself didn't, but I had too much fun reading books and stuff.
And so, and the guy that I was, he was my OJT instructor,
he also claimed that on a different night when he was in there,
that one of them came and peeked at him around the corner
and said, don't worry, the women just want to use the restroom.
He screamed and called the police again,
and they wouldn't come,
and he had a nervous breakdown.
So, you know, and that happened to me.
I said, yeah, don't forget the candy bar machine.
You know, you guys may be hungry.
Right?
And that's what psychological defenses do for you, you see?
That's the difference.
And, and, and, but that's the first one.
I, the, I, he told me the story,
but I didn't actually see the tall whites on that night.
Then a few nights later,
when he had been given an honorable discharge,
because the Pentagon insisted that he and I alone in the warehouse,
on Sunday night, alone in the weather station,
and together work at least one duty shift,
and then he would be given an honorable discharge,
a section eight, which he was.
Then when I was with my next duty shift,
my next OJT instructor,
and he was working a double shift,
I was working swing shift.
When I came left at midnight,
and I was trying to hurry to get to the base up,
to the base chow hall,
as I was walking back the mile or so to my barracks,
one of the new ones being built,
I would, and I, when I turned around,
following me was the tall white girl,
that, the 12-year-old,
and I was about a quarter mile down from the,
base up from the weather station,
and back by the white elephant was the teacher,
and two, Ridge for Harry,
and another tall white guard,
happily watching me from a distance,
and all she was doing was just following me,
intentionally showing herself.
At the time, I,
when you talk about what good are psychological defenses,
at the time, I couldn't believe my eyes,
even though they matched what the guy had told me
just a few days before.
I decided that because I was tired,
I must be sleepwalking.
And I said, well, gee, I thought if you slept,
I didn't realize that you could actually walk
and see things when you were sleepwalking.
And so I turned,
and I tried to continue walking.
I expected to hurry and get to my barracks
before I had a brain stroke or something and collapsed.
And I thought, and I turned around,
and after going a few steps,
and there she was, she still followed me.
And I had been reading a book on the Titanic,
which I can talk about later.
And in the Titanic,
it described a group of angels
who came in a craft,
land one of the lifeboats,
and landed on the ledge of one of the icebergs,
and dropped wreaths
for people in the water to use as life preservers,
which didn't work.
And how one of the angels was good at
floating out over the water
and dropping her hand.
And when I turned around,
and I was just watching her,
she smiled.
That girl,
she lifted up,
turned up the power on her suit,
lifted up a little bit further
till the top of her feet
were about as far off the ground
as the top,
not as top,
almost the top of that chair,
flew over beside the sidewalk,
which was over the grass,
and saw,
and went over the grass a little bit,
and saw on the grass
something that,
a piece of wrapper,
or perhaps a quarter or something
that interested her.
And with her feet still in the air,
lowered her shoulders,
reached down on the grass,
and picked it up,
assuming the very same position
that was described in the book
on the Titanic
that I had previously read,
like that night or two nights before,
described by the lady
in the Survivor of the Lifeboat
that was picked up by the Carpathia
as described in the book
that I was reading.
And it was like,
she was the very same girl,
and considering that
the 12 whites live
600, 800 years,
10 times longer than we do,
she could have been.
Okay?
And when I looked at it,
I was stunned.
And I still didn't make
the association
between those people
an extraterrestrials.
That's what psychological defenses
do for you.
And I decided
that I must just be
sleepwalking
or there must be something
with me mentally.
And I went home
and I went back to my barracks
and life continued.
So, let's get into
the Hall-Photon theory
because,
and just to set this up
for the audience,
also in the 30s,
in 1935,
Einstein, Rosen, Podolsky
come up with their
sort of spooky action
at a distance,
entanglement.
And it's known
as Einstein's dilemma
because Einstein
had always kind of
almost put a governor
on reality.
The speed limit of reality
is the, you know,
speed of light.
And yet,
with photons,
observably,
you see this sort of
entanglement effect
where optical properties,
various optical properties,
seem to mirror one another
at vast distances
just instantaneously.
And so,
how is the Hall-Photon theory
an update on that?
And how does that unlock?
Faster-than-light travel
in the form of a spacecraft?
Well, to begin with,
I'd like to thank you
for this nice interview.
And if I don't,
and having us on your podcast,
I'd like to congratulate you
on just out thinking Einstein.
When you say,
what's it feel like
to be smarter than Albert Einstein?
I say, well,
I know a guy.
It's not just me
because what you say
is correct.
And the easiest way
to see it
is starting with
the way Einstein did
with the Mickelson-Morley
experiment of 1897.
Yeah.
Okay?
In 1890,
which was a failure.
Yes.
In 1897,
everyone thought
that a photon of light
had only two force fields,
an electric field
and a magnetic field
that oscillated together.
Okay?
They ran perpendicular
to one another.
Mm-hmm.
And then they did
the Mickelson-Morley experiment.
And then they wanted
to interpret it
as though it were
an experiment
that you would do
with little boats
crossing a river
and going up and down
in the river
when they didn't know
anything about the photon.
They thought they knew
everything there was
to know about the photon,
that there was only
two force fields,
so they could pretend
that they knew
everything about
how a photon
looks like a little boat
going across the river.
Okay?
When the experiment failed,
then nobody wanted
to say
there has to be
more structure
to the photon
than what we know about.
Nobody wanted
to do that.
Okay?
They,
James Clerk Maxwell
had done his equations
and they didn't want
to say
there's more force fields
that Maxwell's equations
don't include
but should.
Okay?
And they oscillate too.
They wanted to say
we know everything
there is to know
about the photon.
And then they wanted
to say
and we know everything
about the river
and the banks
and stuff
and the little boats
that cross it.
So now they'd reasoned
themselves into a corner,
so what did
the experiment fail?
And they monkeyed
around like that
until Einstein
and they finally
asked Einstein
But I think of it
as a failure
to detect the ether,
the Michelson-Morley
experiments.
Is that right?
To think
a medium
through which
the photons
would be carried.
That would make sense,
yeah,
that there was no ether
but then that left
the question,
so why isn't there
at least some change,
why did the experiment
totally fail?
Okay?
Along the way
they ignored things
about the experiment.
the first one is that
if you do the experiment
with one photon
at a time
in the interferometer,
you get the same results
and that means
that the photon
has to be split in two
for that to work.
Today we call that
photon entanglement,
but back then
they said,
well,
I don't know,
spook you at a distance,
right?
And then if you do it
with photons
of just red light,
then you get
the same results,
but the bright bands
of light
are still red light.
And so therefore,
the explanation
that the photons
would constructively interfere
and destructively interfere
can't be correct
because if they
constructively interfered,
they would have
to change color.
Blue photons
have twice the energy
of red photons,
so that would mean
you would be sending
in blue light
or sending in red light
and looking at
interference patterns
of red light,
but that's not the case.
All that's happening
in the interferometer
is that the photons
are being steered
into bands
of red photons
that needs
another force field
to do the steering.
So what is,
if you have,
in traditional
electromagnetism,
classical electrodynamics,
you have
an electric field,
a magnetic field,
and a wave,
and they're all sort of
running perpendicular
to one another,
what other field types
do you think exist
in the whole photon theory?
A whole bunch.
Okay.
Like what?
And remember,
the force fields
can be different
force strengths.
The electric force,
magnetic force field,
is considered
pound for pound
to be like,
what,
a trillion times,
I might not have
that number right,
a hundred million times
more powerful
pound for pound
than the force of gravity.
Yeah,
it's 10 to the 40th.
But because the force
of gravity is weaker
pound for pound
than the electromagnetic field,
the force of gravity
can move further
than light.
Okay?
So the force of gravity
from our galaxy
can affect
the nearby galaxy,
the Andromeda galaxy,
at 2.7 million light years,
whereas the force of electricity
from our galaxy
cannot.
Right?
But Einstein wanted
to ruin that analogy
by saying,
to protect his own reputation,
I guess,
I have no idea why,
trying to say
that nothing could travel
faster than light,
not even gravity.
But obviously,
if gravity can travel
further than light,
it must be traveling
faster than light.
If you look at the symmetry
of the Andromeda galaxy,
and you say,
well,
it's,
what,
10,000,
100,000 light years,
200,000 light years
across,
and that means that,
and it's so well organized,
gravity must be traveling
trillions of times
faster than light.
Otherwise,
if the stars
were trying to do that,
and gravity was only
traveling at the speed
of light,
they'd all bump
into each other.
Why do you,
so,
is gravity in your model
also orders of magnitude
weaker than electromagnetism?
Because if it's traveling
that far,
and having an effect,
a pulling effect
between mass bodies?
If it's weaker,
then it could go further.
And see,
in the photon,
How does that hold?
If it's weaker,
it goes further?
Because it's like,
it's like the milk truck
delivering milk,
right?
If it's going to go down
the street and hit
every house,
and it's going to stop
and interact along the way,
or at least stand ready to.
But if it's going to
just do one house here
and a house 10 miles down,
the guy can go
into high gear.
But I would think of,
like,
attenuation as being,
you know,
like a wave being,
a certain kind of strength,
and then it attenuates.
The only way
a force field
can attenuate
is there,
say like,
I'll say like gravity,
is for there to be
an interaction cross-section
put up by another piece
of matter
or energy
somewhere
down the road.
and then when it's traveling,
it's not trying
to interact
with the electric field.
It's trying to interact
with another gravity field.
And those are attractive
interactions.
And if it casts,
and because it doesn't have to,
there is no interaction
cross-section
between gravity
and say,
an electric field
that would be traveling through,
then it could travel
much, much faster,
much, much further.
That's what the neutrino is.
The neutrino,
we're told,
can travel through,
if everything between
the center of the sun
and here
were solid gravity,
a neutrino could travel
through it all
and not interact
with anything.
So therefore,
a neutrino can travel
many, many times
faster than light.
Okay,
however,
you say,
well,
what about the neutrinos
that say are measured
at the CERN reactor?
Well,
if they're going to interact
using electricity
and magnetism,
then they have to slow
to that speed
electricity and magnetism
to perform the interaction
because time doesn't change.
Time is always flying
at the same rate.
They're all
in the same time frame.
Do you think
we have neutrino detectors?
That's why neutrinos
are so hard to detect.
Yeah.
But there are rumors
that we have neutrino detectors
like at the South Pole
and, you know,
kind of exotic.
The whole photon theory
says that within
that light is a bundle
of force fields
and there have to,
there have,
so there have to be
a whole bunch
of force fields
in the photon,
okay?
And you must have
to have variations
of photons
that have different collections
of those different
force fields
because you have photons
and neutrinos,
which, you see,
which are very similar.
And those photons,
that means that
even though photons
that we're used to
are limited by
the speed of light
because it,
because the electric field
and the magnetic field
have interaction cross-sections
that, you know,
the permittivity
of free space
and so on,
right?
Okay?
That it has to touch base,
it has to vibrate
all those piano wires,
if you will.
When you,
if you have
those other force fields
be weak force fields,
like the neutrino
is surrounded by
weak interaction force fields,
they don't got to vibrate
the electromagnetic wires,
you see?
They only got to vibrate
their own wires.
They may not have
to do it at all.
If you say,
well,
what are the permittivity
of free space
for those other force fields?
They're much less
than the ones
for electricity
and magnetism.
Therefore,
when you say,
let me compute
the speed of light
for those force fields
as I do
in Beyond Relativity,
you come up with a speed
a trillion times faster.
Charles,
using the Hall photon theory,
how would you
build the UFO
and how would you
basically propel yourself
faster than light?
Well,
I'll give you
some general principles,
okay,
based on what
I personally saw
in the deserts.
The first thing is
the UFO must be
a smooth ellipsoid
like an egg
or a tic-tac
because the first principle
of designing
the different force fields
and so on
is there cannot
be any turbulence.
What about a saucer?
Does that rule that out?
It depends on how
the edges
of the saucer are.
It can't,
and it can't have
anything concave.
An example
of something concave
is if,
like on the camera,
you have the lens
and it's shaped nice
and then around it
is a ring
that sticks out
and in between
where the lens
meets the ring
is concave.
If that were
the shape
of a spacecraft
that you were trying
to use
to propel yourself
through space,
you would be
strictly limited
to less than
about 80%
the speed of light
because
the force fields
in that region
would obey
Einstein's theory
of relativity
because they're not
streamlined
in that area.
They would
go turbulent
and once
they go turbulent
the force fields
will bump
into each other.
the heating
can go to infinity.
The amount
of energy
that's lost
in that little zone
could go to infinity.
But convex is fine?
Sorry?
Convex is fine.
Concave creates
this turbulent
kind of
potential resistance.
but if you took
that lens
and made it
a complete
ellipsoidal
sphere of glass
and you use
that shape
where there's
no sharp edges,
there's no
concave edges,
where there's just
always egg-shaped,
then
when you surround
it with
a bubble
of force fields,
they won't
go turbulent
because they're
streamlined
for high-speed
travel.
When you do
that
and you start
accelerating
towards the
speed of light,
it'll just
continue accelerating
as though the
speed of light
weren't there.
It'll just go
right on through.
When you hear
stories like
Ryan Graves,
Navy pilot,
talk about
a sphere
inside a cube
or other
kind of exotic
looking objects
that do have
pointy edges
and don't
always look
like your
traditional
saucer or
egg or
tic-tac.
In the
2003 time
frame,
a large group
of Boeing
contractors
were operating
near one of
the launch
facilities at
Vandenberg
Air Force Base
when they
observed a
very large
100-yard
sided
red square
approach the
base from
the ocean
and hover
at low
altitude over
one of the
launch
facilities.
This object
remained for
about 45
seconds or so
before darting
off over the
mountains.
There was a
similar event
within 24 hours
later in the
evening.
This was a
morning event,
I believe
8.45 in the
morning,
later in the
evening post
sunset.
There were
reports of
other sightings
on base,
including some
aggressive
behaviors.
These objects
were approaching
some of the
security guards
at rapid speeds
before darting
off.
The force
fields interact
with light.
when you
see, and
you can see
it on the
Tic Tac
video, the
Navy pilots,
when you
look at the
video, the
first question
you have to
ask yourself
is when
you're looking
at the edges
of the
craft, you
have to ask
yourself, are
you looking
at just the
force fields
that are
interacting with
light, that
go away when
the craft
shuts down, or
are you
looking at the
actual physical
metal ceramic
parts of the
craft, see, and
are you looking
at a craft that
was designed to
exceed the speed
of light, or
are you looking
at a craft that
was just designed
for a
specialized general
kind of purpose
here on Earth?
because, remember,
the scout craft
that you see, like
the, for the
grays and the
whites, did not
make the deep
space crossing.
Only the deep
space craft make
the deep space
crossing.
What are the
differences?
What's the main
distinction?
The difference is
the scout craft
what we use
RVs to get
around.
Yeah, see, the
deep spacecraft, and
I speak from
direct observation,
they can all be
individual, like
ships at sea, or
they can be
general purpose.
Like, but one,
for example, looks
like, well, you
see how this
house is.
One that I
personally saw
was a little bit
longer than this
house, a little bit
wider than this
house, about half
again as high as
this house, and
it was all
totally smooth all
around, you
know, no
protrusion or
whatever.
It had the
standard double
hull, and then
it had another, and
the way this house
has this room and
then on the side, it
had another set of
rooms, so it had
the double hull on
the outside, then it
had a boundary area
where you'd store
stuff on both
sides, and then it
had the living area
where you had
actual cabins, the
way you do on
ships, and then
up at the front, you
had the cockpit and
the control area up
on top, and control
lights up on top, and
then in the back, you
had the propulsion
system, and that was
meant to put sand out
to deep space and head
out for stars a hundred
light years away, okay?
I'm quite certain of
that.
And on the other
hand, see a saucer
that you might have
for your children to
take out to the play
area, which I also
saw, it's not meant
to go faster than
light.
It's just meant to go
like from Bishop,
California to
Roswell, New Mexico
in a half hour, you
know?
And it could do it in
ten minutes, but it's
just meant to have a
couple of teenagers
take charge, put in
three younger children,
say eight or ten, and
go out and play, and
just go around places
here on Earth.
So getting back to
how you'd build the
ideal...
See, so when you
build it, if you
build it for deep
spaces, and one that
has like that, where
you have like a ball
inside and then stuff
outside, like a cube
or something, you might
ask, is that really
one craft?
Or is it the center
ball is the real
craft, and the
outside is something
like a car pulling
a trailer, you
know?
See, you have to
first ask, who are
they, and what did
they mean to use that
craft for?
You see?
Because they don't
just come here in a
craft, they build
them while they're
here.
Now, the Norwegians
with 24 teeth can
only repair their
craft when they get
here, at least in
1965.
One of the things
they wanted to be
able to do was to
work with the
American government
and build craft
here.
And that's, see, so
whenever you see a
craft, whether it's
a deep spacecraft or
a scout craft or
whatever, you have
to ask, what's it
meant for?
If you really expect
to do high speed,
like 50, well, like
the scout craft that
the tall whites had
that were ellipsoidal.
One time I asked,
personally asked
Range 4 Harry if
that craft could
exceed the speed of
light.
He was a very nice
guy.
We were like
brothers.
He was very
adamant.
He said it could,
but nobody, I'm
going to use my
words, in their
right mind would
ever take it that
fast.
Once you got up to
about 1% the speed
of light, you were
covering distance so
fast, in his words,
that if anything went
wrong, your friends
couldn't find you.
And he didn't think
it was made very
well.
He pointed out that
to repair it, you
had to sit the craft
down somewhere, like
in the desert, and go
outside and open it
up to repair it.
But that the real
deep spacecraft, you
could repair
everything from the
inside.
So the first thing
that he thought that
a deep spacecraft had
to have was in
addition to a
double hull and
fiber optic windings
in between those two
hulls to carry
subatomic particles
that would generate
the force fields that
you were working
with, that you had
to have access from
the inside of the
craft to repair
them.
You had to be
careful they didn't
overheat.
If they overheated,
you had to have,
the design had to
apply, you had to be
able to repair that
from the inside.
If you got in
trouble, you had to
have emergency beacons
that used the force
fields that travel
faster than light
to send for help.
Because those types
of force fields that
you're using in the
design, like you
could see it in,
you could see it in
the, in the
TikTok video,
if you're going to
control radio,
infrared rays that
are traveling at the
speed of light,
you want to use a
force field that
itself is traveling
faster than the
speed of light.
light.
Otherwise, you can't
catch them and
control them.
How does the, how
does, you mention
that the engine or
the propulsion is the
only thing that the
tall whites didn't
kind of fully give the
humans as far as the
ability to sort of fly
these UFOs.
Direct observation.
So, yeah.
So what do you think
as far as how the, how
does, how do these
engines work?
How are the, what's the
power source?
And then obviously
it's not chemical
combustion.
So what's going on in
the engine?
I'm quite certain that
there's more subatomic
particles, more quarks
than the six they know
of.
There's at least two
more sets.
But how do you, how do
you figure that out?
And when you, sorry, you
have these like large
Hadron colliders.
It's like super expensive
to build.
It costs billions of
dollars.
So when you, when you
design, when you sit
down to design a craft,
there's five subatomic
particles that are
virtually always used
because they're close
to being stable and
easy to work with.
And what you need is to
have ceramic fiber.
You need your, in your
engine, you have to
produce those.
So you have, you don't
have just one engine.
You have to have a way
of producing all five
of those.
And then what you have
are ceramic fiber optic
cables.
Ceramic fiber optics are
49.6% aluminum, 50.2%
silicon dioxide.
That's the same as rocks.
And the remainder is the
semiconductor, germanium,
selenium, and so on, that
you use to coat those
fibers with to create fiber
optics.
And then you wind those
into coils.
And those are, and whether
you power up those coils
or don't power up those
coils, that's how you
control and propel your
craft.
Okay.
And those five, and how
you design those five
depends on what you want
to do with your craft.
There's two more
types of subatomic
particles in that
family that are more
unstable and are only
occasionally used, but
not for craft that you
would ever have children
or a family on.
Because all of the
extraterrestrials travel as
families.
They would only be, you'd
only find them on
military craft.
And then there's two
more, and so far we've
talked about a total of
nine, okay, that are so
unstable that you would
never use them when you
were designing your craft.
You would only use them if
you were designing a
military weapon.
And when you say that
number five, right, and
the number seven, that
seems to ring a bell.
Because we're told that
when Ike Eisenhower was
president, that there was
a day that we're told
publicly by ancient
aliens and the U.S.
press and so on, that
there was a day at
somewhere, the British
guy said it was at
Edwards, other people
said it was at
Alamogordo, but they say
it was, there was a day
somewhere where he was
taken, where they took him
out, the day he was
supposedly golfing at Palm
Springs and was taken to
Edwards.
No cameras, no press, and
sitting on the runway at
Edwards were five
spacecraft with extraterrestrials by
him, and that he, they were
shown to Ike Eisenhower.
Not one, except for the guy
whose name is Charlo, looked at
that and said, that makes perfect
sense that they would do five.
Because what they were showing
him was the general features of
how their airplane, how their
spacecraft were designed.
And you'd say, why five?
It's because they were showing
that there were five different
subatomic particles, and that
when they designed them, they
first said, I'm going to use this
one for this purpose, this one
for the second one for another
purpose, and so on.
And so they were showing him that
they had five different purposes
for that, in the design, you
see?
And, okay, but those who, you
know, who, who mean well, think
that they just arbitrarily showed
five.
Another one is the number three.
See, the fiber optics coils melt
suddenly at about somewhere between
1800 and 2200 Fahrenheit.
Not because they're made by
aliens, but because rocks melt
between 1800 and 2200 degrees
Fahrenheit.
And if they're 50.2% silicon
dioxide and 49.6% aluminum,
that's what they are, is rocks.
And if they melt, as they, and if
the fiber optics melt, as they did
during the Roswell, the two craft
that crashed at Roswell, as
described in my book, The Valley of
the Grace, what you'll see, you
would think, would be melted rocks.
I know, I know, UFO people try to
pretend that there was one saucer,
and it was going fast, and it
bounced, and it hit the ground, and
melted the rocks, and then bounced
up, and went on.
And my answer is, if you haven't,
you know, when was the last time you
saw anything bounce against the rocks
in a Nevada, you know, New Mexico
desert?
I never have.
Once they hit the rocks, they break.
When, the reason there were melted
rocks there is because there were two
saucers, and the fiber optics were
overheating and melting, and when they
melt, they melt like melted glass or
lava, and they have a big chunk that
looks like lava, and a big chunk
falls, and then it hardens and hits
the ground, and looks like a melted
rock.
So, when you see those reports that
the geologist came, and his son said
these are melted rocks, and they left
them behind, and they say, we went out
and picked up all the debris, and we
picked up this metal that resumes its
shape.
I said, those were cigarette wrappers.
Those were gum wrappers that did that.
What you passed over was the stuff you
care about.
We found a piece of metal about a foot and
a half to two feet wide, and about two or
three feet long.
It felt like you had nothing in your
hands.
It wasn't any thicker than the foil out of
a pack of cigarettes.
But the thing that got me is that you
couldn't even bend it.
You couldn't bend it, even though the
sledgehammer would bounce off of it.
So, I knew that I had never seen anything
like that before.
And as of now, I don't know what it was.
So, you're saying Jesse Marcel, that was
just like the sort of memory metal, that
was just the kind of exhaust.
That could have come off from a kid's
toy, okay?
Yeah, because, see, what you have is what
you, after you've put in your melted, after
you've put in your coils, then you have to
protect them from the weather.
Now, when you protect them from the
weather, you're going to have to cover
them with a thin metal sheet, okay?
But you're not going to be able to support
the metal sheet with an outside metal
strap.
You're not going to be able to protect
the metal sheet with an inside metal
strap, because you can't have turbulence
in the force fields, and the metal is
electromagnetic.
We'll screw it up with stray
electromagnetism, and so on.
And when you're designing it, you're going
to start from square one, and then three
times a day, you're going to come up and
say, I don't want any turbulence in this
force field.
I don't want these coils to overheat.
You're going to leave, if you're a gray
designer, and you're designing a craft for
gray children, then you're going to have, as
per the Roswell Museum, you're going to
have something that is missing from their
display model.
On the underside, you're going to have a
little doorway that the operator of the
craft can open anytime he wants, and let
molten fiber optics fall out, okay?
Because he's in desperate mode to save his
fiber optics, they have overheated.
And then he can close the door and take off
again.
And if he does, he may not be able to use all
of his coils.
So if he's by himself, he's in deep trouble.
As in the craft over the plains of San
Augustine in 1947, he's by himself.
And he's got big trouble.
But if he's got two craft beside him, the
fields from their craft and the fields from
his craft will join together, as I've
personally seen Range 4 Harry do with the
high-speed horse formation to form a
single, larger craft when the fields are
present, and stabilize his craft, and now
the three together can fly off to someplace
safe, okay?
Do you need to use specific metamaterials
for these, you know, very intense kind of,
you know, environments and, you know, a lot
of electricity and, yeah, do you need to use
specific materials for the craft?
Before you can know about the materials, you
have to know about the subatomic particles.
Because the ceramic fiber optics are supposed to contain, do what fiber optics do today,
only they do it differently.
I've personally seen the fiber optics when, as I describe in my book, when I was in the
sixth, the summer after my sixth, between my fifth and sixth grade, when Ray Palmer, I believe that was his name, editor of Flying Saucers Magazine, in a store in London, Wisconsin, and his childhood friend who ran the store, came back from Roswell with a stretch about a yard long. And it was, it was woven. It wasn't a thin strip of metal. It was like they took nylon fibers, but it wasn't nylon. It was ceramic.
And wound it. And then when you flowed, shined the flashlight through it, the light would bend without being absorbed. Now, you, but before you do it for the craft, you first have to know about the particles, because you have to know how to build the fiber optics before you can do anything else.
So Roswell, you mentioned the Roswell Grays, and you're talking about the Roswell Craft. The lore is that it made its way to Wright-Patterson, Wright-Airfield at the time. And did you think, you're saying it eventually made its way to Area 51 or to the Nevada test range?
I don't know where it made its way to, but I don't care, because I've seen the real one and I know what it looks like. According to just, according to that...
Where did you see it? Did you see it in Nevada?
In Nevada. I've seen a craft of that type many times. On one, as I describe in my book on the Valleys of the Grace, on one cold and snowy night in the fall back in the 60s, when I damn near died in the fog,
and the scout craft with the young lady in it and some of her friends, accompanied by the deep space craft and the teenage craft, they had gone down to the bend in the road.
And she alone, she was just learning to run the craft, so they didn't let her take it up in the air.
And before the fog moved in, when I was walking down there, I was on the side of a hill, I was alone.
And she had brought the craft in on the paved, on the gravel road.
She just had the control coils running, and she had opened up the door on the side.
I was very reluctant to approach a craft because I knew from experience that they all have those fields surrounding them.
And then if you get too close, it's like walking into the back of a jet engine.
And when the Jinda engine is running, you've got to just stay and let them see you and let them come as close as they want, or you'll get your ass burned.
So I wasn't—but she had powered down the outer coils.
So from her point of view, there was nothing keeping me from just walking the final distance and stepping up into the craft and saying hi,
and meeting her and the others who were on the craft.
I didn't realize at the time that the teenager who was the backup pilot, he was a young gray.
They looked just like someone from Mongolia.
But the other three, she and the other three, were actually humans.
They were young Chinese people that the Gray's had rescued, not abducted, but they had been orphaned and the Gray's had reputed.
And the whole point was that they were trying to return them to human society.
But first, you ought to find a human who everybody trusts, including the children.
And the human has to be somebody who trusts them in return, and the human they had figured that,
they had chosen, had this last name Hall and the first name Charlie, okay?
They're Charles, right?
And you say, well, why didn't they tell me?
And they say, well, that's why we picked him, because he'll figure it out if we just give him time, right?
Why tell him early and scare him, right?
You know, that's why we picked him, because he's perfect at convergent, divergent reasoning, and he'll figure it out.
And that's what they're doing, waiting for me to come.
And what they had was the very same craft of the three that crashed at Roswell.
What they had was the very same craft.
And in the back of that craft...
Do you think we know how to fly these crafts now?
Do you think humans know how to fly them?
I'll finish this sentence and I'll answer it.
In the back of that craft was a restroom.
In the back of all those people are real physical biological entities.
They all have to eat.
They all have to breathe air, drink water.
And they all have to periodically go to the restroom.
And therefore, every craft in the back has a bathroom, you see?
And therefore, when you say, like the crash at Kingman, the young lady that survived, the sheriff there,
said that after she came out and they were waiting for help to come, what did she do?
So, in his own words, he said she went back in the craft and stayed in the back.
And the UFO people say it must be a shrine where she was praying.
And, of course, I think that's really laughable because having seen the craft, there's no shrine back there.
What there is is a bathroom.
And there's also food storage.
And so, if the craft has crashed and she's got to wait a while, like every other biological entity,
they're going to fall back on the bathroom, you see?
There's no reason to fall back on the control panels because the craft isn't running.
That's why they crashed, see?
But the UFO people all have this thing.
Well, there was a time they said in all those crafts, there must be a shrine in the back, you know, where they go and pray.
And you'd say, no, no, no, no, I've seen the craft.
They're going, that's a bathroom, right?
And I have a whole class of stories in that vein.
And so, when I say my advantages that I've been there and seen that,
I say the wreckage that was sitting in the hangar at Roswell that was recovered from Roswell.
When you say, what was that like?
Well, that wreckage had the bathroom on the other side.
And so, that meant for the part that blew in was blowing in on the food storage, you see?
And so, when you went on the wreckage of that, I would guess that you would find on the other side what remained of the restroom,
which might not be very much.
I'm saying when you, okay, but now in answer to your, what was your question that you wanted me to answer?
I asked if humans, you mentioned that these, there were these Chinese occupants of the craft.
Do you think that humans can fly these exotic, you know, ET crafts?
It's like everything else if they're trained, okay?
It's like if they have an opportunity to learn, if they have a trainer.
Yeah, it's not something you can do naturally for the same reason that a Cessna airplane, they tell me it's a pretty simple airplane to fly.
Okay, I've actually flown one as co-pilot for about 45 minutes, but not by myself.
There was a trained pilot, I was in the co-pilot seat, and the trained pilot was in the pilot seat.
And it was a nice night, and all I was doing was flying straight and level and saying, yeah, I'm not moving anything, okay, if you call that flying.
Well, does the training involve the mind-matter connection?
There are rumors that there are no control panels.
Do you sort of psychically connect with the craft?
You don't do anything psychically.
Everything is electronics.
The electronics either are adjusted to tell what you're thinking and therefore react because you're thinking, or to not work at all.
It isn't the person that has to change their way of thinking.
It's the person who's adjusting the electronics has to adjust it.
It's unique for each human.
So how many of these tall whites were out there with you, if you had to guess or estimate?
It varied with how many ships were in port.
See, the deep spaceships would arrive and would come and go on schedule the same way an airport is.
They liked to come and go near the night of the full moon.
And on the night of the full moon, the moon and the earth and the sun all form a line.
And so behind the earth in its orbit is a uniform gravitational field and it's going away from the incoming craft.
So if anything goes wrong, they can back off and the earth won't run into them.
It'll go away.
This is much different than the Norwegians with 24 teeth who want to come in on the front side of the earth
because the Norwegians with 24 teeth, with less technology, must land at any price, even if the earth runs into them.
But the grays and the tall whites, the deep spacecraft of the tall whites, want to come in on the night of the full moon.
The grays, who have a base on the moon, come and go at any time they want.
The tall whites, the craft come on schedule and they have different schedules.
Some are making a two-month schedule.
So the longest schedule I saw was craft that take five years.
And those craft with a five-year schedule, I was told, were coming directly from their home planet.
Of course, since all the craft travel many times faster than the speed of light, I'm not sure where their home planet was.
But if there were no craft in port, then the number of tall whites at the base wasn't particularly large.
I'm not sure what the number was, but it would be rare to see as many as a hundred out in the desert if there were no ships in deep spacecraft in port.
On the other hand, the night that Pamela was supposed to pass her test to head up a tall white technology transfer team,
by dressing up and disguising herself as a human woman and the other tall white by dressing up and disguising himself as a human man specifically named Charlie Hall.
And she would specifically pretend to be his wife so they could go into places like Livermore and pretend to be humans and talk to the scientists, I'm guessing.
Wait, explain what you just said.
In a minute.
The night she was going to pass that—
Are you saying that you're a tall white?
No, I'm not a tall white.
I was born in Brooklyn, Wisconsin.
My parents all came from England.
Well, then, but they mimicked you.
One of the tall whites disguised themselves as you and your wife and then showed up at Livermore Labs?
I'm guessing.
And how do you know?
Well, where did that come from?
I've never seen any classified documents.
I'm guessing only from my personal experience talking with the tall whites.
They've told you that they kind of used you for inspiration to infiltrate—or not infiltrate, maybe that's too aggressive a word, but to enter American scientific programs.
I'm just totally guessing.
But the night she was—
He told them how to not be afraid around humans and to act easily when in the presence of humans.
That was his whole MO, that he was supposed to be there, because they were as terrified of us as we might have been terrified by them.
And it was—that was what the program was.
On that night, there were more tall white scout craft located up the valley and on the eastern side of Indian Springs Valley.
On what night?
The night that Pamela was supposed to pass her final exam, the crowd that formed of tall whites and a few human generals and bigwigs on the eastern side of the valley, there were more than I could count.
I stopped counting at 35, but I guessed there were at least 70 there.
There were so many scout craft and tall whites that that whole side of the valley was white, fluorescent white people, scout craft.
It looked like a county fair over there.
And all they were going to do is watch her, Pamela, while the teacher and Pamela, over where the ammunition bunker was at three and a half miles,
was to watch her, the teacher and Pamela, walk down the paved pathway or one-lane road from the ammunition bunker on the east side
down to about halfway, down to about halfway, where there was a ridge, and then the teacher would wait there.
And then Pamela, with all of her technology turned off, okay, on totally trusting that I'm a nice guy to be around, okay,
otherwise totally helpless against me if I'm not, was supposed to continue walking down the pathway until she got to the range boards.
And then while I was working, while I had released the balloon and I was tracking the balloon,
to just walk over to me disguised as a human.
She didn't have to be disguised as a human lady, just wearing her natural suit, totally turned off,
to just walk over to me, the way you and I are.
And then while I was working, walk around behind me and turn her back to me,
proving that she trusted me, just like the scene from The Man Called Horse,
where the Indian Chief does that to Horse, turn her on and talk to me with her back turned towards me,
totally turned off for everything, and then walk around to the others with everybody watching,
and then walk around and say,
hey, it's been so nice to meet you, Charlie, and then go on, and then she could then leave.
And her husband, the guy pretending to be me as her husband, would then have to do it next, okay?
On that night, she failed the test.
On that night, she panicked and got about, well, she didn't even get down to the quarter-mile limit,
when she panicked and was afraid that I was truly an ugly monster, that she couldn't trust and ran off.
But there came a night when she had to do that, and that's described in my book.
What do you think the Tall Whites want with humanity?
Do you think they have goals for us, or do you think they're just trying to engage in diplomatic relations?
Well, they came here in the middle of the last ice age because we, for the same reason that we have a base on Guam,
the sun and the solar system exists in the middle of a huge void in space.
The next closest star, Alpha Centauri, or Proxima Centauri, is almost four light-years away.
Most stars, or many stars, have another star within two light weeks, okay?
It's not all unusual for many stars to be not more than a light-year apart.
But if you're going to cross that big void in space as you're conducting interstellar commerce for your own good,
then it's nice to have a place in the middle,
because that void is therefore something like eight or ten light-years across,
or six or eight, a big long light-years.
And it's nice to have a place in the middle where you can stop and get food and water,
go outside your spacecraft and repair it, where you can stop and rest,
but also get minerals or other things that you might need.
So it's a pit stop.
It's a pit stop.
Interesting.
And, of course, the reason that there are many of their spacecraft doing that
is because there's only—it's for the same reason that there are many Air Force planes that stop at Guam,
because location, location, location.
What do you make of—
If you're there, it's a big help if you have some locals who grow some food for you,
they're plant-eaters, the Toloites, as the Greys are,
and do the work of harvesting and hand you the food.
What do you make of rumors, stories, that Ike Eisenhower, you know, meeting possibly, you know,
Palm Springs, 1954, this treaty, you know, you say five crafts showed up.
There's another story, you know, Hallman Air Force Base, where there's a landing
and there's a possible interaction between, you know, some generals on the base
and these tall beings, but they seem to actually have, like, almost pharaonic Egyptian headdress.
And this video, I think, was promised at one point to Rod Serling and Bob Emenager,
who made UFOs Past, Present, and Future.
And the video never came.
But I've spoken to, you know, some pretty interesting people in the UFO whistleblower world
who do stand by that account, that that was like a real meeting.
Do you think that that happened?
And was it a tall white that came out of the craft at Hallman Air Force Base?
I'll maintain my policy of never commenting on other people's stories.
And the reason is because my books are based totally on my own experience.
Yep.
And it's not based on anything I've read or any—they're not based on any classified material.
I was never part of any project.
They're based on what—when you say, what was life for me?
Yeah.
And what I'm trying to do in my books, one of the major things I'm trying to do in my books,
is I'm trying to tell my grandkids how it was for me.
And I'm trying to point out to them that when you're personally dealing with the extraterrestrials,
you feel differently than when you're personally dealing with your guardian angels.
Your guardian angels are like brothers who love you.
There's never any fear with the sensation that your guardian angels are there with you.
And because each of us, I believe, has two guardian angels, at least,
who are always with us and have nothing else to do but keep track of each one of us.
And I get so frustrated when I see so many humans who mean well trying to confuse guardian angels
and what God and love and the guardian angels are doing
with what the biological entities who are extraterrestrials are doing.
And so I—and that's what I'm trying to do in my book.
I'm not trying to—I don't care what the government wants to classify.
That's fine with me if they want to classify the recipe for Hershey candy bars
and say, you know, you can have one, Charlie, but don't tell anybody.
Do you miss the tall whites?
Do you feel an emotional affection towards them?
You said that you and Range 4 Harry were like brothers.
Do you ever think, hey, maybe I could contact Range 4 Harry or go back and speak to him,
go back to the range, to Nellis?
Well, if I—let's say if I were out in the desert,
let's say out by Dale here in New Mexico,
which is one of the tall white playgrounds,
let's say if I ever were out there,
and—and let's say I happen to see them.
If I were to just say,
well, I just wanted to, you know,
monkey around and see you or, you know, whatever,
well, that—they might say,
well, now you've seen us and so go on about their business.
See, they're very goal-oriented,
even though they like us.
And it's not that they're being rude.
It's because, remember,
the teacher in 1965,
who had been born when George Washington was born,
when she was playing with—
when she was over at Range 2 that Sunday
with her daughter,
who she called the butterfly,
and the little white girl
knew that she wanted to be friends
with her little—with her daughter
because she—the little girls could be friends.
She was standing there on the side
in a very now—
they were playing on the skip-bomb area,
and the two boys were playing also.
She was standing a little ways away from them
on the higher ground,
slightly higher ground.
She was very nostalgic
remembering her childhood
where she played on the same piece of ground
with a little Native American girl
who was equivalent to her age,
five years old at the time.
But her memories of that
little Indian Native American girl
that was her very best friend at the time,
in the time—because they lived
ten times longer than we do.
In the time that passed,
while she went from
equivalently being, say,
in the fourth grade
to the seventh grade,
for us, those are just a few years,
in that equivalent time,
the Native American little girl
grew to adulthood,
got married,
had children,
went through her entire life cycle
and died of old age,
just in the time the teacher
had gone through
the equivalent lifestyle
of from the fourth grade
to the seventh grade.
Do you think they feel
a fondness for humans?
They do.
But on the other hand,
from their point of view,
gee, I'm 80 years old right now.
You know, I'll be dead
and what for them is
the blink of an eye.
I don't know,
even if I live to be 100,
you know, it's just two more,
I only have two more years to live.
So from their point of view,
if I say we're out there
at my age,
they would,
they might,
I mean, they're friends,
but you have to remember
that socializing and being friends
for them with humans
is a little bit like us
being friends
and socializing
with, say,
a dog in its old age
that we may not have seen
for five or ten years.
There's a guy at NASA
who has a deep interest
in these sorts of things,
experiencers.
His name is Timothy Taylor.
Have you heard of him
by any chance?
Did you say Timothy Taylor?
Yeah.
Oh, he's a good friend of ours.
Oh, so you know,
you know Timothy Taylor.
Mm-hmm.
Tim Taylor.
This is one of those characters
where, well,
if you know,
you know.
But if you don't,
there's probably a reason
why the mood shifted here, folks.
Tim Taylor was a NASA engineer
who became a biotech entrepreneur
and according to Diana Pasolka's book
American Cosmic,
where he appeared under the pseudonym
Tyler D,
has remained actively involved
in launch operations for NASA
up until today.
Pasolka paints Taylor
as an enigmatic figure
who led her
and Stanford microbiologist
Gary Nolan
to a UFO crash site
in New Mexico.
By many,
he's considered a gatekeeper,
well-connected,
with access to crash-retrieval secrets,
as well as personally receiving
what he termed
downloads of information
from otherworldly sources.
He claimed these downloads
were facilitated
by protocols he engaged in,
protocols that allowed him
to communicate
with non-human intelligences.
In Pasolka's book,
Taylor undergoes
a profound conversion
in the Vatican archives,
blending technology
and the phenomenon
and what became
a personal revelation.
And then he decided to convert.
But also what happens
is he changes his idea
of what these things are
that he's feeling
he's getting signals from.
Because we were studying saints
who had these experiences
and he was thinking
that they're more in line
with what they were,
you know,
experiencing.
And outside of her account,
super experiencer
Chris Bledsoe's memoir
openly names Taylor
as a NASA insider
who befriended him
after his encounters.
Sometimes Taylor
would bring other scientists
or officials
to witness Bledsoe's experiences.
I myself was briefly
in contact with Taylor
and I'm not sure
what to make of him.
And even though I was shocked
that his name came up
in this conversation,
I wasn't necessarily surprised.
The deeper cut on Tim Taylor
is that he himself
is some sort of time traveler,
part of a secret program
adjusting timelines.
This doesn't come from me.
Perhaps my favorite figure,
aerospace engineer
and anti-gravity inventor
Thomas Townsend Brown
is connected with Tim Taylor.
This is where the story
gets weird.
Thomas Townsend Brown
was obsessed with anti-gravity,
but gravity and time
have a tight relationship
in general relativity.
This is just standard physics.
So the subplot
of his great biography
by Paul Shatzkin,
The Man Who Mastered Gravity,
is that Townsend Brown
was obsessed with time travel.
He would talk about it
constantly with his friends
and family.
Apparently,
Tim Taylor told Ryan Bledsoe,
Chris Bledsoe's son,
that he was part
of a secret group
in Nassau
in the Bahamas
that dealt with time travel.
I would dismiss this
out of hand entirely,
but there are some
even more interesting connections
between Townsend Brown
and Tim Taylor.
There's an Amazon review
that Townsend Brown's
daughter wrote
on Tim Taylor's biography,
Launch Fever.
In that biography,
Tim Taylor talks about
his time traveling
back and forth
to the Bahamas.
He spent a lot of time
in Nassau.
Townsend Brown also spent
a ton of time in Nassau.
In fact,
his biographer,
Paul Shatzkin,
even coined a term
for a secret group
that used to meet there.
It was called
the Nassau Group
and it included
the elite of the elite,
industrialists
like Eldridge Reeves Johnson,
and even the inspiration
for James Bond
and Churchill's super spy,
William Stevenson,
who helped form the CIA.
So maybe Tim and Townsend
are part of a secret
time travel group.
Who knows?
But it is interesting
that Taylor seems
to consistently pop up
around very important
experiencers
in the United States.
Now back to our conversation.
How did you guys
originally meet Tim Taylor?
He's sort of this
very interesting figure,
you know,
works with NASA
and he's very interested.
He came here
because he found out
about Charles.
And that was when
his daughter,
the one who had
the baby,
was like,
what was she,
maybe in fifth grade
when they came
the first time?
Yeah, we...
Why do you think
he became interested
in your story?
My wife can answer
all the questions.
Because he realized
that as far as
he was concerned
that Charles was,
the real article
was legitimate.
And,
as I say,
it's really concerned me
because I've tried
to email other people
because he brought
other people
to meet us
and visit with us.
One of the guys
cooked right here
in my kitchen
and so I tried
to contact those people
because I had
emails for them
and I never got
a response
about what happened
to him.
Who did he bring?
Let me see.
King.
David King,
wasn't that his name?
And what was the doctor
that was...
I think I still
have the emails.
But he brought
lots of people here
and, oh,
brought them
to Las Vegas.
Kit Green?
Dr. Kit Green,
maybe?
No?
We were at Green's house,
I believe.
At Kit Green?
He flew us
to Atlanta
and had us
meet the,
oh,
what was their
last name?
Now I can't remember.
I know who you mean,
honey,
but I don't remember
their last name either.
We met all his friends.
They had a whole
house full of people
and entertained us.
Interesting.
What did you get
the sense,
did they just want
to learn
or did they,
what do you think
their goal was?
fans.
But because
he introduced
them to us.
What did you get
the sense of,
like,
his job at NASA?
Do you know
what he does?
He said that he
was no longer
involved,
that he went
into business
for himself
and he would,
oh,
that's the
interesting story.
He'd been
all over
to the various
Air Force bases,
et cetera,
but he'd never
been to Creech
before and so
when he came
back from Creech
the first time,
he said he thought
that Charles
underplayed
the strangeness
that was going
on there.
He said they
were there
for a ribbon
cutting ceremony
and he was
standing right
next to a
friend of his.
Oh,
there were no
lower ranking
people,
just all officers
and he said
to the guy,
do you mind
if I just
drive up the
road,
you know,
a mile or two?
I won't get
out of the car
and the guy
said,
oh,
that would be
a very bad
idea and then
just that quickly
he said,
I'm so glad
you could make
it for this,
you know,
like,
I didn't say
what I just
said and,
yeah,
so he was
really even
more impressed
with Charles'
account after
he finally got
the chance to
visit Creech
for the first
time.
Did he ever
say where his
interest in E.T.'s
came from?
I don't remember
that he said
that,
no.
There were
many things.
We never talked
about his work
or things of
that nature
and we also
never talked
about projects
that he was
associated with
or anything
like that.
Did he ever
ask you about
your Hall
photon theory?
I'm sure
we talked
about it.
He was
interested
actually in
buying a
house and
moving out
here.
He seems
to pop
in when
experiencers
have anomalous
experiences.
We never
had any
trouble getting
in touch
with him
and as I
say,
the last
contact we
had was
just when
he said
he was
looking forward
to being
a grandfather
and that
was it.
He just
disappeared.
We never
heard from
him since.
I've heard
that from
numerous
people.
He did
that.
I had
very
intermittent
correspondence
with him
but he
dropped
off on
me,
Chris
Blood
so,
a bunch
of other
people.
It's just
that ours
went on
for so
many years.
You said
15 years?
I think
so,
yeah.
Wow.
It's so
strange that
he would
just not
contact you
after 15
years,
though.
Yeah,
I mean,
we shared
a lot of
really personal
things and
you know,
of course,
he converted
to Catholicism.
Yeah.
Recently in
what,
in 20,
like 15,
16-ish?
Something like
that.
During his
trip to the
Vatican?
Yeah,
and he'd
been to
Rome
several times
after that.
So,
yeah.
Do you
think when
he went
to the
Vatican
archives,
he experienced
anything around
the ET topic?
Any confirmation
of that?
I have no
idea,
but when
Charles and
I went
to Rome
for the
first time
in
2000,
what was
that,
five,
six,
something
around
there,
I took
the first
three books
as a
presentation
for Pope
Benedict,
and a
couple,
you know,
like two
months later
when we
were home,
we actually
got a
thank you
note from
Pope
Benedict.
Really?
Oh my God.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
We put,
I think we
Xeroxed it
and put it
in book
four,
maybe.
Wow.
Could we
see the,
I'd love
to see
the
thank you
note.
That'd be
amazing.
Oh,
it's in
book
four.
Okay.
That's
awesome.
Do you
believe that
Timothy Taylor
has ever
met an
extraterrestrial?
He certainly
didn't say
anything about
meeting one.
Has he shared
any personal
sightings that
he's ever
had?
No,
but maybe
the fact that
he disappeared,
maybe,
maybe he
went off with
them somewhere.
I don't
know.
One night
I was out
in range
three,
and a
group of
new arrivals,
it was after
the full moon,
a week or
so,
and as
usual,
a group of
the guards,
the permanently
assigned tall
white guards
at the base,
at the base
up at the
north end of
Indian Springs
Valley,
brought down,
they were
using the
tourist model
scout craft,
which had
seating for
like two
dozen,
and they
brought it
down,
brought them
down to
the range
tree area,
so they could
see me,
the first human
that any of
those tall
whites had
ever seen.
And while I
was there,
they came
in too
close.
I expected
them,
being new
people,
to stop
at least
at a quarter
mile,
which was
more common,
but they
kept coming
in because
they were
assured that
I was a
nice guy
until they
were as
close as
you guys
are.
Well,
this was
new,
the guard
was in
position.
This was
when I was
still new
and still
not completely
at ease
being around
them,
and since
the new
people are
armed too,
that meant
that I was
somewhat
intimidated.
There was
an older
or a middle
aged lady
and I was
at my
theodolite
stand,
I was
tracking a
balloon.
So I
just turned
to them
and I
looked at
them and
I just
said,
I'm feeling
a little
scared,
so I'm
just going
to put
my stuff
here and
I'm going
to go
into base
and you
guys can
stay and
look around
and do
whatever
you want
and have
fun.
And then
I backed
away and
I went
walking,
not running,
key point,
walking to
my truck
that was
parked some
distance away
on the
other side
of the
generator
shack.
And as
I was
walking,
this middle
aged lady
said to
the guard,
she was
kind of
surprised,
she said,
we didn't
do anything
wrong,
did we?
I mean,
you know,
we didn't,
and,
you know,
what's he
like?
And the
guard proceeded
to tell the
group what
they thought
I was like.
The guard
said,
and I
quote,
well,
he seems
to talk
more than
most humans
and he
seems to
eat a lot
more than
most humans
and us,
but,
you know,
you don't
worry if you,
and he scares
a lot more
easily than
most humans,
but see,
he's different.
He just goes
in and talks
and eats and
then he comes
right back out.
The others,
once we
find him,
would never
come back
and might not
eat again
for a couple
of days.
And they
were all
laughing.
So just
wait here,
he'll be
back out
after lunch,
just give him
time to eat
and talk to
some of the
other guys,
he'll be
right back.
Wow.
You know,
that's what
they thought
of me.
That encapsulates
how...
I wasn't
braver than
the other
guys,
I scared
easier,
but just
let me
eat and
talk for a
while,
I'll get
over it.
Well,
that encapsulates,
I think,
you and how
special you
are,
because it
shows in
the documentary
that Emil
made as
well,
where,
like,
initially you
are scared
and you
don't know
what to
do.
And I
think most
people would
have a
reflexive
allergic reaction
and kind
of run
away.
And your
reaction is
just this
kind of...
I know 41
men that
would agree
with you.
Yeah.
If not all
of them are
still alive.
Right.
Oh,
interesting.
So 41
men who
had nervous
breakdowns...
Sent out
before me.
and came
back compromised.
Compromised
meaning mentally
unstable?
Some of them,
but some of them
just wouldn't
go out there
again.
Well,
the guy before
me had
deserted.
But the one
I remember,
the one I always
felt sorry,
it's the one
I describe in
my book,
he was the
one that was
out at range
four one
night,
and when
they first
sent him
out there,
and the
tall whites
came in
the,
and I'll
use my
words,
not his,
the tall
whites came
in the
high-speed
horse formation,
and they
came from
the northwest
mountains,
when you're
in Indian
Springs,
the mountains
to the
north and
northwest,
they came
down,
and they
were coming
across the
dry lake
bed at
range four,
and they
were very
close to
where,
and he
was at the
weather station
at range four,
and he
couldn't believe
they were
real,
because they
were floating,
and when
he,
so he
went out
there,
and surprised
them,
and he
got too
close to
them,
because they
still had
their suits
powered up,
and they
were still
in the tall
white,
in the high,
in the
high-speed
horse formation,
and he got
too close to
them,
and the
suits,
which put
out radioactive
particles,
and you
could see
them,
when they
were turned
up high enough,
they would
sparkle,
you could
see the
alpha
particles,
and the
beta particles,
coming out,
and the
other
particles,
you could
actually see
the decay
chains coming
off the
suits,
and the
suit,
and his
shoulder
almost touched
one of the
shoes,
and I saw
his x-rays
and pictures
when I was
at the
Nellis Base
Hospital,
and the
doctor himself
said it
looked like
the wounds
from the
victims of
the Hiroshima
blast,
and it
looked like
his whole
shoulder
meat,
everything
had been
cooked off.
Wow.
Okay?
Yeah,
it had been
cooked off.
You know,
the bone was
exploited,
and he just
barely made it
back to base
alive.
Did you ever
experience any
radiation damage
due to
interactions
with them?
No,
not that I'm
aware of.
And part of
the reason
was because
you could
see the
fluorescent,
if they had
their suits
turned up
high enough,
you could see
the radioactive
decay particles,
and of course
I recognized
them immediately
as radioactive
decay particles,
because in
those days,
in the early
19,
that was in
1965,
well, see,
in the early
1950s,
you could
still get
radium paint
and put it
on your
watch or
your toys,
and if
you had
a magnifying
glass and
you went
into a
very dark
room and
waited like
45 or
50 minutes
for your
eyes to
perfectly
adjust to
the darkness
and used
a magnifying
glass,
you could
actually see
the subatomic
particles come
off the
radium paint,
the alpha
particles,
the beta
the gamma
rays,
and see,
so when I
saw those
coming off
the suits
of the
tall whites
out in
the desert,
I knew
perfectly well
what they
were,
I was
surprised by
how big
the part of
the tracks
were and
how far
they carried.
When it
came off
from radium
paint,
the tracks
would be
coming off
just a
short distance
like that.
When you
saw them
out in
the desert,
they would
be coming
off distances
like that
there.
So those
suits had
a tremendous
power.
Charles,
this has
been an
absolute honor.
I appreciate
your time,
man.
Mm-hmm.
And
I
would
tell you
what
a
little
are
going on in
top of
color.
And
yes,
there are
You