The Vatican City of London, you know, Knights of Malta.
Do you think any of these groups have disproportionate power today?
Yeah, like, I would agree with Kozlov.
President Trump is confronting a growing backlash from his own base.
The fight is dividing MAGA supporters.
Donald Trump, he promised them, so he needs to do it.
Just this month, we learned a very hard truth
that our government is not our government.
It's controlled by deeper power structures
involving systems of blackmail and compromise.
Are you still talking about Jeffrey Epstein?
This guy's been talked about for years.
I'm, of course, talking about the notorious case of Jeffrey Epstein,
his handler Ghislaine Maxwell, and their client list,
the rich, powerful elite that he procured sexual favors for
from unwilling underage women.
And on the wall, there was a big artwork of a woman being s**t by a walrus.
Oh, wow.
I'm also talking about Kash Patel, Dan Bongino, Pam Bondi, Trump,
and his whole team campaigning on exposing Epstein's network,
and then turning around and gaslighting the American public,
acting like Epstein was a lone actor who took his own life in jail.
And are people still talking about this guy, this creep?
That is unbelievable.
Just like you have the lone shooter theory with JFK,
claiming that Lee Harvey Oswald acted alone.
He obviously didn't.
You have the lone sex trafficker theory with Jeffrey Epstein.
Nobody believes the state line here.
And this time, due to social media and podcasts,
nobody believes anybody else believes this.
And it's not going away.
I know for a fact documents are being suppressed.
And they're being suppressed to protect individuals.
Wired Magazine, a fairly conventional tech publication,
just revealed that the metadata from Jeffrey Epstein's prison cell video,
that was supposed to point to a suicide, had been edited, likely using Adobe Premiere.
And when it was originally released, a whole minute was missing.
Ghislaine Maxwell is in jail right now for sex trafficking.
But there are no perpetrators of the actual crime.
Who were her clients she sex trafficked young women to?
You have all these women, these victims coming out, but you have no clients.
That's a basic logical fallacy.
Justice now is holding accountable the perpetrators that helped him and participated with him.
That is unbelievable.
Finally, Team Trump is doing something really interesting.
They are just engaging in the typical political food fight.
They could say that the FBI under Biden just destroyed the evidence around Epstein
because Trump telegraphed that they wanted transparency.
But no, they're acting like Epstein was some lone sexual deviant,
who isn't part of some larger shadow network that actively has leverage over American leaders.
They're gaslighting and telling you to look away.
And quite honestly, they're acting like they themselves are compromised.
Is there a lesson for you, for anyone else looking at this?
Well, he's dead. So, you know, in general, you always have to be careful.
Anyways, like I said, everybody knows all this stuff.
I don't have to tell it to you.
What interests me and what we're going to cover on the show are the deeper threads around Jeffrey Epstein.
What was he actually doing?
He certainly was not a financier in any standard sense.
Really?
That was a cover story.
Yes.
The thing with Epstein was he was obsessed with eugenics and creating his own race.
To figure out what the hell is going on here, I brought my buddy Jay Anderson on from Project Unity.
He runs a great channel that's gone deep into UFOs, secret science, and ancient archaeology.
Okay, because if they were taking eggs, they've got underground laboratories, right?
I'm taken there in September.
I think they've taken my eggs.
They clone a baby in 2002.
No one ever hears about anything again.
Perhaps one of the lesser known threads about Epstein was his obsession with secret science.
More specifically, his obsession with gravity and propulsion.
He would fly physicists out to his island.
Kip Thorne, Stephen Hawking, Murray Gellman.
He funded Lawrence Krauss on the order of $250,000.
I desperately want to know why Jeffrey Epstein knew so much about my work.
And I want to know why he was connected to my graduate program.
How did you know he was connected?
You can Google it.
But he was also obsessed with the Casimir effect.
A scientific anomaly that might point to some form of zero point or vacuum energy.
And if harnessed correctly, might unlock an entirely new mode of interstellar propulsion.
On his little St. James Island, he built a temple with occult symbology.
And one of his victims claimed to see a UFO while on Zorro Ranch.
I saw a UFO when I was there, you know, outside at New Mexico.
I went to have a cigarette and I saw weird, like, lights flying.
And then I had the weird thing waking up in the lab.
It was like he was a front, a global honey trap for secret science.
Arbitraging the lameness of modern academia and the sexual repression of its scientists.
Perhaps the weirdest through line with Epstein when it relates to UFOs
is the fact that former OSS officer Donald Barr was headmaster of the Dalton Preparatory School
around the time that Epstein got his job as a teacher there.
Remember, the OSS was the predecessor to the CIA.
Donald Barr wrote a sci-fi book called Space Relations about a future where humans have formed
an intergalactic empire ruled by aristocrats.
Half the book is about this intergalactic elite class systematically trading underage sex slaves
and often using them to gain leverage over other elites.
Ring a bell?
Donald Barr's son is a guy named William Barr, the attorney general under Trump who personally
visited Epstein's jail cell after he died to interview his last known cell mate, Efrain
Stone Reyes, who apparently expressed skepticism around Epstein's suicide.
Reyes died conveniently from COVID shortly thereafter.
This is the kind of stuff that gets you Epsteined.
Here you go!
We discuss it all.
Occult Control Systems, Secret Societies, Mind Control, Epstein, Secret Science.
And we even bring our special friend along, Kurt Metzger.
The only guy who literally didn't work with the CIA is Steven Seagal.
Hey, why do Disney kids turn out how they do?
Well, Disney, the Rosicrucian that allowed the CIA to do stuff to them underneath
Disneyland, and that's real.
Insanity ensued.
Maybe there is a subterranean species that has lived on this planet for a long time.
Jay's expressed some frustration with UFO disclosure.
He's also the only channel to interview a former director of the NSA and deputy director of the CIA
on UFOs.
But he's also more recently gotten into ancient archaeological secrets like acoustically resonant
caves at Malta and skulls that look like gray aliens that they've found there.
He's also as deep as anybody on the mysterious structure underneath the pyramids.
Was there a golden age of aerospace before our history started?
Without further ado, please enjoy this week's American Alchemists,
Jay Anderson and Kurt Metzger.
It's cool, man.
The ADHD in this room is real.
Like, I've got it as well.
Today's episode is sponsored by Incogni.
At some point, you should try this.
Google your full name, plus the city you live in.
You'll probably be shocked at how many random websites are exposing your personal information.
Everything from past addresses that you've lived at, to family members,
to risk profiles you never agreed to.
This data doesn't end up online by accident.
It's collected and sold by data brokers.
Companies you've never heard of that compile your digital footprint and sell it to advertisers,
insurers, political groups, and in the worst cases, scammers.
Incogni is an amazing service that forces those data brokers to delete your personal info.
They contact over 250 of these data brokers on your behalf,
file the removal requests, and follow up to make sure it sticks.
I personally signed up a while ago, and I still get regular updates showing which sites my data
has been removed from.
It works quietly and in the background.
And honestly, that's the way I want it.
No hassle or effort.
And now they've just launched a new feature called custom removals, which is part of their
unlimited plan.
Here's the difference it makes.
If you find your data exposed on any website, even if it's not part of their automated cleanup system,
you can now manually submit that link directly to Incogni.
Their privacy team will personally handle the removal request.
You can do this an unlimited number of times.
It's a huge upgrade, especially when your data shows up on these weird, hard-to-navigate sites like these.
So take your personal data back now with Incogni.
Use code AmericanAlchemy at the link below and get 60% off your annual plan.
Again, that's 60% off.
Just visit incogni.com slash AmericanAlchemy.
It's not paranoid to care about basic online privacy.
It's protecting yourself from bad actors that can mess with you if they have your personal information.
And if you're a fan of the show and into all these crazy topics, that's probably top of mind for you.
We're linking this incredible deal from Incogni in the description.
And now back to the episode.
I'm here with Jay Anderson, Project Unity.
Um, I can't, I've been so excited to do this for years, man.
Oh, dude, I'm pumped, like, it's just, it's good to see you.
It's good to see you in person, man.
In the flesh.
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, yeah.
You've done some OG epic UFO-based interviews I want to cover more recently.
You've done some amazing kind of, uh, alternative, uh, it's dumb that we have to call it alternative.
It's just archaeological, ancient civilization, you know, stuff.
But for now, it's alternative.
It will be the mainstream.
It's getting there.
Piece by piece.
Scan by scan.
That's right.
Um, so I really want to talk to you about what the fuck is under the Egyptian pyramid.
I mean, you tell me, right?
Like, none of us actually know, but it's looking interesting.
It looks fascinating.
I feel like you're as close as anyone to the research team doing it.
You were just with them at the cosmic summit.
So, uh, thanks for being here, man.
I'm most welcome, bro.
It's a real pleasure to be out in Texas for the first time.
Like I said to you, after this, I want to try and find a place to shoot a few guns.
Yeah.
There is another person here that will be revealed in time.
They will be revealed in time.
A special reveal.
And I have a feeling this person knows where to shoot guns in Austin, Texas.
Yeah, maybe you can show me a place or two, brother.
But before we get started, I'm going to pull a Sean Ryan here.
Oh, okay.
And give you a special gift.
This is our American Alchemy.
Oh, look at this.
Let's hold it up.
Hold it up to the camera.
Shirt.
Hey.
There you go.
That is sweet.
Pretty cool, right?
Let's have a look at that.
I love it, bro.
This will be me on my next podcast.
I'll be wearing it.
Yeah, dude.
Aw.
Representing and respecting.
Let's go.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate you, of course.
So, yeah, man.
I want to start with the UFO stuff because I feel like you did some really important early work
on this topic and people need to watch some of these interviews.
You interviewed Oki Shannon, who is a lead project manager at Los Alamos.
Yeah, yeah.
But also was doing research with Hal Puthoff and the sort of vigilante capacity.
Part of the working group kind of thing going on.
Exactly.
Yeah.
When you're with a guy like that, because that was a great interview.
Um, when you're with him offline, do you get the sense that he knows more than he can say?
And that, like, because are you, are you, is there a sense that, like, there is a reverse
engineering program and he just can't talk about it and there's some sort of undetectable
dark matter there?
Or is there a sense that, oh, you've kind of fallen prey to, like, the public narrative
around UFOs and actually it's kind of this other stuff that we don't quite understand.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
You get the distinction there?
Oh, absolutely.
Because, like, for me, especially kind of coming through this subject over the last few years,
I will admit that a lot of it starts to feel like campfire stories, just sometimes campfire
stories with a TSSCI clearance attached to it.
So it's like, you know, like, yeah, that sounds amazing.
But again, where's the evidence?
Where's the actual, like, hard data for it?
It's just a very interesting story from, no doubt, an interesting individual with an interesting
background.
But, you know, someone like Oak Shannon, I mean, he said to me a few things.
He said that their working group in Los Alamos National Labs, it was kind of like an informal
group because he was part of the, what was it, the theoretical physics group in the Pentagon,
the ATP, I forgot the actual name of it.
Yeah, we should give context for the audience, the Advanced Theoretical Physics Working Group.
That's the one, yeah.
And it's with Oki Shannon and Hal Puthoff.
John Alexander and Hal Puthoff, yeah.
John Alexander, Stubblebine.
Yeah.
All these guys who are kind of deep, deep, you know, esoteric alternative physics.
Right.
And, but also kind of, you know, they have real credentials.
Oh, yeah.
I mean, I mean, Army Inscom, Stubblebine, John Alexander, I don't know, I guess maybe Army
Inscom as well, but maybe some DOE ties too, you know, a lot of like very intense kind of
insidery types studying alternative propulsion.
Yeah.
And I think that, you know, so you've got like this element where he was clearly involved in
like maybe a formal, but certainly an informal part of his work was to look at the UFO subject.
And he kind of looked at it as he said that they concluded that they're interdimensional
objects coming down into a lower dimensional plane.
He attributed it to the book Flatland, where he said, you know, the idea of this spherical
object coming down into a two dimensional plane, you're only going to see a cross section,
a shadow of what it truly is.
And he's of the opinion that that describes a lot of the UFO phenomenon.
But again, like, you know, it's like very interesting ideas, interesting stories, interesting
claims, but I've yet to see any hardcore evidence either way for any of these things.
And I think that's the issue that I've come to in the UFO subject specifically.
And maybe that's what's promoted me to slightly transition out of it.
Although I do think that ancient history has a lot of connections and correlations to the
UFO field.
Um, again, collecting these stories over time is really interesting, but I just want further
validation of what's actually going on with this stuff.
You know what I mean?
Totally, man.
It's a, it's, uh, it gives you brain damage.
It's, it's, it's, it's, it's a huge headache.
And there is it, truthfully, it's a far cry, a saucer and a hanger in some ephemeral interdimensional
object are two very different things.
Absolutely.
And I don't know if these things are being, you know, conflated or if there are the, the,
the thing is I was somewhat skeptical of the crash narrative actually.
And then I just visited a crash site and what there, I don't know if you know, Scott and
Suzanne Ramsey are, but they're the deepest on the Aztec crash in 1948.
Oh, the Aztec crash.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I thought that would be an interesting one to investigate, you know, as opposed to
Roswell, which is obviously extremely popular and in the lore.
Right, right.
And I came in expecting to be like, this is the bullshit element of the UFO story.
Yeah.
And honestly, dude, I came out being like, I think there's stuff to the crash.
What was it that piqued your interest the most?
There were, we went to the crash site and the, I mean, this is all filmed.
The trees were like splayed out where a craft seemed to have been drug through the thing.
Yeah, yeah.
With the, and this, this, this couple, Scott and Suzanne Ramsey have spent $600,000, like,
and there's the most salt of the earth, like good people you'll ever meet.
Like there's no, like.
I think I did catch a Richard Dolan interview of them back in the day.
They're very close with Dolan.
Yeah.
And so spending that much time with them, then realizing that the, the story, like how
this story came out was this guy, Silas Newton, they, they claimed that he was part of some
like doodlebug hoax or whatever.
But Silas Newton was worth $20 million at the time, which just for inflation, like it's like
that guy doesn't need to hustle people on a doodlebug oil thing.
Like he was very successful.
No, absolutely not.
Yeah.
And then you have these FBI files on Silas Newton and Gebauer.
Right.
Going way back to the, uh, I think the thirties or something.
And they're, they're totally redacted.
So I don't know, you know, I didn't come out being like, I'm a hundred percent sure,
but it was, it was, it was eyeopening for me.
Yeah.
Like maybe there are these actual.
I mean, I struggle, I struggle with like the crashing of hyper advanced alien vehicles,
maybe the disengaging for some sort of exotic scalar wave weapon system that we have or
something like that.
But I tend to lean towards that.
These are prototypes of our own work that are crashing and, you know, like happening all
over the world, especially since it started kicking off, like you said, Roswell, 1940s,
fifties, cold war, exotic energy, T towns and Brown, like all of these things happening,
you know, cause you've covered so much of that fantastic work on T towns and Brown,
by the way, I absolutely love that deep dive.
I figure it's a hedge, right?
It's like, yeah, if you're deep on the anti-gravity and then you're deep on the,
you know, the UFO stuff, one of them has to be right.
The anti-gravity stuff would explain, right?
Right, right.
I think, I think there's definitely been an incentive to create a smoke screen and a
perception that anything that's operating in the skies, that's going against what we
understand to be like the kind of like standard aerospace and aeronautical abilities is an
alien vehicle.
And I think that's a very convenient smoke screen.
And I do think that, you know, a lot of the stuff, a lot of the talking points
in this kind of 2017 to present day narrative from like, you know, New York times all the
way up to now is trying to create this incentivization that it's actually all alien.
We can't explain all of this.
We don't know what this is.
We don't have this in our arsenal.
We don't have this in our weapons systems.
And I disagree with that entirely.
I think they absolutely do have it.
So I think there's probably like, I mean, I'm convinced that there is some form of non-human
intelligence interface, whether that's dimensional and kind of bleeding in or maybe even terrestrial
to this planet and hidden or actually a space visitor from another planet.
I'm open to all of that.
But I think that there is definitely a case to be argued for a massive smokescreen of classified
exotic energy.
Yeah, I agree with you fully.
One of the other, probably the craziest interview ever done in UFO space, not done by me, Ross
Colthart, you, I don't know if you know what I'm about to say.
I have a feeling.
Yeah, Bobby Ray Inman, who was-
Highest level dude I've ever spoke to in my life.
Highest level dude anybody can ever speak to.
And they're like, that guy ran the government for years.
I have no idea why he agreed to do an interview.
That was remarkable.
So he was head of the NSA.
He was head of NSA.
He was head of-
Deputy director of the CIA.
Yeah, CIA, DIA, I think the-
Federal Reserve branch in Dallas or something.
Yeah, SAIC.
SAIC, who's that SAIC on the board?
He was the head of everything, man.
Of everything.
Like, you know, like the head honcho.
If there is a legacy UFO program, that guy has a fingerprint all over.
Well, yeah, like one of my guys is like a veteran in the US Navy was like, he's definitely
like MJ-12, like, you know.
Yeah, he has to be.
If there is an MJ-12, that guy's on it.
There is an MJ-12, right?
And I love the interview.
The whole thing's hilarious, because like, you're doing this like autobiographical thing
for the first like 45 minutes.
You can tell I'm warming him up, right?
Yeah, exactly.
And then at the end, you go, so, you know-
Tell me about the aliens.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You go, this UFO researcher Bob Oxler called you.
Yeah, well, I mean, like, I mean, in fairness, we absolutely smoothed it out afterwards.
But he did feel a little bit like he was brought in under false pretense.
When I was doing some background research on you, I came across a fascinating little segment
from a documentary.
It was a segment of an interview that you had in 1989 with a man called Bob Exler.
Do you remember speaking to a man called Bob Exler?
Yes, I do.
Yeah, and during this conversation, he asked you whether you believed that the recovered
vehicles would ever be made available for technical research outside of the military circles.
And your response to this was, 10 years ago, I would have said no, but whether time has evolved
and then beginning to become more open on it, it's a possibility.
So, obviously, correct me if I'm wrong, but it just seems like you're suggesting here that
you're aware of retrieved UFOs being studied by the military.
No, the answer was no.
I would not.
There were not.
Absolutely were no retrieved UFOs.
I have high confidence.
Do you anticipate that any of the recovered vehicles would ever be
become available for technological research outside of the military circles?
Again, I honestly don't know.
10 years ago, the answer would have been no.
Whether time has evolved and beginning to become more open on it is a possibility.
No, I mean, like I told him that I wanted to talk about UFOs, but again, the way that came
about was another buddy of mine who was a US Navy veteran had an old number for him.
And so we called that number and it went straight to voicemail.
And so we left a voice message just saying, well, he left a voice message because it's easier
for someone like that, who's obviously got connection to him to speak on my behalf and
just say, look, there's this guy who's really interested in talking to you.
And, uh, basically like a week went by and we had nothing.
And then my buddy was like, Hey, he's messaged back.
And it turns out that this phone number we had for him was an old phone that was like
locked in a drawer.
He just decided to check it on a whim.
He hadn't checked it in years.
No way.
Yeah, I know.
Right.
And he saw this voice message and decided to respond.
That's a, that's a, that's a, that's a crazy synchronicity.
That's why at that point I was like, this man's going to say the truth.
Like, you know, this feels like it's aligned, like this is meant to be like, this is crazy.
So I was like, you know, he wanted, he was the only guest who asked, and it doesn't surprise
me for a pre-approved list of questions and talking points.
Like what are we going to go through?
So I was like, you know, obviously I need to mention the fact that I want to talk about
UFOs, but I started off with obviously like, you know, like the, his career background and
geopolitics and national security of today and what he sees.
And then, you know, at the bottom I was like, and I want to bring up the, you know, 2017 UAP
discussion and everything like that.
Yeah.
So I did say that, but I don't think he was expecting me to know about Bob Exler and
actually have a seat to be ready to kind of come at him with like, you know, challenges.
And I have to say that, you know, with all due respect to the Admiral, you can see the body
language shift quite profoundly when we move on to UFOs.
Oh yeah.
You can see he's relaxed, he's talking, he's enjoying kind of reflecting on his career and
everything, which is an incredible career.
I mean, my God, this guy is just like, you know, up at the absolute apex.
But then once we get into UFOs, even when I'm just asking the question, man, it starts
getting tight.
He starts bringing his body in.
And when I asked him that first question, he was just like, no, no, no, absolutely not.
No UFOs, none at all, like no way.
And then a few times during the interview, which I think must've been him misspeaking,
but it was kind of strange where he kept saying, uh, I am extremely confident that there is no
other life in our galaxy.
I have a high level of confidence that within our galaxy, there is no other living life.
And I was like, you know, solar system would make sense, but he said galaxy like three times.
How can you be confident?
And also at the end of this, he said something along the lines of, I mean, I don't think I've
given you what you were looking for, but I hope you will listen very carefully to what I've said
to you.
So I have listened back and I'm trying to figure out what it was that you might have
been like putting in, but this whole thing where he was like, there's no life in the galaxy.
It's like, we should, we should send our audience off now to decode this interview.
Right, right.
The message, Jay, if you find any sort of meta messages.
Yeah.
Cause I'm fascinated in what he was trying to say.
I feel like he was trying to put something down that I haven't picked up yet.
So yeah, who knows?
Well, that, I mean, that was wild.
Yeah.
So wild.
But the Bob Oxler call is so just crazy and interesting.
Cause you had, you hear Bobby Randman say, yeah, like, yeah, you know, maybe at some point,
this will come out, but not now.
And he's speaking so casually.
Yeah.
And there's a few, there's a few like news clips of Exler going on the news and saying like,
yeah, well, you know, someone said to him, you know, do you think that this could
just be fraudulent and fake?
And he's like, well, Admiral Bobby Ray Inman convinced me that these were flying saucers
from an alien species.
So I'm pretty okay with that.
And it's just like, well, damn, man.
Like he's like reiterating this over and over.
A few people have said that it was maybe, uh, you know, misquoted from that documentary
where you've got the recording, but here's Exler on the news a few different times,
reiterating that Admiral Inman made him, made him like absolutely confident and positive.
So Oxler seemed markedly more reasonable than a lot of UFO researchers.
Like he, he himself was an aerospace engineer.
He was a NASA guy.
He was a NASA specialist at some point in his life.
And again, yeah, very calm, spoken intellectual guy that was just being very matter of fact
with it and just saying, well, no, I mean, from where I'm seeing the Admiral essentially
has convinced me that these are recovered vehicles that we're working on.
And, you know,
And there's no way that you could be mistaken and it could have been an airplane,
helicopter or something of that nature.
Well, Admiral Inman convinced me that, uh,
these vehicles were not manufactured by human technology.
So that's pretty conclusive for me.
That's it.
So again, I think it's, I think it's true.
I wouldn't even go against the idea that there's been some archeological finds from like,
you know, the old world.
I mean, I'm diving into prehistory right now and getting into that,
seeing so many anomalies that are so advanced and so contradictory to our models.
You think about things like the, the Vamanas of ancient India and like, you know,
these stories that you have flying chariots, it's like, okay,
was there a golden age of aerospace before our history started?
Yeah.
Is some of that under the ground?
I think even Grosh talked about recoveries, right?
The Italians recovered something back in the Mussolini days.
1933, exactly.
Yeah, it's like-
The magenta crash.
I think, yeah.
I think there's a case to be said for like archeological finds as well.
I think so too.
Well, somehow it just feels somewhat arbitrary if UFO crashes only occurred 1947 and onwards
because of nuclear.
Yeah, and only in New Mexico.
And only in New Mexico.
That feels like extremely anti-centric or egocentric and nation-centric.
Right, right.
Uh, you know, yeah, there's a whole field of forbidden archeology,
which you're kind of diving into, which this, all this megalithic architecture.
And I'm, I wonder if UFOs, aliens and crashes are a part of that.
I don't know and I don't have any evidence, but it, it would, it wouldn't make sense to
me that there would be this stark dividing line where it just starts in the atomic age.
Right, right.
Well, it kind of gets back to like, you know, where, like, how do you want to look at aliens
from the ancient, ancient perspective?
You look at theologic texts, like the book of Enoch, the watchers or the Anunnaki or the
Nephilim, you know, the ones that came down and slept with the, the women of men and made
these like, you know, hybrid species.
It's like, okay, a lot of different texts speak about this in variations, but there's kind of
a similar theme of giant beings or some other type of being that came and interface with us.
So that's kind of like how you might look at it from the ancient perspective.
And you see some of these megalithic stone building sites all over the world.
It's like, okay, humans aren't capable, at least from our understanding of
history and capabilities at that time, we couldn't do that.
Yeah.
So where does that?
And especially, you know, not to get off on a tangent, but with the ancient megalithic
sites like Stonehenge or other, other parts of the world, it's not just the engineering,
it's the alignment, it's astronomy, it's mathematics.
Some of them are even acoustically tuned to produce strange effects from reverberation.
So it's like, it's a complex set of knowledge that is then globally represented all over the
world.
And that says to me that there was someone who really knew what they were talking about
with a lot of different areas of science and engineering and astronomy that was putting
this together and then inspiring people to do it all over the world.
So whether that's an interface with non-human intelligence or just a completely different variation
of human intelligence that we've long forgotten, I don't know, but there's a profound mystery
there.
There's something else.
There's clearly the primitive to progress narrative that we're being spoon-fed by like
Steven Pinker and you know, it's just obviously BS.
That's like obviously wrong.
Yeah.
And you don't have to necessarily, you know, wholesale agree with Eric Von Daniken.
No, no, no.
To say that like...
Dude, even just taking like one foot off of the conventional path, you start going,
holy shit.
Yeah.
This is not right.
Well, there's just no, yeah, there's just no way some of this stuff could have, could
have been built.
And so I think we have to like not necessarily cross the T or dot the I artificially, but
like there's, there's something going on.
Yeah, absolutely.
Like that narrative is wrong.
And it's kind of like, you know, it's like polar opposites of the argument, like the mainstream
who are very reductive and in their little refined channel.
And then obviously on the polar opposite, you got people who were like, it was absolutely
built by the Nephilim.
Right.
We don't know.
We don't know that, but it's definitely a mystery.
Like it hasn't, hasn't been addressed.
It hasn't been satisfactorily put to the side.
And there's so much of that, like whether it's history or, you know, the anomalies and
UFOs, like that's why I kind of feel like they're cotangent.
They are connected together.
Yeah.
You know, there's a lot of influence and, you know, the wheels of Ezekiel and these incredible
visions that people have had throughout time.
If they had it today, that would be a UFO experience.
Totally.
You know?
Yeah, exactly.
That would just be part of the modern lore.
There's definitely a presence that's been here throughout time.
Yeah, I think so too.
Um, another guy that you interviewed, John Ramirez.
Yeah, he's an interesting cat.
Super interesting guy.
Former CIA.
Yeah, GS-15.
GS-15.
And he's come out now, and I think on your show as well, saying that like, he's sure we
have hybrid programs.
Yeah.
Human-alien hybrid programs.
And that's the word that, uh, Louis Elizondo can't say that everyone's, uh, and everyone
in the Pentagon is expecting him to say someday is that we're all hybrids.
Personally, I believe this is one of the core secrets, but that's my personal opinion.
When you hear him say that, are you like, you know, this is legit.
This is CIA disinfo.
What's your...
Middle ground, man.
Okay.
Like grain of salt.
Like, you know what I mean?
Like, take everything with a grain of salt.
I, all respect to John Ramirez, and I'm not applying this to him, but something that I've
definitely felt over the years of, you know, being thrown into interfacing with people
in the intelligence community is they're really good at becoming your friend.
Right, right, right.
When you've got an influential platform.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Yeah, sure.
Really good at becoming your friend.
And they're very likable and they're easy to become friends with.
But, you know, again, it comes back to that thing of how much of this can be validated?
How much of this has been evidenced?
I'd say, you know, 0.1% of that, right?
Right.
So like John Ramirez, super interesting guy.
I think he's actually genuinely passionate about the subject and he's an experiencer.
You know, you find a lot of these people in the agency, like within the CIA, you know,
it seems to be a hallmark of like these guys who have got quite high up in the ranks of
that particular agency is they've got like some weird ideas and like, you know, that's
that's what they want, right?
They want out of the box thinkers.
So, of course, you're going to get people in these agencies that believe in all of that.
But, but you expect that.
I'm a big fan of this guy, so I'm so happy he's here.
This is how I dress when I watch Jazzy's show at home.
Oh, I love it, man.
I can see that.
You look like a Templar.
Yeah.
Oh, that figures in.
Oh, yeah.
That figures in.
It was funny.
I actually, when I met, I met Eric Mondanigan and I asked, you know, on all these things,
he was like super like, you know, these crazy hand wavy theories.
Right.
And then I asked him about the Templars and he goes, there are secrets that I cannot talk
about.
Mm-hmm.
And I was like, I was like, really, Eric Mondanigan?
Well, you don't, you know, like a little-
What do you work for?
How do you have that antique shop?
How do you function that?
Right?
Was that Eric Mondanigan has an antique shop?
Yeah.
You know, what's interesting about the Templars as well, in respect to Egypt, just a little
bit of quick trivia.
Yeah.
Is that the Great Pyramid of Giza, you know, it's eight sided.
The Pyramid of Giza is eight sided.
It's eight sided.
Very subtle.
And it can be seen from above.
But if you get an aerial of this at a certain point in time, you can actually see that instead
of four sides, it's got these like indentations that create an eight sided pyramid.
Whoa.
The Templar flag is an eight sided pyramid turned into a 2D shape.
So if you take the Templar flag and you create it into a three dimensional object, you get
the Great Pyramid of Giza.
Wow.
Yeah.
You've interviewed a guy who is the modern grandmaster of the Templar?
I traveled through Egypt with him.
That's Timothy Hogan.
Timothy Hogan.
Yeah.
You're plugged in.
He went with Sir Timothy Hogan.
I went, I was, I was brought into the King's Chamber by him personally.
What's his-
So this guy's a real Templar?
He's a real Templar.
Yeah.
He's got his receipts.
Well, I got some, okay.
Well, that's disturbing, but don't you guys think if you were, if they're real Templars
today, they wouldn't like dress up like a like Kurt or be like Timothy Hogan.
Well, I'm not-
They would be like these like subtle-
Well, I mean, like, it's like, it's like there's levels, right?
Like Gypto.
Yeah.
Kurt's at the bottom of the fucking barrel.
What's this?
All right.
When are you doing your Gyptos?
There's Halloween costume level.
Dude.
I'm Zawi Hawass.
Did you watch Zawi?
Of course, I watched the Supercut.
I couldn't do the three hours.
I mean, it looked like they were arguing over a carpet.
It was fucking insane.
Yeah.
Joe, that was probably the worst podcast he's ever done.
He said it.
Yeah.
Like the next guest, he was like, that was the worst fucking podcast.
And Zahi goes, at some point, at the end, he's bombing.
Zahi's doing so badly.
And then halfway in, he goes, I'm doing a speech in Houston.
Will you speak in Houston?
Will you introduce me to him?
He's like, fuck no.
He's like, dude, I'm busy.
I'm busy.
I'm a busy guy.
Yeah.
No, dude.
It was like, you're buying electronics on 42nd Street from Sephora.
You know what's crazy about that is I guarantee you, he still walked out of that studio
going, I did a great job.
Of course he did.
I did a great job.
I've nipped that in the bud.
Well, that's his job.
Yeah.
His job is to go and do that.
I won't lie.
I'm like 50% nervous about going through checks in Cairo when I head out there.
You better be.
You should be.
If I don't come back, bro, I'm gone.
Like someone's taken me.
No, they'll just be like, you can't come in.
Yeah.
Well, don't think if you're on Amnesia platform and you said anything, I mean, I probably destroyed
it for you.
I'm sorry.
Oh, that's okay.
It's all right.
I mean, he sounded like an electronics gentleman.
They've accepted my plane ticket.
I put my passport details in.
I got greenlit, so it should be all right.
But we'll see how it goes.
I was the Wiz when I was younger, you know, in my many astral travels.
Who's the Wiz?
Nobody beats the Wiz, the electronics store.
Oh, you worked for the Wiz?
Yeah, I was a salesman.
Oh.
You know, that's how I developed my-
And Hawaz felt like your manager there.
No, I was in Bricktown, New Jersey, but in New York where those stores-
You know, you don't mess with the Zohan movie, they show it.
Yeah, yeah.
They're like, Sony Guts, Sony Guts.
Okay?
It's a very Middle Eastern bizarre way of dealing with things, and that's how they are.
You come, I show you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, and he's apparently, he's like kind of sketchy.
Like, he sells in the black market, but he literally profits off of that.
I wouldn't be surprised.
And you know what's interesting about Zahi Awaz is like back in the 1990s, I want to say
like 1992, he was giving a speech at a university in Cairo where he was like, there are subterranean
labyrinths underneath the plateau.
There are entrances from the Sphinx to the pyramids that will tell us a lot more about who really
built them.
And then two years later, he changed his tune and has never changed it back.
Okay.
So something happened.
So see right there with Zahi Awaz.
Also, did you know he was funded by the Edgar Cayce Foundation?
I was about to ask if you knew that.
Yeah, bro.
What it was?
So what's the significance?
So you know Edgar Cayce?
I know he was.
He's like a very famous remote.
Yeah.
And he made all these predictions about the halls of Amenti and the lost records of Egypt.
So the Edgar Cayce Foundation funded Zahi Awaz.
So like he started off on this esoteric kind of truth seeker style funding and idea.
And then I want to say about 1993, after that speech that he gave, complete change.
You think somebody like got him?
I would not be surprised.
Wait, hold that thought of Hazawi Awaz.
You can apply that to most of the people.
Yeah, for real, bro.
That are like, why are you 180 degrees from the thing you said before?
Right, right, right.
Yeah.
Oh, well, here's the reason.
You're a compromise.
Yeah.
You don't got a compromise.
Yeah, you don't.
Exactly.
It doesn't have to be blackmail.
It could be, well, how about I make you rich?
Silver or lead is the great Pablo Escobar.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, right, right.
Plato or pomo?
If someone's telling you the real info, okay?
Yeah.
And you're talking about it here, listen, if you ever, remember Gary Webb, the guy that
knew the CIA brought coke into the hood?
Yeah.
The old black guy conspiracy that people, that I was dismissive of, they'd be putting
crack in the hood.
Mm-hmm.
That's exactly what they did.
And you know how I know they did?
Huh?
Because the reporter that reported it shot himself twice in the head.
Hey, yeah.
It happens, right?
Yeah, it happens, right?
You look so ridiculous.
Listen, if you wanted to stigmatize all the shakers.
Kurt Metzger, everybody.
No, I want to make it clear.
Listen, I want to make it clear.
I'm not a journalist.
I'm not in the space.
But you kind of are.
Well, Kurt has a crazy story.
We will get back to-
No, it's cool.
We're doing a survey level.
You know some shit.
I'm happy.
Like I said, I'm fully pumped to have Kurt here.
I love this guy.
Well, you know, Kurt doesn't remember part of his childhood because he was in the gifted
and talented education program.
Dude, it's just smart kid classes.
It's fine.
And now I know a lot of esoteric stuff.
It's not big deal.
Oh, you were in the same-
Well, they teach you remote viewing and all that kind of stuff.
I have no idea.
I don't remember a single part of it.
Damn, bro.
Brother and sister in it.
I asked my mom to like-
And now he's super deep on him.
From what ages?
I don't know.
They don't-
Your parents didn't tell you?
My mom don't remember.
If your parents, they go, hey, your son's got high IQ and you're going to be gifted and
talented.
You think your parents give a fucking shit?
They don't.
They're like, whoa.
Where'd you grow up?
Everybody's conditioned for a pat on the head in this society.
That's the occult prison that you live in.
So you go, oh, I got a good-
I'm an expert.
Right?
That's how-
Kindergarten, you know, the Prussian school that we use for some reason?
Yeah, right, right, right, right.
What the fuck do you think that is?
Yeah, that's weird.
Is that normal to you?
That is weird, actually.
Like, why do we have that?
Because at age five-
We don't call it that in the UK, but it's, yeah.
Oh, it came from-
So we have a lot to thank the UK for here in this country, certainly.
Definitely you do.
But our entire schooling system is designed to compartmentalize you.
Right.
Out of the gate.
I mean, and I'm not telling you any esoteric secrets.
It's written down-
Of course, yeah, yeah, absolutely.
Because it was the Prussian miracle.
So they sent people from all-
How did you get such control over your citizens?
Because this guy found out that 70% of the troops-
I always thought those old-timey guns didn't really shoot straight.
No, 70% of people don't pull the trigger.
They miss on purpose.
This is a problem.
Right, right, right.
How do we fix this?
Oh, you're with mommy and daddy too long.
I got to get you before that third brain wave you get that tells you what reality is.
Six is too late.
Me and Rogan talked about Joe went at age six.
It's too late.
You've already been imprinted with mommy and daddy now.
Wait, he did a-
Wait, Joe did it as well?
Education?
I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about kindergarten.
Oh, okay.
Right, right, right, right.
Okay?
I'm talking about if you go look into how we got our school system, it's real.
It's real weird.
And the goal is this.
So here's 20 years ago, pre-K suddenly became a thing in New York.
Oh, you got to go to pre-K because outcomes are better for kids that go to pre-K.
Wow.
I didn't go to pre-K.
My mom taught me to read at home and I went to kindergarten.
Why is that so important?
Yeah, man.
Because it's not working.
We got to get you away from mommy earlier so that the government can get its dick in
your brain early.
Break up that family dynamic.
Absolutely.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay?
So here's some esoteric, real esoteric.
And I just discerned this like a regular Manly Pee Hall.
You got a right left brain, so you watch these secular materialist scientists.
Yeah.
You're Mike DeGrasse Tyson's and what have you.
Neil deGrasse Tyson?
Neil deGrasse Tyson.
Whatever, nerd.
He just mashed up Mike Tyson.
Well, that'd be a sick combo.
It would be a sick combo.
A fighting physicist.
Yeah, I prefer Mike, personally.
I think he does more.
It's called steganography.
Shout out to DJ.
Okay.
Dark journalist.
Yeah, dude.
Yeah, because the octagon thing I got off of him and Joseph P. Farrell.
Mm-hmm.
I'm trying to get an interview of him.
I love Joseph P. Farrell.
Okay.
Yeah, he's interesting.
That guy blew my mind, dude.
And here's what's so funny about watching, because you're hitting on a bunch of...
I've seen your show.
You guys are on some good points.
Thanks, brother.
How old are you, though?
30.
How old are you?
33.
Okay.
So you're still at the age before you figured out the scam yet.
And by the time I'm 48, finally old enough to serve in Ukraine.
And when you figure out the scam, here's how it works.
Fuck you.
You 48, motherfucker.
The 30-year-olds still believe there's new suckers for the thing.
Believe in what?
Believe in the whole thing.
So now all this UFO shit, what blew my mind was when I looked into it, it turns out a bunch
of this stuff's been disclosed over and over and over, like the wheel of samsara.
Yeah, man.
For sure.
Ad nauseum.
Yeah, but what you don't realize, so then you're like...
But then what's the deeper...
Like, because I like...
Look, I'll watch Dark Journalist, and like, it's like ASMR for conspiracies that never resolve.
He goes, do you know about this?
Well, you're in that same space.
Mystery School.
Yeah, I'll talk about it.
It's interesting.
J.J. Abrams' Mystery Box Storytelling.
Okay.
You remember J.J. Abrams' Mystery Box Method?
He does a TED Talk about it.
Right.
Okay?
Basically, the show Lost and Scientology are the same basis.
Mystery Box, sure.
You stick with it and get invested, and then you get a shitty ending.
Well, that's another thing is the influence of Scientology in the UFO community, because
there's a big presence of, like, that belief system.
Shout out, friend.
Exactly.
How big do you think it is?
Scientology is the sky.
How big do I think it is?
Yeah, how big do you think it is?
Well, I mean, like, you know, they infiltrated the CIA and a few different agencies.
They infiltrated the IRS.
Operation Snow White.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Multi-agency infiltration.
Wait, Kurt, shut up for a second.
What's that?
Nah, it's cool, bro.
It's cool.
It is.
Truly.
What's Operation Snow White?
So that was when they did that huge, like, infiltration of multiple agencies, including
the IRS, CIA, with an incentive to try and promote psychic research and these types of
ideas and prevent them from kind of stopping it.
Tax-free status.
Yeah.
And you don't know about this?
I know about the fights with the government around tax-free status.
The biggest infiltration of the government.
I've heard of Operation Snow White.
It was wild.
But how, like, prevalent was it?
Did it work?
I don't think, well, they got caught.
They got caught.
So I don't think it fully worked, but it worked for a time.
Like, you know, they managed to create influence and obviously they're very powerful.
But I think that there's, like, genuinely a thread of UFOlogy that comes back to obviously
Scientology.
Go a bit further back.
Helena Blavatsky, Theosophy, the Esoteric School.
Yeah, sure, yeah.
And, like, I wouldn't be surprised if some of these people in government, because when you
actually get to know them or you find out more about them, you find out that
beyond the, you know, the tight suit and the nebocracy is an esoteric person that's into,
like, the OTO or Golden Dawn or whatever, right?
That's exactly right.
Yes, brother.
So, like, you know, I think that what they're trying to do, at least in my opinion, and
actually the guy that you wanted to hear more about, my friend who was speaking, he'd
be able to tell you a lot more.
He believes, and I would agree, that there is an element of the government that's quite
radical, that truly believes in some of these old esoteric systems.
And they're trying to essentially manifest the UFO reality into the world by creating a
consensus of it, right?
So, they're creating this narrative, they're creating this push.
Like an egregore cult.
Yeah, like an egregore, because it's just weird how, you know, you tap into these guys
who are, like, you know, bureaucrats and national security, and then you find out that they've
got, like, you know, talking points from OTO and Golden Dawn, and they're drawing pentagrams,
and they're showing you the alchemist triangle, and it's like, you know what I mean?
You see the Matthew Brown who just came out through Covell and Nap, he's this guy,
a magna constellation.
Showing his innocuous mathematics and shit like that, like, you know.
You see the, okay, so here's how I got into my deep esoteric knowledge.
I was, so I was watching the Charles Hall Tall Whites documentary.
I just interviewed him.
He's alive?
Yeah, he's alive.
I have a lot of questions for him.
But he's fascinating.
He's a trip.
A couple of the guys that were with me who had seen them thought that they were ancient
Egyptians who had somehow or another gotten into Indian Springs Valley and trapped there,
and were still using their own hieroglyphics.
Who thought that?
Oh, a couple of the other ranch men, yeah.
So here's what you've never seen.
Like a wind-up dog.
It didn't make sense.
That was weird.
Oh, I think I have some theories.
So Charles Hall, now, usually when you hear UFO stuff, it's like some goofy, like, Star Trek shit.
Right.
And this guy, he made a real specific point that they're not here to save the whales.
In fact, the Tall Whites told him they think it's unusual that we, like, ride horses and live...
Like, they said on most of the civilized worlds to him, the dominant species kills off anything
that could be a threat to them.
Wow.
You ever hear anybody talk that way when they talk about our space brothers?
I haven't.
The way he described it, it sounded like we're Guam or something.
Right.
Okay, now, keep in mind, if you talk to him, he's got a real aw shucks, but you just picked
up on something with it.
That guy's got a nuclear physics degree, so don't be fooled by country dumb.
Uh-huh.
As soon as I'm watching, I'm like...
So I'm laughing when I'm first watching, because they're called Tall Whites.
We're as strong as gorillas compared to them.
That's a detail.
Right.
If you touch one of them, they'll kill you.
Yeah, very weak bodies.
Yeah, and I'm like, wait a minute.
I've heard this before.
Are you telling me there's taller, whiter things that are doing the old British style?
They show up and we're little ugly, like, B-style monsters.
I'll take exception to that.
When he tells a story, it sounds like we're a Raj from the colonies.
Yeah, right, right.
So all I do is look for themes.
Like, Diana Pasolka, I think she made this word up, myth themes, but I like it.
That's the Legos the stories are built out of.
Right.
And they repeat.
So I watch everything, man.
I don't just watch, like, I'm on a news show.
See, and I notice with everybody that follows this stuff, just the idea that you're wondering
if you can, the intel people are gonna, that's because you're compartmentalized.
Right.
Remember Eric Weinstein?
I don't know if he was with you on that video, but on Rogan, he goes, don't tell me it's
compartmentalization.
Why would I not tell you that?
Yeah, right, right, right.
Do you understand the pyramid structure that we seem to be obsessed with?
Well, the ultimate compartmentalization would also be-
Your brain!
These occult sort of, yeah, compartmentalizing a person.
Yeah.
And like, there's a Terrence McKenna quote that I sent you, that's like-
I love that guy.
Amazing, right?
And you've done some awesome videos on that.
I think I've absorbed every lecture he's ever done.
He, like, haunts my brain.
He's incredible.
And he says, you know, a secret is not something that isn't told, it's something that cannot
be told.
Right, right.
Which is like, that's the ultimate, if you want a control system or something, like, that's
the best way to create it.
Well, you think the Templars got from their journey to the-
To meet with the old man of the mountain.
They got some shit, that's for sure.
Let me throw out a goofball hypothesis of mine.
Okay.
That I got after Rogan told me, intel people told him China was injecting their people, their
kids were stuffed up, raised their IQ.
Right.
And immediately, I know we did way worse than that, automatically, because China did it.
Yeah.
Okay?
And so now we got one in 32 autistic kids.
That's wild.
Yeah.
The rate-
Oh, yeah.
I wonder how that happened.
Yeah, it's insane.
Okay.
You know, don't attribute to malice where you contribute to incompetence.
Uh-huh.
No, it's malice, my friend.
And, okay, let's look at what are the features of autism.
Okay?
Hyper focus.
Yeah.
Weird about sex.
In fact, you could program them and tell them what gender they are, and they'll believe
it.
Chris Chan, the inverted Christ, is that, if you've ever heard of Chris Chan.
There go our sponsors.
Are you sponsored by Sonic U comic books?
I think we don't have to be sponsored by Monsanto to get them pulled for this episode.
No, no.
You don't understand.
They made these.
They love all the products.
No matter how bad you cock up Star Wars, they're going to watch it, and tears will form in their
eyes that a new Star Wars came out.
They buy those stupid vinyl bobblehead whatever the fuck people buy.
They're the perfect consumer.
Cut.
The goal laid out when they invented kindergarten.
Who hurt you, bro?
Literally the entire system I'm in.
It sounds like something real.
I went to kindergarten.
It sounds like a beef.
Also, I was in gate.
All right.
Well, he was in.
So, this is interesting.
I don't know nothing about it.
I'm not accusing him of nothing.
Right, right, right.
You have Jake Barber coming out talking about gifted and talented education program.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, yeah, he talks about it also in the context of, you know, Skywatcher and these sort of
psionic assets.
Uh-huh.
You know, it seems like the Stranger Things kind of narrative might be more real than we realize.
It was called Montauk originally, and there is a girl that was 11.
Did you know that?
No.
That's a real person?
Yeah, you know, a lot of this stuff.
So, I sent you the link.
You sent me too many links to go through.
I cannot.
Well, they've already got you because you, look, here's what I, when you said ASMR, this
is why.
Yeah.
So, Nathan Reynolds is who referred me to dark journalist, and what I love about it
is I don't care about your production and all that other bullshit.
I already feel that's a layer of a cult between me and what I want to know.
Right, right.
Sure.
So, and Dan's productions are low.
He's holding up.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
That makes me trust him more.
I hate you.
You want me to trust people less?
Good production.
Right, right, right.
That makes total sense.
But I just, I want him to map it out a little more clearly.
Sometimes I'm like, there's not, I don't know if there's a there there.
Yeah, man.
I will, I'll listen to the whole thing and I'll be like, what happened?
I don't really like, I'm with you guys on all the interesting esoteric drama.
Yeah, you've got to watch everyone.
And look, all you have to do.
Yeah, that's right.
That's a fucking mystery box, bro.
You're just saying it now.
Okay.
Here's why.
You can lie to me if you want.
I don't care if you're an intel guy.
I don't have nothing to hide and I don't give a fuck.
So go ahead and lie, whatever.
I'm going to get data off you either way.
Right.
Because I'm going to figure out why you're lying to me.
Well, to be honest, like.
It's built in the lie.
Well, that's why the move in this space is like talk to everybody because I think you.
No, it isn't.
It's not.
Certain people, and I want to talk to people you can't talk to.
Who would you talk to if you could talk to?
Okay, my friend Emma has a show called Imagination Podcast.
It was on YouTube about MK Monarch, which the link I sent you has been acknowledged.
I didn't know that.
I'm obsessed with it.
Oh, MK.
On the audience, what MK Monarch?
MK Monarch, yeah.
Well, that's one of the successors to Ultra.
Right, right, right.
Oh, your King Charles has that little butterfly.
Yeah, little butterfly.
He's in a portrait in Hamburger Me.
Dude, that portrait is one of the fucking scariest looking things I've ever seen.
It's just like crimson blood.
Like the whole thing is just red.
It looks like Burgermy.
It's freaky, dude.
And then like you said, little monarch butterfly.
And him and Lord Mountbatten and Jimmy Savile used to all hang out together.
Oh, yeah.
And they all had special black berets made.
Now, that's not in the military there.
That's a special unit of just the three amigos.
Dude, Jimmy Savile was so influential in the UK that he was spending his Christmases at
checkers where the prime minister would spend it and he would go in and out.
Who is this guy?
I don't even know who this is.
Jimmy Savile, he was a BBC presenter, very famous.
And he's the most prolific sex offender and child sex offender in the UK history.
You know who's victim?
Whoa.
He was never caught during his time.
It all came out after he died.
Whoa.
He had written, do you know what it had written on his gravestone?
You know that?
Well, I forgot.
On his gravestone, it was fun while it lasted.
Oh.
Yeah.
Now, but did you notice with Jimmy Savile, now, at the time when I saw this story, I
didn't realize that he was like a wizard.
Right.
But then I went, his charity, because he did, they didn't know.
It's like.
Dude, he had a spare key to a child's hospital.
He would like live there.
That's what, a hospital?
Yeah.
He had a spare key.
He would live on the wall.
You never heard of the truth.
It's just a demon.
He was a demon.
An absolute demon.
Good friend of King Charles.
If any of them exist, this motherfucker is a demon.
And he was good friends with him.
No punishment for the BBC people.
He could waltz into Buckingham Palace like he owned the place, man.
And then you fast forward and you've got Epstein and Andrew.
It's like patterns.
And then, isn't there like a photo of Kevin Spacey at Buckingham Palace?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And then Rolf Harris did the Queen's painting.
He's a pedophile.
What do you guys think of this Kash Patel going on Joe's show?
Being like, if I would have a hit.
I've heard your opinion.
He goes, Epstein killed himself.
And then you have Dan Bongino next to him on other interviews.
Such bullshit coming in in his sportswear and telling us what to say.
First of all, number one.
Apleasure.
I want to make this clear, because this is how a cult's fucking projected.
First, you reframe the argument wrong.
I don't care if Epstein killed.
We're not looking for justice for Epstein.
Right, right.
Okay?
So first, they keep it on that to trick you.
Right?
Now we're not even talking about, why are all the people that went there still in power?
Exactly.
Hey, Trump's in now.
Right.
Hey, I remember QAnon.
Where's all the arrests?
Where's all the whatevers?
Then I'll watch UFO shit and they go, oh yeah, they actually executed these people on the moon.
Right?
Oh, Psy-Up time.
And then you go, like, the discrepancy with Pan Bondi saying there's thousands of pages,
the oldest evidence, the capital saying this, and it's like, whoa.
Oh, I forgot, Iran.
I forgot about that.
What's going on here?
It's so, yeah, there's a clear discrepancy there.
And then it's like, it's just, if you zoom out, it's so obvious that this was this compromise
gathering technique in order to blackmail operation, in order to control things at the highest level.
It makes sense.
Who are they blackmailing?
That's what we want to know.
I don't care about the list.
His client list is like, it's Israel, but whatever.
I wonder, I kind of wonder if, like, the Elon-Trump thing, I don't know.
I believe Elon more than Trump because Elon's black guy and his, now, I watch people say
this, I can't believe how stupid this is.
Oh, he must have been on ketamine and he rage tweeted.
Is that what ketamine does?
The horse tranquilizer.
No, you have to believe that Elon believes that Trump was on the Epstein list.
For sure.
It was interesting.
He said files.
And Trump is.
We know that already.
Elon gave us no new information.
He threw out a shot, but he didn't reveal anything.
Trump is in it.
Everyone who's in charge is in that file.
But that's the thing.
It doesn't mean they did it.
Exactly, because, you know, Epstein was, like, such a powerhouse in the financial sector
that, you know, it's going to just be a given that people will interact with him in that
world without ever touching the sides of what he was doing in the background.
You know what I mean?
Tuesdays with Stories, Mark Norman, Joe List show.
They probably won't appreciate me promoting it because they're going to, it'll be bad.
But Lewis Black was on and blew the whole thing wide open.
I've tweeted it.
I repeat it all the time.
Lewis Black went to Epstein's mansion in New York with Bobby Slayton, my buddy from doing the
Nasty Show.
Right.
I know that Bobby and Lewis Black are not doing a thing.
He was an influential New York billionaire in the biggest house in New York.
That's crazy rich.
Okay?
So, yeah, all right.
I've done, gone all kinds of, I've met all kinds of people from this.
Lewis Black's story is so interesting.
He walks in the door.
There's a marker board where they go in.
And there's all, it looks like football plays or something.
And Epstein goes, yeah, the defense minister of Israel was just here.
We were just going over defensive ideas.
And Lewis Black says in the video, look, it's on my Twitter, look it up.
He goes, he got so creeped out.
He goes, first of all, where the fuck was that guy here?
Right.
Why would he talk to you about it?
Why are you telling me that?
Right, right, right.
Right?
Wasn't it documented that Ehud Barak and Epstein?
Oh, yeah.
They were picked up.
And Bill Richardson.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Bill Richardson, New Mexico governor.
They were picked up.
Oh, you talked to the New Zealand woman.
I did, yeah, yeah, yeah.
One of the victims, right?
Yeah, Juliette Byron, I think her second name is.
And what did she have to say?
Well, she approached, she got brought in as a young model.
She was trying to start off her modeling career and she got introduced to them and flown out
to the island.
And from there, it was kind of like, you can't go anywhere and you're now a prisoner.
So she was very quickly brought into that, not as a child, but as a young model.
And on the wall, there was a big artwork of a woman being raped by a walrus.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, I'll share it with you if you want to share it.
The scary thing is that it's not really a painting.
It looks more like a photograph.
And the girl's lying on a glacier and she's got like ECG things here and she's being basically
raped by an walrus.
And she, alongside some of the other women, think that they were actually harvesting
their eggs.
They were?
You know, like Zorro Ranch.
Oh.
Where they were trying to, yeah, well, the thing with Epstein was he was obsessed with
eugenics and creating his own race.
Like he would talk about his own DNA.
Yeah, yeah.
Like that egg guy, you know.
Right.
So like maybe, you know, maybe he was doing something along those lines with people like
that.
She certainly felt that way.
Okay.
Because if they were taking eggs, they've got underground laboratories, right?
So then 1996, they cloned Dolly the sheep.
They cloned a sheep.
1997, Bill Clinton banned use of federal funds for human cloning.
Apparently in 2002, they cloned the first baby, Eve, in December.
So right.
I'm taken there in September.
I think they've taken my eggs.
They cloned a baby in 2002.
No one ever hears about anything again.
It's all on 60 Minutes or BBC, one of those things.
They were all talking about when a human is going to be cloned.
Suddenly it shut down.
I mean, it's very, someone like Epstein seems like he was very multifaceted.
Like there's an element to him where it was like almost like your primary objective is
compromise, right?
Is your primary objective is to do that.
But then he's using his money and he's like, I'm going to create a race of my own people.
It's like this dude is crazy.
Well, I wonder if, because this is really, this is a full schizo right now.
Oh yeah, let's do it.
So Charles Manson was probably an MKUltra patient.
Oh yeah, I think so.
I would say definitely.
So definitely, right?
You have this book, Tom O'Neill Chaos.
And you have, you know, Jolly West, who's like running this thing, had probably an office
at the Haight-Ashbury Free Medical Clinic where, you know, Manson was always going.
And then you have this kind of conversion of Manson from this kind of petty criminal to
the sex god kind of cult leader or whatever.
So there's tons of evidence there.
Here's the trippiest thread of the Manson thing that connects with Epstein.
That's so weird.
So Manson would carry around a book called Stranger in a Strange Land by Robert Heinlein.
Did you read that at school?
No, no.
I did.
1968.
Great book.
So he would carry this around, but Manson was illiterate.
So, and then he models his whole life off this book.
His son, he calls Michael Valentine or whatever, who's like one of the characters in the book.
Right, right.
Jubal, Roger Smith is his parole officer.
Jubal is the protector in the book.
He calls him Jubal.
What?
He tries to start a race war, which is what they're trying to do in the book or whatever.
Right, the whole helter-skelter thing.
Exactly.
Helter-skelter, yeah.
Oh my God.
So, okay, but we'll just fucking listen for a second.
So this is what's crazy.
Donald Barr is the headmaster of Dalton.
He gives Epstein his first job at Dalton School, which is in New York, this prep school or whatever.
And his son is William Barr, who's the attorney general under Bush 41 and under Trump,
who basically obfuscated fucking justice to get Epstein out of trouble.
So Donald Barr writes a sci-fi novel called Space Relations.
Okay.
And this is really, it's about-
New to me.
This is new to me.
This is so nuts.
It's about-
I read it.
It's so great.
It's unreadable almost.
It's almost unreadable.
And it's about this human traveling to an extraterrestrial planet, and he is sold as a sex slave.
Okay.
Why is he going though?
Do you remember why he's going?
Why is he going again?
To negotiate with the rulers of the galaxy.
The rulers of the galaxy.
To end slavery.
Oh, man.
That's right.
He just becomes a fuck pet.
Yes.
That's sad.
But how weird is that?
Yeah.
Isn't that, is that not so strange?
Exactly.
Like the connections.
Maybe some MKUltra thing going on?
Yeah, absolutely.
I think so.
Well, you just said about Stranger of Strange Land that I did not know.
Mm-hmm.
Um, so that was his programming.
Right.
One of his personalities was probably illiterate, but MK Monarch, which they have admitted is
real in 2024.
I didn't know that.
Mm-hmm.
It's very clever.
NSA Archive.
How is Monarch different than Ultra though?
Oh, well.
What was the incentive?
Because Monarch, the people now that you're like, why is Kanye so crazy?
That's why.
It's the, all your favorite Disney.
Hey, why do Disney kids turn out how they do?
Well, Disney, the fucking Rosicrucian that allowed the CIA to do stuff to him underneath
Disneyland.
And that's real.
I don't know if you know about Rosicrucian.
Well, he was, he was Opus Dei.
But their victims are talking.
He was in Opus Dei, like the, like the early Freemasons, kind of like before you turn 18.
They've all come together.
I would say, you know, the last thing I saw of Gary Wayne, by the way, I'm not religious
at all.
Also, isn't it like Club 33 or something?
Yeah, it's weird.
Yeah, yeah.
Club 33.
Yeah, no, it's all, it's all there.
He was a Freemason.
Why are all our beloved movies Bavarian fairy tales?
That's weird.
Right, right, right.
Hey, Disney sucks now.
Hey, it always sucks.
Why are you pushing princess chicks still?
Something that got me was Joe Rogan bringing up that scene in Pinocchio, you know, where
it's like, we take them to the little island.
And you know this scene in Pinocchio?
This classic scene.
It's freaky, dude.
It's like literally Epstein.
You got these like, you know, villains sitting around the table at the tavern.
And one of them, like the big banker, he's like, I know how to make a real bit of
money.
And he starts whispering to them and they're like, take them to Pleasure Island.
And he's like, yeah.
And he goes, but they're just little boys.
And he goes, well, they don't come back as boys.
And they all start laughing about it.
And I take them to Pleasure Island.
Ah, Pleasure Island.
Pleasure Island?
But the law, suppose they.
No, no, there's no risk.
They never come back as boys.
Pleasure Island.
Whoa.
Jesus.
Like very symbolic of what we're now discussing.
It really spoke to my subconscious and I want to be famous now.
Right.
So you got a masculine feminine side of the brain, which as the Templars will tell you.
Yeah, man.
They tried to preserve the defined feminine Ashtar worship of the fucking pagans.
Yeah.
So, but, you know, Purple Lady, I saw when I did the MT the first time, but not like
a woman, but I, you know, you've heard of the Purple Lady.
I believe that's my right brain feminine divine side.
You're, those collective unconscious, that's the meat internet, dude.
That's the original internet.
All the tech freaks are going to make an artificial version of every.
So if you see a, we're going to have brain wifi.
That's how you know ESP exists.
Oh yeah.
They're going to copy all the real, they're not going to tell you about them, but they're
going to copy them to get back to Atlantis times.
And so all this art, Oh, well, could it be archeological?
Yeah.
Oh wait, could this be the Nephilim from the bottom?
It's all of that shit.
Don't you get the, the jump?
It's kind of like, you know, they compartmentalize the names into like different names and you
go, well, that's Bible shit, but that's UFO.
You don't know what anything is because they controlled it.
Right, right, right, right.
And that's why they're called Freemasons, even though they don't build nothing.
They built their matrix.
Tom DeLong when he was, Tom DeLong when he was kind of doing the rounds.
What happened to that?
Early, early days of the UFO subject.
Yeah.
One of the things that he brought up.
And I don't know how true it is.
So I tried to find some like validation of whether or not these statues really were outside
SAIC headquarters, Science Applications International Corporation.
Dude, I've been wondering about that ever since.
Those pyramids.
Yeah.
So you've got like, do you know about this?
No.
Yeah.
These two statues.
One sitting there is one sitting there is a...
It's cool, man.
The ADHD in this room is real.
Like, I've got it as well.
All of us.
Yeah.
Like, everyone's trying to jump in.
But no, like outside this tech center in...
Do you remember where it was meant to be?
Was it in San Francisco?
Or like, you know...
I was in L.A.
L.A.?
By where I lived and I wanted to go there.
Right.
So like, it was meant to be the old SAIC headquarters.
And Tom DeLonge, when he was, you know, back in like 2017 doing the rounds, he was like,
oh, you guys, you know, there's this place outside the SAIC headquarters where they got
these two statues where you've got this Egyptian pharaoh sitting on a like temple seat holding
a pyramid in his hand.
And it says the past.
And then on the other side, you've got a kind of futuristic looking female goddess type
pharaoh holding a pyramid.
And it says the future.
I forgot.
Past and the future.
Do you know Epstein said that?
Yeah.
The new Atlantis.
The new era.
The golden dawn.
Right?
Wait.
You saw the clips from the Bannon Epstein document.
He has 14 hours of footage interviewing Epstein.
Yeah.
No, I use it for comedy on Kyle Dunnigan's channel.
I can't remember what we call it.
We had a news show.
It was really funny.
And it was the talk down.
Right.
Hollywood celebrities tell you the news.
It's called the talk down.
I like that.
So we did like the more you know parodies because my boy Jason Bermas, from Loose Change
back in the day, who was right.
Oh, yeah.
Loose Change.
Yeah.
He was right.
I didn't think he was, but he was.
Well, it's so funny.
They're kind of admitting that at the highest levels.
There's like a 9-11.
Like people are like, we need to look into the 9-11 file.
Right.
Like Kash Patel and like Tulsi are saying that shit.
That would have been, if you were to say this five years ago, you'd be called, you'd be
laughed out of a room.
Any room you're in.
Well, I mean, you'd probably be debanked.
The thing is, I feel like there's only so far they can go in investigations with 9-11
before they start blaming their greatest ally for it.
Right.
So it's kind of like.
It takes a village.
Yeah.
Oh, of course, our best aircraft carrier was involved.
Don't forget Pakistan.
Yeah.
You're talking about Osama, right?
So Seymour Hersh released probably what happened.
And he's a impeccable journalist.
Fantastic.
Okay.
I didn't hear of it.
In 2011, it came out.
And there was some, oh, I think Zero Dark Thirty and shit.
Yeah.
Which is nonsense.
It's a propaganda, propaganda.
He was a guy that was, and I remember watching now that guy Shrek from Delta Force talk about
it on things.
He goes, that guy went dialysis.
He crossed the mountains and got away.
Well, first of all, he had to get away because how can we go to Iraq if they killed the guy
that did 9-11?
How can we go to Iraq then?
Mm.
Get it?
Mm-hmm.
You ever see a Tony Clawson speech?
How do we get to war in Iran?
That's a real speech.
I think it's interesting that, like, obviously you've got Rumsfeld talking about 2.3 trillion
missing dollars from the Pentagon, and it cost about that much to do the Middle Eastern
invasion.
So it's like, is this a big money laundering operation?
Is there a lot of cash flowing through this?
Like, yeah.
Talk to Catherine Austin Fitz from HUD under George, I think H.W. Bush.
Yes.
There's like $23 trillion missing since 1997.
Yeah.
And I know Joseph P. Farrell, that smart motherfucker, he keeps track of financial crimes around
the world.
Yeah.
And he put together all these weird missing amounts of money with fake bearer bond, but
they're not.
They're obvious, like, fakes.
It doesn't make sense.
This is the kind of stuff that gets you Epstein'd.
Break away.
For sure.
The craziest thing about Epstein that I learned recently is that, did you know that Bill Gates'
science advisor is the backup executor to Epstein's will?
Doesn't shock me.
Didn't know that.
But it doesn't shock me.
How crazy is that?
And he was, he said, he found out.
And then he goes, I was shocked to find out that I was listed.
Whoa.
Did he come from Bill Gates?
I remember Bill Gates where he's like, well, he's dead now.
So, you know, like, nothing more to say about that.
Who's his family?
Oh, yeah.
That's right.
In that interview.
Yeah.
Well, he's dead.
So.
Is there a lesson for you, for anyone else looking at this?
Well, he's dead.
So, you know, in general, you always have to be careful.
That's a threat.
I took it.
Yeah.
Like, shut the fuck up.
A lot of people could be dead.
That's how I took it.
Yeah.
Because that guy, he's the grandson, of course, of, like, one of Rockefeller's fixers.
Right.
What?
Is that true?
I thought he was a middle class kid and Steve Jobs was a hippie.
I think he was the other nerd.
His dad was military, I think, right?
Oh, you don't say.
I think so.
Yeah.
But then he was, his grandfather was a fixer for the Rockefeller.
Rockefeller.
And that's where he learned to buy the press.
Because, as you know, Rockefeller, everybody hated that motherfucker because he was a piece
of shit.
And then they had the idea to do PR.
So, that's Bernie, the, the, the.
Edward, Edward Bernet.
Right.
What do you think PR is?
The blackest of magic.
Mm-hmm.
Okay?
They have big pharma'd old occult shit.
So, the mind control part.
Okay?
That's old, dude.
That goes to Egypt.
Right?
You got your pharaohs who were inbred like those LA vape dogs that are like, stop inbreeding
them.
Come on.
Stop doing that.
Right?
A corrupt priest class.
And I got some of this from Rudolf Steiner.
Yeah, I know Rudolf Steiner.
He's very boring, but he has gossip.
He has gossip.
He has very interesting.
He is because he tells you backstage, like how I would talk shit about a comic.
Uh-huh.
He talks shit about a cultist.
Mm-hmm.
That's the juiciest, best part.
Right, right.
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
And I found out all kinds of shit from just his gossip.
The main shit is almost ... I don't know.
I get off track.
No, I disagree with you.
I think the main stuff's really interesting.
Okay.
All of these things are the same thing.
Kabbalah.
So, did you study Kabbalah?
I can't say it normally.
I wouldn't say I studied it.
Familiar with it.
Oh, well, it affects your life deeply because all these esoteric groups that ... Fraternities?
Were you in a frat in college?
Didn't have frats in the UK.
No.
That's a purely American phenomenon that I've seen through American pie.
Yeah.
You've already got Oxford shit.
Yeah, dude.
Okay.
I didn't go to Oxford.
But you have it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, but I know everybody got Israel.
We got that.
But guess what?
We're even worse and UK is the one that got that shit going back in the day.
Oh, yeah.
Well, we've got old school esoteric belief systems going on.
That's right.
And that's why there's no justice about Jimmy.
People are mad about the grooming gang.
Now, I used to write for Sacha Baron Cohen on Who Is America?
Okay?
The pranks we did.
That's cool.
Yeah, it was fucking awesome.
I love that shit.
Dude, I miss them guys.
That was like a good ... His group's like a band.
They're not like a writer.
Yeah.
So, he does round tables like the great Cecil Rhodes.
Yeah, Cecil Rhodes.
Yeah, and so they picked me to write to stay on.
They don't do that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I got on with them dudes immediately.
Ann Hines and Dan Swine.
Those dudes, I love them dudes.
And I really like Sacha a lot too, but understand he's old money.
Mm-hmm.
He's co-anime, which is like real old money.
Went to Oxford.
The reason I got along with them is because their sense of humor, they're like smart-ass,
smart kids.
Right, right, right.
Yeah, his whole family's super smart.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm Jersey Shore trash, but I can always get a lot-
Not smart too.
Gifted and talented.
Well, I was in ... I'm gifted and talented.
Do you know about the city of London within the city of London?
Of course.
Yeah, do you know about that?
No.
So like the original city of London isn't the city of London.
Okay.
The financial quarter, which is one square mile of London, is called the city of London.
Wow.
And that's got its own mayor.
It's got its own police force.
It's got its own laws.
It's basically like the Vatican sitting in the middle of the city.
There's some conspiracies about them-
Oh, huge.
Running financial flows.
There is.
Who would have thought?
So like there's a really good documentary called The Spider's Web, Britain's Second Empire.
Like that will open your eyes to just how much financial corruption runs through London.
Like the Swiss have got nothing on us, man.
Like we really do run the financial sector of like high crime and it's the-
You read Anglo-American World Power, you said.
Yeah, I love it.
Well, you mentioned Cecil Rhodes.
Yeah.
So that's why it's like this.
That book, well, let's get into this because maybe they dovetail because Carol Quigley wrote
this book, The Anglo-American Establishment.
Right.
Talks about round table cultures, Cecil Rhodes and Lord Alfred Milner or whatever and like
them having-
Those secret societies led to the intelligence agencies that we have today.
What is it based on?
The Illuminati.
Right.
Old school Bavarian Illuminati.
The Jesuits.
And like, yeah, yeah, Jesuits.
He based his group on those.
It's in the-
What's that movie that's pretty-
They're pretty good, the first one.
Kingsman.
Oh, Kingsman.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kingsman.
Yeah, they ripped that stuff right into those shows.
Like for real.
I'm a writer and I study this shit because I've got to make-
I want to write jokes and I want to fucking make movies.
So I know sometimes they might be doing predictive programming, certainly, but understand there's
a dude like me that looks at this shit because you can find the best- because you got to write
something new that you haven't heard before.
That's how I could tell if you're lying to me a lot of times because you're telling me
a myth theme as Diana Basoka calls it.
I've seen this one, man.
Weapons of mass destruction.
I saw that 20 years ago.
I could spot it now.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's not that I'm that quick.
I don't-
It's yellow cake all over again.
Right.
Like the same shit.
On that though, I don't-
I'm maybe a heretic here in that I think Tucker maybe overreacted.
Look, I think-
To which part?
I think a surgical- whatever surgical strike Trump did is not the same thing as nation building
in Iraq like we did for as long as-
Shot for shot.
Right.
Sure.
But like-
Wait, wait.
That's three years before-
Just stand what the implications of that?
Yeah, but let's not get into some meta layer.
I'm just saying like on a basic geopolitical level-
Fucking Matrix, man.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm not sure that that was like a bad move and didn't set their program back for a while.
There are eight levels.
Do you know this?
There's eight levels of top secret above the president, and the reason for that is-
I didn't know that.
Yeah, well, most people don't, but-
Well, I don't think you know that.
Highest is nuclear.
Why?
Did I not wear the robes of a wise man?
That's true.
You are-
Am I not holding the baton aegypticus?
Why would you think I don't know that?
Well, I do know that, and you do, because you read that book.
Carol Quigley was given cosmic level clearance to go to the-
As Douglas Murray says, have you been to the archive?
He's been.
He's definitely a spooky guy.
Carol Quigley also is a professor at Georgetown who Bill Clinton said defined his worldview
more than anybody else.
Oh, yeah.
So, if you go through that thread, Anglo-American establishment to today, do you think the city
of London still has, like, the Vatican City of London, do you think any of these groups,
you know, Knights of Malta, you've done a lot of amazing work in Malta.
Yeah, yeah.
Do you think any of these groups have disproportionate power to that?
Oh.
Yeah, like, there you go.
There you go.
Yeah.
Oh, I wonder.
I would agree with Kurslaff.
Like, I mean-
Holy shit!
Yeah, like, England-
Oh, I wonder if they do.
Yeah, I'm asking Jack.
England is such an old country, man.
I think we're just very good at being quiet with the amount of influence and power that
we have.
How many crab claws have you had, brother?
I had this three claw podcast, and I-
Three claws down, and I haven't even had one.
You didn't even bring me one.
The worst tranquilizer.
Okay.
Do you think-
Bring the crab claws out.
I just want to-
Bust them out.
I want to be on your wavelength right now.
I want to be on your bandwidth.
You should have.
Yeah.
I got one more.
I don't want it.
You can have it.
I'll have it.
Yeah.
How many white claws have you gone through this morning?
Oh, yeah.
White claw, that's it.
Not grab it.
I'm going to start a podcast called, Do You Hear Yourself?
Do you think the secret societies are the most popular, the most powerful people who ever
lived?
I think-
Have undue influence?
Oh, I wonder.
Sometimes-
But you know what?
You know what, Kurt?
It's easy to say-
Because of the truth?
Well, no.
It's really easy to be hand-wavy about this stuff, and that it's much harder, and this
is my criticism of dark journalists, to actually understand how any of this stuff works.
And sometimes-
I don't think I have a really great map of the world.
I suspect that some of this stuff exists, but I think asking these questions is very
of value.
Sometimes you've got to ask an obvious question for people that don't know.
Exactly.
I watch the show, and I appreciate you having me on, brother, and I hope you understand
that.
No, I do.
I just think it's important that people understand, if you think they wouldn't do
that, they would do that.
History tells you they would do that.
Whatever you think they wouldn't do, not only would they do it, they did worse already.
And I think that when it comes to somewhere like the UK, when it comes to somewhere like
the UK, we're very good at being kind of diplomatically quiet in terms of influence.
A lot of people would say, oh, you know, the British Empire, it's done.
That was a long time ago.
It's like, not so much, actually.
Not with the financial element at play.
So I'd say that we hold a lot of influence over the financial kind of global market.
A lot of bad money flows right into London.
And then like, yeah, the city of London, this weird kind of like financial sector.
Like I said, they've got their own mayor.
They've also got the only unelected members who can go into parliament called the Remembrancer.
This guy called the Remembrancer.
Yeah, for real, right?
For real.
The Remembrancer.
What is this?
So he's an individual, or she, who works for the corporation of the city of London.
That is older than London.
Okay, so that's like the OG.
So that's kind of like, you've got the financial sector, you've got the city of London financial
sector.
The beating heart of that is the corporation of London.
All right, very dystopian stuff, right?
And so the Remembrancer, what a title, right?
Will go into parliament and sit and listen, and then report back to the corporation, and
they'll make a decision if they're actually going to pass that.
That's the real government behind the government.
So interesting.
They're a human, they're a Mentat from Dune, is what you're telling me.
Pretty much.
Yeah.
It's the same kind of a vibe.
You know about Lake Havasu?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Of course.
I played that game.
London Bridge is in Lake Havasu?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, you know, these people move up in there?
Yeah, they moved it.
They moved London Bridge.
They took, yeah, they took London Bridge to America and built it Lake Havasu.
Lake Havasu is just like the old city of London and the Vatican.
And Freemasons laid the first stones in Lake Havasu, like for that.
Well, Lake Columbus is the controlling interest.
And the reason they brought that bridge is because there's kids' walls up in it, and
it's a negatively charged...
My God, I don't know about that.
Oh, yes.
Well, Nathan Reynolds, go check him out.
But see, I started...
Here's what I do, because I'm on a news show, okay?
So, I'm looking at the current events.
What's your show?
Jimmy Dore.
I'm on it.
I'm a psychic on Jimmy Dore.
Oh, you're on Jimmy Dore.
Okay.
So, I'm getting actual news that nobody's getting, because all the channels that people
think are news are literally propaganda for the one guy who's president at the time.
So, Fox is entirely for Trump.
I know your boomer parents watch it.
They can.
It's the program Trump.
Of course.
MSNBC was for Supreme Biden.
Okay.
Well, I want to see Morning Joe.
It's all for one guy, and they're a bloodline with the British.
I will say that, like, from a British...
Wait, wait.
Yeah.
Bury the lead.
Bloodline with the British.
From a British perspective, like, our propaganda is a bit more nuanced and subtle than the
Americans.
Used to be.
Well, I would argue it still is.
And the, you know, when you look at CNN and NBC, like, at least from my perspective, it's
like, well, you can tell that they're drenched in bias.
This is just political talking points.
You've been stuck on a tarmac, too?
Yeah, bro.
Well, that's what I'm saying, though.
It's like, it feels like the BBC, for example, they're fucking clever, man.
Like, they'll drip it in very subtly, you know, in this lovely British accent.
So, you really feel like you're being informed.
But it's the exact same thing.
It's just a little bit more subtle.
Speaking of which, do you see this Wall Street Journal article about the UFO stuff?
Yeah, man.
Like, again, I feel like there's a mix of, like, some actual truth to what they're saying
and also, you know, an incentive to try and kind of, like, disrupt what's going on in
the UAP conversation.
But I would argue that there is definitely a level of, like, you know, bringing people in.
Again, it comes back to this campfire story thing.
Like, how many, no offense, but how many whistleblowers have got up and gone, like,
yeah, I was told this.
I was told this.
I was told that.
You didn't see shit.
You didn't know that.
You didn't see it.
So, you've been told this by who?
By Lou?
By Chris?
By Gary Nolan?
By whoever it might be?
And it's like, where's the seed?
I want to trace the seed back to the origin point.
And where's the actual information?
Because whenever you ask these guys, they got told it by another GS-15 or another high level.
Yeah, well, I'm friends with his cousin.
They fucking hate each other.
John Ward of the Fifth.
Yeah, John Ward of the Fifth.
Yeah, I know, right.
He's a great classic character.
He's great.
Mellon has the expert tech file.
Yeah.
What happened to Academy of the Stars?
Where'd that go?
Yeah, exactly.
I was talking about this not that long ago.
Like, To the Stars Academy.
That's, you know, Tom DeLonge, I feel, got thrown under the bus.
He was what they would call a useful idiot.
No offense to the guy.
Yeah, like, you know, he was all excited.
And I'll quickly, do you know how he initially started this?
Like, Tom DeLonge?
He spent his personal fortune to find out?
No, he performed at a lot-y holiday party or something.
Yeah, so he's always been involved in, like, you know, the UFO subject because he's got
the money and the connections.
He actually knew a dude at Lockheed Martin who was like, there's like a family and friends
meetup happening.
Would you be interested in introducing the bosses onto the stage?
And he was like, I want 10 minutes with your boss afterwards, but yeah.
And that's when he had, right?
So literally, right?
So he walks into Lockheed Martin and then he gets taken, you know, through the classified
facilities to a meeting room where he sits down with the big bosses, skunk works, all
this stuff, and he pitches to the Stars Academy.
And he was saying on the radio, you know, you have to go and be of service.
I wanted to be of service.
So he basically went in there and was like, here's a template.
I am your medium into the public, into the, you know, the youth of today.
Use me however you like.
And one thing I'll say real quick is that despite the controversy, and I wouldn't say I trust
this guy a hundred percent, but Stephen Greer was kicking down doors at that point.
He had like, you know, 6 million, 7 million views on Netflix.
He's talking about unacknowledged special access programs, illegal programs, real repercussions
that need to happen.
This is an uncontrollable asset who's out there making noise.
Suddenly, Tom DeLonge turns up to the heartland of classified security, right?
Lockheed Martin.
And he's like, guys, use me.
Here's what I want to do.
Tell me what you want to do.
Suddenly, Tudor Star, suddenly, Lou Elizondo, suddenly, Chris Mellon, suddenly, the New York
Times, and it just feels like they were like, this is the opportunity we needed.
There's a disruptive guy out there who's giving this narrative about illegal programs.
It's going to cause trouble for us.
Suddenly, here's a really famous guy who's got a link straight to the youth of today.
And he's saying, we can fucking model it ourselves.
There's an email, I think, between him and Podesta where he's like, yeah, between DeLonge.
They were tight.
This came out on WikiLeaks.
And DeLonge is like, I want to, you know, give the truth, but I also want, you know,
I don't want people to, I want the government to be portrayed as cool or something.
So these emails that came out, yeah, dude, dude, so on WikiLeaks, what's interesting
is they are gone.
I've tried to find these WikiLeaks emails where he's talking about Edgar Mitchell and
something.
People have scraped it.
But they're 404 on the website.
Every single one about Tom DeLonge interfacing with Podesta and people like that.
But back in the day, bro, he was literally saying to Podesta on emails, like, I really
want to try and get the youth of today to be more pro-military, more pro-government, and
this is how we're going to do it.
And so the Secret Machines books and the TV series was all about trying to build confidence
back into the institution.
And yet, and yet, and yet, I look at the people he was talking to, Neil McCaslin, Steve
Justice, where I'm like, where'd Steve Justice go?
Where'd Steve Justice go?
You know what I mean?
Totally.
And I share your frustration around the campfire story stuff.
But I'm like, these guys are high-level dudes.
And like, I don't think-
Like I said, campfire stories with a TSSEI clearance attack.
Yeah, totally.
Totally.
And I don't think they would be spending this much time with the front man of Blink-182
if there wasn't something-
But that's what I'm saying.
Where's the seed?
Well, I want to know where that kernel of actual data exists that they're then echoing
back into these circles of people who are like, well, I got told by Lou and Lou told
me this.
It's like, right, so who told him and where does he find it?
I can tell you that.
Go for it.
So, MK Monarch, the thing that they have admitted was real.
Now try to stay on it.
Yeah, yeah.
Most of your favorite stars-
I think, really, the only actor who didn't work with the CIA is probably Steven Seagal.
The only guy who literally didn't work with the CIA is Steven Seagal.
But in the program, which is the continuation of MKUltra, Tom DeLonge's family, are they not
Air Force?
Yeah, he's got intelligence backgrounds.
Like Willie Schreiber!
Yeah, no, another member of the band as well actually helped this.
I'm not going to remember it, but I found this out and was like, what?
So then another member of Blink-182 had family members in the intelligence community and he
actually helped with something in the military, in the IC.
It was like some software or programming or something he would help with.
So there's two IC-mil connections in Blink-182.
Wow.
Tom DeLonge and this other guy, I think the bassist, but I can't remember.
It's like all the rock stars of the 60s.
Yeah, dude, it is weird.
It is.
It's like all of them.
Yeah, in the 60s.
Yeah.
Dear brain.
Monarch!
But it's just, I don't know, like, you know, did Tom DeLonge have a natural interest, natural
money?
I think he did.
And then he got brought in and got fucked around.
Did you hear your story?
You know, that's what it feels like.
I want to be used by you.
Well, I hear stories.
You do that?
Yeah, exactly.
But I think that is not programmed into him because he's from an early age, from one of
them fans.
Right, right.
I want to be of service.
Yeah, yeah.
For sure.
But then I hear stories of, you know, people like Neil McCaslin, who ran, I think, the
AFRL, Air Force Research Laboratory at Wright-Patt and stuff, like, serious dudes taking Peter
LaVenda's work.
So Peter LaVenda co-wrote, you know, this book with Tom DeLonge.
Going back to the occult and, like, you know, Peter LaVenda, OTO.
Yeah, going back to the occult and the grimoire and all sorts of things, like, very seriously.
And I don't know what to think of it.
Because I'm like, even my own relationship with the sort of more esoteric elements of this
stuff is like, I find it fascinating, but it's definitely, to the extent it's entangled
with reality, it's inherently, like, sort of covert and occult means hidden, you know?
There's definitely a Gnostic theme running through a lot of these guys, like, what they
believe in and this idea of the Archons and even Tom DeLonge on, like, 2016.
I got breakfast with Tom DeLonge and he told me that he thought these were like Archons.
Yeah, yeah.
And there's, like, you know, in Gnostic tradition, you have a Demiurge that's a lower god that
controls the material world.
Poppeteer of our reality and then the gods of that reality, the Archons, who kind of,
like, recycle us back into the super reincarnation.
Have you ever thought of scaling that down and applying the Archon title to your human
leaders who call themselves that because they think it's their divine right to do that to
you?
Yeah, I would say it's a very similar type of a thing.
And then, like, you know, you look at Tom DeLonge was, like, so excitedly talking in 2016
on the radio about this when someone asked about the Archons and he was like, yeah, dude,
like, we've been developing weapon systems because we know they're coming back and we've
been waiting for them and, you know, this is why they can't tell you about the UFO subject.
And it's like, right, I have a massive issue with this.
Like, I have an issue with people who say, like, we've been doing this in secret.
That's why we couldn't tell you.
Okay, so these things are transdimensional.
They apparently interface with consciousness, can apparently bend space-time fabric, but we can keep
a secret from them.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like, come on, bro.
Oh, that's a great point.
That's weak source.
Right, right, right, right.
We can prepare and they wouldn't know.
If Tom DeLonge's sitting there on, like, you know, the radio going, like, no, trust me,
dude, like, we're hiding it because of the aliens.
Like, what the fuck?
They've heard it.
Like, you know what I mean?
So, like, that doesn't wash with me.
Yeah.
I think that, you know, someone like Tom DeLonge, he got brought in and he was so excited
and it's kind of like, you know, on a lower level, similar to me when I was first
meeting people and, you know, like, hanging out with CIA officers and you think this is so cool.
Like, these guys are actually giving me time, but they're so good at becoming your friend.
Like, you know, that's what I was saying before.
They're good at doing that because they see you as someone that, you know, can send a message
through.
Yeah, showbiz is called.
Yeah.
Like, not every time, but I think there's a lot of that in the UFO community because it's
like, it's like perfect ground zero for them to interface with the public and create a
bit of a rumor or, you know, a bit of a campfire story.
What do you think the point is?
Because a part of me is like.
Confusion.
A confusion.
Absolute confusion as to what is actually going on.
Because like, again, there is definitely something going on.
There's something going on.
Something really, really important and probably non-human.
Do you have like a best guess at that?
Or do you think that maybe the PSYOP above all else is that they don't know?
Yeah, that could be.
And so you just create.
They haven't got a clue.
Because I suspect that no one knows.
Well, that's kind of where I lean is like, they've got maybe slightly higher fidelity
information and ideas, but they don't really know what it is and they don't know how to
address it.
And it's like, you know, how does the premier national security apparatus go?
We have no idea.
They can penetrate every system.
They can destroy us.
They can take you out of your room at night.
Like, you know, all that kind of stuff.
Like, yeah, I think that there's an element of that.
But then there's also like, you know, like I said, the classified exotic research and,
you know, using the alien as a smokescreen for that.
So there's so many incentives to keep us in the dark and also spread all these different
stories, which we've seen since like the 1940s when they started these UFO conferences and
these spooks and spies would come in and they'd give people ideas.
But look at what we're dealing with now.
A spaghetti junction of narratives with a thousand people saying a thousand things and that they're
all true.
This is the narrative.
It's like no one actually knows.
That feels purposeful.
Yeah.
Feels like it's generating noise because, again, there is something to look at.
And it's maybe the implications are so deep that they can't risk people knowing about
it.
So it's better to believe in gray aliens coming from Alpha Centauri or whatever, you
know.
But again, like you said, I think that there's a likelihood that they don't really know.
They don't really know.
And that scares the shit out of them.
Yeah.
There's clearly their patterns.
There's clearly a.
Old gods or something like, you know, like whatever you might think.
Like, you know, did you read that book of the Collins elite?
Oh, man.
I've read a few things on the Collins elite.
You know, at the final events by Nick Redfern.
Yeah.
Nick Redfern.
Now, whoever he was talking to was feeding him horseshit.
Right.
But the book's still very interesting.
Radical, Christian ideologues.
Yes.
Because I watch Jason.
I always call him Jazz Jabroni, but his name is Jason Georgiani.
Because he.
And again, I don't need to agree with all your points.
Everybody's got a little piece.
I just want your piece.
Yeah.
Okay.
And he, he points, he goes, this Collins elite that are fundamentalist Christians.
Yeah.
George W. Bush years.
Okay.
So I'll be calling Powell's in on that.
There'd be a lot of these people in on that.
And they're fundamentalist Christians.
Then you read about what they did.
Well, first we met aliens and then we're like, can we use this to assassinate people?
Well, are you guys Christians?
I thought you were Christians.
Right.
Christians do that.
Yeah.
No, they don't.
So now I'm being fetished.
By the way, Collins, just so you know, is one of the old Barnabas Collins from the, what
do they call it?
The Dark Shadows.
Johnny Depp played him in the remake.
Oh, I don't know, man.
Yeah.
It was a 70s thing.
All right.
From England.
Barnabas Collins.
Very popular.
Dark Shadows.
Johnny Depp later played him in the Tim Burton remake movie.
Okay.
Wow.
But that name Collins, that's one of them, the 13 families.
Right.
Big, powerful name.
First, first warlocks in America is their claim to fame.
I wonder if that's the same Collins elite.
Maybe.
Hey, I noticed a lot of occultists all think that they're Christian and they say it like
they are, like your J.R.R. Tolkien's, who, by the way, was a Rosicrucian.
Yeah.
Just like Disney.
He was, yeah.
He was a Rosicrucian.
Yeah.
And his Catholic priest's son was a vicious pedophile.
Didn't he, didn't Tolkien eventually convert to Christianity fully because of C.S. Lewis?
Oh, I don't know.
Am I making that up?
Yeah, I don't know.
Or maybe it was the opposite.
Maybe C.S. Lewis eventually-
I know he had ties into these esoteric communities, though.
What's up, guys?
One of today's sponsors is us, American Alchemy.
We just launched what I think is maybe the coolest merch line in the world.
When you're wearing it, it's not like you're shilling me or the channel.
They're just really epic and I think they look good.
We have a couple of amazing designs for you.
We have our cowboy UFO tee.
Pretty epic.
You see there's a rancher.
He's witnessing a UFO.
A little cow is getting abducted by the UFO in the background.
And then you know that I love mid-century history, specifically spooky science, atomic era stuff.
And so we have our atomic age tee here.
Pretty cool vibe.
You got a robot serving this guy.
A little martini and then a UFO off to the side.
I think it's pretty epic, too.
And then finally, we have our hats.
This is just one of the hats.
We have many different designs, but I think they're pretty epic.
I think you can wear these around and they just look like a generally cool brand.
Doesn't necessarily mean you have to be obsessed with UFOs or even my channel.
I think they just look epic.
But buying these does support the channel.
I no longer make any money from any of the venture capital stuff I used to do.
This is my sole source of income.
So buying the merch is a really amazing way to show your support.
Go to AmericanAlchemyMerch.com, AmericanAlchemy, M-E-R-C-H.com, to check out all of this amazing new apparel.
The cowboy tee that I'm wearing is 100% cotton, super relaxed fit.
We went for quality on these.
So check them out.
Okay, Mormonism, Lord of the Rings, a bunch of stories.
You hear the themes over and over.
Yeah, same kind of thing.
Campfire stories.
Yeah, yeah.
The theme is Atlantis over and over.
Yeah.
And thank you, dog journalist.
Metaphorical overlay.
I got that word from him.
I didn't make that up.
It's a metaphorical overlay.
Once you realize that principle of a metaphorical overlay, then you go, I've heard this story before.
Like I'm saying with the tall whites.
Oh, this sounds like some racist came to an island and we're like a cargo cult that tries to make the same planes out of wood.
But I got news for you.
I think they have all those metamaterials now.
The Helium-3 and the Bob Lazar Muscovium-113 because I text you about it.
They made that in a particle collider in Russia.
That's what CERN is.
How much metamaterial could I get out of the biggest one or the 30,000 ones we have all over?
You know something wild about CERN, right?
They're not opening portals.
They're making their shit.
Well, you know what's interesting about that?
Because, I mean, like, obviously, like, everyone's making theories about CERN and, you know, what's going on there.
But there was that woman who I look-
Astrid Stuckelberger.
Yeah, man.
And she's got a hell of a resume.
She has a really impressive-
Really impressive resume.
She's kind of like a public health policy expert, but sits on all these interesting boards.
And she's in an interview and she goes, physicists from CERN are telling me that beings-
Beings are coming out of portals.
Are coming out of interdimensional portals at CERN.
There are lots of physicians.
I know some.
They're doing very strange experimentation.
There are beings from portals coming in and out.
It's physicists from the CERN who told me this.
They've testified to beings coming in and out of portals.
Yes.
So this is what's crazy.
Right.
I reached out to her one summer, like last summer, not- maybe two summers ago.
Because I was fascinated.
That interview came out and I was like, I need to- because I do think high energy physics,
whether it's Thomas Townsend Brown, Tesla, nuclear stuff, you get weird stuff showing up.
You can yield anomalies.
Yeah, for sure.
Yeah, yeah.
That's where you're testing the boundaries of our reality and the whole Feynman, there's room at the bottom.
That's how you get into that.
And so I was like, okay, this is really interesting.
So I reach out to her, no response.
Then I throw that clip in a long video I did with this guy, Riz Virk, who does simulation theory stuff.
She got back to you.
And she emails me and she was like, we must talk now or whatever.
And it was-
What?
Yeah.
And it was responding to my initial inquiry, clearly because she had read it.
Right, right.
And-
Just didn't know who you were and was like, whatever, I don't know who this guy is.
Yeah.
Like, yeah.
But clearly she did.
Clearly she did.
And I was like, okay, let's talk this week.
And then just ghosted, like never heard from her.
So, so strange.
Well, that's the thing.
She was on like some obscure interview on Bitchute or something like that.
You know, she wasn't on like YouTube or anything like that.
And I think because she was also talking about COVID and it was during that time where you just couldn't say shit.
But I found it very interesting what she was saying.
And I don't know, man, like, you know, so many theories about what they're doing over there.
And it's a difficult one, but high energy physics, like you said, I mean, I've heard some things from people who, you know, work in the quantum computational industries and kind of like some of the high level simulations they're running on like black holes and dark matter and weird shit is going on localized to the computer.
And there's a famous crash in the U.S. at South Haven, right next to Brookhaven National Lab.
Right, Brookhaven.
That's where our largest particle accelerator is.
So that's our CERN equivalent in Long Island.
Right.
And you have the police chiefs there and a bunch of local residents say that it was collected by Brookhaven, the crash itself.
And Brookhaven's Montauk, right?
That's Montauk?
It's near Long Island.
Yeah, it's kind of like in that vein, like weird shit going down at Brookhaven Labs.
They had a gate program.
Yeah, they had something going on.
They're getting talented.
So do you guys think the Montauk experiments were real?
Because you've had on Eric Hecker.
Yeah.
That's my boy, Eric Hecker.
Yeah, Eric Hecker.
Yeah, I know you guys were chatting in a space a lot of long ago.
Oh, hey, you know when we bombed Iraq that day?
They had a five point.
No shit.
Two earthquake.
Hey, you know Syria where we just installed Al-Qaeda?
Remember, we went to war.
Your brain makes too many connections.
That's what the government tells me.
Yeah.
Think about what you just said to me.
A little context for the audience real quick.
Eric Hecker.
Who's Eric Hecker?
Eric Hecker, he was a plumber, like quite a high level plumber.
He went out to a lot of different, like, you know, interesting clients.
But he ended up getting a contract via Raytheon to go out to Antarctica and do work out there.
Ice Cube.
Yeah, Ice Cube neutrino detector and things like this.
And because of his role, like people kind of like shrug it off because, you know, you're just a mechanic, just a plumber.
But because of that role, you get access to so many different areas of like the sites and the facilities to do basic work and upkeep.
And he said that he had noticed that like energy was being transferred from one area to another area where it wasn't supposed to be going.
Like a huge amount of energy was being sent off to these places when he was, you know, trying to de-energize the cables and things like that.
And he was like, you know, where's all this going?
And they were like, don't even worry about it.
And then he, I can't remember the specifics of how he's kind of come to this conclusion, but he's pretty sure that the Ice Cube neutrino detector, which is like embedded into the ice.
I mean, it's absolutely insane.
This thing with all these like doms that are going deep down into the ice.
It's essentially like, you know, this three-dimensional technological construct.
But he thinks that there is, well, he's found documentation to be fair to him, like documents that insinuate it's a two-way device that the energy can be used to actually emit instead of just receive.
So it's not just a receiver of neutrinos.
And?
It's an earthquake gun.
And it's an earthquake gun.
You know, that's what he believes.
Yeah, Christchurch, New Zealand.
New Zealand.
I don't know how true that is because I haven't really seen satisfactory evidence for it.
You know about ELF waves?
But that is the claim.
That is what he's saying.
And he's become quite well known for, you know, talking about that.
And I know you've connected to him pretty recently as well.
Oh, yeah, I just did a thing with him.
I talk to him all the time.
Yeah, he's an interesting guy.
But he also talks about, because he says he was in like a childhood.
Yes, he was.
Yeah, sorry.
Yeah, yeah.
Early on.
And then he talks about the Montauk experiment.
I grew up on Long Island.
I had a very peculiar history of nefarious activity with the Stargate program.
Yeah.
You know, I've forgotten the name.
But Inisfarda, Inisfarda, that was the name of the school that's now been turned.
It was renamed and then destroyed.
But I did find the place.
It was real.
And it was called Inisfarda when he was there.
And it was like this weird school for gifted children.
And they would do the remote viewing stuff.
And apparently they would take him to the library and put this like fluid in their eyes
that would make everything turn slightly yellow.
And he said he'd remember like being really like pumped to go outside and like see if it
was still there because everything would be in yellow.
And he didn't really know why they were doing that.
But it was at this time where he was being, you know, kind of prompted to remote view.
And, you know, there's no wrong answer.
Just tell us what you think.
And he didn't really understand what was going on in this setting because it was very different
to his school environment.
And like Kurt said, you know, this is something that a lot of people seem to have been brought
into, especially in America.
It seems you guys have been running that because I don't know about the UK, but I haven't heard
many stories of like, you know, that kind of stuff.
I know like at this point four or five people who, if you met in any other context, you'd be
like, this is a normal, credible person, say that they like, they're brought into this
some program as a kid.
They don't remember a certain year of their life.
It's really interesting.
I think there's some truth to that, brother.
Like, you know, of course you would try and get some of the best and brightest and try
and, especially if you genuinely are interested in parapsychology, but you can tell the world
that.
It's like, right, find these kids.
See if they can do it.
See if they can interface.
I mean, NASA had the star kids.
That's even like mainstream knowledge.
Now we know that NASA was getting these kids and trying to get them into remote viewing
and yeah, Andre Pujaric had an institute in upstate New York.
And a lot of the astronauts did remote viewing.
I mean, Edgar Mitchell's really known for that, doing experiments when he was up on the moon
and Gordon Cooper discussion about space kids and stuff.
You put a blue Masonic flag on the moon.
You know, people think the moon landing's fake.
Right, right.
I don't think it is just based on they put a blue Mason Lodge flag on it.
Yeah, Buzz Aldrin.
Do you think the footage that we saw might have been faked, but not the actual mission
itself?
That's my belief.
That's kind of where I am.
Yeah.
I wonder, because some people say, like, you know, people say nukes aren't real because
some of the footage is fake.
Yeah, I don't believe that.
I don't know about that.
Smart guys.
Smart thinking.
Yeah, Mark Andreessen said that.
Yeah, yeah.
I've seen that floating around the heat.
He's an absolute liar.
He's a dumbass.
I'm sorry to tell you, he's one of them.
I watch him do it.
Tell that shit to the Japanese, man.
They might have a few things to say about that.
Yeah, exactly.
Okay, they're like, what about the radiation?
Yeah.
I got this from Joseph P. Farrell.
This is a great little tidbit.
I've never heard anybody say this before.
He remembers from being a little nerd kid when, what's the German guy that ran the rocket
program, the famous one?
Wernher von Braun.
Yeah.
He has a blurb in Time Magazine that his mom got, and he's reading it.
Wernher von Braun, he tells the, while he's talking about the moon facts, you know, he
goes, well, the point in neutral gravity where he gives, like, double the amount for what
they said it was.
Right, right.
And then, who does?
Von Braun.
To what we're now given today.
Not only that, so because he's such a turbo nerd, Joseph P. Farrell, he puts it together,
that means it's more dense than they're saying.
It's farther away.
Right.
Oh, right.
There's a race to the moon.
Remember how we got to get to the moon?
Don't know why, but we got to get there?
Yeah.
Before we rush it?
Well, Sputnik was beating, yeah, they were beating us.
That's what they said.
That's what we're told, right?
That's what we're told, for sure.
How did we get all the good Nazis after the war, but Sputnik was beating us in space?
How does that work?
Oh, maybe the same way Pearl Harbor worked, where you cut off Japan's oil, so they have
to attack you because you want them to.
So you think Sputnik was a false flag?
No, I think they wanted Sputnik to go ahead, so they go, hey, we've got to start working
a lot harder, guys.
It provided the impetus to do that, right.
And what's weird as well is that there's a clip, there's this really good clip.
I mean, it's just like a real what the fuck moment with this NASA astronaut who's like,
oh, I'd go back to the moon in a nanosecond.
The problem is we destroyed that technology and it's a very difficult process to build it
back again.
I'd go to the moon in a nanosecond.
The problem is we don't have the technology to do that anymore.
We used to, but we destroyed that technology and it's a painful process to build it back
again.
It's like, what?
Yeah.
And like, how did we get through the Van Allen radiation belt at that time, but now we
can't.
Yeah, it's really interesting.
We're only in LEO low Earth orbit now.
You know how Starship's, what their plan is to get to the moon?
It's wild.
What is it?
So it's, Starship is, you know, Elon's latest rocket, 150 to 200 tons or whatever.
And this is a state of the art, you know, thing.
It's obviously much more tonnage than what we were dealing with back then.
It's meant to like carry, you know, huge payloads of starlings and shit.
But still, this is what we have to do now to get to the moon.
And we did this before we had something like an iPhone, like, you know, the entire computational
processing of NASA couldn't even fit in my pocket.
In your pocket.
You know what I mean?
So these things now go up to low Earth orbit.
They burn nine tenths of the fuel tank just to get to low Earth orbit.
Right.
And then they're orbiting around.
And then you have to get another one up.
That burns nine tenths.
It does butt-to-butt refueling with the first one.
So you get two tenths in that first one.
Nice.
The second one then disposes of itself.
You have to do that 10 times to get a full tank in low Earth orbit.
And then that one that's fully refueled goes to the moon.
Yeah.
I feel like that alone debunks and asks some serious questions.
It's insane.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Unless you've got another energy source.
Where the fuck?
Also, oil's not rare.
Colonel Prouty told us.
It's like diamonds.
Like De Beers.
Stay on track.
It's all on track.
Fucking-
All on it.
No, it's a little-
King of non-sequiturs.
But-
You don't-
Okay, look, look.
I'm telling you this for real, dude.
Part of the thing for people in the program, they have a list of you can read.
You're a non-linear thinker.
The ability to synthesize seemingly unrelated events.
Now, when I read that, that's how I write jokes.
The reason I look at all goofy shit and I look at everything is so I can have jokes.
A lot of my jokes that I made as jokes have come true and it's disturbing the fuck out
of me.
Dianne Pasolga needs to write American Cosmic 2 about Kurt and his brain.
American Cosmic 2 and Electric Boogaloo.
He gets downloads.
Electric Boogaloo.
Dude, look-
He has protocols.
Yeah.
You all should be seeing the-
I want to make this clear that I'm not smart.
I fell for 9-11 back in the day.
I was in New York.
And they go, we got to go to Iraq.
And people rightly pointed out, that makes zero sense.
And I said, shut up!
I made a lot of faces Jesse made here on the show today.
Be a patriot.
I'm joking.
Come on.
Well, I just, I think you have to, like, with 9-11 even, like, I now suspect more than
ever that there's some fuckery there, but I don't know.
And I think you have to stay in that not knowing zone to be an honest-
Let me give you a good parable from the, uh, uh, do you remember, um, when we starved half
a million kids in Iraq with those sanctions?
And, um, what's her creepy name?
She was the bird bitch that, she'd get an interview on 60 Minutes, uh, Albright, Madeline
Albright.
And, uh, and the lady goes, and I'm watching-
You're probably the first female Secretary of State at that point.
Oh, that matters.
I'm just saying.
Well, that matters if you're a lizard person, doesn't it?
Let me get through it, okay?
I don't get a nervous rich kid feeling.
I'm just trying to get through it.
I know they're your friends.
Just relax.
Okay?
I don't blame you for the FTX kid.
I'm not like the others.
So, Madeline Albright's sitting there being asked-
Getting fucking roasted.
I'm a comic.
She's being asked, hey, over half a million kids starved from our sanctions.
You know when we canceled Iraq?
Yeah.
And their kids starved, because that's what we do, the good country.
And was it worth it?
And Madeline Albright, she goes, like a zombie she is, she goes, I think it was.
Oh, God.
The first woman said that.
Damn, bro.
I think it was worth starving half of-
Now, luckily, we have the numbers.
There's only a quarter million Iraqi kids, so.
But, if she would do that and say, I think it's worth it on a goddamn camera,
you'd think that bitch wouldn't drink a baby in the woods with an outfit like this on?
Are you dumb?
Are you young?
Right.
You haven't figured out the scam yet.
So, I think of this like scams.
They don't know what it is.
They thought they knew.
They got Nigerian prince scammed.
Get it?
Think of it as crypto scams.
Be Coffeezilla about it.
Coffeezilla, who I recommended to Rogan Show.
I want to admit, he, Kermit's Trezorgasmos, the writer of As the Carpets or the Drapes.
I recommended him.
The guy does killer work, right?
Just apply that.
Just do a metaphor.
It's so easy.
It's just pattern recognition.
You can see the game that's being played on you.
Hey, this reminds me of this.
You just got to do that.
All humans can do this shit.
They're literally training you not to do it.
Have you noticed?
I believe there is some, you know, ambient evil in the neoliberal world order or whatever.
And neocon.
Which are kind of synonymous in many ways.
Yeah, man.
But like, when you meet these people, I don't know.
I'm not sure they're drinking baby blood in the woods.
The reason for...
Like, I'm sure...
I know there is weird shit, like the Epstein shit, of course.
You know the MPI Ultra reason, right?
Manchurian Candidate is based on that.
What if we could have a secret agent that don't know they're an agent?
Wouldn't that be great?
And if they get captured, they honestly didn't know they did it.
We achieved that.
That's been achieved since ancient Egypt, but we achieved it.
We big farm it with the Nazis we saved.
As that's a matter of public record, not a conspiracy.
We brought Nazis here with big fucking scars down their face to run NASA, which had the
Space Kids camp.
I wonder what went on there.
And we had them run it to some reason, beat the Soviets to the moon.
Wait, NASA had a...
Get to the moon and destroy the ship.
NASA had a Space Kids camp?
Yeah.
I didn't know that.
Like I was saying, you can look it up now.
It's like kind of general knowledge.
They had like Space Kids and like the Star Kids, I think it was called, or something like
that.
I know about Puharich or whatever, but did NASA have official...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
NASA had something like a gifted children's thing, but I think that it's kind of like,
you know, there's a mainstream acknowledgement of that.
And then the surface layer of that is people saying, yeah, and while we were there, they
were teaching us remote viewing.
That's kind of like the thing that's not necessarily discussed publicly, but was part of that program.
Yeah.
Wow.
Nonsense.
Yeah, man.
No, I don't remember doing anything like that.
Maybe I didn't pass and nothing happened, but I just don't remember.
Well, Wernher von Braun apparently encouraged also Edgar Mitchell to go up and do this
sort of parapsychology, like pick this card sort of thing.
Yeah.
Well, I hit Busters beginning.
Remember that?
No.
Are you going to go to Busters and Bill Burr?
Dan, I've gotten dinner with Dan Aykroyd.
He is obsessed with UFOs.
Yeah.
He loves all this shit.
Dan Aykroyd is probably a high-level Freemason, and that's why he's into...
Well, he says his family is like, you know, psychic research for a hundred years.
That dude knows a lot of stuff, I promise you.
And stuff he ain't never going to say.
He also smokes a ton of weed, so maybe that opens some portals.
On the MKUltra list of what drugs do to control you?
Yeah.
Marijuana breaks amnesiac barriers and interferes with the programming.
So in Montauk and Monarch...
That's probably why I'm so dope.
Look, don't worry.
They fixed the problem now.
So the weed, I'm sure...
Oh, lame, man.
But why was weed illegal so long?
Well, it interfered with the mass mind control.
Can I give you my crazy MKUltra theory?
Go right ahead.
Okay.
So Jolly West, you know, one of the architects of MKUltra, like, I feel like a lot of it was
like he had this, like, Center for Violence Studies, violence reduction.
I kind of think it was, like, local violence creation for mass pacification or violence
reduction.
Interesting.
So it's, like, things like Manson where you have this, you have a symbolic scapegoat
where, like, Manson was synonymous with, like, the hippie movement.
Right.
And you have him...
This is the way that you then go, we've got to stop this, guys.
Exactly.
Because look at this one.
Look at this one.
Thomas Thompson writes it down and it becomes legend.
Right.
Right?
That was, oh, they're those hippies.
So that's the guy closing the book on that little op right there.
And if you read the Franklin scandal, I didn't...
I was like, nah, he wasn't there.
Then I'm like, wait a minute.
His death's a bit suspicious, isn't it, Hunter S?
Pretty sure he was shot with a suppressed pistol or something.
Looking at his life, it's worse.
Yeah.
And, you know, all the crazy to talk about adrenochrome, I know, where did I hear of
that?
I heard of that in Fear and Loathing Law.
Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas.
I wanted to find some.
He wrote about adrenochrome?
Well, have you seen Fear and Loathing, the film?
Uh-huh.
So in that, there's a scene where they take adrenochrome, he's like, I got it from
this Satanist.
You can only get it from a pineal gland, like a real pineal gland.
And it's like, oh, shit.
Like, they give the whole spiel about adrenochrome.
I thought it was a hallucinogenic, see, they made it look like it's like a hallucinogenic
or like, yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
But now when they talk about it, have you noticed this?
They talk about like it's a narcotic, like a cocaine.
Right.
Now, here's a weird fact.
I don't know how it fits in.
Maybe you heard some.
The stuff for an EpiPen, when you have allergies.
The adrenaline, right?
That's adrenaline.
And if you let that go bad, it turns into adrenochrome.
Oh.
But it looks like red powder.
So why can't you just use that if it's a drug?
I mean, like, I don't know.
I definitely think there's something to adrenalize blood.
Like, you know, this whole idea that, you know, you get someone into a perpetual state
of fear.
They've got all this adrenaline running through them.
Like that blood's going to be rich in adrenaline.
Whatever that really does to someone's mind, if they just drink it, I don't know.
But like, you know, they definitely don't want us to think that there's anything like
actionable or real.
What's an internet troll, dude?
They try to, somebody, a disembodied thing, feeding on your, they say stuff to provoke
you.
Right.
To feed on your negative emotions.
Does that story sound familiar to you?
Yeah.
Again, the same kind of fractal pattern.
As the cartons, so the drapes.
We're going to technologically create.
It's like a demonic, demonic trip.
Yeah, no, absolutely, man.
Like, absolutely.
And I think it happens in different levels and layers of society in different ways, you
know?
It does not suck, because I found your show in there.
Yeah.
I learned.
Now, I don't.
No, that's true.
That stuff's dope.
Like, the fact that you can make connections that you can never make, but we're going to
make more progress and all this stuff.
They fucked up putting it in there.
They fucked up.
But it also, sometimes I'm like, I just got to get this out of my brain.
Like, the people you sometimes get focused on, and then sometimes people attack you for
no reason.
It can be very overwhelming, actually.
You have to lose your show about it 100%.
You have to lose your ego.
And the issue with that is that this is a very egotistical space.
Like, you know, a lot of competition between people and like, you know, like influencers and
content creators and whatever, whatever.
And like, that's something that I found very tiring is just like dealing with the egos in
this field.
Well, it's so ironic, right?
Because it's like UFOs.
People say, I've got a massive ego.
Maybe I do.
But yeah.
Well, UFOs should like, UFOs should be like this sacred thing.
Yeah.
And instead, you have all this like jockeying around like, you know, I want to be the disclosure
person or this or that.
And it's a cottage industry.
There's a lot of money to be made.
Like, you know, people don't think there's any money in UFOs.
Like, have you been to some of these conferences where they've got the whole place hired out?
And it's like, there's money there, dude.
There's money there.
That's how they compromise your work or anything.
And then all the CIA people are at these conferences.
Yeah, they are.
Like embedded within the crowd, talking to people.
I was never offered money, okay?
I don't want to say these things I'm saying, but they won't pay me.
Yeah.
They'll not say them.
Still wearing my picture.
I haven't even thought to do that.
Yeah.
Not once.
Rude.
Rude, yeah.
Because my cape isn't as nice as some people's capes.
Yeah.
And my angstaff, yeah, maybe I got it at Party City before I came here.
But don't show that I have that soteric knowledge.
And yeah, maybe my cult leader sunglasses are, I got them at the 7-Eleven before I came here
when I got my claws.
That don't mean I don't know what I'm talking about?
I offered way too much, more money than I can afford, to be honest, to have Kirkpatrick
come on my show.
And then my buddy doubled it.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, you sold it.
It's at 100k.
Yeah, dude.
And I don't think he's going to come.
No.
But I think it's a revealed preference that he's being paid off.
Kirkpatrick, Sean Kirkpatrick, you know who this guy is?
Oh, okay, okay.
He's not meta bad enough for you because you want only pro-disclosure people to be bad,
but they're anti-disclosure people who are also bad.
It's too simple.
But it's also like, you know.
I'm not judging you, good or bad.
I judge if you lie to them.
I definitely.
Well, he is a liar.
I'll tell you that much.
Right.
But I definitely get frustrated with like the pro-disclosure activists who are kind
of like anyone who's coming out from the government who isn't Lou Elizondo is wrong about what
they're saying.
And it's like, yeah, okay.
But like, again, I would say that someone like Lou, for example.
But on the facts, Kirkpatrick got so much wrong in that article.
Right.
Oh, no, absolutely.
I'm not disparaging that.
Like, you know, Sean is a shady character.
Shady.
But so is Lou.
Sure, sure.
So is the guy that drops fake UFO photos on stage and in congressional settings and they
get debunked in 24 hours.
He was wrong long before that.
Like, so much is, but I know, bro.
I've been following it for a long time.
Okay.
So Sajban Cohen, who, by the way, has a mutation in his eye that he can read tiny writing that
no one can see.
Are you serious?
That's kind of cool.
That's fucking awesome.
What a wild little superpower to have.
He doesn't improv.
That dude don't improv.
He writes the lines you say.
Holy shit.
Word for word.
Yeah.
When he would go into character.
He's a genius.
Dude, it was.
He would go into character.
So we did this billionaire character, Gio.
And he's talking to a yacht salesman about putting girls in a boat.
And now I want to tell you, all these pranks, it's all these rich kids that are funny kids
and they burn family connections to do pranks.
Okay.
This is 2017.
I'm doing this.
Hysterical shit, dude.
And we had these people, we had Dick Cheney on and he asked him to sign his waterboard and
you know, all kinds of fun stuff.
Yeah, yeah.
That was hilarious.
He goes, my waterboarding kit.
He goes, oh, he signed my waterboard.
My favorite was.
So funny.
Oh, is this in the, this is America?
Who is America?
Oh my God.
Some of that was disturbing, bro.
Yeah.
So I, every time I go, no one is going to fall for this.
This is too stupid.
Right.
Okay.
I was wrong.
I was not right one.
Right.
Dude, they did these fake charities.
I wrote about like skinny shaming the kids of Sudan and say, my body, my choice.
Like we had some rockers go, they'll say anything because the camera's on them.
It was unbelievable.
But the Gio one, that's what I want to talk to Weinstein because his story of meeting Epstein,
it sounded, dude, it sounded like what we did on the show.
Like, was Epstein doing a prank show?
And then I realized, oh, we were doing what an Intel operation is.
But for fun.
Right.
So I had some ones I think are funny and I thought they were so stupid.
Who would fall for this?
But in Georgia, Eran Marad, the Israeli commando.
Oh my God, that blew my mind, dude.
And when he was getting the guy to have like the little teddy bear guns for kids and stuff.
Oh yeah, they did that before.
I think they built a mosque.
So in case they'd act.
Oh, it's so funny.
And he's like, you build your cubicle into a mosque so they can't attack you.
The guy's wearing a turban and genie shoes.
Holy shit.
And he's like, has a flute and a rubber.
I mean, come on.
And so it's like, what do you do?
He goes, I'm a Muslim.
He goes, what are you eating?
Hummus.
Okay.
And then the office came up.
Then I had the pork shield and the gay pork, you're gay.
Like to chase the shooter out.
Yeah.
And they actually do it.
That's the thing that's crazy about it.
These people who are like senators, they were actually on the show doing it, doing it.
So what do I do?
I move towards him with my ass.
I can say, America, America.
See what the thing is from what I'm saying?
Yeah.
These people are fucking actors.
The guy from the Federal Reserve.
Why do we have to borrow money that we print?
Right.
What the?
Yo.
Who's running this?
Is it with you worse than any UFO story?
Yeah, dude.
What the fuck?
None of you know how anything works?
I feel like I shouldn't have better intel than the president of the United States.
I don't think it's because I'm a super spy.
I think because there's a big problem at the top.
That kind of goes back to the UFO subject in terms of like, do they even know what's going on?
Like we barely, they barely even know what's going on in the Federal Reserve.
Do they really know what's going on with like, you know, ancient aliens and like any of this stuff?
It makes it rife for counterintel because of that.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
Because it's this, it's both real and it's ephemeral.
And so it's so co-operable.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
It's a Rorschach tell.
Yeah.
You can say it's that.
Yeah, sure.
Yeah.
You can say it's like all these things.
I know what Schrodinger is.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You know, he was a bad, you know, all the physicists are Schrodinger at a journal of
the 12 year old girls he would court.
He said no one should go to, oh dude.
Schrodinger?
Yeah.
Oh.
No.
You look into, oh, and how about the physicists?
I bet you met him who invited Rogan to Epstein Island.
These people, you'd be shocked.
Wait, who invited Rogan to Epstein Island?
Krauss.
No shit.
No, really.
Lawrence Krauss.
Really?
We mean no really.
He's got a record.
Lawrence Krauss is on Epstein Island, but did he invite, he invited Joe Rogan?
Oh yeah.
I won't say no more on that.
I mean, a lot of people got invited.
A lot of people got invited.
Stephen Hawking was out there as well.
Oh.
People go, I'm disappointed.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If Stephen Hawking was there, he's the victim, stupid.
Obviously.
He's in a wheelchair.
Obviously, right.
Yeah, yeah.
No, but I think, I think again, it's like, you know, like something like that.
Something like that though.
It could be the fact that, you know, like, hey, there's this individual called Jeffrey Epstein.
He's very interested in science.
He's funded a lot of stuff.
Would you be willing to come to his private island?
He'd love to like host you.
And it's like, cool, I'll go do that.
Then you leave, you had no idea that it was an island of rapists.
A hundred percent.
And they're arbitraging stagnation in academia.
Yeah.
Where like nothing vital or interesting is happening.
Right, right.
Great point.
So you pay them off.
You have prestige.
Exactly.
And you have, you even, you have probably of age girls.
And some of these guys are single.
I mean, for God's sakes, you have one paraplegic who can't talk or whatever.
And it's like, they don't know, you know, or in certain cases they probably did.
But others, they didn't.
It's a mixed bag.
Yeah, yeah.
I mean, Bobby Slayton went to his house in Europe.
I know Bobby Slayton didn't do something.
Yeah.
A rich guy and you're a comic.
Want to, let's hang out, go to this thing.
You get creeped out and they're watching.
How do you respond to this?
Eric Weinstein explained it.
Yeah.
They got the American flag coffin table to see if he'd spill his drink on it.
Well, the Weinstein thing's crazy because he was like, it was almost like Epstein knew
about his theory.
Of course he did.
Right.
But like, right as he produced it, it was like, Epstein was tracking.
Right, right, right.
It was like, oh, you produced it?
Boom.
Come up.
Yeah.
You know, come.
A bit too fast.
Yeah, a bit too fast.
A high frequency trader for like theories of everything and interesting science and shit.
Yeah.
Oh, that's interesting what you just said.
It is like high.
Yeah.
Because it's like, yeah, that's a good way to put it.
Yeah, it is.
It's rigged.
You could bet in the market, but it's high frequency trading, so you'll never get access
to it before certain people do.
Right, right, right.
And that's how we have this secrecy.
Well, I was kind of wondering, so this is getting into really weird territory, but it's
like, I wonder if he was a fly trap for like deeper, like exotic propulsion science.
Yeah, I wonder about that.
I wonder about that.
He was obsessed with the Casimir effect.
Yeah.
The Casimir effect.
Of course.
The Casimir effect being like, you know, this sort of dark energy shown between two non-charged
but conductive plates that seem to attract, you know, that like geckos, this is a real
force.
Yeah.
And he's like, how could we harness this ostensibly for propulsion?
Like.
I mean, this is like not really like necessarily evidence, but I think it's interesting.
There was that woman, I can't remember which one it was, who was a victim who did like
the murals and the paintings, Maria Farmer and like there's a mural called like the
centiles, which is like the elite spell backwards.
And it's like this big mural of all the different people that were associated.
Les Wexner.
You can see all the characters.
Ghislaine Maxwell is depicted as a dragon biting a child in half.
It's all very nasty stuff.
And then there's also a, an antenna going up with an FBI flag on it with a flying saucer
hanging off the top of it with Epstein's face inside the window.
So it's like, okay.
So like who knew and what was he actually trying to achieve in terms of his own scientific
ideas and explorations?
And obviously, like I said, he's funding all of these different movements.
He knew everyone on the Nobel Peace Prize board.
Yeah.
Everyone.
I have an answer for you, brother, because I give it up to Daniel on this.
Here's what, what's his name?
The wheelchair robot man.
Stephen Hawking.
He was those ruins that came out in National Geographic of possible Atlantis.
And then they never talked about it again.
Right.
And the pictures were on legacy.
Oh, what?
Underwater or?
He went in a submarine to go look at that.
But remember, Guy Lane.
Yeah.
He was about to ocean.
Terramar.
The Terramar Project.
Like she had a whole thing going on there, which is interesting.
She's the controller, not Epstein.
Do you know about Terramar?
She's the handler.
No.
It was like their kind of like overseas and like Atlantic Ocean trading network they
were trying to establish with people like, who's the guy behind Virgin?
Branson.
Or Richie Branson.
And like he hosted them all on his island for the Terramar Project.
Whoa.
It was like basically these elites setting up some sort of like, I don't even know how
to say it.
Like they kind of considered it their own country because when she was being interviewed, she
was asked if she's a citizen of any other country.
And she said Terramar.
It's like, okay, so what is Terramar?
I forgot that, dude.
She did.
She said it was her other citizenship.
Yes.
And it's like this elite network of trading routes, trading routes and shipping containers.
Going around places like near Antarctica, off the grid.
What?
And it was being held by all these fucking huge elites.
So there's something about the Terramar Project, man.
Dude, I forgot that.
That went under the radar.
No.
Yeah, dude.
Whoa.
I forgot that.
I didn't even know.
That's wild.
Well, I sometimes wonder if on that note, this is crazy speculative, but like, you know
what William Stevenson is?
Maybe by Facebook name.
He was Churchill's super spy, but he helped start the CIA with Wild Bill Donovan and OSS.
And he was really close with a lot of US-based scientists like Charles Steinmetz and Thomas
Townsend Brown.
They were close confidants.
And he was doing a lot of stuff in and around the Caribbean, the Bahamas, the Virgin Islands.
And he ended up spending the rest of his career in the Caribbean doing shady trade stuff.
And I wonder if there's a connection between, like, I feel like he and Robert Maxwell had
to have known each other through MI6 circle or something.
Right, right.
So I don't know.
I mean, this is getting crazy.
It is interesting.
What Eric Hecker said, did Eric, oh, I don't know if he said that, I think, but so the people
he worked for.
Yeah.
So, you know, people go, Elon Musk, the richest man in the world bought Twitter.
He's not the richest man in the world.
You, what do you think?
They would put that in Ford?
Right.
Richest man disclosed.
They're telling that to you, you idiots.
Publicly.
Yeah, yeah.
I go back and forth on that.
I don't know.
Are you guys sure?
I mean, I'm not sure of anything.
I'm not either.
I'll bet a million.
I agree that, like, maybe it's like.
That's the X bucks.
I mean, you know.
That's zero dollars.
Old money people that have got, like, holdings in other countries and, like, vaults of treasure
and things like that.
People think, you know, poor people think people are rich and, like, hey, you're a rich
kid.
And they have no concept of what it's like at certain levels to not understand.
The rich kids don't think they're rich.
I'm not rich.
That guy is rich.
You know, you always have a new.
Yeah, yeah.
And I live in New York.
I did comedy.
So I could just go to all the things and get a perspective on what shit is.
Right.
And that's the compartmentalization.
And that's how it's supposed to be.
And all the.
So are there hybrid kids?
Yeah.
When they say bloodlines, it sounds spooky.
Why do we keep track of royalty at all still?
Does anybody wonder that?
Why do I give a shit about Meghan and Harry and the prince?
British people I know don't even care about it.
I guess they're a human flag.
Is that their deal?
Most of the younger generation fucking hate the royals.
Of course.
All populist things got to be crushed.
Right.
So how do you crush them?
With nonsense distractions.
I mean, it's endless, dude.
But we got woke after Occupy Wall Street.
Remember that?
Woke happened after that.
And that is a way of controlling populism because, you know, what do we see these days when there's a populist front?
It's just immediately a right wing, far right racist movement.
And that's the way that we disregard it and we get rid of it.
And it's like a lot of these populist movements are just popping up because of the fact that it's a direct reaction to institutional power and control and censorship.
And they turn it around and they switch it to make it seem like you don't want to be supporting these.
You realize these are Nazis or racists.
But in Ukraine, it's cool.
Right, right, right, right, right.
Yeah, exactly.
I can't deal with the hypocrisy.
Those are the good ones.
Can't deal with that hypocrisy, right?
Like, let's all salute Azov Battalion.
But, you know, don't worry about these people who are just trying to create some freedom in their own country.
Like, you know, it's crazy.
Yeah.
United Fruit Company story.
We should talk about the pyramids.
We haven't even gotten it last year.
I know, I know.
I was going to-
Oh, sorry.
We got to talk for a second.
All right, I got to piss anyway, so-
All right, so do I, but I'll let you go for it.
You go, come back.
You go, maybe come back.
Maybe come back.
We've had Alex Jones on the show and Kurt, you are 10x crazier than Alex Jones.
And I love it.
I know why the cage bird sings now.
I used to judge Alex Jones, but I know why he's like that.
He's a cage bird?
Here, wait, hold the staff while I'm going.
This is wonderful.
Okay.
We got this.
Man, you know what?
I love him.
Oh, he's fantastic.
He's great.
He's awesome.
It's kind of like if you brought me in and we were like, right, let's get some dude from
the underpass on as well and bring him in like, dressing his cape, like, let me tell
you about the secrets of the Illuminati.
Nah, Kurt, could.
Or if we were both on a mega dose of LSD.
That's what it feels like.
It feels like I'm rolling on something pretty strong right now.
No, that was really good, dude.
Like, the pyramids, though.
We should talk about that.
We should get into that because it's interesting.
What's going on?
What's under the pyramids?
What's happening?
Because you're in touch with the research team that found this through synthetic aperture
radar Doppler tomography.
These structures and they're reconstructing the structures.
Is any of this real?
Yeah.
I mean, like, my opinion on it is at this point, there's 100% things underneath the Giza
plateau and the pyramids.
Whether or not we can completely correlate that to the very interesting 3D models that
they've created.
I think that's more of, you know, kind of an inspired artistic recreation.
But at this point, I would say it's undeniable that they are finding significant subterranean
signatures below the Giza plateau.
And like, there's been so many assumptions.
Like, even actually driving here on the way, I got into a talk with my Uber driver and I
was like, you heard about the pyramid scans?
He was like, yeah, yeah.
But like, none of it's been like done before and none of it's been peer reviewed.
Right.
And I was like, no, that's not right.
So in 2022, they actually did a Giza, the Great Pyramid of Giza scans, and they found
hidden chambers beneath the Great Pyramid, which they then were peer reviewed and accepted
and fully just like a validated thing.
Now, granted, they weren't saying that there were huge structures underneath, but that's
because they were tuning the technology to specifically look at a localized area of
the pyramid.
And that's when they found these hidden chambers at that time, 2022.
But they've also done experiments in Italy at the Grand Sasso laboratory, which is 1.4
kilometers inside a mountain.
And they mapped it out.
They mapped it out.
They managed to find the centrifuge and like the areas that they were focusing on.
And they've produced tomography scans showing the subterranean infrastructure of the Grand
Sasso laboratory.
And they've also done the Mosul Dam in Iraq, and they use it for structural integrity for
bridges.
Professor Filippo Bionde, who's the synthetic aperture radar expert on the team, works for the
Italian government, serious guy, real fun, like such a nice dude.
And I've had like the pleasure of because I put out that video, which was only like eight
minutes long, just kind of saying, hey, guys, like there's this team and they're doing this
kind of blew up.
Joe Rogan played it.
Like, you know, so like I got connected to the team quite quickly because they saw my viral
video on it.
And yeah, I was out in Malta with them a few days ago, actually, before the Carolina conference
and for their first international conference where Filippo Bionde was presenting in a lot more
detail, the scans, the science behind it.
Granted, some people struggle with the dialect.
I think in the UK, it's a little easier for us because we're used to European dialects
like Italian and French and German.
And the Americans seem to struggle a bit more because they have got quite a thick accent and
they are trying their best, but they're speaking English, which isn't their first language.
But it's very interesting because what they're doing is they're not scanning two kilometers
into the earth, five kilometers into the earth.
Like, you know, they're not penetrating using radar in that way because that's impossible.
That's what a lot of the mainstream critiques were doing, including some people that I just
think, why did you not do your homework?
Like Flint Dibble, like this archaeologist in this world, right?
Like, he's just like, they've never tested it.
It's never been done.
It's like, wrong, wrong, wrong.
Like they have if you actually just spent 10 minutes trying to find it instead of having
a knee-jerk reaction because it's going against your model.
And that seems to be such the case with mainstream archaeology, mainstream history and sciences.
If it goes against the model, there's a knee-jerk reaction and they didn't actually
do the homework.
So like, yeah, like what we have detected other underground things using Sardoppler
using Sardoppler tomography.
This is a thing that we can do.
It's well, it's a thing, but this is certainly a thing within a niche community and beyond
Dave, Filippo, beyond they seems to be the one that's really specialized in that.
So it's not like a general accepted mode.
It's like a novel sense of fusion.
But I even, it's funny.
I even watched Sabina Hassenfelder's like video on this.
She's a, you know, kind of a mainstream physicist, critical of string theory and stuff, but like
pretty conventional and like well-regarded.
And she was like, you can, you know, map magma chambers and volcanoes using Sardoppler
tomography.
And then she, like you said, said that they took liberties, obviously on the reconstruction,
you know, this sort of energy grid that it seems to be mapped out.
That might be a bit of a stretch.
I don't know, but I think it's interesting that it doesn't sit in a vacuum because you've
got historical reference to labyrinthian passageways beneath the plateau and entranceways into the
halls of records.
Like there are, there are old, uh, going all the way back to ancient Greece and further
of like, you know, statements from people who went to Egypt and wrote about like being
taken into these corridors and then early like 1800s explorers who said the same kind
of a thing.
And then like I was saying to you before, even Zahi Owas before about 1993 was saying the
same thing.
Yeah.
So like, you know, there is, uh, there is definitely a pattern to be connected in relation
to like subterranean infrastructure.
And we find that across Egypt anyway, regardless of the plateau, like there's a lot of different
places that are subterranean and, uh, seem to be of a different stonework of a different
kind of method to what we then see with dynastic Egyptian temples.
Yeah.
Same with the pyramids as well, actually, because one of the biggest, uh, signifiers of that is
the fact that there's absolutely zero hieroglyphs in the pyramids.
There's not one other than the cartouche that's written in red ochre that we attribute to Khufu,
which, uh, by the way, if you look into the images of that red ochre, uh, cartouche that's
been drawn on and compare it to, uh, some other red ochre marks that were found inside the
pyramid.
It's so obvious that this is basically just drawn on with lipstick.
It's fresh.
It's got like flaking from the ochre on it, but the older stuff, it's like the ochre's
gone.
It's just ionized onto the rock.
So it's like a shadow imprint of this very light red ochre.
This stuff is like literally like someone got lipstick.
And that's the only thing that we attribute to Khufu for the Great Pyramid.
This is like this 1800s explorer.
I forgot his name, like Voss or Vass something.
And he was hired by, uh, the British museum.
He was running out of funding.
He was running out of time.
Lo and behold, he suddenly finds the signatures of Khufu written in very suspicious ochre.
So other than that, there's no hieroglyphs in the pyramids.
Now I've been to like the Valley of the Kings and the Valley of the Queens, where they've
got these tombs and they've got these entrance ways.
And it is literally, you can't even find a square inch, which isn't covered in motifs
and symbols and gold calligraphy, go into the pyramids and it's just blank.
There's literally nothing inside the pyramids other than precision engineering and
the studies of acoustic signatures in the King's chamber, which show that it was acoustically
engineered.
And then like, you know,
Do you think there was some sort of, cause you, you've covered this in other contexts
too, in Malta and other places.
Do you think there's some sort of ancient, uh, acoustic based technology?
Yeah.
Uh, I, this is one of the things that interests me the most.
And like, we call it archaeoacoustics and there's also a term psychoacoustic architecture.
The idea that some of this architecture is deliberately designed to produce harmonics that
then influence the brain.
And one second, my brother, let me just get off this tangent.
And then, so they really, really interesting, a really interesting element of like the acoustics.
You just mentioned Malta.
Yes.
So I got back from Malta recently.
There's a, there's a temple in Malta, this subterranean temple carved directly out of the
limestone.
They date it back to the Neolithic stone age period, but that's just because they can't
date it back any further with conventional narratives.
Right.
Yeah.
And this place is precision tuned to 111 Hertz.
Like they've done enough studies in there to show that this place called the Oracle room
resonates at 111 Hertz.
It's this like incredible overlapping architecture, like these kind of like multiple layers of,
uh, of like concaves and, and, uh, entrance ways.
And inside the, uh, Maltese subterranean chamber of the hypergium, they actually found elongated
skulls.
One of them's on display in the Valetta museum and the interesting thing about these skulls
in particular, unlike some of the ones in like Peru, where you've got evidence of head
binding is that this skull actually lacks the sagittal suture, which is the vertical crack
that goes all the way down the head.
When the two preteal bones are pushed together, when we go through the birth canal and fuses
the skull together.
Yeah.
So we have one going across here and then one going all the way down the skull.
That one doesn't have it.
Doesn't have it.
So that's like an, and it's a, it's an adult skull.
It's not an infant skull.
So this thing was walking, talking and acting around without a critical component of our,
um, bone structure.
What do you make of that?
Well, I mean like there's one in Valetta, but the story goes and it's even written in
the museum and you hear it from the Maltese locals that they found fucking hundreds of
these skulls, hundreds of these skulls.
Then the guy who finds it mysteriously dies.
Someone from like some Smithsonian Institute takes over all those skulls vanish away.
What does that person look like in their time?
Exactly.
Like, you know, we don't know, like, you know, there's, there's recreations of it that
kind of look like an alien gray.
Like, you know, it's like, they don't really know how it looked, but it's, it's elongated
enough to be significantly different to a human being.
And then like the Maltese legends in that area are that there were giants once on these
islands and that they helped build these temples.
Cause what's crazy about Malta other than the fact that it's the, it's got the largest
concentration of megalithic stone building sites in the world.
Like they're like so many there, but when the bronze age settlers from Italy and Sicily went
over to Malta for the first time, they were already there.
No people, just temples everywhere.
And so we don't know who were the original builders of these temples, but it goes back
to your question about acoustics.
Like there's so much acoustic knowledge that seems to be incorporated into megalithic neolithic
stone age, stone building cultures.
And that is not something that you can just arrive at naturally.
We're not talking about like the creation of a flute.
We're talking about multi ton geometric alignment, not just with solstice and equinox and all that
incredible stuff, but also acoustically resonant in a way that when chanting or any sort of like
mantra is performed in these sites, seems to excite the brain in certain ways, bringing
it into alpha state, bringing it into meditative states.
Is that true?
Oh, absolutely.
Absolutely.
And how, how do we, how have we tested?
So we've tested like things like Stonehenge and again, the hypergeum for the acoustic
wavelength that's propagated naturally through it.
When we chant, when we hum, when we drum and 111 Hertz is what they find in the hypergeum.
There's like quite a few studies actually done on this where they've concluded.
And then what they're doing, like.
And then, so like you look at binaural tones and the Monroe Institute of Applied Sciences
and the stuff that we're at a fledgling level.
This is what's so impressive is that we seem, we seem to be at a very fledgling level of understanding
the acoustic effects on the brain and these people seem to have been fucking masters of
it.
Like we'll like play like an instrument now and then we'll, we'll do some like EEG scan
of the brain or something while we're doing that in this hypergeum structure.
Yeah.
I mean like structure and they've done a series of acoustic tests, not only just to test the
bandwidth of it, which comes out 111 Hertz, but then like actually module, like scanning
the brains and seeing how people react inside these kinds of a chamber, but also like, you
know, you put some headphones on and listen to your favorite music.
You can laugh, you can cry, you can want to work out, want to fight someone like it changes
your emotions.
So we know that acoustics has a profound impact on our perception, our emotions.
And yeah, the fact that some of these places seem to have been tuned to Hertz ranges that
excite the brain and change the brainwave state into theta and alpha.
I would say that there is an ancient science of like conscious induction, like consciousnessly
acoustically induced, sorry, conscious expansion.
And then you see these elongated heads.
You start wondering, you know,
See the elongated heads, you see astronomical alignment with a lot of this megalithic architecture
that seems just very odd, if not intentional.
Like it probably was intentional.
Once you get a pattern around the world of different sites that have the same kind of a
tuning, like Newgrange and Island, Malta, the pyramids of Giza, like all of them have,
I mean, the pyramids are an incredible example.
It's a perfect scale.
I can't actually remember what the scale is, but a lot of these places, like there'll be
an error of margin of like the actual kind of Hertz range.
The pyramids are perfectly scaled as you kind of rise up through the grand gallery into the
King's chamber.
The acoustics that have been picked up are like the perfect number.
It's like no margin of error.
So it's like this incredibly tuned building.
So fascinating.
And it's funny when you hear Randall Carlson or Graham Hancock or, you know.
I was hanging out with him.
I love it.
How cool is he?
He's such a cool guy.
He's the best.
Such a cool dude.
He's like Hagrid or something.
Yeah, he is.
He's a wizard.
He's like our personal alternative history Hagrid.
He's awesome.
And like he'll say stuff, you know, about like possible, you know, ancient acoustic technology
and you laugh it off.
And then you realize that there, you've talked about this, there's a field called cymatics.
Yeah.
Where you put sand on vibrational plates.
You know that there's a real effect there.
We know that electromagnetic fields affect the body via, you know, cellular communication
occurs via, you know, voltage gated ion channels, which get affected by local EMFs.
So I was doing an interview of a guy called David Elkington recently, who's like a, he
would call himself a recovering academic because he came from that world and is now seeing things
in a different set of eyes.
And he's really interested in the acoustics of the ancients.
And I'm going to have some images of this in my podcast because he actually did some
experiments alongside some other scientists in the King's Chamber where they, they stretched
a membrane over the sarcophagus of the King's Chamber, like a cladney plate, like a cymatic
plate.
And they put Egyptian sand on the plate and they sent vibrational frequencies that match
the frequency of the King's Chamber through it.
And it turned into the Eye of Horus.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And I've seen photos of it where it literally is pretty much on point with the Eye of Horus,
which would suggest what?
That the King's Chamber was tuned to an acoustic, the cymatic of which is a representation of
part of their own language.
Well, you see.
What does that say?
The level of sophistication well beyond.
I mean, you see like, you know, go to Chichen Itza and you like will clap and hear this bizarre
noise or like, you know, during the equinox, you know, you get a snake running down the
steps and it's like, we can barely do that stuff.
And what did Tesla say about frequency and vibration?
That this is the key.
Totally.
This is the key to the universe, to understanding it.
And I think that there's a real truth to that.
And whatever these people in the prehistoric time were doing, they seem to have a very advanced
knowledge of how to attain transcendental states through acoustics.
And like you said, with the cymatics and the geometry, it is fascinating that when you
vibrate these sands on these plates and you get these geometries that are essentially the
visual signature of the sound you're hearing, you will then find them in pretty much every
religion, monotheistic or otherwise represented in the geometry of the cathedrals and the paintings
and the motifs.
Once you understand and look at and recognize cymatic geometry and what it is, you go into
these places with new eyes, man, you're staring around and you're just like, well, there we
go.
There's a clear pattern that is a harmonic signature and it's written on the wall.
And so it would seem, and also what's one of the most prominent things inside of churches,
it's not actually the crucifix, it's the pipe organ.
The pipe organ is the most prominent thing.
I think that these places were deliberately designed and like the Gothic cathedrals are
a fantastic example of potentially reaching an apex point with this.
You know, this lineage of acoustic knowledge that seems to stretch all the way back into
prehistory.
Yeah.
Well, even the Freemasons would say like the brothers of the serpent from Egypt or there's
some like connection.
They had their hand in building the Gothic temples.
Building the Gothic temples.
And these things are not just geometrically incredible when you look at them, but they
are also acoustically profound and like, you know, meant to be these spaces for induction
into the mysteries via sound.
Speaking of acoustics, you've talked to Stuart Hameroff, an anesthesiologist who's also
fascinating, fascinating guy, worked with Roger Penrose, Nobel Prize winning physicist who
dares to broach the question in physics, how do we see kind of macroscopic reality when it's
sort of supposed to be quantum and probabilistic?
And I think they present a very bold theory that might be right.
I don't know.
But it deals with this sort of, I think maybe the most underrated part of it is that there
could be some geometric component because there are pyramidal structures in the tubulin
and the microtubule.
Yeah.
Right.
Those maintain coherence.
Yeah.
As above, so below.
Right.
So you wonder maybe if like you're in one of these sort of mega structures, does that
somehow affect, does it, does it, if, if, if these things are maintaining coherence for
a certain amount of time while space time superposition is building up to the one graviton
limit, does that increase the amount of time so that you're staying in a coherent state
and then your perception presumably would be very altered?
I think that might play a role.
And like, you know, this is, again, it's such an interesting thing when you look at like
the, the, the bleeding edge of mainstream physics and quantum theory, and they're only
just getting to a point that seems to have been represented in the ancient past.
Now, I'm not going to say that they were quantum physicists, but they might have got
it from intuitive processes or maybe older knowledge, but it's clearly represented in
things like the pyramids and the hypergeum, this kind of acoustic technology.
And then like you say, when we get into what that really does on the quantum level, on
the level of microtubules and neurons, it changes us, it changes our perception.
And maybe like you say, this is an elongation of the process, kind of like drawing the process
out even longer through sitting in these acoustic resonance complexes.
But the pyramids are a weird one because there's a lot of different ideas and theories about
what they could have been and multiple make sense.
So it's almost like we're looking at a multivariate technology, quite a few different
things.
It's a really interesting guy that I bumped into in Malta, and I'm going to actually go
out and meet him in Cairo when I go out there next month, because he lives out in Cairo
with his girlfriend.
He's American, but he's lived out there for a while.
His name's Jeffrey.
I can't remember his second name, but he's got a YouTube channel called The Land of Chem.
You might have heard of it.
No, I've never heard of it.
Have you heard of it?
Yeah, yeah.
It's really interesting.
His theory on like how these were essentially giant chemical plants.
And because Egypt was originally called Kemet, and that's where we get chemistry from
and alchemy, like, yeah, like the buildup from that comes to alchemy and chemistry and
like, you know, Hermes, Trismegistus and all these like, you know, alchemical type of minds.
And it's really interesting when you kind of understand that these things were situated
around a waterbed at one point.
The Nile River was right next to them.
Right.
And then if we invoke these strange spiraling structures that they seem to have found,
it could almost be drawing water up and producing an oasis, right?
These things might have actually been agricultural nodes that promoted fertility in the local
area.
And it's really interesting.
I mean, his idea about it, because it even extends to like the dolmens and the hinges that
we find all over the world.
So they're all made out of like piezoelectric materials, rose quartz, like something high
quartz concentration.
And what his theory was, and I'll murder it because I don't know it properly, but it is
really interesting, was that these are conduits for lightning.
And the lightning would excite the piezoelectric materials.
And this would in turn cause natron, I think it's called, to be infused into the ground, which
promotes fertility and growth.
Right, right.
It's like a terraforming technology.
Like a type one civilization of a different order using holistic technology from the earth,
right?
It's so trippy, but that would so explain, I mean, I don't know, but it's like the,
why is quartz being taken from the Aswan River Valley 500 miles away?
Yeah.
It's crazy.
In the form of 50 to 70 ton blocks, which is just insane.
Wow.
And one of the things I brought up in my presentation, which is not necessarily about that kind of
technology or lightning strikes or anything, but just about multi-ton stone lifting.
There's a place in Lebanon called Baalbek, interesting place named after Baal, the storm
lord, Baal, you know, this like, and it's the Baalbek lord of the Beka Valley, which funnily
enough, if you read the book of Enoch, the watchers, right, the weird beings came down
on Mount Hernan in Lebanon.
So this is like this weird ground zero point for the ancient stories of these fucking wherever
these beings were, right?
But Baalbek in Lebanon is a quarry site where you've got three megalithic blocks that weigh
one of them's like 1,200 tons and it goes up to 1,800 tons.
Absolutely insane megalithic blocks made of limestone.
They never left the quarry, but 500 meters up the road, give or take, you've got this
place called the Temple of Jupiter, which we attribute to first century Romans.
A lot of the temple was built by first century Romans.
It's obvious, but the foundations and some of the upper tiers of the foundations, right?
There's a series of stones called the Trilithon stones, which are raised about 30 feet above
the foundation blocks and placed with precision.
They weigh conservative range, 800 tons each, coming up to about 1,000 tons.
The Romans bragged about their heaviest lift, which was the Lateran obelisk, which sits in
Rome, taken from Alexandria to Rome, weighs about 350 to 400 tons.
So even at a conservative estimate, these Baalbek stones are double the weight of what the Romans
claimed to be the heaviest lift.
They never spoke about Baalbek.
They never spoke about lifting these stones, but mainstream archaeologists will attribute
it to the first century Romans because they found the foundation and they built their Roman
temple above it.
So they look at it, go, Roman temple, it's all Roman.
What about those 800 ton stones that were impossible for them to lift with wooden pulleys?
No, Roman, shut up.
800 tons.
Yeah, 800.
And that's conservative.
They could be up to 1K.
Wow.
And to give you some perspective on that, you'd need one of the biggest cranes in the world,
I think it's called the Libra 17000 or something, to actually lift that with precision and place
it.
And we believe that they did it with wooden pulleys and ropes.
It's ridiculous and crazy.
So there are so many places around the world where it seems ancient foundations, Peru as
well.
Peru is like a smoking gun of ancient history and contrasting between what we attribute
to the Inca and what is so clearly megalithic multi-ton precision from a time long before
them.
Totally.
And even they will say that, like the indigenous oral traditions of the Peruvian shamans will
say that they found Saxa-Wolmer and Ollantambo, the Nazca lines.
There are no roads leading up to the lines.
No, sir.
No.
And so you'd be like excavating all this earth, but you don't know how or for what.
For what?
And then from the highest vantage point locally, the lines don't make any sense.
You have to be at least like, I think, 150 meters.
Totally an aerial.
An aerial, yeah, for it to make any sort of comprehensive sense.
It literally doesn't make sense unless you're from an aerial perspective.
So I was going to ask you actually on the Malta thing, if you have these sort of beings
with the elongated skull.
I was just down in Peru.
Oh, I'm so jealous.
How long were you there for?
Two days.
Don't be jealous.
That's not enough time.
Not at all.
Don't be jealous because I was in and out.
I got sick.
Oh, yeah.
No, yeah, yeah.
But there are these three-fingered, three-toed beings, the tridactyl beings or whatever.
And they apparently, according to these forensic experts, don't appear to have undergone the
sort of traditional head-binding rituals that you'd expect.
Right.
And some of them apparently have like metal inside them.
They have osmium and cadmium inside of them, which are rear earth metals that were found
in the 18th and 19th century.
So super strange.
You know what's weird about that as well?
It's I kind of feel like there was an intelligence psyop done on that very early on because Jaime
Musan showing those kind of ones that were absolutely fake, like the ones that were literally
just like bone and plastic.
I'm not even a...
Oh, yeah.
No, there was one that was like proven to just be bullshit.
But that's not Jaime.
That was Flavio Estrada.
Oh, my...
I apologize, Jaime Musan, for attributing that to you.
Well, because...
Well, this is...
It is important because Jaime's gotten so much flack.
Right.
And I'm sure he has gotten behind BS, you know, Hokuto in the past.
But I spent some time with the guy.
Right.
And like, he's just a cool...
He's like...
He looks at the fact pattern and he's extremely open about scientists coming down, like taking...
Yeah.
He spent a ton of his own money to like protect this stuff.
And he's very like boldly stated in a way where like he gets stuff wrong.
But he's like, it's real, you know, like that's...
Yeah.
But he...
I got no like weird surreptitious vibe.
No, but what I meant by that is like early on, before the Tridactyls, before these very
impressive large ones were really discovered, there was that little one.
So that...
So in 2023, so Jaime rolled out the J-type, which is not my highest conviction body type for
being real.
There's an M-type.
Those are like the more hominid ones.
The J-types look more like the kind of Close Encounters of the Third Kind thing, but they
also look reptilian.
The bodies look a little...
Yeah.
They look fake.
And so I wouldn't have rolled out one of those.
I would have rolled out one.
These ones don't look fake.
These ones...
These ones do not look fake.
Don't look fake at all.
And so he rolled that out.
But what you might be referencing is then at the airport, there's this guy named Manuel
Caceres, who's a local journalist, who made merchandise as a knockoff of that.
That might be where I'm getting my wires crossed.
And everybody got their wires crossed.
Yeah.
Because then Reuters picked that up.
And this guy, Flavio Estrada, this official archaeologist from the Ministry of Culture
that's similar to Zayuwas, man.
It's the same shit.
Right.
They were like, this is fake because of this like wood glue, you know, these things stuck
together, which are obviously...
Obviously.
And I interviewed this guy and he's like, this was art.
This was not the real thing.
And he's like yelling and stuff.
I repeat, that one is fake.
It's craftsmanship.
Constructed, built.
So what I find interesting is when you were describing your Maltese, the...
The heads.
That sounded so similar to honestly what I saw.
I was like, maybe there were some beings or whatever.
I mean, I don't discount it, man.
I really don't because there's so many references in different cultures and countries to, you know,
the times of giants and it's like, I love that in Genesis.
Like, not that I've really read the Bible, but I love that in Genesis where it's just
like, there were giants in those times and in the times before that.
Great, mighty men of renown.
Yep.
Anyway, moving on.
It's like, oh, I want to know a bit more about the giants, please.
But, you know, they don't really tell you much about it.
I think that there's a level of truth to at least some sort of interface with something
that if not giant in stature, giant in intellect, right?
I mean, you go down to like the Dendara temples in Egypt where you've got the light bulb,
you know, the kind of the classic light bulb.
I don't know.
Oh, it's incredible.
Like, you know, people call it a light bulb or a crook's tube because it's like this big
Atlantean style, like pharaoh.
And the only reason you can say he's a big pharaoh is because you've got depictions of
very little people below, like kind of praying and like in reverence of him.
And he's holding, you know this, right, Kurt?
He's holding this giant kind of like bowled out.
You must.
It's such a famous.
Maybe.
I don't know.
But it's like this big light bulb almost with a snake running through it.
And there's even like a cord that's coming back through it and then running along the
wall into like a box that's just like etched into it, right?
It's a very interesting iconography of, and it's not repeated around Egypt.
This is just in this subterranean element of the Dendara temple.
I've got footage so I can send it to you.
Oh, yeah.
Lace it in or whatever.
Yeah, let's do it.
But, you know, this whole idea of like intellectual giants, you know, like people who were just so
superior to us.
And, you know, you think of like Gobekli Tepe in Turkey, where we attributed that area to
just hunter gatherers.
Then lo and behold, this, you know, incredible ancient, the oldest megalithic temple site
pops up out of the ground and the mainstream will just say, oh, I guess the hunter gatherers
did that.
Yeah.
Well, that makes absolutely no fucking sense.
Because they did they get out of their deer high tents one day and just start erecting
multi-ton stone with astronomy alignment.
It's like a sundial.
And it was purposely buried.
Right.
Intentionally buried.
So I get the sense that maybe they were like, you know, kind of like survivors of that
pre-time, this cataclysm that I think clearly did take place.
There was pockets of survivors who went and where would you go?
You'd go to the hunter gatherers, right?
You'd go to the ones who knew how to live because you're just a fucking idiot.
You're an intellectual.
You've been preaching in Atlantis for all your life.
You're not someone who could like, you know what I mean?
You know what iconoclasm is?
Right, right, right.
Yeah, exactly.
Could Gobekli Tepe be iconoclasm?
It could be.
Yeah, I think it could.
Exactly.
And but it's interesting how, you know, this place is buried over and it just makes me
wonder about like, you know, the hunter gatherers of that era.
And maybe they were like, you know what?
We don't want you doing this again.
Look what you brought down upon this world by inciting the wrath of gods.
You tried to be the gods.
So they were like, I wouldn't be surprised.
They were like Luddite.
They fucking murdered these people and buried their site.
That's like, no, no, no, no, no.
We're not doing this again.
I wonder about that.
But this idea of like, instead of literal giants, giants of intellect for sure, I think
was the thing.
Stood on the shoulders of giants.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Right.
Well, I find this, this, the time we're in so exciting because I was just actually in
the context of looking into these Peruvian mummies.
I was looking up how many, like how fast these discoveries are occurring.
And so I was, I was doing this kind of calculation about like how much older has our civilization
just gotten in the last 70 years?
And like all these megalithic sites, a lot of them are like the last 70 to a hundred
years that we, I mean, archeology as a field is only 200 years old.
Exactly.
So it's almost, you should, we should come up with some law where it's like the older
the field gets, you're getting, the civilization is going to get older.
Right.
Like sophisticated civilization.
Right, right, right.
It's not like the Mesopotamia cradle of civilization thing is bullshit.
Yes.
And then similarly, I was looking up hominids and like we have 21 to 30, depending on like
how you, you know, categorize a hominid overall that have ever walked the earth.
Guess how many of those have been discovered in the last 10 years?
Oh, go on.
Five as your base case.
And then depending on how, again, strict you are with peer review and that sort of thing,
10 at the highest.
That's crazy.
There's a lot of them out there still that we haven't managed to categorize.
So many.
So I look at this thing in Peru and I'm like, I feel like, you know, I talked about this
with Rogan a bunch and I'm like, was I?
You crushed it, by the way.
You crushed it.
Thanks, man.
Well, I almost.
That's the hot seat of all hot seats.
And you did a great job.
I was fucking nervous.
Yeah, I bet you were.
I bet you were.
I was fucking so nervous.
Like when this came up, I almost, my self critique is like I was too conservative.
Like I, it got in my head, man.
I think, I think we found a new hominid creature and we're going to DNA test it very soon.
We're going to do another DNA test.
You found in Peru?
Yeah.
So it's in Peru and not because of me, but Jaime and my other friend is making this epic
documentary.
This guy, Michael Mazzola.
Right.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
This is not a hoax.
Good dude.
Yeah.
Um, he's going to, uh, uh, uh, uh, he's DNA testing it with these like independent aerospace
contractors that, and they're going to do some double blind stuff.
So there's no cheating allowed.
So I love, and that's why when people like, you know, come at Jaime, the fact that Jaime
is down to do this in a way that it could totally falsify, you know, everything is fucking
awesome.
And so I'm so pumped for this to just, you know, it's, I think the definition of a, of
a grifter is someone who wants to keep something in a liminal space.
I want it to collapse into true or false.
And let's, let's see.
I want, I want these things to be proven.
That's why I'm in it.
I want it to be evidenced, you know?
And I also think it's a BS excuse.
Like there's so many things to cover and there's so many anomalies in the world that you're
never going to run out of mysteries to talk about.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Let's try and prove some mysteries.
Let's, let's do that.
Yeah.
There's so many.
There's a backlog.
You know what I mean?
But you know, one thing, do you want to hear my weird idea about the greys?
Yeah, let's hear.
Like, I don't know if this would explain everything in relation to the greys, but I find it very
interesting that there's a lot of Aboriginal stories from around the world that seem to
be applicable to the greys.
And you see some cave art in places like Australia and even the Native Americans where you've got
these large eyes, these large heads and this depiction of them.
And there's certain tribes like the Hopi tribe, you've got the ant people and like these different
stories where they would come up from the ground and they would assist people during times
of great trouble and strife and geological trauma and famine and they would teach them.
Right.
And then you look at, um, there was a fascinating podcast that went out a few years ago where
these two guys got some Amazon, Amazonian tribesmen on the show and they were straight
up from the Amazon basin.
They only spoke their own language.
They needed an interpreter.
They were in the headdress.
They were fully, you know, of that, uh, culture.
And they asked them if they, uh, had any thoughts on aliens.
They didn't know what they meant by alien.
They were like, I'm sorry, we can explain that better.
And so they got a magazine out and they're flipping through.
They found an alien gray and they showed this alien gray and the Amazonian tribe and
went, that's Makunwabu.
That's Makunwabu.
And then they went into this whole thing about how Makunwabu is a human that became an ant
and it lives underground and it can appear in the divine light of Mishipan or whatever
it was, which is their version of the holy light of something.
Right.
And it's a very dangerous creature and it will take your soul underground and you need a very
good shaman to bring your soul back.
And they were taking it very seriously.
This other tribes and was going, yes, yes, yes.
Makunwabu, you need very careful with that.
And so my idea about this is that maybe, maybe there is a subterranean species that has lived
on this planet for a long time.
And a bit like the mycelial network, it went for the subterranean route.
It didn't get affected by the surface traumas that happened to us.
It didn't get reset by great fires and floods because they were deep into the ground.
And if that's true, you have all these indigenous stories of, you know, beings coming from the
underworld and assisting them.
Big eyes, translucent gray skin, no sunlight, large eyes to adapt underground.
Then you hear like the inner earth stories and also coming out of our oceans.
Right.
You know, these UFOs.
What if, just what if there is another and the missing subcategories of humans like you
just mentioned, right?
Yeah.
And in Peru, you've got a tunnel.
So what if, just as an idea, there was a species that decided to opt in for subterranean
living and has essentially been undisturbed since the beginning.
And they are really, really, really advanced.
Right.
And that's what we think of the ingredients.
So this fascinating.
Just an idea.
Could be, could be, could.
Who knows?
Throwing it out there.
Well, well, yeah, why not?
And when they are, they're very similar to us.
And in Kalki, which is the local dialect of where these, you know, in Nazca, in Peru,
where these mummies were found.
Yeah.
The local region translates to laboratory for insemination and hybridization.
What?
Yes.
In the actual language?
And you can see this.
There's a book from 2006 where that shows this or whatever.
Blow my mind.
Nuts.
So a part of me wonders, yeah, I mean, maybe there is some sort of guided, you know,
like maybe evolution is a locally functional theory via Darwin, but maybe there are, you
know, some, some artificial interference.
Other subsets of that.
Yeah.
Well, I think what would happen to us if we opted for underground, subterranean, dark
living, you know, your eyes, your skin, it's all going to change dramatically.
And yeah, I just wonder because obviously they seem so hyper advanced, whoever the greys are,
you know, either being in flying saucers or literally just appearing in your bedroom at night
or apparently helping tribes, you know, they seem to have a vested interest in us for some
reason.
Some would say it's experimentation.
Others would might say that they're actually, you know, caring for us in some way.
But yeah, the idea that this could actually be, like you say, one of those missing subsections
of the human, of the human lineage.
And they've just gone for that underground living and they interface with us selectively.
Have you ever read this book called The Coming Race?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Edward Bulwell-Lytton.
Yeah.
That's the favorite of every neo-Nazi, right?
Because whenever I put that out there, people are like, why are you promoting this Nazi material?
Because Hitler was into it or something?
Yeah, well, you know, and this is what got Graham Hancock in trouble is when he went out
and was talking about Lanzis, suddenly you had Rolling Stones and, you know, the independent
thing is a racist right-wing propaganda.
Graham Hancock's the most, like, boomer liberal.
Dude, he's got a multicultural family, for the love of God.
Yeah, Santa, his wife.
His wife's, like, you know, dark-skinned and, like, he's being called this racist piece
of shit by the media.
And at the end of all of his speeches, he goes, we need no nations.
And we're like, what are you, that guy?
You racist, my God.
But, like, you know, it's interesting.
Yeah, the Nazis were obsessed with Atlantis, like the top tier of the SS and, like, certain
elements of the SS believed that the Germanic race was a seed race that came from these,
like, like, Limeria and Atlantis.
And they had a term for it, like, the Hyperboreans or something like that.
And they would go all over.
This is what's so crazy for a lot of people.
It's like they see Indiana Jones, they just think that's a film.
That was a straight-up documentary.
No, Heinrich Himmler was looking for the Ark of the Covenant.
They were going through Peru and Nepal and Tibet.
There's photos of them with, like, you know, these, like, high llamas and there's, like,
swastikas in the background.
It's like, no, they were legitimately interested in doing that kind of stuff.
And the issue that you run into these days is if you try and invoke Atlantis or you try
and invoke Limeria and you try and talk about that, the mainstream will say, well, you're
just promoting racist right-wing ideology.
This is the talking points of the Nazis.
It's like, well, only because they found out about this stuff rewaging texts, man.
Like, don't lump in the idea of Atlantis with neo-Nazis and the ideology of that era.
That doesn't make any sense.
They just picked up on it and became interested.
But it's used as a way to attack.
And that's what happened with Graham, very noticeably.
No, there are always ways to bucket in.
I mean, Nietzsche or whatever was not necessarily a Nazi.
It was, like, a sister that got in with the Nazis.
It's just crazy.
It's just mushy brain thinking and ways to scapegoat people ad hominem.
What do you think about anti-gravity research and how far they got ahead?
Because that's one of the big, like, lines of law is, like, oh, it's German tech.
It's German tech.
Dude, I don't know, but I find myself, the Scylla and Charybdis, for me, are, like, the people that say there's nothing.
Because, dude, I'm so high conviction in the Townsend Brown stuff.
Oh, for sure.
And a lot of the, you know, Kammler-Stab was totally real.
And I think they were doing some really trippy shit.
Right.
I don't know exactly, I know way more fundamentally about what Brown was actually doing versus the Kammler-Stab people.
There's a lot of reason to believe, I think, Kammler-Stab was doing frontier interesting stuff that got, and that was part of the impetus for Paperclip and why we needed it so badly.
And that the Habermal side made it to Russia, but we, you know, needed to get a lot.
And we now even have Air Force documents knowing that Hans Kammler was apprehended by the Americans.
So I think there's something real there.
And then Townsend Brown himself parachuted behind enemy lines into Nazi Germany.
And there's a telegram from William Stevenson, who I mentioned earlier, you know, inspiration for James Bond, to Josephine, who's Townsend Brown's wife, saying that, you know, your husband is safe, but he's been injured.
And there's a photo of him in Catalina.
He's recovering.
Wow.
Yeah, a lung injury.
Yeah, so I think there's some weird connections there for sure.
And then the Scylla and Charybdis is the people who are like, there's nothing here, or they're posturing around it.
You know, even I love Eric Weinstein, but even him is like, it's always like hedging where it's like, you know, there's a lot of, you know, disinfo in the space and like, but like, look first principles at the Brown stuff.
Like there is something there.
So there's like this side where I like have to argue that there's something real here.
And then there's like the Ashton Forbes side where like, again, nothing against him.
And like, I'm down to have him on my show, like whatever.
But like, he is so sure that we have like teleportation tech in, you know, deep black circles.
And I'm like, dude, where are you getting this?
How can you know?
Me and him bumped heads quite a few times online.
And then he was at the conference I was at a couple of days ago.
It was the first time I met him.
Yeah.
We shook hands and became friends in that sense.
I don't agree with him.
And I think MH370 is fake.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
No, I basically feel the same way.
And I'm still happy to talk to the guy.
But like, so I feel like those are the two, the two failure.
But the Brown stuff, I'm pretty sure is real.
Yes.
I'm pretty sure it was classified.
And then to me, it's just a black box as to where that, what happened next.
And we were talking earlier about the disclosure stuff.
That felt like I'll fucking talk to anybody.
I don't care who they are, you know, what their past is or whatever.
The Brown stuff for me popped up.
It was like the most orthogonal to like all of the like shit getting like, quote unquote, like, you know.
Oh, totally.
You know?
Yeah.
Like, it was like, this came out of left field.
So, like, I know that shit's fucking real.
It wasn't like somebody came out and was doing like the circuit of interviews and like saying something.
No, there's a trail of receipts for that.
Yeah, yeah.
Absolutely.
So, I'm really high conviction in that.
And then beyond that, man, I don't fucking know.
And it frustrates me.
And I wish we could make progress.
I don't know.
What do you think?
No, I'm in agreement with you.
I find it fascinating.
Like, where do these stories come from?
Like, you know, the idea of like the Vril Discs and, you know, like the Nazi bell.
And, you know, what's the origin point for this?
Is it disinformation?
Is it a smokescreen from Western intelligence?
You know, during paperclip and like, right, let's say this stuff and we'll do this stuff over here.
Look at the right hand while the left hand's doing something else.
You know what I mean?
Like, I think that there is a hell of a lot of kind of smokescreening involved in some of these rich laws within UFOlogy because it's about trying to protect the technology and keep it away from people.
So distraction techniques that will send someone off on a paper trail that leads nowhere.
Yes.
You know what I mean?
And I do.
I wonder if, you know, if you believe I believe in non-human intelligence.
I think that is totally real.
I've seen enough of my own eyes, man.
Totally.
I've had orbs hover over my house.
There you go.
So that's a firsthand experience that you have to try.
And I am somewhat sympathetic to the three body problem narrative in that, like, I think science is much weirder than meets the eye.
And it pattern matches to revelation when these scientists have their discoveries.
So I wonder if they have their own counterintel for some of this science.
Possibly, right?
And it's disseminated in this slow drip.
And it's not maybe the Philip Corso clean narrative where it's, like, just based on metamaterials that reverse engineering.
It's more like mental, like, you get a download for a thing and then it gets, like, unlocked.
Where did that come from?
Exactly.
Yeah, I find that interesting.
It's not just us that might be doing the op.
It might be something else that's doing the op.
Well, it's funny.
Eric Davis, you know, went in front of Congress or whatever.
And, like, the whole thing was kind of this weird dog and pony show.
I think Congress is, like, sort of really dumb on a lot of this stuff.
Yeah, they weren't that good.
But my favorite line from his, and I have disagreements with him, a la on the Brown stuff, but, like, my favorite statement of him was he goes, the NHI are controlling disclosure, which I loved.
And that's fucking true, man.
I don't think, like, that's why, you know.
Well, do you remember Obama on Jimmy Kimmel?
And it's like, you do it with a smile, but what are you really saying?
He's like, the aliens won't let it happen.
They exercise strict control over us.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I have a crazy story about it.
Yeah, yeah, it's off time now.
Can I say one thing before you go?
My crazy story on that is I have a friend who I think heard from Eddie Vedder, the Pearl Jam guy.
He was at a campfire with Obama.
Oh, no shit.
And, like, everybody was kind of wasted or something.
And Obama, and he was like, dude, I gotta know, like, what's actually going on?
And Obama goes, read the three-body problem.
No shit.
Yes.
Wow.
And Obama's, now his production company's doing a movie on Betty and Barney Hill.
Yes, yeah.
And talk about predictive programming.
And they did the Leave the World Behind.
Leave the World Behind, like the grid goes down.
Like, oh, yeah, yeah.
Like, basically, the step-by-step to destabilize a nation.
Exactly.
Yes.
Go on, brother.
We got, we got for us.
Three-body problem.
Just wrap in.
As far as the impossibility of Fast and Light, I don't buy, or the dark, the dark forest thing,
that's some bullshit from psychopaths, serpent race people.
But the Sofans, remember the Sofans?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The Sofans.
They were using atoms.
Coming into the CERN and messing up our fundamental physics.
They're called Sofans.
Is that not the guy who told, what's his name about Atlantis?
Sofans?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know.
Yeah, Sofans told.
Oh, no, Solon.
Solon.
Oh, yeah, Solon.
But the Sofans, the thing, Mark Andreessen, in an interview with Barry Weiss, he said he
wanted to work on AI, and they go, no, don't bother.
We're only going to let two or three guys do it and do, like, you know, a state capitalist
thing.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And he goes, what do you mean?
And he goes, yeah, we classified a whole area of physics.
Like in a Cold War, no problem.
Now, in your school, the three states of matter I learned, water and steam and ice, but plasma,
which is the fourth state of matter, we didn't really get into that ever.
No, we don't.
And that's where a lot of secrecy lies.
And you did something on Kenneth's shoulder, exotic vacuum object.
Yeah, well, I mean, like, I can't really claim that I did it.
I've had some guests on, like, a pretty mysterious guy called Mr. X.
That's right.
Yeah, dude.
That was back in the day.
That was when I was first getting hooked up with Richard Dolan and Mr. X, who just doesn't
want to be named.
He's not a government guy.
He's just, he's a savant.
He really is a savant.
He did so much work on EVOs, exotic vacuum objects, and it's like self-organizing plasma.
And like, if you want to hear like deep dives into the technicalities of what plasma might
be, like check out my oldest interviews with Mr. X from like four years back, five years
back.
Like that dude's a fountain of knowledge.
But yeah, like the Sapphire project and things like this that popped up for a bit.
Like, you know, we're balling the stars.
We're doing it.
Bloop, gone.
Hal Putoff got involved with that project for a little bit.
Sapphire.
He's got his hands and everything.
He's always showing up.
Your story about the, about, first of all, Peru.
I didn't know you just went to Peru.
That's fucking wild.
Yeah, that was great.
That's where we get the name, you know, did they talk about Amaru at all?
Amaru.
Their god.
Oh, no, not too much.
The American he's named after.
Oh, wow.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Wow.
Yeah, Marigo Vespucci changed his name to be more like that, not the other way around.
Yeah.
Have you been to Peru?
No, my good friend is from there.
It's on my list, man.
I need to go out there.
You guys never want to check out the mummies.
Who used to tell me crazy stuff about it all the time.
I didn't believe him back then, because I wouldn't have believed none of this stuff.
I would be, like, dismissive of all the things that you're saying, like, 20 years ago.
Yeah.
I'd go, there's nothing.
Were you, were you, were you, like, a normie back in the day?
You're two degree.
Really?
I can't pick them.
I was a minister.
I used to be a Jehovah's Witness.
Right, right.
I stopped when I was 20.
Really?
I read the Bible.
Damn, you were a minister.
Yeah.
Everybody knocks on your door, you get baptized.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I mean, I read the Bible quite a lot.
What woke you up?
What took you out?
Yeah.
Of that?
Oh, pussy.
It was just pussy.
It wasn't any.
But you have to understand, if I believe something and I'm in a cult, okay?
And I call, the only reason I call them a cult is because you actually have to do the religion.
Right.
That's the only reason I call it a cult.
Right, right.
So my definition is different than a lot of people's.
I always want to be Catholic because you don't have to do it, you know?
Oh, that must be fun.
Just say you're sorry when you die.
But you couldn't have talked me out of it.
You couldn't have talked me out of it.
You could go show me all the evidence.
You don't leave the cult until it don't work for you the way they said it was going to work for you.
They tell you it's the answer to everything.
All the answers.
And then when it don't work, that's when you go out of it, okay?
So that's when I left.
Now, that thing you said about the underground, the ant people, and I didn't know they said they were sinister.
They did that.
That particular tribe did.
They were just like, don't fuck with it.
Okay, so this is what I'm talking about, metaphorical overlays, okay?
So they're underground.
Now, I think the little greys are some type of homunculus.
If you ever looked at Greta Thunberg, that's the evolutionary pattern of us.
Patient zero, right there.
Well, she's a completely astro-curved construct.
Why would I care about anything about her?
Because they made that.
Yeah, she was grown in like a World Economic Forum vat.
It's just vegan too early.
Born into a mold.
Basically, but vegan too early is the same difference, okay?
So they went underground.
So, you know these AI freaks, like that creep with the hair lip that made Little Sophia?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Little Batman.
Oh, yeah.
He went with Epstein to Africa to map kids' brains.
Of course he did.
What?
Yeah.
And he had this doll, a doll called Little Sophia, this creepy-ass doll.
It was like, to make him think about STEM.
Also, Sophia is a Gnostic reference.
That's right.
For wisdom.
Wisdom.
And it spies on your underage daughter.
It excites her about STEM.
It was crazy, okay?
Full speed ahead.
All these AI guys go, oh, yeah, it's going to be terrible when AI.
Do you watch these tech guys talk?
It's insane.
Yeah.
They go, yeah, first it's going to suck.
They've all built underground bunkers, you might have heard.
Yeah, they're ready for that shit.
Yeah, like the ant people you might have heard from those guys.
Yeah, yeah, right.
You see in the commonalities here?
Yeah.
There's a bunch of rich, high-tech people that are going to transhuman you.
You're going to be half an iPhone.
Yay!
And then it's going to suck, and they're going to go underground when shit fuds again.
Yeah, yeah.
And then they'll come back up and teach the rest of us how to live again.
Yeah, like, well, shit, dude.
Yeah.
So look for themes.
Yeah, man.
The details, I don't believe or not believe.
That, I don't know, nothing to do with nothing.
You can lie to me.
I want to know a new thing I ain't heard yet that don't make me bored.
Would you guys ever get Neuralink?
No.
I would never get it.
I interviewed the guy that got the first one.
Oh, yeah.
How was that?
Yeah, yeah.
Arbaugh.
Guy in the 60s?
Nolan Arbaugh, like something like that.
Because he had a couple that went loose.
Whoa.
A couple of threads that went loose, but he was the first one.
No, the real first one was in 1970.
Right, okay, right, yeah.
Leonard Kyle worked for Polaroid.
He was very jealous of his girlfriend or something, and he went to a therapist.
He was able to help him with that, and unfortunately, his psychologist worked for the CIA, and they
put a chip in his skull without telling him.
What?
Because Carlos Delgado has that.
You ever see the video of the bull, and they can stop its aggression?
They can make it nonviolent?
Oh.
Carlos Delgado, CIA, great.
And, okay, this is wild.
Mm.
They put it in his head.
It was a disaster.
And the microwaves that are beaming the shit to the head were giving him horrible pain.
He's a real smart guy.
Yeah.
It turns his brain to Joe Biden's soup.
Shit.
He ends up in a boobie hatch.
People go to visit him.
I'm telling you the truth.
He has a metal garbage can on his head.
Because even though he's crazy, he's smart enough to know it blocks what they're doing.
Right, right.
So, wait, ready?
Wait, wait for the punchline, dude.
The tinfoil hat.
So, then they started giving him tinfoil instead.
No shit.
And that's where we get tinfoil hat.
That's where you get it.
The tinfoil hat from the CIA mutilating an American citizen.
Whoa.
And it's a big joke now.
Isn't that funny?
Is that true?
I just told you it's true three times.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
So, I like to dress up like a clown and tell people these things.
Because they can't believe it.
Did you like my Hannibal Directed shirt that I wore?
Yeah, dude.
It's my old band.
Google it.
Nice.
Yeah.
So, tinfoil hat, a thing we mock was someone mutilated by intel service.
But they're going to tell you the truth about UFOs.
I'm sure they will.
You were a minister.
Yeah.
That's wild.
But could you imagine his fucking, his, what do you call it?
You know, you guys hit like three things that I'm like, oh my God.
It was like fascinating, like, hearing this shit.
Because I know a lot of this shit, dude, but.
Well, let's go to, we go to dinner, didn't we?
Yeah, we'll go to dinner.
Those little pieces, and I just, like I said, I don't care who anybody likes.
Right.
Or what do I give a shit?
I just want data.
Just give me data.
And I'm like, get that data.
Yeah, man.
However I got to get it, I'm going to find it.
I don't know why I'm obsessed with it, but I am.
I hate you doing that.
Yeah.
And so, there's, people are going to, as soon as you, who here, raise your hand.
If someone from somewhere like DOD, or D, what is it, DID, someone from one of three
letter agencies can maybe met you somewhere and go, hey, I just want to tell you, like,
you're about 80% right, your analysis.
Mm-hmm.
Because I've heard someone else.
That's happened to me a bunch of times.
I've heard it.
That's happened to you a bunch of times.
Yeah.
Did you get a nice 80%?
The guy said to me.
Well, I got told that I was flagged as a Russian disinformation platform by the DOD, apparently.
No way.
But they're still letting me in the country, so.
You were flagged as Russian disinformation?
According to someone who had, like, contacts in the DOD who said, oh, yeah, no, we love
Project Uni, but we can't actually watch it because it's been flagged as a Russian disinformation
platform.
I don't know how true that is, but that's what I was relating to.
I have a bunch of, like, Twitter bots calling me Russian disinfo.
Oh, yeah.
I'm like, what are you talking about?
The moment I open my mouth about Ukraine.
I'm going to buy a guitar myself.
Yeah.
I've seen you saying that, dude.
I've seen you saying that shit.
Yeah, no, I mean, like, you know, I think at a certain point when you talk about these
kind of subjects and you hit a certain perception and everyone's like, oh, he's controlled
opposition.
Oh, he's this.
He's that.
He's the other.
I've heard about you as well, bro.
So, like, I know the people.
Oh, it's all over Reddit.
What you learn is the way this system works.
Yeah, dude.
A lot of victim, I'm not calling anybody perpetrator, but perpetrators are victims as well of it.
That's how the pyramid system works.
Because the whole way it's designed is the compartmentalization levels are so that you
don't know anything.
So, people go, oh, he knows that guy.
I know all kinds of rich, famous people.
That don't mean shit.
Dude, Jack Krause, who I think is very good info, thinks Rogan's a honey trap.
Right.
Yeah, Rogan's called controlled opposition all the time.
All the time.
None of that.
You know it by its fruit.
So, what are the fruits of what you produced?
Does it go nowhere or did I learn from it?
That's all I'm looking at.
Yeah, man.
Well, that's why it's like Dark Journalist has called me that before.
Well, has he, yeah.
I'm like, dude, you are into the Townsend Brown stuff, and I went way deeper on the same
shit.
Right.
Where's the daylight between us?
If you can give me substance on how I'm doing it, it's just weird.
It's thrown out there pretty frequently.
It kind of is, yeah.
Everybody does it.
And I get it.
I get it.
But sometimes it's true, and then sometimes it's some keyboard warrior Reddit mushy brain
bullshit.
Which is most of the time.
Most of the time.
Have no ego.
You have to dissolve your ego to do this.
Yeah, yeah.
That's what they teach you in them things.
But that's another thing.
There's just too many people trying to LARP as spooks and spies, and they want to be,
you know, I'm close to the insiders.
I've got information.
It's like, you are the most easy to fuck with.
You realize that, right?
That you're so desperate to be involved with these people.
They love it.
Because they'll just feed you full of bullshit, kick you out into the world, and say, go preach.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
There's so many of them.
Yeah.
So many of them.
You've got to be really discerning in this subject.
And that's something that I've done as well.
I've made mistakes.
I've had people on, like, there was a DARPA dude that I had on, turned out to not be from
DARPA, because I got a fucking email from DARPA.
Yeah.
I got emailed by the security manager of DARPA, who was like, I'm really sorry to email you,
but we've just seen your video.
And this guy has never worked for DARPA.
Who is it?
Michael Moran.
Yeah, watch out for that motherfucker.
He's a Scientologist, I think.
He's just, like, out there trying to spread his, like, agenda.
But I was actually, I won't say he told me he was DARPA, but he was someone that I actually
did trust.
He was in the IC, who we've brought up his name on this show.
And he was like, oh, no, you need to get him on.
Whoa.
And I just didn't do my due diligence, got him on, and then, boom, turns out he's full
of shit.
You know what I mean?
If you cover this stuff, you're going to swing at some bad pictures.
You're going to swing at some bad pictures.
Exactly.
I've definitely gotten shit wrong.
The healthiest thing to do as a normal person is just to go, I got got.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm not perfect.
I got got.
And, you know, so many people refuse to, like, do that.
No, no, no, no.
I was being fucked with by the intelligence.
It's like, no, just admit you made a mistake.
Yeah.
You're doing real work.
You're going to get fucked with by intel.
You're going to get fucked up.
Exactly.
I don't care if you're wrong.
Yeah.
You could be wrong.
Who made up this thing you can't be wrong with that flicked people dipshit?
Exactly, dude.
Oh, yeah, the Nazis are going to come to Zeus and Atlantis.
Remember that shit?
Yeah, dude.
Like, you know.
That's an obvious op to smear you.
You're allowed to make mistakes.
Yeah, so I care if you lie to me.
Joe Rogan, who's not a scientist, he didn't make a single mistake about COVID.
Not one.
Nah, he was crushing it.
He was pretty right.
He was crushing it.
Okay, so all the people that talk about science to me, I want to know if you got your booster.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I want to know if women have dicks or not.
Okay?
We need to establish a baseline of sensibility.
Before you look down on a flat earth.
100% bro.
Tell me that women have dicks.
Oh, they do?
I guess anything's possible.
They're all as fucking crazy as each other, but, you know, I get what you're saying.
It's just we live in a dog-eat dog.
It's Hobbs Leviathan.
The system's set up.
It's how you divide the population to rule that.
But that's what I think the judo move is.
The failure mode on what we're talking about is caring too much about the disinfo or the intel or whatever.
Where it's like, the cool thing is to just be in your locally good positive bubble.
Yeah, man.
And just search for truth.
Yeah.
And just do your thing.
Well, that's honestly, again, that's why I've stepped a bit away from UFOs and that kind of subject.
Because it's just like full to the brim with intelligence, spies, and spooks.
And it's like, I find it really refreshing to be looking at ancient history.
And not only is there like an actual data trail, but no one's trying to fuck with me in the same level.
No one's trying to influence my stuff as much as they were when I was doing UFOs.
And I just feel like there's really good signatures in ancient history to say like the models are wrong.
Like there's evidence that the models are wrong.
Whereas with UFOs, even though I've seen, I've literally got into a meditative state.
And made requests for something to turn up and had orange orbs float down and hover above my house.
Which is why I created my YouTube channel in the first place.
Picked up a camera phone, put it on a tree branch.
And was like, hey guys, I'm a person.
This happened to me.
And then suddenly you get thrown into this world of like espionage and spooks and spies.
And it's exciting.
But you come out on the end of that.
And you're like, I didn't actually learn anything from these guys.
Like, you know what I mean?
Like lost.
Like KJ Abrams.
Yeah, dude.
So like, I find it refreshing to step into another subject where it's like, there's an anomaly.
There's something to look at here.
But there's actually some pretty good evidence for it.
And then it ties into the Anunnaki, the Sumerians or the Watchers.
It's like, there's a connection.
But this modern stuff just feels like it's been CIA sealed and packaged to send out to us.
There's a lot of that.
But push back slightly.
Go ahead.
Robert Hastings and the nuclear stuff.
Like, extremely grounded patterns of like these guys who, if you speak to any of these Q-cleared guys, they're not.
They don't have any counterintel background.
Yeah, no, not all of them.
I'm not throwing every single one.
You're not now, you're saying?
I'm not throwing every single one of them under the bus.
Not at all.
But I just feel like the UFO community is specifically populated with a lot of intelligence influence.
You have to be so careful who you trust, who you listen to.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know.
No, and what I don't like about it is it's like there are like channels that are seen.
Like, I always, the thing that's made me uncomfortable about this year is I want to off myself as some like, like, I don't want anybody to see me.
That's why I have, you know, Kurt on my show.
I have no respectability.
No, it's beautiful.
It'll give me a healthy taste.
A little refreshment.
No, which is a prophylaxis.
I destroyed your career today.
Fantastic.
No, no.
No, I think it's great because it's like you don't want to be the guy.
No, no, you don't.
It's the worst position ever.
No, you don't because then you'll just get shot down the moment you make a mistake.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, no, exactly.
And it's good to interdisperse the seriousness with a bit of fucking levity.
Take the heckle because just from being on stage, dude, if you're going to get your feelings hurt, you don't, I'm a clown for a living, so I don't get to have dignity, you know?
Yeah.
So what happens online, and by the way, it's part of the DARPA, we want to talk about DARPA bullshit.
Right.
To get you pulled into a nonsense spinning samsara endless wheel.
Mm-hmm.
That's very much like the cycle of reincarnation.
Right, right, right.
And you're in a prison and you got to go back.
All these spiritual things, hey, unified field theory is as above, so below, I think.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, no.
Yeah, for sure.
Because you can scale this shit up and down.
Yes, yeah, yeah.
And you can see what the picture is, but you got to look at other shit.
Dude, I read the Bible a lot, and me trying to reconcile all these different things, then you start to see.
And once you know who gets paid for doing what, you can start putting it together.
Yeah, dude.
It's not beyond you to put it together.
It's not.
A hundred percent.
On that beautiful note.
Damn, how long have we been going for?
We've been going for a minute.
Dude, my girl's mad.
She had an orb experience, and she's impatient with this.
Okay, okay.
Well, guys.
Dude, her truth is crazy, yeah.
It's been dope.
Jay Anderson, Project Unity.
Kurt Metzger.
Thanks, brother.
Yeah.
Dude, good to meet you.
Yeah, you too, man.
We'll link up later for a meal or something.
Hell yeah, we'll get dinner.
Appreciate you guys.
Yeah, that was really good.
Crazy.
All right.
We'll wrap it for a meal or something.
We'll catch you later.
We'll see you later.
Bye.