There was one time I jumped in to a conversation.
It was about the Skinny Bob stuff.
Oh, yeah.
There were people just talking about like, oh, you know, this video is amazing.
And I'm like, are y'all still talking about this video?
It's clearly CGI.
It's like a motherfucker, dude.
I'm here with one of my production heroes, Flying Lotus.
I feel like I can't even categorize you.
I have to call you a creative because you are an amazing director.
You make films.
You're, I think, one of the best hip-hop producers ever.
Well, you come from maybe the most kind of interesting musical family I could think of.
Alice Coltrane is your, what, is your great aunt?
Is that right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
She was like Yoda.
You know, she was like a Yoda-type person.
When I play it, it makes me recall Egypt, ancient Egypt.
It makes me seem to remember that I have a past or a history there somewhere.
She just had, she was tapped in for sure to the source.
Maybe this is something that we were, you know, connected to earlier in our development as human beings.
You know, maybe we were closer to God, closer to the source, closer to the stars.
You saw a motherfucking, like, frozen alien or something yourself, right?
Did you see that?
I might have.
Yeah, you saw it.
I saw a thing with three fingers and three toes.
I think Spielberg knew some shit.
And then he looked around the room and he said, and there are a number of people in this room who know that everything on that screen is absolutely true.
People would call in and they're like, we're doing time travel stuff at Area 51.
What we're thinking of as aliens, they're extra dimensional beings that an earlier precursor of the space program made contact with.
I'm here with one of my production heroes, Flying Lotus.
I feel like I can't even categorize you.
I have to call you a creative because you are an amazing director.
You make films.
You're, I think, one of the best hip hop producers ever.
And yeah, man, just an all around awesome guy.
And I didn't even know you were interested in UFOs until we started DMing, I think, on Twitter or something.
And it was, that was so surreal to me because I was like, I've been listening to this guy for 15 plus years and he's into the stuff I'm putting out.
What's going on?
It was pretty surreal for me for you to respond the way you did too, because I was just like, you know,
I felt like I was reaching out to a few people just to try to get some info and some insight on, you know, what people knew.
And, and you responded and you're like, whoa.
I was like, whoa, because I've been following you too, you know?
So it was, it was a trip and I'm, you know, I'm really excited to do this.
Same, man.
Well, you were asking amazing questions.
You were like, why can't we just get Lou Elizondo and Kirkpatrick in a room together?
Yeah, why not?
I'm with you.
It was like, why is that so hard?
Why are they, who's, who's not making it happen?
I feel like one of them would, would love to do it.
And the other doesn't.
Yeah.
It's a lot of like cheap shots from afar.
It's like, why can't we get Grush and Elon Musk in a room together?
Why can't?
Yeah.
Why not?
Who's, who's afraid?
Who's afraid?
Well, in my experience is usually the anti UFO side that it's like, they're hiding something,
they're guarding something.
And they probably put up that whole front, like, oh, I have no time to talk to these people
who are, they're clearly liars and all this stuff.
So I don't know.
It's kind of, kind of bizarre for me to like on the outside where you're just like, you're
seeing all this, all this testimony and you're hearing all these things.
And then everyone's just kind of like talking in their own little echo chambers and speaking
about it.
And it's just, it'd be nice to just have a round table with all these people, you know,
have, what's this, what's that cat?
Um, what's, who's the skeptic?
The big skeptic?
Nick West.
Yeah.
Put him in there, you know, put everybody up there.
Everybody.
Let's just work it out together.
Do you have any favorite UFO or alien conspiracy?
Oh, yeah.
I love, um, I love, there's a few.
I love, obviously, Bob Lazar's story is super amazing.
Yeah.
And that touches on a lot of the stuff on the shirt.
For sure.
Bob Lazar's story is, is one of the, it's like one of the gateway drugs.
It is the gateway drug.
Yeah.
Um, there's another, I forget the cat's name, but the guy who worked at Raytheon.
Eric Hecker?
Yes.
That guy.
The dude that said that we have a neutrino emitter and detector on the South Pole.
Yes.
But it also was the reason for the Christchurch earthquake in New Zealand.
Yeah.
Crazy.
And, uh, I love that.
I mean, I don't know if it's true, but I fucking love that.
It's wild.
It's such a, such a wild idea.
Um, and you know, I don't know how much of it is true.
I don't know what's real, what's not.
I feel like he must've been there.
I think there's photos that he shared.
He was at Raytheon.
Yeah.
He was there.
Um, but you know, he said a lot of stuff was like overheard, like water cooler talk.
Right.
So, you know, who knows what that even means, but, but yeah, Stephen Greer, fascinating dude.
Yeah.
You know, he hates you, bro.
He hates me.
I loved watching that episode of him talking to you, man.
I'd never seen him be so fucking mean.
He showed up to that.
Dude, he was like, he was out the gate, like not fucking with you.
He called me a dilettante, like four times.
Dude, he said a lot, man.
He said a lot.
Oh, if you let me finish, I'll tell you.
He was like, ah, look, I've been in this for 30 years.
He was like, you don't really know anything.
Yeah.
I'm like, okay, I'm sorry.
But it's funny though, man.
I, I, I, I was actually, um, on my way here, I was thinking about how, just thinking about
the community in general, because I've, you know, ever since I've started liking tweets,
all I get is UFO stuff, um, and my feed and there's like, you know, the usual suspects
who are posting stuff, John Greenwald and, um, it was like UFO Joe.
UFO Joe.
Yeah.
You know, UAP, he's amazing.
Um, but I always find the, just the, the auxiliary community so interesting.
Yeah.
Um, and I don't really engage with them.
Kind of a lurker.
That's, that's good.
That's a better position to be in.
Trust me.
But there was one time, there was one time I, I jumped in to a conversation.
It was about, it was one of those, uh, UFO accounts that was talking about the skinny
Bob stuff.
Oh yeah.
And like the, the skinny Bob video.
And I was like, there were people just talking about like, Oh, you know, this video is amazing.
And it's like, I'm like, are y'all still talking about this video?
It's clearly CGI.
It's like a motherfucker, dude.
I know.
I said that and people were pissed.
They were mad.
They were pissed.
They were like, who's this blue check I had never heard before?
He got a whole bunch of followers on.
Like he's sounding, he's sending disinformation out there.
Like, I was like, Oh shit, son.
Like people want to believe this shit so bad.
They want to believe it so badly.
And I feel bad now because we're in a time where like, we're making all these crazy AI
videos and all this stuff.
And it's just like, man, these people, they're, I feel bad.
No, it's a religion for most people that are into it because they're like, if this stuff
is real, it has to incorporate into some larger metaphysical worldview.
Right.
And then it's like, that's all that matters.
It's the only thing.
Cause then reality is not what it seems.
And then you see them get so argumentative and angry and dig their heels.
And if you hit one of the things that they're like sure about, and it's, it's one of the
things that's hard about the quote unquote communities.
You have to, you have to.
I feel bad for you.
I feel like any time, like after the Joe Rogan thing, I think I saw people just feel like
Jesse Michaels is like a paid and somebody fucking working for the government or some shit.
Like, you know, you're like the billionaires are in your pocket and all that stuff.
And like.
Yeah.
I think 20% of Reddit thinks I'm like a CIA agent or something.
It's ridiculous.
It's crazy.
Well, it's kind of shitty because not only are there like dangerous situations or like
seemingly dangerous situations.
I feel like I'm in vis-a-vis those people.
Right.
But I'm also.
And now I'm fucked.
Now you're fucked, bro.
Now these motherfuckers are going to come for me.
They're going to get tracked.
You don't fucking believe the Skinny Bob video, you dick.
I'm blocking you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But I'm saying that you get it on both sides when you get deep enough.
You get like the conspiracy theorists think that you're part of the establishment.
Right.
And then the establishment is probably keeping tabs on you.
And you're like, fucking A, this is crazy.
So thanks.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Oh, man.
Well, this is.
My shit is tap now.
It wasn't tap before.
Just be in here with you.
Oh, that's funny.
Yeah.
Well, I don't know.
Where do you think it goes?
Do you think it.
What?
Just the whole UFO conversation.
Do you think this ends with something getting unveiled?
The Area 51, a saucer and a hanger.
Do you think the president.
I feel like that moment right there, the president makes an announcement.
I always think about that.
And I always think about how many people be like, well, Trump said it.
I don't believe it.
Right.
More than there's the people that are.
Trump said.
Well, I definitely believe.
Yeah.
But I know that the weight of that is somewhat diminished in this term.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
It's something about it.
I mean, if he comes out and says that shit, everyone's gonna be like, well, why did he
say that?
Totally.
What else?
Well, we know already, but where's the video?
Yeah.
They show you the video.
It's like, well, it's AI.
Yeah.
Oh, well, I mean, honestly, you gotta be like, hey, they gotta be here with us.
You know?
And, and like.
It's gonna take so much, I think, at this point.
You can have the material.
I got this piece of metal.
Scan it.
Yeah.
You saw, you saw a motherfucking, like, frozen alien or something yourself, right?
Did you see like that?
I might have.
Yeah.
I saw a thing with three fingers and three toes.
What do you call it?
The tridactyl.
The tridactyl beings in Peru.
Yeah.
Dated from the Nazca period, where there's cave art all over there.
One of the, the bioinformatics genetics people found a mutation that matches a human mutation
that involves digit differences on the finger.
Crazy stuff.
That one of them has a fetus that might be tridactyl inside of it.
Yeah.
But eggs, right?
One has eggs.
Yeah.
So it's like.
But.
Yeah.
Isn't Jaime Moussan part of that.
Situation.
He's a known fraud.
So like, it's all bullshit, isn't it?
And you know.
I don't know.
I'm just saying.
And I met.
I spent a lot of time with Jaime.
I love Jaime.
I think he's awesome.
I went to the unveiling of that.
Oh, you did?
That's right.
I went.
Yeah.
It was like.
It was like down the street from my house, basically.
So I was like, shit, I'm going there.
I'm going to check that out.
What was your take when like on the spot with the, with the beings?
Well, they didn't have them there.
Okay.
There was a presentation like saying that they are, you know, they were showing the photos
and the, the x-rays and all that stuff.
Yeah.
Um, so it was a little hard to really have an opinion when you don't have, you're not
seeing it with the, you know.
Sure.
But I just take it all with a grain of salt.
I find it fascinating.
It was, I had a great time.
Yeah.
Met a couple of cool people there.
And left.
That's the move, man.
You, you have the right orientation towards this whole subject, which is like, it's fun.
And like, we'll see what happens.
Yeah.
We'll see what happens.
Um, I will say though, there's times where I'm like, nah, man, this is real.
You know, there's been, there's been those moments, but then there's been moments where,
you know, it's just like, well, of course it's us.
Yeah.
Of course it's our technology.
Right.
Why would they want to say, why would they want to admit that, um, you know, we're making
all these crazy things.
Anti-gravity propulsion.
Why would they want to share that with anyone?
I think the way to back them into a corner is you go as deep as you can on the anti-gravity
stuff.
And then you go as deep as you can on the UFO stuff.
And then it's like, okay, unless you have all these fighter pilots lying, then one of
these is right.
Yeah.
So I would think, I don't know.
I'm not saying the pilots are wrong, but maybe they're seeing Lockheed Martin stuff.
Yeah.
And I don't know the whole, um, what was it?
Jay Barber.
Jay Barber stuff.
Yeah.
But the Skywasher stuff.
That's really fascinating.
Super trippy.
Really interesting.
When Jay Barber came out on that, what was it?
With Ross Cullhart when it came out, man, that video, he was like,
talking the whole time.
Me and my buddy was like, all right, let's take a shot if he blinks.
This cat didn't blink at all.
We were sober like a motherfucker.
That's funny.
But like, but man, it's, it's, it's really interesting, fascinating stuff.
And I don't mean to poke fun or whatever, but I think it's, I mean, if you follow this
stuff, I really do hope that you have a sense of humor about it.
You need to.
You got to.
It's, it's just like, you know, you get so worked up.
People get so worked up over these things.
I can tell just by the tweets and seeing stuff.
Um, but yeah, people need to touch grass and be with families, you know.
Sometimes people get so heated.
I'm like, just relax.
It's all good.
Yeah.
You know, if it, if it is true, your life is not going to change.
You're still going to have to go to work tomorrow.
That's right.
Yeah.
Hey, whatever it is, at least right now is like weakly entangled with our reality.
Like we are, you got to still be a good person.
You got to pay your bills.
You got to do all these things that like, yeah, aliens don't really affect it.
You know how we're always diving into the edge of science and consciousness on this show.
Lately, I've been thinking a lot about aging, not just in terms of years, but in how it actually
feels in the body, slower recovery, lower energy, that middle-aged fog that sneaks up
on you.
I feel like I can barely go out and drink alcohol anymore.
That's why I started using something called qualia senolytic, and it's been a major shift
for me.
Let me explain.
As we age, our bodies accumulate what scientists call senescent cells, also known as zombie
cells.
These are worn out cells that stop dividing, but don't die.
They hang around in your body, draining your energy, clogging up your recovery, and
generally making you feel older than you are.
Qualia senolytic is a first-of-its-kind supplement formulated with nine plant-based compounds designed
to help your body naturally eliminate these zombie cells.
It's not something you take every day, just two days a month, but it supports your body
in aging better at the cellular level.
Since I've started taking it, I've felt sharper, lighter, and like my body's resilience
has come back online.
It's vegan, non-GMO, and grounded in serious research.
Experience the science of feeling younger.
Go to qualialife.com slash jesse for up to 50% off your purchase, and use code JESSE,
again that's J-E-S-S-E, for an additional 15% off.
That's Q-U-A-L-I-A-L-I-F-E dot com slash jesse, J-E-S-S-E, for an extra 15% off your purchase.
Thanks so much to Qualia for sponsoring this episode.
And like, I'm sorry if Ross Colhart really knows where there's a giant UFO, he knows where
it is.
I feel like there's ways of leaking that information that doesn't, you know, get anyone hurt.
I just interviewed him, and of course I asked him that.
Is there anything, Joe Rogan just talked about this, everybody talks about this amazing bombshell
thing that you reported on, you know what I'm going to say.
Yeah.
This UFO possibly found that they needed to build a bunker around that was like, you know,
a mile plus long.
Anything you can say about it?
I do not resile from saying what I've said previously, which is that there is a buried
or at least built upon UFO that was too big to move.
And that's it.
He did not.
Give me the answer.
Something tells me, you know, he might be bending the truth a little bit, you know.
I don't know.
He implied, and I can say this because he said this to me and it's coming out, he was
like, it's an extremely sensitive site that you'd endanger personnel on the ground, like
maybe soldiers or something.
So that makes me think like current war zone.
It's a very sensitive place.
That should be enough of a guide for you.
And to reveal the full extent of what I know would compromise the lives of young men and
women who are doing good things for America, completely separate from the UAP program.
And they're probably oblivious to what's sitting downstairs.
There's ways to leak information.
Yeah.
He knows that.
You know, it doesn't have to trace back.
It's come to him.
Right.
Ross.
Yeah.
Come on, man.
If you can really change the world.
Yeah.
You should.
Come on, Ross.
So that's it.
You know, it was like.
I understand his spot, though, too.
Because say he hasn't fully corroborated that that's true.
Like he's somebody told.
Then he shouldn't be saying shit.
Right.
He shouldn't be going.
Because he's very confident when he says that stuff.
Yeah, it's true.
So it's like, haven't you seen it?
You know, I remember when those, the Chinese drones were flying over and he was always like,
my sources say this.
And my sources say that.
Yeah.
And he's so confident about sources.
And then the sources keep changing the story.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Still.
Well, he just came out with something about the drones recently.
His sources did.
Yeah, his sources did.
Yeah.
He said that something about the drones being American military exercises.
Like, yeah.
Yeah.
So, I don't know.
His sources told him it was the Chinese, too.
Before.
Right.
At first.
It was like, there's some.
I mean, if anyone out there is really about to change the world with this stuff, I feel
like the powers that be might forgive you, might not go to jail forever, might not get
executed.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know, I think it's worth, I think it's worth it if you really got the goods.
Right.
Yeah, like.
Would you?
Would you do it?
You'd be the people's champion.
I would do it if I wouldn't be torpedoing.
Like, if it was like a person that was like, you will get me killed or something.
Like, I can't do that.
But if it was.
It was like, you'd be like Julian Assange, dude.
Like, you don't want to.
But Julian, look at where Julian Assange is, man.
But.
It's not a fun life.
Yeah.
The difference, though.
Right.
It's like, that information is totally different than.
True.
It's not like you're just going head to head with Mike Pompeo and the CIA.
It's totally different.
It's like, this is just pro human.
You'd be the people's champion.
Yeah.
I mean, people like Luigi, man.
Whatever.
Like, yo, that's next level.
You could play him in a movie.
What's that?
You could play Luigi in a movie.
Oh, I'm down.
Yeah.
I heard Super Mario Brothers were.
It was a very high grossing film.
Oh, man.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You got to pay a pretty penny if you want me as a, you know, I'm rocking my green.
I'm talking about the fucking guy who killed the.
Oh.
Luigi Maglioni.
Okay.
Damn, man.
Why are you going to throw that at me?
The United Healthcare Killer.
But you know what?
He's the people.
He was the people's champ.
You know.
For a while.
I don't quite know why.
I mean, I kind of get it because United Healthcare sucks, you know.
Yeah.
It's like, also, fuck that guy.
Not that he deserved whatever happened.
Yeah, it's a weird one.
I don't think that killing people is the way to, the way forward.
Definitely not.
With anything.
But, you know, in terms of making a difference and stuff, if you got the goods like that.
Yeah.
Like UFO goods like that, like world changing.
Come on, man.
It's interesting.
I think you met my buddy, Chris Ramsey.
We were hanging out in Austin.
Amazing magician.
Has an awesome channel, Area 52.
Yeah.
He asked me on the podcast, he was like, is it the logical conclusion that you will
be shown a UFO?
I hadn't even thought of that.
You personally?
Yeah.
Like, that'd be cool.
Like, I wonder if like Art Bell was shown, you know, Art Bell coast to coast.
Yeah, of course.
Like, was he shown a UFO?
Like, he had these things, arts parts, these little bits and pieces of UFO stuff.
I don't know.
And I wonder if he was ever given access to anything.
Because he was in Nevada area and like, I don't know, he just had so many crazy, crazy
whistleblowers back then.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
People think the whistleblower thing is a new phenomenon.
Like, then people would call in and they're like, we're doing time travel stuff at Area 51.
They know I'm running from them.
I just quit or whatever.
Like, people would call in saying this shit.
It was crazy.
I've kind of been running across the country.
Oh, man, I don't know where to start.
They're going to triangulate on this position really, really soon.
So you can't spend a lot of time on the phone.
So give us something quick.
Okay.
What we're thinking of as aliens, Art, they're extra-dimensional beings that an earlier precursor
of the space program made contact with, they are not what they claim to be.
They have infiltrated a lot of aspects of the military establishment, particularly the Area 51.
The disasters that are coming, they, the military, I'm sorry, the government knows about them.
And there's a lot of safe areas in this world that they could begin moving the population to now, Art.
But they're not doing, they're not doing anything.
They are not.
They want the major population centers wiped out so that the few that are left will be more easily controllable.
Discharged.
Well, this was certainly interesting.
We are now on a backup system, everybody.
A backup system.
And that one caller that I had on the air, I guess we were about in the middle of his transmission, his telephone call,
which was one of the strangest ones I've ever had.
And the entire transmitting system by satellite went down here, and we were notified we were off the air.
And it would appear to be from this end, and some sort of massive transmit failure.
So we are now using a backup system to be on the air.
And not that I would normally believe this kind of thing, mind you, but I can't help but wonder if somebody, somebody zapped us in some way.
Yeah, man.
I mean, look, if they got the goods, someone needs to say something, or else you're just going to get a bunch of the same stuff that we've been seeing.
And it's going to take a lot to move the needle, I think, at this point.
You know, everyone's, like, waiting for that movie with the Age of Disclosure to come out or whatever.
Like, that's going to make a difference.
It ain't going to be a difference.
Like, it's just going to be another, same people talking the same thing, ain't showing nothing different.
Yeah.
So, we'll see what happens.
Yeah, I'm curious, man.
I'm going to watch it, though.
What's that?
I'm still watching it, though.
Oh, me too.
It's a great movie.
Do you, will you help with the whole thing by making a movie about one of these stories?
Well, yeah, I would like to try my hand at it.
I get a little discouraged because I know old Spielberg's coming out with his.
Disclosure.
Yeah, he's going to do his thing.
I don't know what angle his is going to be.
It's a love story with Emily Blunt.
Of course, it's a love story.
They're all love stories.
Steven Spielberg.
Yeah, but what's the other thing you're trying to say?
Do you like Spielberg?
I would guess that maybe you're not the biggest Spielberg fan.
It's funny you say that.
Because I feel like you don't like conventional shit.
Yeah.
I love Spielberg.
Really?
I love conventional movies.
I love it.
When you can do the whole hero's journey thing well and it works, it's amazing.
And I'll be honest with you, a big part of my love for Spielberg is John Williams, though.
Oh, amazing.
You know?
I mean, the music.
So, like, you want to go back to, like, well, Jurassic Park is actually, like, top movies.
Oh, yeah.
You know?
Ten years old, seeing that movie for the first time.
I want to be a paleontologist after I saw that.
Yeah.
I was like, I'm going to change the trajectory of my life kind of movie.
But I think there was something about his movies with John Williams that synergy, that connection,
just really, it brought in the sense of wonderment in the film.
And it just made, like, I didn't realize until, like, last year.
I went through a Spielberg thing last year.
I watched all of the movies, all of them, because I was really, it was more so a John Williams
thing I was going through.
So, I had to watch all the Spielberg stuff.
But, you know, Close Encounters, I had actually never seen that one before.
Oh, wow.
And it was, like, perfect timing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And all the UFO stuff.
And I was just blown away.
Yeah.
And I saw, I'm embarrassed to say this, but I only saw E.T. for the first time.
No way!
This year, dude.
I love E.T.
That movie destroyed me, man.
That's amazing.
I was, like, I was watching that movie, like, as a grown man, but I was also, like, a 12-year-old
boy watching that movie.
And, like, the last half hour, I just couldn't stop crying.
It was just, like, just endless.
Just couldn't stop.
Dude, that movie is amazing.
That movie just destroyed me.
I could think about that right now and probably start crying.
It's so good.
And when he's biking, and you have E.T. with the hood on, and he starts flying off the
cliff or whatever, and the John Williams.
John Williams.
Things comes in.
And it's like, oh, my God.
I think Spielberg knew some shit about UFOs.
I think he has some inside sources.
Yeah.
Because you watch Close Encounters of the Third Kind.
There's some stuff in there.
You have the crates that say TRW and Skunk Works in the late 80s when nobody really knew
that much about those two frontier R&D.
Something was up.
He was definitely clued in.
And it was, like, it was some weird stuff, too.
Like, the orbs.
They had some, like, orbs that trailed after the big UFO thing.
Oh, I didn't even know that.
There were some, like, weird little, little, they were like, here we go.
Just right past.
It was, like, little stuff.
Like, it was, like, really weird.
The sunburn that he gets when the UFO passes over the mountain or whatever, which that's
really interesting.
Dude, I didn't even pick up on that.
Oh, yeah.
It's, like, it's, like, electromagnetic radiation damage, which if you, like, you know, Kit
Green and Gary Nolan, you know, CIA spooky stuff, they're looking at biological effects
of people who've witnessed or encountered UFOs.
It's the same stuff now.
And then E.T., you have the kid lock on with E.T.
And they have the same biorhythm and heart, you know, readings or whatever.
And that's, like, Jake Barber, where it's, like, he's locking on to the craft.
And then the final one, this is my favorite one.
You've seen Back to the Future.
No.
You're like, I live under a rock.
So he executive produced that.
Yeah.
So we've talked about this guy, Thomas Townsend Brown.
Yeah, he's a boy.
I love Thomas Townsend.
He's a boy.
Can't get through an interview without mentioning this anti-gravity, amazing anti-gravity inventor.
But in general relativity, time and gravity are related.
So his whole life, he's obsessed with time travel.
And if you watch Back to the Future, it's Emmett, E-M-E-T-T Brown, Thomas Townsend Brown,
flies on his flux capacitor, which is a capacitor experiment.
It was Brown.
It took place in Pasadena, which is where Brown lived.
That might be coincidental.
I don't know, man.
Oh, it's so rude.
I don't know.
And then it was the year that he died.
It was 1985.
And then it goes back to 1957, which is when he proved his experiment.
And it was powered by Mr. Fusion.
His experiments were powered by, he wanted them to be powered by nuclear reactions.
Now I want to watch it again.
Yeah.
I want to watch it again.
I think that movie might even, because if some of this stuff is time travel, that movie's
fascinating because it points to us mistaking the UFO thing for aliens, extraterrestrials,
when actually it's time travel.
Time travel.
Because the kid, I don't know if you remember this, but the DeLorean comes back in time and
it hits, it goes into the shed and the kid has a magazine, like a UFO magazine.
And he's looking at the thing and he goes, it has no seams.
It has no rivets.
He goes, it must be a flying saucer.
And then when Marty goes back.
He comes out like he's an alien too, right?
That's right.
It looks like it is.
So they mistake it.
And then when Marty comes back, his father goes, he's trying to get his mom and dad back
together so that he can exist in the future timeline.
And his dad goes, and he's like, dad, like, you know, he doesn't call him dad, but he
goes, you know, she really likes you.
Like, come on, get together.
He goes, I wouldn't listen to you unless you were an alien showing up in my bedroom from
another galaxy.
And then he shows up.
So it's almost like showing how we might mistake.
And then Steven Spielberg in an interview says, what do you think is more likely, you know,
distant galaxies, Zeta Reticuli, you know, Andromeda, you know, whatever.
Or.
Did he say Zeta Reticuli?
He said one of those.
I was like, I was like, damn, son, he's going there.
And he's definitely clued in.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I don't know if he did.
I might be putting that in his mouth.
Or he said, and he says, is that or is it us thousands of years in the future?
And they're keeping track and trying to, like, adjust timelines.
What if they're not from an advanced civilization 300 million light years from here?
But what if it's us 500,000 years into the future?
He said it with Colbert recently.
And he apparently said it to the Deadpool creator.
So I don't know.
You might know some shit.
He was in the White House screening room.
Yeah.
And Reagan got up to thank me for bringing the film to show him, to show the president,
the first lady and all of their guests.
And he just stood up and he looked around the room, almost like he was doing a headcount.
And he said, I want to thank you for bringing E.T. to the White House.
We really enjoyed your movie.
And then he looked around the room and he said, and there are a number of people in this room
who know that everything on that screen is absolutely true.
And he said it without smiling.
But he said that.
And everybody laughed, by the way.
The whole room laughed because he presented it like a joke, but he wasn't smiling as he said it.
I think it's perfect that he's doing this movie and you can get him on your podcast.
Oh, let's go.
How do we do that?
Reach out.
Start now.
Start reaching out now.
Well, he's a hardcore UFO.
He, he blurred, you know, James Fox, of course.
Yeah.
So he like wrote a little complimentary thing, like a review for James Fox's first movie,
Out of the Blue, which James Fox-
I haven't seen that one, actually.
It's from 20, maybe 14 or something like that.
It's from a while ago.
So it's like, just shows how hardcore.
He's into it.
Spielberg's into it, man.
That's wild.
I think it was funny though.
Spielberg was like, I heard him say something like,
um, he, he gave a lot of props to Denny Villeneuve for Arrival.
And he was like, yeah, this is the best UFO movie since Close Encounters.
I was like, damn, bro.
Like you, you really on your shit like that.
You really feeling yourself.
That's funny.
I think it's great.
Since my movie.
Yeah.
The best one since I did something.
Arrival's amazing.
Arrival is amazing.
It's incredible.
Do you ever read the book associated?
What is it?
Ted Chiang?
No.
I haven't either.
So I just want to, I have nothing to say about it.
Oh, well, it'd be cool if I read it and talk about it.
Um, yeah, but yeah, Spielberg, he's, he's switched on, man.
And, uh, James Fox.
How do you feel about that moment of contact?
That, I thought that was really interesting.
I think that's his best movie.
Well, I think the phenomenon, James Fox is amazing.
I love him.
I think he's got the best energy.
He, he's like the type of guy I would love for him to be the guy to film the first UFO
or find it.
Cause he's been, he was, uh, valeting cars and painting fences while he was making his
first movies.
He's so passionate and he just in it for all the right reasons.
He's so collaborative.
He just loves everybody.
So he's the man.
Um, the phenomenon I feel like is the best, like entry point.
Absolutely.
If you don't know anything.
I always show that to people who are like, what are you, what are you, what's going on with
this?
I was like, yeah, watch that one because it's like, it breaks it down in the best way.
It's like overview.
Gateway.
Best gateway.
Yeah, exactly.
And then moment of contact, I think is one of the best docs on this ever.
So, and it's, I love that it's so out of left field.
It's not some official U S government thing.
It's like these people in Virginia aren't lying about this stuff.
Yeah, man.
It's really, really fascinating.
I just FaceTimed him.
He's making moment of contact too.
Oh really?
Yeah.
What else are you going to say about it?
Dude, there's a lot of new crazy stuff.
New stuff.
Yup.
Okay.
Well, I'm curious.
Yeah.
Curious.
Do you think that more, like, it was such a revelation to me to see that you were into
this.
I was like, this is the coolest collision of worlds.
Do you think that more people in just general culture continue?
Cause I think it's on Twitter.
It's like you and father John Misty to me, like the cultural icons who are like peeping
into UFO Twitter and like liking stuff here and there.
I don't know if you know that.
I didn't know that.
That's cool.
Oh, it's really random and funny.
Yeah.
And he'll, he, he wrote like something like, uh, when I, when I heard Diana Pasolka say
that Chris Bledsoe is the new Paul Benowitz, I realized I needed to get a life or something.
That was just like recent tweet.
That's perfect.
It's like, bro, like you are deep in it, you know, at that point.
Also a dude from what?
Blink 182?
Oh, Tom DeLonge.
I mean, he's, yeah.
Dude, what?
See, that's your autism, bro.
That's your autism.
You got, you got everybody's name.
Like you're so good with names.
I watch you do interviews all the time.
And you know everybody.
The name was like, oh yeah.
I don't know how you do that.
Like somebody bring up some obscure book that someone wrote and you know, the author's
name and everybody who was in it.
And that shit, dude.
Like I forget everybody's name.
I don't know y'all's name back here.
I'm telling names already.
You got Sam and Mauricio.
Sam and Mauricio.
Are you lying?
No, I'm not lying.
I got that right.
Yeah.
But I find that to be like, that's actually super powerful.
That's my, first of all, it's a totally useless skill.
No, it isn't.
You don't need to have chat GBT.
You don't need memory.
It's a parlor trick on a podcast.
No, no, no, no, no.
It's always impressive to me.
Well, I appreciate that.
That means a lot.
That, it's funny.
It means a lot to Sam and Mauricio too, that you remember their names.
Yeah.
Well, hey, what can I say?
I mean, I think it's, I think it's my only skill.
After the Rogan thing, we hung out at the mothership at his comedy thing and my girlfriend
was there and she was talking to him for a bit and he was like, it was the best compliment.
He was like, Jesse's memory is next level.
And to me, his memory is next level.
Well, I mean.
Because it's like, he knows all sorts of crazy facts about all the, like, I'm in a narrow
domain.
And I probably have a decent memory on some of the other stuff, but like.
He's got diverse interests.
Yeah.
He's next level.
He's actually one of the people who got me to try DMT for the first time.
No way.
Yeah, yeah.
Really?
Back in the MySpace days.
Whoa.
He was, he was talking about it.
And I think this is even before he was like doing the podcast like that.
But yeah, he was.
Yeah, he was early on DMT for sure.
Yeah, he was, he was, you know, got me on Rick Strassman's book and all that stuff.
And, uh, I brought some DMT for you, actually.
Let's go.
Just kidding.
Oh.
I think this would be the most absurd environment.
Don't smoke DMT here.
Don't, don't do it here.
Don't do it here.
I would break.
But you should try it.
Maybe I will.
Talk about that last time.
Honestly, I don't really.
I've done ayahuasca.
Oh, that's right.
Technically, I've done it.
That's right.
But not the, not the fast acting.
Yeah.
Maybe, maybe check it out if it comes your way.
Okay.
Yeah.
Check it out.
You've told me some stories.
Hey, you know, it's, um, it's fascinating stuff.
I feel like my brain don't think of the stuff that, that showed me.
So I find it to be really, really interesting.
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
It's like you were in another objective reality.
Like, where does that, if that's not in your mind.
Yeah.
Cause you know, I always think about, you know, people saying when they trip, they talk about
like, Oh, I was, I was in Jimi Hendrix's guitar when I was listening to his music and all
that stuff.
And I'm like, Jimi Hendrix was nowhere to be found in this reality.
It was like really just stuff that I'd never, my brain doesn't go in this direction.
But it's funny though.
Cause I don't really recommend it to people anymore, except people like yourself.
Hmm.
I feel like my worldview is so trippy though.
I worry.
I worry that it was like.
Why are you saying that?
Yeah.
Like you're, you're afraid that like you're not going to come back or something afterwards.
Because I'm already.
So like my, my worldview is very different, I think, than the average person.
Cause I'm in all the weird shit all the time.
So I, I feel as sensitive as I ever have around like, you know, just keeping this thing on,
you know, straight.
No, I feel that.
But in the right set and setting, if it were, you know, to come across my path serendipitously,
I would do it.
Who would you throw a DMT with then?
Maybe you, man.
I mean, who else?
No, maybe you.
That'd be awesome.
Yeah, that'd be cool.
I wouldn't do it though.
It'd just be you.
Um, that's why Rogan got you into it.
Maybe, man.
It's, um, I saw he follows you on Twitter.
Yeah.
From like forever ago.
Like when Twitter first came out, you know, I could see him liking your music.
I know he likes hip hop for sure.
Oh man.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know what's up with Joe.
I, I find him to be an interesting dude.
Um, but as far as DMT.
Yeah, man, I think, um, I think you need to try it.
Yeah, that'd be crazy.
What's up guys?
I want to tell you about my new favorite boots.
These things are epic.
I've been wearing these everywhere.
They're called Brunt.
They're insanely comfortable and durable.
These things last for years and they're super versatile.
I wear them for hiking, for hanging out.
They look pretty swaggy if you're going out.
They even look good in work meetings.
They feel incredibly comfortable.
There's no annoying break-in period.
They just kind of form fit to your foot right off the bat.
They're lightweight.
You don't have to lug them around, but they're also super weather-resistant, waterproof, and durable.
Brunt is committed to making sure you're 100% satisfied with your new gear.
With over 500,000 customers already on board, these boots are the best in the category.
Take it from me.
Brunt makes the most epic, durable, and comfortable work boots.
For a limited time, our listeners get $10 off at Brunt by using code JESSE at checkout.
Just head to bruntworkwear.com and use code JESSE and you're all set.
Even better, Brunt lets you try all their products on the job risk-free.
Just go to bruntworkwear.com and use code JESSE for $10 off.
Again, that's bruntworkwear.com, code JESSE.
After you purchase, they will ask you where you heard about them.
Please support our show and tell them that we sent you.
The way it came to me, though, was so weird because I remember after hearing Joe Rogan talk about it,
I remember saying something on MySpace, just talking about, like, I'm very curious about it.
And then I was in Australia.
I was in Perth on New Year's Day.
They celebrate the day there this summer.
It was a morning party that I was at.
It must have been, like, noon or something like that.
And I'm, like, throwing down, played a really cool set.
And I don't usually, like, toot my own horn if I don't deserve it, right?
Like, it was actually a good set to play.
I was pretty wasted, though, too.
Some people, like, carried me outside.
Carried my big ass outside, you know, like, because I was so wasted.
And I'm, like, sitting out on the patio of this venue, and some dudes, just random Aussies came up to me and just, like, dapped me up and was like,
yo, I heard you just wanted to try DMT and just gave me, like, a fat sack of it.
And I, like an idiot, smuggled it all the way back to the States.
I did a whole tour out there, smuggling it the whole way and brought it back.
I would never do anything like that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But, yeah, it was some amazing stuff.
I've never seen any DMT that looked like that ever since, actually, yeah.
Do you feel like it changed the way you think after the experience?
You know what?
It didn't, but it was more so validation to the idea that maybe there is some more than this.
Yeah, yeah.
I think that's what it was helpful for, just showing you that there was way more going on.
Yeah.
Being behind the curtain, you know, and I think at that time, my life, I needed it.
You know, my mom had passed away, like, months, months before that.
So, I feel like it was really a way for me to connect to the other side and still be here, you know.
Yeah.
So, yeah, I think, again, I don't recommend it to everyone just because I do feel like if you are susceptible to, you know, schizophrenia or any of that kind of stuff, it could set you off.
So, do you feel like the pain of your mother passing, you say that it kind of influenced Cosmogramma a lot, right?
Yeah, absolutely.
Do you feel like pain creates great art and it can spur on great art?
I think it's a weird one with that is I don't know if that's real, but I'm just grateful to have art to turn to when I need to go to church.
It's an outlet.
Yeah, I need to, when I have to say something.
I'm always so grateful for that, to be able to create music whenever I need to go back to the source.
It's kind of awesome.
Like, when you feel overwhelming emotions, you have, like, a thing that you can just port it into.
Yeah.
And I think a lot of people don't have it.
They don't.
They don't have it.
I'm really grateful for it because, you know, in a way, I get, my job is to go to therapy.
Yeah, yeah.
Pretty much.
Yeah.
It's to just heal, you know, and try to understand more about the world and the universe and stuff and ask questions through the music.
It's a great job.
If you could smoke DMT with anyone in the UFO world, who would it be?
Whew.
Good question.
Man, I'd be down to smoke one with Bob Lazar.
I'd be down.
I'd be down to get big with Bob Lazar in that way, man.
That'd be fun.
Yeah.
I wouldn't, you know, I respect that experience so much that it would take a lot for me to do it again, actually.
I've only done it, like, two or three times.
Okay.
And to try it again would be a lot.
Yeah.
I wonder sometimes some of these UFOs might be, like, it's like, is DMT, like, you know, night vision or, like, infrared or something?
And if you were to hook those up to the optic nerve, you could see that.
And DMT is, like, another version of that where it's like a window into.
I think Jake Barber was talking about that without saying so.
I think he was alluding to that a little bit.
And I think that maybe some of the other whistleblowers might have, too.
But, like, I do feel like there could be some connection.
At least, at the very least, that maybe this is something that we were, you know, connected to a bit more earlier in our development as human beings.
You know, maybe we were closer to God, closer to the source, closer to the stars.
And I think that part of that was maybe seeing some of those places that you can access on DMT.
Yeah, totally.
And I feel like the reason a lot of people don't believe Jake's story is the reason I do believe it.
Because it involves this, like, mental connection.
And I think for a lot of people, it's like you are grouping in ETs or NH, non-human intelligence, along with psychic stuff.
Give me a break.
I'm not going to, you know.
Dude, I'm going to be honest with you.
It was a lot, though.
Yeah.
It dropped a lot on the day.
And it was, like, even for me, someone who was, like, I'm trying to be down.
Yeah.
You know, like, I was like, ooh, buddy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know, you're going to lose some people with that stuff.
For your second half of that story, you should have just stayed on the first half, show the egg, and let it go.
You know?
Shit.
Next interview, you could talk about that.
But, man, he dropped a lot on it and didn't blink either.
I was like, bro, like, go easy on it.
Well, both he and David Grush have this, like, googly-eyed, I've seen some shit look in that, in both of their interviews with Ross Coulter.
I don't know if it's Ross's lighting or if, like, they've seen some shit, you know?
And, like, they have that, you know, kind of, you know, like, I've seen something kind of gnarly.
Grush blinks, though.
Grush blinks.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Jake's got that.
I don't know about that, dude.
I was just like, what is going on?
Is he an alien?
That's funny.
I think it was a little chiller in my follow-up interview.
Totally, totally.
And I'm just talking shit.
I'm just having a good time.
But I have so much respect for all those cats, honestly.
I think it's, they're all, I think they're all brave to just even knowing how crazy the community is, knowing how crazy the stakes are, all this stuff.
I do feel like it's a level of courage that is pretty next.
And these people aren't media personalities.
They're not trained to be in front of the camera and stuff.
So, you know, we've got to give them a pass.
No, they don't know what they're doing often.
You kind of have to help hold their hand and stuff.
No, they're scared.
And they're scared.
And I see it firsthand because I often all get thrown in with them or whatever.
They get a lot of backlash.
Yeah.
Like, they got Randy Anderson, who, he went underground and he saw this, like, gauntlet thing that, like, emitted hieroglyphics.
And he was stationed at Naval Surface Warfare Crane in Indiana in 2014.
He was taken down a bunch of floors in an elevator to a deep underground military base.
And then he was taken basically through a tunnel past a bunch of skiffs into something that said, I think it was, like, off-world or off-planet technology.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard about this.
Was he talking to Greer?
He was talking to Greer before I met him.
Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I had been talking to him for about six months.
He was talking to UAP Curve, actually, before I met him, too.
Oh, cool, cool, cool.
And I had some inklings that, like, this year was going to be kind of crazy as far as whistleblowers coming out.
And I was like, dude, if there's ever a time, I think you should come out now.
And he was in Vegas and came down to L.A.
But, like, right after that, you have all these guys being like, he's not a Green Beret, and he didn't pass these tests, and he wasn't at war.
And it's like, I spent, I've got dinner with him the night before.
I spent a lot of time with him and his friends, like, hours.
And I've met, you know, two of his colleagues.
But you're a psyop, dude.
But I'm a psyop, that's right.
They don't, they don't.
Yeah, that's right, that's right.
I'm a psyop.
I don't believe you.
Yeah, well, there you go, there you go.
But it's like, you know, and his friends are like, you hear their frustration, and you see their DD-214, like, their background.
You're like, is anybody seeing this?
And then you have these people, I think it's fine, and I think he would even say it's fine, to go after the experience, be like, I don't know, maybe that was bullshit.
Maybe he was psyoped.
But when they, then they go after his, like, background as, like, a war hero, it's like, come on.
It's a lot, man.
It's a lot.
And it's, no one wants to deal with that.
No, and anyone, all these whistleblowers are watching how everyone's reacting to this stuff.
They're doing their research.
Why would anyone want to be, put themselves out there like that just to get picked apart?
Yeah.
And be called liars and all that stuff.
A hundred percent.
It's not cool.
That's not fun.
It's not fun.
But I'm optimistic after this Wall Street Journal article.
The reason being, I think it's really interesting.
They say it's all part of this Air Force hazing ritual, which is really dumb for the Wall Street Journal to say.
Because I think then all of the witnesses around UFOs and nuclear weapons, all these Q-cleared employees, all these guys, sue the government.
Right.
You know, or Wall Street Journal, follow up and show the program.
You're not allowed to do that to the American populace, dog.
Literally.
You can't do that.
There's like federal torture claims provisions.
So they're fucked.
Because I think it's totally fake.
There's no hazing ritual.
Or if there have been, it's been in little spots here and there.
That does not explain the whole thing.
So they kind of back themselves into this interesting corner.
I think that's the problem is trying to blanket all of it ever.
You know, it's like, I think so many of these things can be true, personally.
I think there's so many parts of it that can be true.
There could be future human.
There could be some grays.
There could be some stuff that we're doing.
It could be some stuff that China's doing.
All these things can exist, I think.
Yeah.
And it probably is.
I've been trying to figure out, personally, well, how I feel about all this stuff, still.
Because I go through this ebb and flow of just kind of being like, I'm always going to be fascinated.
Yeah.
But in terms of my own personal beliefs, I'm just kind of always like, ebb and flow with it.
Like, I'm really in.
Or I'm like, eh.
I'm like, back in.
And I'm like, I don't know.
So it's really something that fluctuates for me.
But I think I'm always going to be curious.
I'm always going to be following it, whether or not I believe it.
I just think it's all fascinating.
Especially because it's all playing out on TV in Washington.
And we're having congressional hearings about it.
It's crazy.
What got you into it to begin with?
Well, I mean, I've always been into sci-fi.
I've always been into the idea of aliens and stuff.
So I've never seen anything.
And if I do, I probably can't say anything because I'm like the least credible person out there.
Because he's like, yeah, of course Fly Lotus saw that.
Of course he did.
But no, I haven't seen anything.
But I've always felt that there is more out there.
And I've made a film about a couple of films with alien themes.
A few, yeah.
Yeah.
And I think when I was filming Ash, when we were filming that movie, Aaron Pohl told me about David Grush.
Mm-hmm.
Because that video, the videos of him with Ross Colhart has just come out.
And I saw that on my timeline, but I was just kind of like, I don't know, I'll go through it.
But then he was like, yo, man, you got to check him out.
I believe this guy.
And Aaron, I wouldn't have guessed that he was like really into the topic.
But, you know, I watched it and then it kind of took me down the rabbit hole, I guess.
Yeah.
But Aaron, you know, he's wild.
He talked to Bob Lazar.
He talked to Bob Lazar?
Yeah, he talked to Bob Lazar.
Aaron Pohl?
Aaron Pohl talked to Bob Lazar.
Yeah, and like they were like writing messages to each other.
No way.
I know.
I'd love to be a fly on the wall for that.
You got to get him on the show.
I would love to.
Well, I guess Breaking Bad is kind of a Vegas-y show.
Like I don't, I'm trying to think where that would even have occurred.
I don't know how the connection is made, but like he's a fascinating cat.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Well, Ash was amazing, man.
I loved it.
And this set kind of reminds me, I was texting you, I was like.
This is not a set.
We're in a spaceship.
We're in an actual spaceship.
Yeah, yeah.
And you have the coolest shirt.
Oh.
If you want to show it to the camera.
We got Lockheed Martin, Aurora, antimatter, matter reaction, antigravity.
It's crazy, man.
I have another one too.
Like the Lockheed Martin reverse engineering program.
No way.
Yeah.
It's ridiculous.
I think it's fascinating.
That whole thing, that whole side of it has just been like, just super interesting to me.
It's so interesting.
The reverse engineering stuff and how much of that, because there's definitely weird deception
and like, you know, psyops going on with aerospace.
And then how much of it is real?
Because there's a lot of evidence that there's something there as well.
Yeah.
So it's fascinating.
But it's funny that you said like, of course, Fly Low is seen in Alien.
Yeah.
When I first heard your music, I was like, this dude's in Alien.
Because I was super into like Dilla and Pete Rock and DJ Premier, all these like 90s hip hop producers.
And then you came on the scene and I think it might've been around your album, Cosmogramma or Los Angeles, like 08, you know, 2010 era.
And I just, I saw you play actually with Thundercat in New York.
And I remember, cause like Dilla would mess people up because his stuff wasn't quantized.
And then I remember hearing your stuff and I was like, this guy's on another planet.
Like, this is crazy.
Hey, well, you know, they made it okay.
They made it okay for us to go there.
Yeah.
So.
Well, you took it to the next level.
Hey, well, hey, doing my part, doing my part.
Yeah.
But, you know, it's, it's funny though, because I got, you know, just like everybody else, probably I got a lot of flack in the beginning for doing my thing.
You know, and being, being that person, like I keep bringing this up lately because it's so bizarre to people.
But like back when I was first getting on and the scene, like around like what, 2004, um, I get a lot of shit.
Can I say shit?
I'm a person.
Yeah, you can say shit.
Oh yeah, yeah.
As much as you want.
I used to get a lot of shit for using a computer to make music.
Really?
Back in that, back in the day.
Instead of an MPC.
Yeah, you had to have an MPC, you know, or, or SP or something like that, or else you wasn't making hip hop.
You was making techno or computer music or whatever.
They was just like, there's no way, there's no way you can, you ain't, there ain't no swing in that computer.
You can't swing with that.
So it made me more determined to, to like really get in there and get the sounds and to try different stuff.
And, and I actually was, was really encouraged earlier on in my development to, you know, just to do the other thing, just to try and go in different directions.
And so I owe a lot to the people around me really who supported me to just like not do, not to do what everyone else was doing at the time.
Well, you come from maybe the most kind of interesting musical family I could think of.
Alice Coltrane is your, what is your great aunt?
Is that right?
And then, uh, Marilyn McLeod is your grandmother and she, she wrote love hangover.
And she also wrote, uh, I get hot or I get high as the styles P, um, uh, uh, Swiss beats sample.
Uh, but it's, it's no, it's, it is.
I get high too.
Right.
Yeah.
The original free to paint.
She wrote that as well.
So you just come from amazing, you know, family when it comes to this stuff.
They still was looking at me like I was crazy though.
And I was like, why does shit sound like some garbage, hitting on some garbage cans?
You know, like why, what is, what is this?
And, uh, I was like, but you guys are crazy too.
What are you talking about?
Um, but yeah, I had to find, find my way.
Just like, um, just like we all do.
It is true.
Your, your drums, I think set you apart.
So it's like that plus the crazy synths, like the, like sounded like it was like you, you leaned into the computer thing.
Yeah.
And it was like that plus the drums, which, you know, it was like, yeah, it was like garbage, like back alley, like crazy.
And it was like, oh my God, this is crazy.
Yeah.
Well, yeah, just, just went for it, man.
Just went for it.
Um, a lot of support from, from my grandmother though.
Um, she was the first person to put a machine in my hands.
You know, she had was the, the six, six Oh six, the T TV six Oh six or something like that.
Like one of them drum machines with like, you know, those weird analog sounds and stuff in there.
And she was just like, here, take it.
I was just making drum beats and stuff when I was really young.
And that was kind of what, what set me up.
And then just being around different family, like my cousin, he was making music on a Mac to CI, like old, old Mac.
Like back when that was like super foreign to record on.
And, um, you know, I was watching him while I'm playing Sonic the Hedgehog.
Like he's like making stuff that sounded like Prince and stuff.
And like, I was just always surrounded by music and always surrounded by people trying to make stuff.
That makes sense.
You played Sonic the Hedgehog.
Cause it, I feel like it's that Sega, like wave racer vibe.
Oh man, no doubt.
And those loops, man, they still in my head, man.
You know, I still, I still be sampling Sonic too.
Still to this day.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
So was Alice an inspiration for you early on?
My aunt Alice was such an inspiration, but I feel like my appreciation for her and her music grew, grew over time.
You know, like when I was, I feel like kind of in high school, all the stuff started to make more sense to me and I was really starting to see it.
But then when I went to college and really started like vibing there and like, you know, trying mushrooms and stuff and like, you know, leaving my brain and stuff, I'm like, oh, I get it for real now.
You know, it was really starting to make sense.
And, um, and I had just the deepest appreciation for it.
But, you know, I'm still to this day, like, I feel like every other year I'll go back and listen to music that she made and just be like, whoa, what was she doing?
How did she do that?
Why, why did she do that?
That was a weird choice.
Great choice.
But, you know, like, I'm still, still picking it apart after all these years.
And you said she never saw her practice.
I never saw her practice.
That's crazy.
Never in my, in my entire, and I, you know, she was like the Coltrane side.
The, they're like the closest family to me in LA.
And, um, so I spent a lot of time over there.
I, you know, I went to this, to the school right by their house.
So I walked from school to hang out over there all the time.
And, you know, I would see them very often.
I never saw her practice.
Never.
And, um, I remember when I, one time when I was like, maybe like 10, 11 years old, I went over to the house and she had a beautiful piano, beautiful grand Steinway piano.
Um, surrounded by, you know, her harp and all these amazing instruments.
I went in there and I was like, hey, can I go play your piano?
Yeah.
She was like, well, are you going to play it?
I was like, I don't, I don't know, actually.
What do you think she meant by that?
She meant, am I going to get down, dude?
Like, don't mess around, you know?
Like, don't go in there, like, messing around on my piano.
You're going to go in there and play it.
You can go play it, but you better play.
So I was like, I took that like, so I didn't do it.
I never, I never touched that thing ever.
And she was very kind of spiritually tapped in as well, right?
Oh man, yeah, she was the most, she was the most tapped in.
I would say, yeah, there was a lot of influence, but I guess it would be more non-denominational leaning.
But, but yeah, a lot of, a lot of influence there.
Definitely.
Yeah.
She's amazing.
I mean, just hearing, what's it, I think it was Turiya and Ramakrishna.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's like that old blues kind of vibe.
And it's just so beautiful.
It's like ethereal and beautiful.
And you're like, where is this coming from?
It's amazing.
It's wild because it can always be, you can always hear the blues and then it just goes to some other, just crazy places.
And I remember being with her in, in Paris once she, she had me come with her and, and Ravi, they play the show in Paris toward the end of her life.
And, um, I just remember just hearing her, you know, she was like a, she was like Yoda.
You know, she was like a Yoda type person where she was like real, she was really tiny and, you know, moved very slowly, very gentle with everything.
But, you know, she just, when she went on that piano, boom, was busting out all crazy, you know, like, who is this person?
And it was like, even, even Rodney, her son, she was like, whoa, what is going on?
You know?
So like, she just had, she was tapped in for sure to the, to the source.
Well, John was tapped in as well.
I mean, I think he might be like at least top three, maybe favorite jazz musician of all time.
Are you a fan of his as well?
Absolutely.
And, and I think, I think I was a fan of his first.
And it was, it's funny because when I was growing up and I would, people would want to talk to my aunt and be around people who want to talk to her.
I always want to talk to her about John Coltrane.
All I want to talk to her about is like, what was it like being around John Coltrane?
What was he like?
And she would always answer very humbly.
And, you know, and then now it's like everyone wants to talk about Alice Coltrane.
And it's, it's really awesome to see that, just to see the turn happen.
But I, I do wish she, that she was here to, to see her, her influence, um, in the way, because I feel like now I'm hearing way more about her than him.
Even though he's, you know, I go to sushi restaurant, it's always John Coltrane playing, you know what I'm saying?
But like, I just feel like the, the young, the young folks around are, are really vibing on our music right now.
And it's really cool to see.
Absolutely.
Well, she really, I think just pushed the envelope and experimented.
Obviously he was amazing too.
Yeah.
Um, that is cool to see.
And it's interesting how music kind of like your UFO interest ebbs and flows and changes.
And how do you feel like, do you feel like it's in an interesting place right now?
Do you feel like it's in a weird place?
Like what music, music in general, is that even a, is that even a question you can ask or is it just, it is what it is?
You know, as far as the industry and all that stuff, I, I can separate it and think about it in terms of like the actual music itself.
And there's always some good stuff going on.
Always.
Always interesting.
You just got to look for it.
Yeah.
You got to seek it out.
But, you know, if you're only going to listen to what the charts are telling you, then you're probably going to be thinking it's, it's all the same.
It's definitely weird that it's now filtered by, is the person a good social media personality?
Absolutely.
That's weird to me.
And like the numbers, like people, people even see like, okay, well, they only have certain amount of listeners on Spotify.
So they're probably not that good.
Yeah.
They're probably not that great.
They only got like 10,000 listeners every month.
So they're probably, eh.
Right.
It's this like infinite force ranking of everything.
Absolutely.
Everything's a beauty contest.
Oh, dude.
Yeah.
And I feel like in the past 10 years, you know, the, the numbers thing really got into the fandoms of rappers and stuff.
Like, you know, first week sales and stuff.
Like people are like, kids are talking about rappers first week sales, like selling what?
What are people selling anymore?
Like y'all buying records and stuff?
Like what is, what is, it's just, it's super weird that that's actually part of the conversation in terms of like, is something good or interesting?
Like, it's like, what are they selling?
How are, how much are they moving?
How many units are they moving?
Yeah, right.
Like, it's like old barbershop conversation or something that has just now become like a very, very popular bit of a conversation, unfortunately.
Well, you started an amazing record label, Brain Feeder.
Do you feel like, and I didn't even realize some of the people you had signed.
Yeah.
I was independently fans of and doing research for this.
Oh, I like that.
I was like, I like, like who?
I was like, Taylor McFerrin.
Like, I was like, I was like, of course he signed in like, it's like similar drums and like.
Of course you'd be into Taylor McFerrin.
Oh, I love like that.
When I first heard, I think it was Degrees of Light.
I was like, wow, like, this is crazy.
Like, what is that?
It reminded me of you a little bit.
And Daedalus.
Daedalus.
Yeah.
And I'm trying to think.
There were a couple others on there where I was like, damn, I didn't even know you guys had worked together.
Yeah.
Brain Feeder has been going for a minute, man.
It's been going for a minute.
And it's, it's something that I'm actually really, really proud of because it's, it's, you know, something that is kind of flourishing on a, on its own at this point, you know, and I'm still doing a lot of work with Brain Feeder and curating and, you know, the A&R side.
But, you know, that, that's like a, it's a machine that's moving and it's awesome to see.
And maybe through that, you can fight back a little bit where it's like, I don't care if you have 10,000 weekly streams or whatever.
Like, I love it.
You know, it puts you on.
Absolutely.
And, um, you know, it's, it's become a thing where it's, there's a lot of risk in the personal sense because I want to do right by the artists.
But as far as everything else, there's no risk for me.
You know, I'm not trying to make money there.
I'm not, it's really not my source of income like that.
It is, but it's not, you know, at the same time.
So I just was like, it's, it's my, a passion project.
But like, I've been so grateful to be able to see all these different artists flourish and have their careers and, you know, they're doing their thing.
Yeah.
Being there.
Super cool.
Is there anybody you're into now that the public probably doesn't know about?
Oh yeah, absolutely.
Um, there's a, there's an artist just named Thing.
Okay.
Just Thing.
I love it.
Drum and bass, some drum and bass, like classic drum and bass, but sometimes we'll mix up some like, some like, um, UK, like two-step, you know, kind of garage, UK garage kind of vibe.
Um, you know, smaller following.
Uh-huh.
Doesn't matter.
Don't care.
But like, I'd be in the gym.
It's like, ah, da, da, da.
I don't want to listen to Amen breaks and stuff.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
So it'd be, it's kind of random, but, um, and the cat puts out stuff like every week.
It's pretty crazy.
I know.
It's.
Thing.
Yeah.
Go check out then.
Thing is dope.
Yeah.
Sick, man.
And you've worked with some of the most legendary artists like ever.
Yeah, man.
Yeah.
I mean, one of the guys I feel like you're just probably friends first and then collaborators second is Thundercat, who I saw you live with in New York.
Yeah, yeah.
Um, he's amazing, man.
He's so awesome.
And he, he credits you for having helped give him a voice and cause he was just playing bass primarily.
Right.
And you kind of helped him out and you were like, look, man, you should just sing over your, over your tracks.
Is that right?
Yeah.
He was doing some oohs and ahs on stuff and I was like, what's going on?
You know, let's do it.
And, and then there was one day I'll never forget.
And I think about it all the time.
We were sitting in my apartment, my sweaty apartment in Northridge.
Um, and he just, you know, we were working on some music.
I had these like, like portable, portable lunch tables.
They're like, they're like, uh, you know, the classic picnic tables or whatever.
That's what I had all my, my gear set up on.
And it was like surrounded by all these like medicinal marijuana jars.
And it was, yeah, he just looks over at me and he was like, man, I want to be your artist.
And I, I was like, yeah, what does that even mean?
You know what I mean?
Like, what does that even mean?
I've never, I've never done that sort of thing before.
And, um, yeah, we've just been going at it, man, ever since we've just been going for it.
And it's, it's been awesome to see.
And, and honestly, something that I take so much pride in aside from my own work is, you know, just seeing how his music and his message and his influences affected the world.
Yeah.
You see, he's another guy who like, you know, back in the day, I think was always respected, like as a, almost like an artist, artist where it was like, he's amazing on the bass.
And then like in the last five years, I feel like people are just like, everybody knows who Thundercat is, which is so cool to see.
Yeah.
I was, I was randomly at dinner and they're, they're playing his music just randomly, you know, and it just comes along.
I'm like, let's go.
Yeah.
I love it.
Is he into the alien stuff?
Like I could see, he seems like such a, like a fun kind of goofy personality.
Like I could see him being in the, you know, I feel like he's, you know, he's kind of like come over the house and I got like some weird alien YouTube videos on and I'm like, I turn them off real quick.
Like, I'm not watching any of that stuff.
I don't know.
But I don't think he's really into it.
Okay.
I don't think he's super into the stuff.
But, you know, because he's probably an alien.
Yeah.
He doesn't want to be exposed, you know?
Exactly.
He doesn't want to like the exposure.
Or maybe you'd act into it like you.
You never know.
Maybe.
We might be, you know, it might be walking among us.
Right, right, right, right.
Maybe.
I want to list some artists and you've either collaborated with them or you might have something to say about them.
I want to get just one sentence about each of these guys.
Jay Dilla.
Oof.
Man.
Um...
One of the greatest ever.
Very grateful to have met him a couple times close to the end of his life.
I feel like I saw him maybe a week or two before he passed away.
It's crazy.
I delivered a check to his house.
Yeah, let's tell that.
You told me this.
It's so crazy.
I used to work at Stone's Throw back in the day.
And he...
Were you like...
You were like...
I was an intern.
Intern.
Yeah, I was an intern there.
Um...
A paid intern.
Okay.
I was working there long enough that I had to start kicking me down a little bit.
Um...
But, um...
Yeah, I was there and, uh...
Yeah, he was finishing up the donut stuff.
That was happening.
Mad Lib Sound Directions is...
He was doing that.
It was like...
He started...
Mad Lib starting to play drums live and stuff.
And that was kind of like the time I was there.
Um...
And yeah, they were...
They were finishing up some business and they sent me over to the house.
Like, yo, um...
You might see something over there.
Just, you know, be cool.
Because he wasn't in really good shape.
Yeah.
You know, toward the end.
He had like a blood disorder or blood cancer or something?
Uh...
Lupus.
And...
And I don't know what else.
Yeah.
But something else.
I think something else was going on too.
But, um...
But yeah, I was...
I got to see him.
The machines were still on.
You know?
He was in a wheelchair.
He looked really bad, man.
I cried after I left there.
I was like...
I was fully in tears just because...
Not only because of what I saw, but just because I still felt the energy.
I still felt the power still.
I still felt the force.
It was strong still.
Man, it was really strong even toward the end.
And it was, um...
It was really, really, um...
It was a lot.
But I was very impressed that even then, you know, everything was still lit up.
Like, it was still working on some shit.
Was he good energy?
Was he...
Oh, it was great.
Yeah.
It was great.
I mean, you know, I could tell he didn't want anyone to see him like that.
Yeah.
And that was the thing, too.
It was like...
I didn't even really want to look him in the eye, bro.
Just because I could just tell he didn't...
But he still was, like, holding it together.
Yeah.
And he was at Common's house, right?
That was Common's house, yeah.
I think they were...
Yeah, they were living together.
But, yeah.
Wow.
And his mom was taking care of him around him, too.
Yeah.
Yeah, you listen to some of those tracks.
Like, that, um...
Isley Brothers sample, Don't Say Goodbye.
So you call it Bye or whatever.
And you're like, oh, my God.
He's, like, saying goodbye.
And it's so ethereal.
It's so, like...
Yeah.
It was a lot.
Or Donuts of the Heart, that Jackson 5 sample.
Mm-hmm.
It's like...
Yeah.
When I was there, I think it was finishing up The Shining.
The Shining stuff was happening.
Okay.
Donuts was already done.
Oh.
And by then, we were already, like, hearing all that stuff in the office.
Wow.
And, you know, we were getting, like, donut deliveries, you know?
And, like, there was, like, a couple beats coming through.
And we would, like, gather around the record player and, like, or whatever.
And just be, like, oh, it's...
You know, just be, like, blown away.
That's interesting.
So he was doing The Shining after Donuts.
Well, yeah.
Yeah, I think there was still little ebbs and little ebbs and flow, little bits and pieces
that were kind of, like, you know, still lying around for Donuts.
Like, I think, I can't remember exactly which one, but there was some stuff that wasn't all
finished.
Okay.
It wasn't all finished and delivered.
There was, like, pieces of that.
And I think Shining was finished by, I think, J-Rock or Kareem Riggins back then.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, Stone's Throw was so interesting.
Like, what a constellation of amazing...
You know, Peanut Butter Wolf started with him and Charisma and San Jose, and then they
came to L.A.
Yeah.
Kind of for Mad Lib, who was blowing up at the time.
Yeah, yeah.
And, like, man, was that an inspiration for you for Brain Feeder and just being there?
It was a huge inspiration.
Before I, you know, I was actually living in San Francisco studying film.
And a buddy of mine was like, you know, he was, we called him Crazy John because he
was crazy.
He was an insane dude.
But he had, he had great taste in music.
And he was like, oh, you like hip hop?
Well, you need to listen to LP.
You need to check out MF Doom, Metal Fingers, okay?
Victor Vaughn, Mad Lib.
And I was like, okay, I'm gonna check these people out.
And I went and bought these records and my mind was blown.
And I was like, you know, just, yeah, started getting back into making beats.
I'd made beats when I was younger, but when I was in college and, like, hearing that stuff,
I was really, I got really into it again.
Like, and more so on the sampling side because all the stuff I had made before was kind of
like synth-based and, you know, messing with, um, groove boxes.
And then that was like the gateway into sampling, getting back into that stuff.
Um, listening to Wu-Tang and hearing all that, but.
Favorite Wu-Tang Clan member?
The RZA.
Yeah, of course.
Yeah.
Hard to argue with that.
You can't ask the producer.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Although, JZA had some amazing beats, too.
Absolutely.
Amazing beats.
Bariza, Heart and Soul.
Yeah.
But, but yeah, when I was, when I was in school, I remember just being like, you know what?
I'm gonna skip history of film school, history of film, and just, like, work on some beats
right now.
Wow.
And I'd be doing that.
And then I heard about this label, Stone's Throw, that was in L.A. back home.
And I was just like, you know, maybe I need to, the whole scene was in L.A. too.
So I was like, man, I need to get out of San Francisco, go back and be around these people
and get in that energy.
So that, that kind of led me back there.
Stone's Throw brought me back in a weird way.
I love it.
All right, let's keep going on the artists.
Sorry, I was only supposed to give you a sentence.
No, no, this always happens.
I love it.
It's, uh, it's, uh, we're flowing.
No wonder your shows are like three hours.
Yeah, man.
It's just, it's always just, I think the best conversations are just free association,
just what you're, you know, whatever comes up.
Yeah, sure, sure, sure.
Um, speaking of which, you just named two people I was going to ask you about.
So let's go Mad Lib first and then, uh, MF Dune.
Oof, okay.
Um, Mad Lib was, was definitely one of the most inspiring folks around, um,
considering he was one of those people who was like, oh, it don't matter what you use.
You know, and I'm like, okay, well, I use a computer.
You know, it don't matter.
Just make something.
And then it was like the output.
You know, I, I remember being, being an intern and they showed me the, like the, the box,
you know, like all the Mad Lib beat tapes or whatever.
And they were like, all right, you know, check these, check these out.
And it was like, it was insane.
Just being able to like, it'd be like hundreds of beats or like, he would fill up all these CDs.
Crazy.
And I would listen to all them joints, man.
And just be like, whoa, what is going on?
You know, and just crazy.
And it would make me feel lazy.
You know, it would just make me feel lazy.
And it just, but also it was one of those things that just kind of lit the fire.
It was like, okay, I need to work on this.
I need to keep going.
There you go.
So it was, uh, he was definitely influential in that.
And just the energy, you know, he was just such a cool, humble person.
And, you know, whenever I got to be around him, it was just like a, it was a special day.
It was always a special day just because, you know, he was, he just had such a, an impact
on, on the whole community too.
Like there was, aside from, you know, the, the stone's throw thing,
you've had this kind of adjacent squad of, of producers who would hang out kind of around
like the, any kind of stone's throw related event, you know, there would be like the cast
like DiBiase and Georgia and Muldrow, Ross G, you know, take, and all these other great,
um, producers who went on and go and do great things.
We started to build a community kind of on the side of what they were doing.
And, you know, we'd be out front of whatever parties they were throwing with, uh, little
boom boxes playing each other's beat tapes and stuff.
And that was really, you know, with, oh man, Madlib came by earlier, you know, with, you
know, dudes who worked at, you know, Poobah Records and Amoeba, they'd be like over there
like, yeah, man, he came in, he got this record, this, that, whatever.
So it'd always be like, um, you know, legendary Madlib stories of what's going on.
Um, but always, always really influential and really inspiring.
And he, it wasn't Quasimodo like an accident.
Like that's how prolific he was.
It's like, I think Peter Butterwolf like found that or someone was like, dude, this is actually
pretty cool.
And then he kind of ran with it.
Yeah.
That's exactly.
So crazy.
Yeah, man.
Um, and Doom, Doom was, I mean, to me, he's, he's my favorite rapper still to this day.
You know, I, I think, um, he's kind of, he mastered the, the, the persona of, of the, the
character he created.
He really did.
He was really the villain, bro.
Like, I mean, all the stories you heard about Doom are true.
I don't know.
They're not, they're not legends.
It's all true.
Uh, like not showing up, like not showing up to stuff, like not showing up to stuff.
I remember there was, there was a gig.
We invited Doom, you know, um, I had, I had a show in London and he was going to play and
you know, we fly out to, I fly out to London.
I think he's already there cause he had been deported or something.
I think he was already living in the UK.
Uh-huh.
So we're like, great.
Get Doom on stage, you know?
Um, and I think as we were sound checking, we're, I'm in the venue.
Yeah.
It was like, this is the day, I think day before, cause we had to set up that whole visual
show the day before he canceled the gig.
Uh, and, uh, it was, that's kind of unheard of.
I mean, you'd hear that and it was like, oh, okay, well, but doing that sort of thing
in this business is not cool.
Especially when you have flyers and all this stuff, promoting everything.
We actually got Jay Electronica to fill in that spot, which is also a really crazy thing
to do is he's also like.
He's another guy where it's like, you never know when he's going to release his album
or show up.
But I think, I think he had reasons to come visit the UK and, uh, well, he was, uh, is
he married to like a Rothschild?
I didn't want to go there.
I did.
I went there.
I wasn't going to.
I said it for you.
I said he had a reason.
I don't know what the reason is still.
Uh, but yeah.
Very elite.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um, but he came out and rocked it.
It was wild, but, um, yeah, it was, it was really, it was really scary.
And that was that moment.
I was like, Oh wow.
He really is the villain.
He doomed me.
I got doomed right here.
Um, but man, you know, it's like after that happened, you just kind of, well, it's the
villain.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's what he does.
I feel like he's just the most elusive, interesting, like, I don't know.
It's interesting with him too, where we were just talking about Thundercat.
You know, I feel like 10 years ago, it was still more kind of underground hip hop, obscure
circles where hardcore fans of Doom, now he's on TikTok, like, he is mass media.
It was like Biggie.
They biggied him, man.
It's wild.
It's super cool to see.
Mm-hmm.
I just, for some reason, I just thought of, like, the first time I met Doom, though.
I met him at, at Peter Butter Wolf's Halloween party.
Mm-hmm.
I was like bathrobe, man, because that was all I had was a bathrobe.
I couldn't, I didn't have any other costume, but you had a bathrobe.
I was like a dude in a bathrobe and some sunglasses.
I'm Hugh Hefner.
And, uh, and Doom shows up.
He just got into town.
He just, he just shows up as himself, of course.
Um, and I'm like, you know, hey, man, how's it going?
How, what's, how are you living?
How, how long are you in town?
You, you, welcome to LA.
How long are you out here?
And he was like, can I trust you?
It's like, I was like, I hope so.
You know, like, that was the first thing.
That was his response to me.
And I was like, okay, he's a, he's a special, special cat.
Very special.
Well, you hear him way back in the day.
We were talking about this last time when we hung out, he was in a group called Third
Base and he is in that song Gas Face and his voice is like different.
He seems like more of like, like he's trying to be this like more square, like cut and
dry rapper.
Yeah.
Like Tribe Called Quest vibe a little bit.
A hundred percent.
Early nineties.
And then he like goes off grid.
I think he's homeless for a while and he comes back as Doom and you're like, oh my God, like
his voice is different.
Man, yeah, he, he'd been through something.
He, you know, he'd been through a lot actually, but, um, but yeah, there was, there's something
about it.
He locked in.
He figured it out.
He just fully embraced the villain.
Yeah.
I think there's, um, a really cool movie to make.
Definitely.
Why don't you make it?
You're the, you are the most qualified cause you make amazing movies.
I am the most qualified producers and estate.
You knew the guy, you made music as close to that genre.
You have a, you were on a track with him between villains with, uh, Captain Burpee.
There's two tracks.
Yeah.
There was a, we're supposed to do EP together.
Okay.
We had a whole bunch of stuff on his computer.
You know, the, the classic, classic tale of like a hard drive full of stuff and a lot
of it.
There's a lot of my stuff on there.
Um, and, uh, Thundercat.
What's going to happen to that?
Let's get that out.
I know, I know, I know.
Estate.
Movie and hard drive.
Yeah.
Um, Thundercat actually got to see him close to the end.
He went, I think he saw him at his house in, in London.
He was over there.
He was, he was staying in London for a while.
So gotta have him talk about that.
Oh, I'm curious.
That's amazing.
Okay.
Let's keep going with the, the crazy list.
Uh, Kendrick.
Oof.
Actual genius.
Mm.
Weird little guy.
I remember asking Kendrick, yo man, what books are you reading?
He was like, oh man, I'll, I'll be reading, man.
You know, power of now.
I was like, okay.
All right.
That's cool.
Yeah.
I was so, so, so surprised.
Someone like him who has so much to say and, um, very thoughtful.
Mm.
Didn't, didn't read, didn't like reading books and stuff.
I just felt like it was all in there.
I thought it was all books.
Yeah.
I felt like he was always referencing books in his work.
He is referencing.
I wonder if he, some people are just kind of tapped into and they're channeling and it's
just like.
Yeah.
Actual genius.
He, um, you know, it's the kind of person that shows up, writes it on the spot.
Mm-hmm.
Does no, no fanfare.
Yeah.
You know, he came through wearing some, like, you know, some, some slippers with some socks
on and wear some shorts and a hoodie and just kind of, you know, just kind of came through
and killed it, bro.
Like, um.
Would you say best battle rapper of all time?
Hmm.
I wouldn't put it in a battle rapper category personally.
I think he's, he's, he's definitely one of the most important voices in, in music.
Um, to Pimp a Butterfly is, is a classic album.
Amazing.
Um, yeah, I, I have one of those people too.
You're just like, it's, it's so, you're like, wow.
Okay.
I don't want to get in your way.
Like, I don't want to, I actually don't want to be, I don't want to be near you.
I just want you to be able to exist and not, you know, like it's, there's something very,
um, he has this sort of, um, I don't know, this vibe about him where he's just like super
quiet.
Yeah.
So maybe he's in his head, he don't say much.
So I just was like, I just want him to do his thing.
I don't want to interfere or interrupt whatever his, whatever is going on.
His process.
Yeah.
Who's, who's, uh, top five for you?
MCs.
Oof.
He's up there.
Um, if not, you know, number two, number two, you know, top three, at least.
Yeah.
Him.
Doom.
Man, this is the worst question to ask.
I'm on camera.
I don't suddenly don't know any right now.
They've all fallen off the face of the earth right now.
Um, what else you got?
I got, I got, I got a couple more.
I want to get through a Q-tip.
Ooh, Q-tip.
He's a super, super inspiring dude.
Um, amazing producer that, um, as well as rapper.
Mm.
Um, I think he didn't get, he doesn't get enough credit as a producer.
Uh, from my perspective.
Yeah.
Really great beats.
Um, really great energy.
The voice.
Mm.
Um, I don't know him that well, but we try to collaborate on some stuff.
I think sometimes the thought of working together is better than the result sometimes.
For sure.
You know, but, um, uh, I would love to, to have another go.
Yeah.
At that.
Yeah, for sure.
Yeah.
What about Apex Twin?
Mm.
Apex is, is, uh, interesting, interesting in that because.
You know, he was, he was one of those people that I listened to back before I was in college
without knowing who or what or why.
It didn't matter.
It was just dope.
It was just cool electronic music to me.
Mm.
Um, Square Pusher, Amon Tobin.
Those guys were kind of, like, in my sphere.
I wasn't, like, fully in the electronic zone.
Yeah.
Um, but those were, like, the kind of auxiliary, uh,
pillars, uh, for, for my ears.
Um, but, and I always found a lot of inspiration from the music videos.
Mm.
Um, Chris Cunningham videos.
And when they did that director series back in the day, the DVDs, they had just had all
the collections of music videos from, like, Chris Cunningham, Michel Gondry, and, and so
on.
Mm.
Um, and I always just would run those.
We'd run those so much and just, like, just pick them apart just because, you know, being,
uh, in film school and thinking about music, music videos, like, those were the most cutting
edge.
Mm-hmm.
Those were, you know, that series, that director series.
Yeah.
I wish they would re-release those on, you know, 4K, whatever things now.
I don't think it'll ever happen.
Yup.
Okay.
Final one in this series, Kanye.
Ooh.
You know, Kanye.
It's funny, man.
I actually, I never really had the, like, I'm a super Kanye fan.
Mm.
I never had that thing.
But I did love Yeezus.
Mm-hmm.
I didn't like it when I first heard it.
Then it really grew on me.
And I think that that album, regardless of what, you know, he has become.
Yeah.
I feel like that album was really, really ahead of its time.
And it set a tone for many years in music.
Mm-hmm.
Not just hip hop, just in music in general.
So I think that sound, um, it kind of expanded and it, people took it in different directions.
And, um, I think, you know, there's so much of, like, electronic music that has come from
that and hip hop and the intersection.
That's very influential stuff.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
But, but yeah, what a fucking nutcase.
Yeah, a little crazy, yeah.
Yeah, man.
I'm not one of those Kanye sympathizers, man.
I'm really not.
I fell off the train when he said slavery was a choice.
I was off that motherfucker.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're a rip.
Yeah, I'm going to get off now.
Fully, fully tripping.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I just hope he's okay, man, because he's musically a big, I love him.
I think he's amazing and I just wish, uh, I don't know, I wish he would just stop whatever
is going on now.
I don't know.
It feels like it's, he's definitely trying to get a rise.
Like, it's like, if there is a third rail, he'll touch it.
Yeah.
He'll hit it.
And then there's some other part where you're like, is he even in control?
Like, I don't, I don't know.
Yeah, well, you know, mental illness is a thing, man.
Yes.
It's a thing and people are capable of being very successful and mentally ill at the same
time.
Mm-hmm.
Um, that is a thing.
Often they're correlated.
Yeah, right.
And, um, also too, like, you know, the dude, he's just like, yeah, got probably like a lot
of yes men around, people like enablers, people just like, I mean, he's got a cult, you know,
and people who are still apologizing for him constantly and just be like, oh, he, you know,
he's just, he's, he's going through it, you know, but it's also got to be really hard for
someone like him to have been at the top of, of the music pyramid or whatever.
And to now just kind of just be existing among other, other great people, not being the greatest
top selling, most Grammy collecting person or whatever.
Like it's got to be a little, a little difficult for you.
A hundred percent.
Yeah.
A little fall from grace there.
It's got to be, it's got to be, it's got to weigh on you.
Mm-hmm.
Who are your biggest inspirations when it comes to filmmaking?
You put David Lynch in one of your videos and songs.
You already know.
Did I just answer it for you?
Yeah, I think you did.
I think you did.
Yeah.
David Lynch.
Ooh.
He was.
You have a favorite David Lynch movie?
My favorite David Lynch movie is probably Eraserhead.
That's makes sense because of the movies you make.
That is such a crazy movie.
Yeah.
It's, it's a crazy, all this stuff is pretty out.
Lost Highway.
So I got into David Lynch through being a fan of Trent Reznor.
Mm-hmm.
Back in the day, which is really, it trips me out when I think about it.
Because he worked on Lost Highway.
He did some music for Lost Highway.
And I was following him at that time.
Okay.
And then I was like, oh, what's this movie?
Who's this guy?
Lost Highway.
Loved it.
Um, and then I kind of got way in at that point.
And that was, he was one of those people too, um, early on where I was like, oh, maybe, maybe I should go to film school.
Maybe this is for me.
Mm-hmm.
Because I really, I really love this.
I really love this.
And I think he also really got me inspired, aside from the filmmaking, more so like the living the art life, as they say.
You know, where you just kind of fully commit.
You just, you're fully, you're fully in it, you know.
That guy's tapped in.
Yeah, you wake up, you smoke, and you, you get to work, and you, you, that's your life.
Just create.
Yeah, that's your life.
And that's how I live my life.
Sans the smoking part.
I've, it was weed, but I've, I've given that up a bit.
Um, but yeah, like, um, seeing that, and seeing that it worked for someone.
Mm-hmm.
And that they've made their, their best, some of the best things.
It's like, oh, okay, it's okay for me to be this way.
Oh, yeah.
You know, it's, I can, I can do this, and I can live this way, and it's okay, you know, to, you kind of make sacrifices, the, you know, you have, to have, like, whatever that regular life is.
Um.
It's almost like his life itself is art.
It is, yeah.
Like, you see him doing the weather in the morning, and I remember I ended up at his house because of some TM, you know, transcendental meditation benefit.
Yeah, yeah.
And he was giving some speech, and it was about, you know, it was like, all you gotta do is tap in twice a day, you know, the old TM thing.
And I was like, this guy's on another level.
Like, he's on another planet right now, and he's getting downloads, and he's, he's truly amazing.
And I feel like a lot of filmmakers try to do the David Lynch thing, and they fail.
Like, they get so hard.
Yeah, well, I think, I think, um, the issue comes from, you know, people still feeling like they need to satisfy the audience and, and have some sort of, like, making sure everyone knows what's happening and having closure.
And it's like, there's a difference where I think with his work, it's more so about how something feels versus how something, what it means or what it's supposed to do or where the story is supposed to go.
It's more so the feeling that it gives you.
And I think he always tells people that you know what it means, even if you don't think you do.
Yes.
Yeah.
And it's, it truly, I feel like he'll break a lot of sacred cows or, you know, do things that you're not supposed to do.
But it, like, it just works.
And I'd say Blue Velvet, for me, is one of my favorite movies of all time.
Oh, it's so good.
It's so good.
I love that one, too, because it's a, it's such a good gateway David Lynch movie, because it, on, it starts off, you know, like most movies in a way.
It starts off kind of simply in it.
Actually, of all the stuff, it is kind of more commercial leaning.
Mm-hmm.
So it's one of those ones.
It gets weirder.
Yeah.
And they have those moments.
I'll never forget the scene near the end.
Spoiler alert.
That, uh.
You know what?
They deserve for it to this club.
If you haven't seen Blue Velvet.
Do you, can you show a clip of this?
Can you show a clip?
I might be able to.
We'll try.
Well, maybe a frame?
Yeah.
We can show a little frame, for sure.
All right, all right.
Fair use.
So the frame is, is when, um, what's the guy's name?
Um, what's his name?
Kyle McLaughlin?
Kyle McLaughlin.
Yeah, the main character.
Um, when he walks into Homegirl's apartment and some shit had already gone down and there's the,
the detective who's, like, wearing the yellow suit.
Mm-hmm.
And he's just standing there.
He'd already been shot in the head, but he's, he's standing there still.
Mm-hmm.
I love that image so much.
It was so haunting, dude.
Like, uh, that kind of thing.
It's just so surreal and such a kind of, like, wait, is this a mainstream movie?
Is this not?
But it's just one of those things, like, that's, you should, you can see his painting
background.
Yeah.
Right there.
Because that's, like, that's just, like, some, uh, yeah, some bugged out business.
And I feel like it's a juxtaposition between this, like, suburban, like, kind of fake light
vibe.
Like, in the first scene, I think, is, like, some dude watering the garden or whatever
and he, like, chokes himself.
Fire truck going by, all of the, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, he's, he's the best man.
And so, you, like, how many years, it's been, like, eight years that you've been making movies
now or have you, or maybe before that on a smaller scale or how long have you been making
movies?
Um, well, if you want to go there.
Yeah.
Um, for a while.
I, I started messing around with camera a long time ago.
Okay.
When I was, when I was a kid, um, when I was at film school, I made a, a short film called
Use Me, which won the Audience Award at the time.
Um, and I was, I've just been always messing around with stuff.
My friends have seen all my work, but the rest of the world hasn't.
Dude, I love it.
It's crazy.
Like, Kuso and VHS and, and Ash are all epic and they break your brain.
Like, they, that's what art is supposed to be, I think.
Like, it's really, they're all insane.
So, everybody gotta go watch.
Kuso was fun.
Kuso's crazy, my favorite, I think.
Kuso's fun because it's at that point now where people are re-examining it and they're
like, man, that movie, I love Kuso.
And, but at the time, people were just like, what the fuck were you thinking, dude?
What are you doing?
You can't do this.
And it was, it was really right, that movie came out, like, right before you couldn't
really do anything anymore.
It was like, right when they started, like.
Oh, the little cancel culture vibe.
Right, right.
And I feel like I felt that coming on.
Like, you know, just peoples were getting a little sensitive to stuff and, but I feel
like now, because things have gotten so stale in a way, something like that kind of stands
out.
It's coming back.
Yeah.
I think like Gen Z, Gen Alpha, I think they're just like, fuck this.
Like, we like good art.
Like, it's all good.
It was the, some of the people who saw Ash were like, oh man, I don't know.
It's not like Kuso, man.
I'm like, well, all right.
Fair enough.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's definitely not Kuso.
No, Kuso is the, will break your brain.
Ash is a little more of a, a movie movie.
Yeah.
It's structured and Ash is amazing, man.
And I feel like it like really plays on themes that are growing in the zeitgeist right now.
It's kind of the AI theme a little bit.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And it's also, you know, it's a little bit of the pandemic COVID thing going on as well,
where you have this kind of brain eating, like, you know, parasite that takes over.
I don't want to spoil that either.
You spoiled it all right.
I might've just spoiled it.
Yeah, it's true.
Let it happen.
Just let it happen.
It's cool.
But that was amazing.
It's an amazing cast.
It's funny though, because when I think of that movie now, I feel like if only I had
done it now that I know so much about the, you know, the, the lore, the UFO phenomenon
lore.
Yeah.
It would probably be a little different or I would have a different take on some of the
stuff that I did.
How so?
I don't know off top, but I just feel like now I shouldn't be making the alien UFO stuff.
And maybe the next one will be, but, um, I feel way more qualified to tackle the topic
now just because I've been so deep in it, you know, but, you know, there are so many stories
to tell, you know, so many, so many that are, that are, you know, one of those things where
it's like, it's stranger than fiction.
I was, you just took the words out of my mouth.
I was like, that's what I love about the UFO topic is it is weirder than fiction.
Yeah.
And that's a cliche to say, but it's true.
It's absolutely true.
You hear some of these stories, you're like, what happened?
And then you're like sitting in front of the guy and you're like, you have no mental health
history and you were in a high position in government and like security clearances, all
that.
He's saying all that.
Yup.
Wild, wild, wild, wild.
But yeah, I find so much inspiration and just listening to the stuff, whether or not it's
true or not, it doesn't matter.
It's like, I just find it fascinating.
I'm like, yeah, keep talking.
Well, I can't wait to see the fly low UFO alien movie.
Neither can I.
And neither can I, and neither can my friends because I can't stop talking to them about
it.
So they're ready.
I love it.
It's one of those things where once you go down the rabbit hole, it's like hard to not
be annoying about it.
I know.
I really had to just try to just not go there.
But, you know, some people be like, all right, so what, give me the doubt.
What's been going on?
And you always get looped back in.
You get tired of it and you're like, ah, this is crazy.
There are all these psyops.
There are all these bullshit people.
And then you take a break and then something happens.
You're like, fuck him back.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
True.
Yeah, man.
When that damn, because I used to really fuck with Jeremy Corbell and George Knapp.
But then when Jeremy Corbell went on that whole tangent about the missing page and the fact
that he, his name was taken off of the whole thing and it just really rubbed me the wrong
way.
The whole thing made a big old stink about it.
Yeah, that was weird.
And it was obvious that it's like, it's not about you.
It's not about you.
Yeah, yeah.
It was like, that's an official government document.
And what really got me was Matthew Brown met Schellenberger before Jeremy.
Right, right, right.
So it's like, and he's not putting a cover letter promoting his podcast or what.
So like, I didn't, I didn't quite get that.
Are you going to separate the Matthew Brown interview into three parts to next week, kids,
for the next episode of Disclosure?
Yeah.
I like Jeremy, but yeah.
I mean, I'm still watching this shit.
So obviously I do too.
But it's just, it's, it's all the stuff just makes me, it makes the unease part creep in.
Totally.
Well, Matthew Brown also requires a follow-up.
Like the stuff that he said, it was like, you know, I saw these documents, Immaculate
Constellation.
Here's the, maybe the weirdest, most interesting thing.
It was like, I figured out Immaculate Constellation.
Lou Elizondo's name was tied to that program.
And then Lou Elizondo's testifying with Michael Schellenberger saying, you know, I can't
confirm or deny whether I was read in, basically saying I was read into this shit.
So it's like, Lou, like, tell us, man.
Like, and then you have Corbell like doing speaking tours with Lou and stuff.
So it's like, let's take this thing a little bit further.
And then Matthew Brown gets into, he just tweeted the other day.
I don't know if you saw this.
No, I didn't see it.
Oh, he tweeted the weirdest, like, it was like talking about how the White House has like
a crystal ball, basically.
Like they have some proprietary AI that like predicts future timelines, which is from a
story base.
Like if I were trying to be inspired for like a movie, like so interesting, but like, it's
like, dude, what, where are you getting that?
Like, it's, that's fascinating.
Like that would be crazy.
If true, crazy, if true.
And I want to know, and we DMed a little bit, but Matthew, if you're out there, follow up
with me.
I know you said you wanted to talk because that's, that's insane.
If true, that's like, that's fascinating.
And implying that like, what else was, did he say?
And he said a lot in that interview too.
Said a lot.
And he said that there is a God, but that we're in kind of like this prison planet and
that these, you know, beings are, you know, we're kind of like captured by some of these
beings.
What, we're like an energy source or something like that?
An energy source.
Yeah.
We're a resource.
That's what he said.
Yeah.
I don't know.
That's kind of dark.
I don't, I don't, I don't know.
I don't know if I want to believe that that's it.
You know, hopefully there's some more meaningful shit going on.
I hope so too, man.
We're not just getting mined.
I wouldn't be surprised though, but they'll stop eventually.
They're like, Hey, you know what's funny though?
I keep thinking about this shit, like aside from, um, the Barney Hill, any of the black
abductees out there?
Well, is it like that is the OG, that is, we talked about this last time.
That is the OG, you know, abduction.
So, but that's a great question.
I mean, aerial school, right?
Aerial school for sure.
Then there's that little girl who says, she says, um, in space, there's no love and we
have love.
And so that's why the being wanted to come down and interact or whatever.
I think that in space, there's no love.
And down here, there is.
There is love.
Yes.
So.
But yeah, like they're not.
But you think the ratio is a little off.
They're not taking no black people at nighttime, coming in your crib and like taking, that
just is, it's for some reason.
You think it's a, it's a lower percentage than the percentage of the population.
Or, I mean, maybe it's just not reported or something, but I don't, I don't know.
It's, I find that really fascinating.
That, that's it.
If you, if you could find some, like a book of black abductees or whatever, I want that
book.
Let's, audience, let's get the stats on that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's a, it's a, it's a funny thing.
Yeah.
Well, yeah, I mean, the first one, I mean, I don't know if they were the first, but the
first very documented, you know, but that is interesting.
I don't know.
Well, Flylo, this was an honor, man.
That's it?
No.
How long?
I think we wanted three hours or something.
That was three hours?
No.
This was amazing, man.
I'm, uh, anything else that we're missing here or what?
I'm trying to think.
We might've got it, man.
We might've got it.
But keep fighting the good fight, man.
Thank you, bro.
I will.
And you too.
And I'm doing my best.
Yeah.
But play some more of them beats though.
Y'all don't know that that's his beat in the intro to the show.
Like, yeah, I found, I figured that one out.
Oh man.
Most of my beats.
Put some more beats on, dog.
No, dude, I can't, I can't be talking to you about beats.
I'll tell you to do it.
I'll tell you to keep going.
Okay.
Yeah.
Keep going.
I need to.
It's therapy, you know?
But then I hear your beats and other people who I like admire and I'm like, I can't make
beats, man.
It's supposed to be fun first.
Okay.
It's fun first, man.
Like have fun, you know, and just explore, you know, if something happens, great, but like
just have fun with it.
I do.
That's the thing I have to remind myself.
Yeah.
You know, like there's so much pressure when I sit in the chair to do anything now that
I have to remind myself that like no one has to hear or see or anything.
Like I can just have fun doing this.
Isn't that interesting about art where you start and there's no self-consciousness and
then you become this thing for other, like Flying Lotus.
You're like a concept for like other people, but you're like still in your head.
You're like, I'm just this dude.
But maybe sometimes when you sit down, you're like, ah, I got to like adhere to this level
of quality that I've done.
Absolutely.
And it's a daunting thing to just have a catalog and a lineage and a history and all this stuff.
But at the end of the day, I know that people can hear when I'm having a good time.
I know it.
That's beautiful.
I think y'all can hear it.
Yeah.
You know, you can hear when I'm inspired and when I'm having a good time.
It's like, it's obvious, I think.
Do you sometimes look back at your life and you're like, damn, like this is stranger than
fiction.
Like, it's a movie.
The amount of people you've intersected with and your own insane career and then how much
you've been able to do in cinema and you've done, I mean, deeper cut people know Captain
Murphy that you rap to and hip hop production, like everything.
Do you ever think about that?
I do.
And I'm, I feel like, I just feel very grateful, man.
I feel very grateful every day.
I have this written on my refrigerator.
Be grateful.
Because I am, it's just, I have the best job in the world and I have so much love and
support for all my endeavors.
You know, of course, some people don't like what I do.
Some people like this.
Some people don't like that.
Oh, Cosmogram was the only good thing you did.
It's fine.
You know, but like, I'm, I'm having a great time.
I'm creating stuff and I'm, I always try to hold on to that part that, the, the innocent
part of, of that because it's, it's, they want to take it from you, you know, as soon
as you start putting stuff out, they want to take that and, you know, your management,
you got managers and people in your pocket and your families and then people want, need
money and you got to like support, you know.
And the legal aspects of music and the ownership and the, yeah, instead of just like creating.
Yeah.
And it's all, all gets in the way of, of the fun and all gets, it gets too heady.
So, yeah, trying, trying to hold on to that, man, is, is a thing and like kind of trying
to always stay inspired, always chasing whatever that will keep me happy and inspired.
It's a thing.
I love it.
Well, I don't know if I'm going to start making beats again, but maybe I'll send you
some samples because that, it's funny.
I have a little bit of an encyclopedic mind with the UFO stuff and then it's, and then it's
samples.
I know.
It's crazy.
I was so shocked when you started like, you know, dropping, dropping tunes on me.
I was like, dude, you know your thing, man.
I mean, I love it.
Very impressive.
I love it.
I don't know.
Well, it's, uh, it's more impressive to make this stuff.
You got to send me some playlists, man.
You got to send me, I'll send you, I'll send you some stuff.
I'm sure you've heard everything that I'm sure you're deeper on all this stuff.
I may, I may know a thing or two, but it's still nice to hear where your ear's at.
But I'll send you some old soul, like, I'll send you some samples.
Come on, dog.
I will.
Let's get it.
You promised me those samples when we first started talking.
I feel like that was early this year and I still ain't got nothing.
Okay.
I'm going to send you some samples.
I will send you some samples.
I know you're a busy man, you know, you got, you got a lot going on, so I give you paths,
but I'm, I'm, I'm waiting.
Okay.
I will send you samples and you can do so much more with these samples than me.
So I really need to send you a sample.
Yeah, get sued.
That's what I'm getting.
That's what's going to happen.
You can't really sample anymore, huh?
It's just, you got to just interpolate or whatever.
It's a wrap, especially, you know, where I'm at, you know, people are like ready to flag.
Oh, because you're so big.
Whatever you want to say about it.
They know I'm.
They're looking for it.
Yeah.
So like, it's, it's not fun.
So like, that's why I end up doing a lot more keyboard stuff and less sampling just because
it's like.
Why did that?
Cause like back in the day, they would clear sample.
Like you think about like.
They would?
Yeah.
No, they wouldn't.
Well, I'm just thinking about like, uh, Juicy Fruit and Tume or whatever, or like, I don't
know, Upside Down from Diana Ross.
And you know, it's like, you're taking the whole song.
Like that's not even sampling is generous or whatever.
You are literally taking a loop from the song and then putting some drums over it or whatever.
Yeah.
Like, so like I look at that and I'm like, why aren't they getting, why isn't there some
big legal thing with that?
Maybe some of the samples were cleared.
They were cleared.
But a lot of times it's not necessarily the artists who will sue you.
It's their kids.
You know, like that.
The grandkids coming after you, you know, like, cause they're in charge of the estate
and they be listening.
Right.
Like that Robin Thicke, Pharrell, blurred lines, Marvin Gaye, the bass line or whatever.
Yeah.
That was bad luck though.
That was bad luck.
You think that was just like really like too much?
Yeah.
You should have saw something.
Interesting.
You should have saw someone looking over.
You should be looking over your shoulders doing that kind of thing.
Yeah.
That was, that was an obvious bass.
That was kind of maybe a little rip off.
Well, it's hard to say.
I don't know, I'm usually pro the person taking the stuff and it's like if you're doing something
new with it, you know.
I am too, but again, you can't speak for the estate and being a person who's, you know,
my grandma, she wrote Love Hangover and people sampling her music is how we ate for years.
Yeah, totally.
I love that song, by the way.
Yeah.
If there's a cure for this.
But, you know, people sampling that was like, you know, Bone Thug sampled it, like Will
Smith sampled it, like so many people had sampled her stuff and yeah, man, like we probably
would have been out on the streets if it wasn't for, you know, people clearing those samples
and playing stuff on the radio.
Yeah.
That was, that's how we ate.
So I totally see, I know the game.
I get it.
People got to eat.
So, uh.
Yeah, that makes sense.
And she deserves all the credit for that.
I mean, what about, didn't she do stuff for Lamont Dozier back in the day too?
I believe so.
I don't know though, actually.
I think so.
I don't know.
What, under a different, under a different, uh, there was a group or something?
Cause he would, Lamont Dozier was in one of those groups.
I'm blanking on which one, but he also had a solo career and he was a great solo artist,
but I thought she might've written something for him.
Mm-hmm.
But.
Put me on, dude.
Tell me.
I mean, that'd be awesome.
Uh, I mean, look, people have been telling me stuff like that though.
Um, like she was, she had done some stuff in her Motown era that I hadn't heard.
You know, my grandma was around.
She was like more so writing, trying to write new songs and trying to, you know, write jingles
and stuff.
Mm-hmm.
So she wasn't really focused on the back catalog as much.
It was just like when those samples and things would come up, it would just be like, oh.
And like, even the Free to Pain and I Get High, I didn't even know she did that until
the Styles P thing.
Styles P.
Yeah.
I get, ah, ah, ah.
I didn't even know she did a song without getting high, dude.
I was like, what, grandma?
That's so funny.
I had no idea.
That's a beautiful song.
The original is amazing.
It's like ethereal and opulent.
Dude, you got some really amazing sound in there.
I feel like writers back in the day, in that Motown era, were the most underappreciated.
Like you think about, I think about the Motown roster, obviously like greatest of all time,
maybe record label, maybe ever.
And, but like really the linchpin, I feel like it's Smokey Robinson who was writing all
the stuff for everybody else.
I'm like, damn, like how did you write that?
It's wild, man.
And like some of the, just some of the session musicians, you know, who they would call back
in and all the stuff that'd be like, that would be part of the sound.
That'd be part of like the, the foundation for all this great music.
And then they would sometimes get sick of writing and they'd be like, we want the, we want to
be up in front, up, up front.
Like, um.
Like Thundercat.
There you go.
That's a great example.
Yeah.
Or I remember like, you remember like McFadden and Whitehead, like, hey, no stopping us now.
Like they were writers before, you know, a lot of it.
Yeah.
My, my grandma was doing, she had her own music at the time too.
And, you know, I don't think much happened with her own stuff, her own personal music.
But yeah, there was, I think a lot of those writers were musicians and wanted to have a
career singing and, you know, name didn't pop off, but they could write.
So, but it's a, it's a thing I would see still.
Um, she wrote for Junior Walker too.
Yeah.
That just came out.
I love Junior Walker.
It's awesome.
But yeah, man, like even in, in modern days, you see it, there's just, there's people who
was like, Sia, she was like a songwriter, but she was like, kind of like a background
character, didn't want to.
And then, yeah, she eventually was just like, you know what?
I'm doing my thing.
I'm not going to show my face though.
Yeah.
Never.
World.
That's, she won.
That's the move.
Right.
Yeah.
If you're that big.
And you can just hide.
Incredible.
Yeah.
Maybe she was inspired by MFD.
I was just thinking about that, dude.
I was like, man, dude, he really did figure it out, didn't he?
He figured it out.
Yeah.
I was funny because I, I only just made the connection to the gladiator mask.
Oh, dude.
It looks the same.
I did.
I just didn't.
What do you just said?
I only made the connection.
I was like, what is that?
That's, that's, oh, yeah.
That's wild.
Yeah.
So he must've been basing it off of gladiator.
Is gladiator?
I feel like that.
I don't know where the mask comes from, but that is like the same mask.
It's the same mask.
Yeah.
Cause you have it going, it goes below the chin.
Whoa.
That's trippy.
Yeah.
Man, he, his stuff is so like the metal fingers, beats and stuff too.
It was funny, man.
When I first got into that stuff, I was like, these are some of the worst beats I've ever
heard.
Well, they're just.
They're just like raw as hell.
And then eventually they're like, come the best beats you've ever heard.
Oh, yeah.
You know?
Yeah.
Well, he would just take, well, they were all named after roots.
And then he would just take like a Doobie Brothers loop and just throw it on there.
And throw the worst snares on.
Yeah.
And then eventually you're like, okay, I get it.
We'll just kind of work.
Yeah.
Absolutely.
Like, okay.
Yeah.
I love it, man.
Well, round two.
Yeah.
All right.
We'll actually finish this.
Actually wrapping up.
I could talk to you for hours, man.
Yeah, man.
Fly low.
This was an honor, true honor.
And hopefully we come back when you are making your movie, your crazy movie.
I would love to.
And thank you for having me.
Honestly, it's so cool to be on the other side of this, man.
Oh, man.
I appreciate it.
And I owe you some sample.
I'm now publicly being held accountable for this.
Yeah, yeah.
I need it.
It's time.
Okay.
I might not put it out.
If you did, that would be a life moment for me on the order of like, probably more important
than anything I've done.
You know, when you do a thing in the domain, you kind of know you're okay at or whatever.
You're like, all right, fine.
This would be so much cooler for me.
Now it's got to happen.
So send me some shit.
Let's get it going.
I'm going to send you some shit.
That would be crazy.
It would be.
Appreciate you, man.
Thank you, man.
Thank you.
You know, that just got me thinking like.
You know, Joaquin Phoenix provided Pusha T with a beat.
No way.
Do you know about this?
Nah, nah, nah, nah.
I think like that King Push song.
No way.
Yeah.
I don't know if he gave it to him and it was produced by somebody, but he, yeah, it
came from Joaquin Phoenix.
Joaquin Phoenix gave the beat to Ye.
So when I got the beat from Ye, it was, yo, Joaquin gave me this beat.
That's interesting.
Really weird.
I've been hearing about some low-key producers.
Robert Pattinson be making beats.
No way.
Yeah, dude.
Is it good?
I don't know.
I've been trying to get them.
I've been trying to get the beat.
That's crazy.
So just for my curiosity.
Yeah.
Gotta know.
Oh, wow.
Oh, that's so cool.
Yeah.
I just, I don't know how to do drums.
I'm so good at the sample selection and then I just always sucked at drums and I-
Do you program them in?
Yeah, just MIDI.
Yeah.
That's why.
Oh, you gotta play them.
Some, it's-
But I don't think I can play them.
I just, I don't know.
You can.
Really?
You don't, you don't knock it yet.
Just try it.
The click in the beats thing is difficult.
It's difficult to get a vibe.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
From that.
It's really difficult.
And I actually do that sometimes knowing what it's gonna sound like.
Like sometimes I want stuff that sounds rigid on purpose.
Yes, yes.
But like it's only then because like I just cannot.
And a lot of people do that.
A lot of people just click a man and all.
I just cannot do it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If I want that feel.
Yeah.
But like you got it.
You just got it.
But even, I remember like there's a Kanye interview where he's like, I can, he says
he, I mean he's amazing, but he was like, I can never figure out drums.
He was like, my drums didn't slap like Dilla.
He was like, my drums were not like Travis Scott.
Like, yeah, but his drums, he did his thing with what he's got, you know?
And I think, I think, you know, Doom did his thing with what he does.
But when you listen to early Kanye, like his first track ever for Rockefeller, I think
was Beanie Seagull and Jay, This Can't Be Life on one of Beanie Seagull's random mixtapes.
And you hear the drums and you're like, these are garbage.
Like these are not good drums.
Yeah.
And then half the drums are like impeach the president, you know, fucking generic ass
shit.
But you just got to try sound for sound.
Don't do like the whole kit.
Don't be trying to play the whole kit.
Just do like, just do some hi-hats first.
Play those in.
Play the hi-hats in.
You know, you can even quantize them later, but just put the hi-hats in.
Okay.
You know, do the snare.
Do the kick.
Okay.
But another thing for you.
Yeah.
In that case.
Because now you've put me on.
Yeah.
Is do your drums first.
Oh.
And then try to form your sampling around the drums versus using the sample.
Mm.
Trust me.
Okay.
Yeah.
Like, I have trouble with that sometimes.
Like, because finding the right pairing can be really, can be really challenging.
Yeah.
But like, if you set the drums first and you get a good groove.
With them drums, then something else can happen.
Wow.
Then maybe you might think.
I feel like you're more optimistic than me, but I will try.
Oh, man.
You can do it.
You just got to have the time.
Appreciate you, man.
Yeah.
All right.
We're actually done now.
Actually done.
All right.
Quick heads up for you guys.
American Alchemy merch just dropped.
It's all super high quality, 100% cotton, embroidered hats, clean designs.
I wore the logo tee on Rogan.
It's up now.
Go to AmericanAlchemyMerch.com to check it out.
Thanks for the support.
It means a lot.
All right.
You