what's up everybody we have a very special show for you today apparently dreams do come true
i achieved one of mine when i went on the joe rogan experience the episode is live today i don't
really get nervous for anything but i was pretty nervous for this i've been a super fan of joe's
show for the last decade and so it was tough to contain myself and lay low when leading up to the
episode he had been texting me talking about binging our show american alchemy and loving it
joe is a hero of mine i think he's a strong force for good and free thought and he showed a ton of
courage under fire during the pandemic so saying that this was an honor would be a massive
understatement on the show we talk about all sorts of crazy shit from artificial intelligence it
doesn't matter whether agi you know hits some like perfectly turing passable point you're gonna get
this like these weird cult-like dynamics like the meta sociological thing is you're gonna get like
religions dedicated to ai oh for sure oh for sure without a doubt there'll be people worshiping
certain branches of ai to secret science and i think there is technology that is black technology
and science that is black science and then i think there's stuff out in the open and so i think this
has already maybe happened in certain contexts and you know super secret department of energy
facilities which i think it's crazy to say that that hasn't happened you're saying that
it only happened with the manhattan project and it hasn't happened since that's insane there is black
science to exotic propulsion gravity is out here hanging out by itself on an island so you have the
standard model quantum field theory and you have einstein's theory of gravity and the two are not
reconcilable it is my belief that if you were to reconcile them you could create exotic propulsion
to ufos i saw a thing that looked like a fucking school bus it looked like like no visible propulsion
this like sort of low humming noise or whatever it was maybe 50 60 70 feet high like above the tree
right above the treetops those bizarre nasca tridactyl mummies that i flew down to peru to see
what do you think is going on there they break my brain i don't want to be overly sensationalist about
the if it's a hoax it's the best hoax ever and finally the legendary thomas townsend brown
townsend brown's biographer has him on record in a phone call that is recorded saying the tests were
very tricky but in the end we got it to work and he's on his deathbed but before you go and watch
that just wait a second we have a very special episode for you today before going on joe's show
i had already been friends with his producer young jamie jamie is an awesome guy he knows a ton about
ufos and is down some pretty crazy rabbit holes so naturally we hit it off he's also a huge golf fan
serendipitously one of the best golfers in the world victor hovland reached out to me last year
because he's a huge fan of american alchemy and happened to be coming to austin in late april victor
is the absolute man outside of being a top 10 golfer in the world the sensation from norway is humble
down to earth and super smart in his spare time he's reading play-doh and learning about ufos
let's all root for him in the u.s open this month so jamie victor and i did a little golfing at barton
pitch and putt when victor was in town they watched me absolutely embarrass myself as we discuss a bunch
of trippy fun topics without further ado please enjoy this week's amazing american alchemists jamie
vernon and victor hovland oh and one more thing we just launched maybe the coolest merch line ever
which i'll link in the description i mean just look at these designs we have our cowboy ufo tee
and our atomic space age tee so go grab those and watch my episode with joe rogan but not before
watching this amazing special episode of american alchemy
what got you into ufos dude it's cool yeah oh no there's like a lot of evidence there crashes
and that they have anomalous stuff how much and how deep it goes is kind of the question what's the
deal about the the pyramids what was i doing wrong before like i'd hit it where do we start
summon the egg summon the egg okay yeah multiple different factions he has some conspiracy theories
okay i don't even know if they're conspiracies never thought about it until right now i might
want to pull up my phone pull it up jamie he's like fuck you
my driver game is broken right now not that i'm gonna ask you for any tips but i'm any driver
only right now i'll take a look bro i might go till i run out of bars because i know i'm gonna
fucking whack it into weird places oh you're fine this is sweet all right who's first you're going
first you want to send it that's too hard not bad there you go just hit the shot first and we'll
see what we got okay yeah man not working with much
well all right not bad it's gonna run right down there
whoa that's it what got you into ufos obviously those um videos that were released or leaked from
the pentagon that came out yeah um gimbal and is it nimitz the other one go fast yeah and then it's
just been this like slow bleed of listening to joe rogan's podcast and hearing bobble czar and like
that's yeah interesting but that was like the first story or um that i'd heard about it and it's
very easy to go okay that's just one guy just dismiss him yeah and then you just move on with
your life but then you hear more and more guys coming out like that and it's very hard to just
dismiss all their information totally especially when a lot of their um stories like corroborate each
other yeah you start to hear about the case in virginia or um babe grush mentioned in 1933 it was
in italy it's long been known that the regime of dictator benito mussolini documented numerous uap
during this time this internal memo from the italian secret services includes crude drawings of
the uaps it's true it's real yeah that actually happened italian government moved it to a secure
uh air base in italy for the the rest of kind of the fascist regime until 1944 1945 and you know the
pope pius the 12th back channeled that so the vatican was involved yeah and told the americans what
the italians had and and we ended up scooping it there's so many places where it's happened all over
the world 46 in sweden they had ghost rockets which looked like modified v2s and eisenhower sent
general james dolittle out there to investigate and there were like over a thousand of these like
v2 rockets that seemed to like be able to move in and traverse in ways that like v2s would generally
just you know they wouldn't steer themselves that much or whatever and they would go like way faster
than v2s and so nobody knows like what those are and yeah i don't know i guess i think sweden itself
has like a lot of ufos so they have like a big ufo contingency okay and there's like an astronomer
there named beatrice vioreal who's big in this stuff but i don't know that it just seems like
everywhere else outside of the u.s the governments are like they're it's easier for them to kind of
keep that information on the down low versus here in the united states there's so many people who
are anti-governor government and kind of think for themselves a little bit so they push the
narratives out there yeah um but it is so frustrating because you don't really have anything
concrete and like hard evidence yet yeah even though there seems to be so much out there
coming from your videos and like the deep dives that you do it's it's unbelievable and you want
it to be like you just want to have something you want to believe yeah yeah but it's hard to just go
like full deep into it until you have for sure you know something concrete but hopefully that's
going to come soon you're the youngest in the top 10 i might be i don't know to be honest i thought
you were you think how old are you're 20 you're 25 uh 27 27 uh oh that's it dude drop damn just
hitting everything far see anduril moved to ohio yeah i think we at least that's a giant spot there
for sure yeah the intel plant there is a little bit of a situation right now but um they have anduril
yeah quite a few data centers uh-huh i guess there's like uh it's specifically because there's
like no seismic activity uh-huh it's like no fracking no other things going around yeah it's
obviously important but interesting there's also other stuff in that neighborhood yeah yeah yeah like
what i mean it's not a giant state so jamie's from um ohio columbus ohio yeah battell memorial
institute is there and battell manages all the nuclear sites across the u.s it's also very close to
bright patterson yeah which is a lot of stuff has happened there supposedly at least so he has
some conspiracy theories okay i don't even know if they're conspiracies just truth
kick up there go wow yeah nice job jamie no it's all right yeah whacking old lady
i know they're just there it happens unfortunately what's coming up now for for you what do you got
planned um so going to mexico peru yeah um and then doing this i i interviewed these sky watcher guys i
was just talking to jamie about it have you seen these guys they're like sky watchers no they like
claim to have this thing called the dog whistle which is this frequency
frequency and that attract that attracts ufos like 100 of the time and they have sensors and
they like pick up a lot of weird stuff okay so i want to see what's up wow okay yeah even more
effective than the ce5 yeah well they also have that they also have like um psychic like they call
neuromeditators or whatever and they like try to summon uap and jake there's this guy he had to
start for four years and then jake barber when he came out joined him and they had like eight
classes of uap and then he he joined and they're adding the egg is the ninth and they're trying to
get the egg which jake retrieved or whatever in the mid-2000s to like come down and like to summon
the egg summon the egg okay yeah wow and like do it in front of everybody which obviously if they do
that that's yeah that's gotta be some of the that's guys that should be next step if everybody can do
that yeah on tape please yeah yeah on tape all right damn that's that's cool where are they at
it's a bold uh it's a mobile uh like sensor unit so they can set up anywhere but they did operations
in palmdale and then finley the finley mountain range okay uh in east texas or west texas actually
um which is a critique of theirs is people are like oh it's next to like sensitive sites so it
could be like you know but it's not their method or north or no it could be like stuff like spoofing
them or could be done in conjunction with that you know yeah okay it's a bold claim that's cool
that's where i'm gonna give myself we'll give it to him yeah you do exactly
not bad put on the hill all right no it's just pathetic
here we go you have to name any names but do you talk about this stuff on tour at all with anybody
uh people look at me pretty crazy oh yeah that came out like what victor thank you like you okay
pretty much pretty much i feel like you're good at spinning the questions that you get back to golf
you're like yeah it's like you can't be dogmatic with your golf swing either but it's so true though
it's like in everything in life yeah obviously i was trying to connect it together but it's like
you you have to question everything and yeah and in doing so you find that either you get rid of the
beliefs that you have or you believe in the things you believe in even more deeply yeah so it's like i
think it's good to just be open-minded and ask a bunch of questions totally especially to that topic
that you're involved in it's like you spend more time researching it you just get more questions
and it's it's so interesting yeah and the implications of all of it is i mean if just
objectively speaking if that's not interesting then what else is what else is interesting yeah nothing else is
wow that's it looks great that could be pretty good actually yeah it's pretty good this is a hard hole
just over that jesse did you see what he did do that
copy him
nope that's not bad get up
what was i doing wrong before like i'd hit it
yeah it's uh where do we start
all right yeah that's better
there you go partner golf most improved
it's a low bar
do you feel like you get to when you travel you can like see the places
you go or are you like it's so focused generally when i feel like i'm playing pretty well and
i'm trying
i'm trying more to conserve my energy yeah i like to just find a cool spot in the town that i'm in or
yeah like a couple years ago i was in london and stonehenge wasn't too far away so all right let's
drive an hour and a half and check out stonehenge or sick like in um ohio or columbus yeah uh for that
tournament i drove to serpent mound uh-huh oh yeah nice yeah there's a few things in i mean you'd be
there like a month if you're going right yeah there's a couple things around town yeah there's some
cool things there and it's like it's just nice to mix it up and get away from the golf course a
little you're really into the like ancient civilization it is cool yeah it's awesome man
so i liked your uh graham hancock uh interview that was that's cool i love graham you see a
debate on rogan with uh flint dibble yeah yeah what a name that is
yeah that was uh that was interesting but uh like in the moment i'm like man uh flint dibble is
like he's obviously really smart felt like it kind of didn't get anywhere if that makes sense
i mean yeah i just those debates aren't like usually the best debates even because they're
really kind of coming in not really i don't think most people are willing to like budge they're coming
in to like say what they had to say yeah exactly kind of get those clips recorded and i said it's
like it's not a conversation of trying to figure out what's going on it's like my side is gonna win
or yeah it's can so just hear me say it again yeah now they'll believe me yeah yeah exactly and
it's just two different like data sets like like graham has his stuff and flint hasn't even like
looked at it yeah and then he has some slide with team shipwrecks that like you know didn't even
happen he's got a good point like you haven't looked everywhere it's like we haven't looked
everywhere exactly yeah yeah we know as you know i'm always on the hunt for things that help me stay
sharp focused and full of energy while i'm diving into life's mysteries and making this show happen
and i've got to say mud water has completely transformed my mornings back in the day i used
to struggle with that post coffee crash and let's not even get into the caffeine jitters mud water gave
me the smooth steady energy i was missing it's packed with functional mushrooms like lion's mane
chaga and reishi plus turmeric and cacao all working together to keep me focused calm and grounded
honestly it's like coffee went on a yoga retreat and came back zen what i love most is that it's not
just about replacing coffee it's a whole new ritual it's a simple nourishing way to start the day
and i actually look forward to it every morning every ingredient is usda certified organic vegan
non-gmo and there's zero sugar it's energy that doesn't mess with your sleep or make you question
your life choices at 3 a.m ready to make the switch to cleaner energy head to mudwater.com that's mudwtr.com
and grab your starter kit today right now our listeners get an exclusive deal up to 43%
off your entire order plus free shipping and a free rechargeable frother when you use code jesse
that's right up to 43% off with code jesse at mudwtr.com after your purchase they'll ask you
how you found them please show your support and let them know we sent you keep your energy natural
and refreshing all year long with mud water because life's too short for anything less than clean
delicious energy what's the deal about the the pyramids what they're discovered underneath the
pyramid is that just like a weird gadget that they're reading that stuff or is there actual
physical structures underneath the pyramid i guess that's what they're maybe debating i'm a little
skeptical like the answer is yes yes yes what what's your take have you looked there's definitely stuff
under the pyramid that's how much and how deep it goes is kind of the question i've heard that too
but why do you think why are you high conviction that there's stuff under the pyramid well i mean
just that people have like gone under it i'm showing it on video i think yeah like there's like at least
a chamber but this new thing is like synthetic aperture radar which doesn't penetrate below the
ground enough to be able to get like these generators at that level of granularity be able to draw
them up so i'm skeptical of this latest like italian they seem very you know like i don't know if
excited or but like very like adamant about their point like no we did this is it yeah we did find
this but i don't think anyone's gonna let them go dig to check either though right but can you not
figure out a way maybe like from you you dig a hole from i don't know half a mile away and try to
get close to it i think they've people have been asking to go underneath the sphinx for a long time
and they're not letting them do that they think there's stuff under the sphinx well they got the
minister of culture in egypt zahi hawaz is like as a keeper clamped down on that entire area he said
in the 90s he said there's stuff under the sphinx and then i think they dug some really superficial
thing and they're like nothing to see here and then didn't didn't like pursue it further so i there's
probably some like you know like planned obsolescence like with like apple products or something where it's
like it's i think they i think they like to like dribble out like the reveals for like tourism
and they don't like things that go against the egyptian national pride like if something predates
egypt that's not good they can't claim it they can't claim it so i think it's like too much all at
once it's kind of a threat to them do you think there's uh do you think they know kind of the the
bigger history of the pyramids but they're not deciding to release it or is it like i don't think i
don't think they fully know like but i don't know i believe the like graham hancock and robert shock
john anthony west theories that like limestone damage on the sphinx shows that it predates you know
whatever it was the old kingdom or you know 5 000 years ago or whatever yeah and you know maybe
there's a tropical climate at that time and then maybe the pharaonic headdress was like retrofitted
onto this like older structure but beyond that i think there's decent evidence actually that the
pyramids themselves were built uh during the uh ancient egypt so i don't know what do you think
i'm yeah i'm without going yeah somewhere like that i don't know i was just trying to think in my head
could be a silly question i'm trying nowhere in the bible do they talk about the pyramids do they
well i don't i don't know that's kind of i should probably have google in front of me to ask that
kind of question i don't think so no so it has to be two to three thousand but that's what why
wouldn't they or did they just not they could have easily just taken those passages out if they didn't
want it in there i don't know that's just a thought i just had literally the jews were like the slaves
but then yeah were they are there because they don't talk about building them either like we were
being used to build this giant structure right and we're tired of it maybe they didn't know what was
going on in egypt because they were obviously in the middle east so it's like it's pretty far away
yeah you would think they were that word i don't know though there's that uh but it was in egypt
like the exodus was they say it's this is speculation under ramses the second in egypt and
so but then i yeah i don't know if they talk about pyramids yeah i just never never thought about it
it's all right and i might want to call up my phone and pull it up chat gbt pull it up jamie
he's like fuck you
oh yeah okay
go go go go yeah was that um harold meldgren video that you did was that maybe the craziest one that
you've done or i think so i kind of think so because it's like hard to argue with his credentials
yeah like they're kind of unimpeachable you know like i mean there might be now after they changed
the wikipedia page it's so crazy that's wild it's insane they literally changed do you see this jamie
yeah yeah they uh they literally changed him from like top presidential aide uh you know jfk lbj
nixon ford to like american writer and lobbyist and said he was like part of the japanese whaling lobby
and like and then involved you know involved in some other scandal or whatever it's insane and if
you hear him speak like to any discerning person you're like he was an extremely like elite player
in politics yeah like you just know you hear how sophisticated he is it's just insane but um
so i yeah i think i think so like i thought about it after that and i'm like
how much deeper can you get without like unveiling a saucer in a hanger you know yeah and i could i
don't have the knowledge that you do but i could see that in that interview as he's talking you're
just like making all these connections like with certain things that he's saying and the people that
he's been around it was like it was just pretty cool to watch from like an outsider's perspective i was
like what the fuck like he the magenta thing yeah what else did richard bissell tell you he said this
didn't start last week this has been going on he mentioned that in 1933 and magenta he did yes
richard bissell mentioned the 1933 magenta crash yes that's amazing exactly that is such corroboration
because that is a highly conflicted you know account 1933 was the first recovery in europe in
magenta italy i fully trust david grush but that's amazing that there's some corroboration from back
then he mentioned it wow it's pretty crazy that the bluegill triple prime test like there's so much
data around that probably involving some sort of anomalous object yeah this guy jeffrey krukshank went
really deep into but then it's also tough it's like he said like he said majestic that word like
from the majestic 12 yeah and then i didn't even nick was actually filming it and like i didn't even
hear that we had to transcribe it later because it's what he he survived throat cancer 12 years ago
oh wow his voice is not good and so he said that on the phone to me and if i had more time with him i
would have asked him a hundred questions about that yeah so he could have been using that in its
counter intel context like just referring to some group but like he didn't want to say the name of
the group or whatever so it's just it's hard to say on some of the stuff like i wish i had more
more time with him but yeah but still like and the fact that they changed his wikipedia right after
like that makes you pretty conspiratorial when you see something like that i mean like why would you do
that yeah why for no other reason than to discredit what the man said totally you can come up with
these like meta games that they could be playing where it's like they want to show he's credible by
by like faking some detraction on it but it's it's crazy at a certain point you're like i think they
just take it at face value or whatever and then there are other things like he's at the end of
his life and like you don't always remember everything perfectly correctly but like i don't
know if you add up the fact that richard bissell who like literally like was the designer of area 51
like was briefing him on other world technologies and then you know he's holding the thing lawrence
i mean we should ask jeff bezos like what because that's his grandfather that gave him the the uap
material or whatever so uh what a crazy connection how crazy is that so this is kind of a weird
question but yeah if jeff jeff bezos has connection to the intelligence uh community and like maybe they
know something that most people don't yeah like why are him and like elon out there shooting chemical
rockets into space like if they have more advanced technology or crafts like why are they pushing it
in that direction yeah i i think about this a lot and like i i think if they do have stuff which i do
think they have stuff i don't think they know how to use it and i think if there are psyops it's like
convincing people they do or something it's like softening the enemy yeah i wouldn't imagine they
test that like every week or every night and i'd be like every six months like all right we've got a
test everybody's in place we're gonna do it at like 3 a.m to 5 30 a.m yeah and we'll get back next
week and we'll see right now oh shit they saw it ah no no delete what's supposed to happen how they
see it who saw it yeah now let's pivot in this direction yeah all right stop we have to three
months later i have to take a break that's also a little bit too extreme too like it can't just be
that either yeah but like the only you don't have a ton of evidence that they know to use this stuff
it's like bob lazar dan barish you have like a few possible data points and then otherwise
there's like i think a lot of evidence there crashes and that they have anomalous stuff
and then it could be like a usb drive for like a caveman where it's like even if they don't know
how to use it no idea even if you know how to use it doesn't mean you know how to make it
or deconstruct it or recharge it right refuel it you know who knows like right i don't know who
knows really i guess what what on the physics sides do you find the most uh convincing because it
seems like there's potentially a lot of different ways to get to kind of the same outcome of
technology yeah but a lot of at least the physicists that i'd like to listen to or have thoughts of
they they come at it from many different angles and it's like which one's correct and like can you
test it can you try it i think it's hard to say like you have all these like em drive and like
al cubi or warp drive and you have like how put off like electrically polarized vacuum you have like a
million different frameworks but i like to start because i'm dumb on the physics level like what
doesn't seem like it but no really i got you know i could like barely keep up but like i think finding
like the the like initial effect that was like an anomaly that got classified is like probably the
best starting point and i think this guy towns and brown figured out basically a way to manipulate
gravity with electromagnetism and then a lot stems from that that's like more sophisticated
so i like to like start there yeah but i don't know i'm sure they're like way more advanced at this
point um yeah you would think so or you would hope so i think so yeah and there's like i don't know
like aerospace graybeards that i speak to when i bring up brown and that sort of thing they're like
you know we can't say but like wink wink nudge nudge like or it's the opposite where they're like
bizarrely like aggressively like there's definitely nothing there i saw your video but there's nothing
there and it's like why are you watching my video yeah like you're like you're like some like walkie
like exec or something you have there's so many physicists that are talking about like okay advanced
whatever technology and you can use a quantum vacuum or whatever the word they're trying to say and
then you have so many other scientists whatever the establishment that are just fully materialistic and
uh any anomaly that we see it's just prosaic or conventional and it's like why do you have such
there's such a big divide yeah and it's like it's i've been listening to um uh avi lobe on uh your
buddy chris ramsay yeah he did a great job yeah and like i love listening to avi but even he is like
he's trying to find aliens yeah and he's like i haven't seen anything i don't believe in anything
else outside of that so it's just interesting how you can have one faction of people particularly the
people working for government but avi also comes from like an intelligence background he worked on
the he worked on star wars yeah like i thought he said that he didn't in that uh uh podcast but i
might have listened wrong no i'm pretty sure it's about star wars yeah maybe i i i think so maybe i'm
wrong but um i wonder if he knows a little more than you maybe yeah or he said the high meshed like
did you hear that no i did not so this guy like ran the israeli space force and he's like there's a
galactic federation and we're working with like aliens on mars like crazy shit and he's like i think
he knows that from his intelligence background and i'm like how would you know that yeah this show is
sponsored by better help if you are going through something anything i always think talking about it
helps i've also always believed that taking care of your mental well-being is as essential as staying
physically fit especially when life keeps you on the go for me it's interviews projects and travel
sometimes you just need to blow off some steam i've seen firsthand how a solid support system
can transform your day to day traditional therapy costs anywhere from a hundred dollars to 250 dollars
per session it often takes a lot of time to book the sessions it's hard to know who's a quality
therapist better help makes weekly therapy perfectly accessible with a flat weekly fee that saves you a lot
of time and money you get instantly matched up with an amazing therapist and you can vet them based on
their track record what i really appreciate is how easy it is to connect with one of better help's
over 30 000 licensed therapists no waiting rooms no rigid scheduling just guidance and support delivered
online whether you're tackling everyday stress managing anxiety or simply looking to build better
coping skills don't let these things fester or build up better help provides a straightforward
affordable way to get the care you deserve your well-being is worth it it's the most important
thing in your life even more important than aliens so visit better help.com slash alchemy pod today to
get 10 off your first month that's better help.com slash alchemy pod a l c h e m y p o d after you sign
up they'll ask you where you heard about them please support our show and tell them we sent you that would go
a long way mcgonigal mcmonigal mcmonigal yeah you're the cia remote viewer yeah that was that was a wild one
yeah dude because he pulled out on your here we go all right aliens are coming sound they got us
but but yeah remote viewing millions of years ago mars yeah but then also they say that like
only 30 percent of what they were seeing was accurate yeah for sure and some of the images
he showed me i like debunked like some of them are not legit so i who's just i don't know but the
mars thing i think it's actually dogmatic and crazy to say zero percent chance that there was life on
mars you have the water caverns you have the like the excess of like argon the other thing i have i've
read and i don't believe it's true is that the uh the current rover up there wasn't equipped with
anything to actually look for signs of life it's just got like cameras and it's looking for other
stuff like the goal wasn't to look for life interesting but the same reason i heard someone
talking about the moon landing stuff again recently i'm like you're going through this whole process and
you have to also film it because no one believes you exactly it's kind of a tough process and thought
process to get through because like you're doing all the have to go don't care film it that's not my
i'm here to like make sure the rocket goes and doesn't explode and yeah we get there and we get
back and these other guys like you gotta film it no one's gonna believe you yeah it's like i'm
starting to be like it's a tough i still believe in the moon landing and all that but like it's still
a weird thing like you don't believe uh bart cybrel or whatever joe does i don't even know if he does
there's just a fun conversation to have it is a fun conversation that's really a lot of it's just
joe was arguing with uh who was it dave smith or well he joe was really into it at one point
yeah and he's just back and forth i think we've talked about just depends on the day you wake up
you're like where am i at today like i'm a little more this way today yeah it's so funny keeps it
interesting yeah yeah yeah oh jesus i'm back right i got it on one green
sorry
when's your next tournament next week oh is it okay so you have the week off and then yep
go to philadelphia and then it's charlotte and then to memorial yes
if you want to get good at golf yeah stay friends with him
keep getting tips i like that just act like it doesn't exist oh that's really good look at that
dude crazy that was insane so it's 100 you have a perfect 100 shot then yeah it's right in your head
yeah it was uh i had to club up for that one oh yeah that's nice to sit though bounce right
yeah dude come on come on down oh let's go come on down
uh-oh get through where'd it go i don't even see it just dropped down right down the bottom of the tree
oh it didn't get through yeah the vibe is sweet
nice good shot
how did uh youtube get linked up um i mean just through it was osmosis yeah it would have happened
eventually yeah i think one of his videos i found i just found his videos and i dm'd him after one of
them yeah and then the link the real link was after townsend brown video i don't know if you watched
that one yeah we were already talking and i texted him i was like are you telling me
that doc brown had a moment of like lightning and drove back to his lab in pasadena and created
time travel sounds like back to the future dude and he was like holy shit you're right and then
he googled some stuff and he got back to me he's like and there's even more that you don't know and
i was like okay oh wow that's weird that's weird nice jesse let's go i think back to the future
definitely touches on some real stuff because when the when the delorean comes back it crashes
and the guy has like a little comic the kid has a comic book with like alien ufos and he's like
it has no seams no rivets like it must be an alien ufo or whatever and it's actually a time travel machine
so he's like mistaking it in real time or whatever oh shit
damn so and then uh and then the guy townsend brown like doc brown is emmet townsend emmet
yeah you pull up the tt thomas townsend brown i was just with doc brown i was like that was close
enough because driving to pasadena which is where it took place and all that stuff which is where
townsend brown did his experiment and it's called the flux capacitor which is townsend brown's experiment
as a capacitor like but what what do you make of that are they like are there like hollywood
movies is that scripted in a sort of way according to tom delong it's all on purpose i think i think
or or is it just like the wild synchronicities of life that like simulation yeah i i lean more
towards that because there's so many weird ones that pop up i don't want it steven steven spielberg
executive produced it and he that guy knows some shit even if you look at uh close encounters of the
third kind they're two crates those are like the most advanced r&d programs at lockheed and
northrop respectively that would have to do with this topic like how would he know about that
in like the late 80s like yeah i don't know i'm gonna do this bad some stuff yeah i don't know who
made one of my favorite ones fly to the navigator i've told you about that's a disney yeah i know
that director randall klycer i never heard that name i first met jake barber at disneyland
ran really yeah just a safe place he was there with his family okay and uh i drove down from la
that was also a pretty uh crazy uh interview i thought with jake i thought so too like i think it
was too much for people to stomach like the psychic stuff and uh yeah ufo retrieval stuff all
at once yeah and the fact that he says he's handled these crafts himself like you don't hear that
stuff very often no you definitely no i mean it's like if that's i i don't know you know where to
shake out there like i think if he's incredibly sophisticated and like so everything checks on
the surface like it's almost like we'll never know he's so he's so sophisticated and if it is true
it's the tip of the spear it's like that and lazar and like what what's farther than that there's an
assumption that the united states government is this whole encompassing thing and they all work
together and they all know everything and they've got computers and they all talk on chats and emails
and everybody's friends that can't it's like now that's nowhere it's probably the farthest from the
truth it would have leaked and there's multiple different factions even within factions and factions
within factions and yeah maybe there's a small group of three guys that found something and stored
it in a locker somewhere and like they're afraid to say what they got because they don't even know
and it turns out and just has more this group has 50 of them that's what the barber was saying
with the egg like they might not care about the egg yeah they have too many it's like what a crazy
thing to say i know and that's what he said i was like what'd you do with it then you just threw it
back like dropped it off in the ocean like where did it go yeah just left it we're like how many do we
have and he's like who is us he's like sure it's like all these like factions fighting against each
other i imagine if you told some there's got to be a black market on on the dark net for
ufos what's in that box buy it and find out but then how is this more ubiquitous then how is it not
more leaked and more yeah yeah if it's that many i no one i just back to the like it's no one knows
they don't it's hard to figure it out you can see something and not know if you don't have the
right tool to get in there right just an egg shape yeah if you find an iphone in 100 years
but it can't be there should be more concrete like evidence that i agree i feel like everything is
so much more into the almost a theoretical like you listen to certain people and they've got this
whole framework kind of figured out but nothing to kind of show for it yes unless unless you have
a thousand if you have it over a thousand of the eggs or whatever then there's one of them's gonna
leak it's just well in the modern day like i you know so it has to be like less than that and yeah
there is this whole like theoretical ontology around a thing that we don't even know don't even
know yeah it's just like crazy so don't speculate and and like i think a lot of the ontology kind of
makes sense yeah um when you kind of when you listen to people explain it like that but again
you got to have something concrete to show for it for sure it also could like be a bunch of different
things like the things you're summoning or the things that show up around nukes that like look like
blobby like lights or whatever aren't the saucers in you know lockheed hangers or whatever like those
could be two fundamentally different things yeah so it's just hard to say like it could be like a zoo
of like there's just like the spooky science world the doe has like a lock on like a lot of it or
whatever because that's where you have like the most secretive atomic stuff and then that's where you
would put the most secret science it's where we do like the most you know like intense high energy
physics okay stuff so not darpa but like a different arm darpa is a part of the doe yeah so
so they you you think they have just a lot of different departments kind of each specialides to
particle physics to whatever the cloning dna well they the doe also paid for the human genome
experiment so like they like have like a lot of genomic data that you know other departments don't
they have the tightest security like since los alamos and if you even look at like the special
definition of nuclear material like in the atomic energy act of 1954 it's like anything emitting
alpha beta gamma radiation is like born secret it's like restricted data upon finding it so you could
just contract out a lockheed or a northrop or whatever and if they like stumble onto a thing it's
like it's like immediately secret and then you have these i don't know like the largest particle
accelerator in the u.s is like at brookhaven national labs it's called cosmotron and so
a lot of the secret science stuff is going on at these doe sites and that mountain said that too yeah
do you think that's just from what i've heard like um you know the technology in the iphone the screen
whatever um wireless um wi-fi all that stuff is like kind of leaked from darpa i just heard that
do you know have you corroborated that at all to some extent that's a hundred percent true and not
conspiratorial like uh there's a a search engine called men x which was pre-google okay that darpa
had been experimenting with you know well before google arpa e uh created the internet like jacques
who's actually a ufo pioneer was like working with doug engelbart on like the earliest part of the
internet in like the 70s wow okay any uh people from like lockheed or northrop or uh any of those
companies that you have a chance to maybe um interview and like see from that angle because
there's most of it i feel like you're coming or there's a guy i met from skunk works who's like
really smart doesn't believe in you he thinks like the ufo stuff is kind of he believes in ufos
like in the ephemeral like you see them outside or you see them you know like you know around like
nuclear sites or whatever okay but i don't think he thinks that's the same thing as like he thinks
it's just human tech like at lockheed and other places and so but he works for skunk works he used to
used to yeah for like but like for like 30 years okay and he but he's he's kind of trippy and he
believes in a lot of like i think he thinks that we've made a lot of progress on a lot of like secret
tech that after he left lockheed or no like since even while he was there but like he kind of hints
at stuff like he can't always like you know what's up guys i want to tell you about my new favorite
boots these things are epic i've been wearing these everywhere they're called brunt they're insanely
comfortable and durable these things last for years and they're super versatile i wear them for
hiking for hanging out they look pretty swaggy if you're going out they even look good in work
meetings they feel incredibly comfortable there's no annoying break-in period they just kind of form
fit to your foot right off the bat they're lightweight you don't have to lug them around but
they're also super weather resistant waterproof and durable brunt is committed to making sure you're
100 satisfied with your new gear with over 500 000 customers already on board these boots are the
best in the category take it from me brunt makes the most epic durable and comfortable work boots for a
limited time our listeners get ten dollars off at brunt by using code jesse at checkout just head to
bruntworkwear.com and use code jesse and you're all set even better brunt lets you try all their products
on the job risk free just go to bruntworkwear.com and use code jesse for ten dollars off again that's
bruntworkwear.com code jesse after you purchase they will ask you where you heard about them please
support our show and tell them that we sent you well fellas enjoyed it great plan man it was an honor
it was an honor thank you for uh bringing yourself down to our level it means a lot well yeah we we meet
each other halfway i i go down on the golf thing and you go down with the ufo stuff so we meet each
other halfway no i mean i might not know more than you you know it's fascinating to talk about so it
definitely is and i think i think there's gonna be a lot of momentum in this world for like the next
i just i feel like it's in the zeitgeist like there's so much even if it's like a vague sense
that there's just i don't know like you asked me this you were like uh what if the ufos just like
don't go anywhere and i'm like i just don't think that's gonna be the case and that was like six
months ago yeah yeah i i would i would believe that it's gonna like keep keep growing take off yeah
you know a fake walk-off or just take off yeah
can you see me drive away
you
Thank you.