what do you have no this is Stan Friedman I'm a nuclear physicist with a very strong interest
in flying saucers I'm in Kansas City Missouri on July 24th 1991 I'm here to do an interview with
Gerald Anderson a very important witness with regard to recovery of a crashed flying saucer
in New Mexico in July 1947 we have just had a visit with a holograph examiner who says he has
seen no evidence of deception this is after spending several hours with myself and Gerald
mostly with Gerald a full report will be forthcoming so with that we will talk to Gerald Anderson
my name is Gerald Anderson where were you born and when I was born October 4th 1941 Indianapolis
Indiana okay and give me a summary of what happened in 1947 with regard to a crash flying saucer in New Mexico
well we had just moved to Albuquerque New Mexico on July 4th 1947 this was approximately the
it was the day before we went out on the plains of San Augustin with my uncle Ted my cousin Victor
my father my brother Glenn and myself we drove down to the plains of San Augustin which is west of
Socorro New Mexico in the Magdalena daddle area and we were down there looking for banded in moss agate
which according to my uncle Ted and my cousin Victor was prevalent in the area my brother being an
amateur rockhound and wanted to get some of this and it was a way of showing us around the area and
they had relatives down in Magdalena that they wanted to introduce us to so we had gone down
there and we got down in the horse springs area and had driven off onto the plains down an old
rutted road for a mile or so and seemed like a long ways we parked the car got out of the car and
walked down a hillside a semi forest that I guess you could say it had pinon trees and scrub oak and
stuff like that on it and we'd walk to well not scrub oak but cedar and walked down the hillside into
an arroyo or dry wash and then walked south down to dry wash toward where the agates were supposed to be
at and as we came around a bend in the arroyo that had pinon and cedar trees growing on we were able to
see farther ahead down the arroyo and on the next ridge line there was a large silver disc-shaped object
was embedded in the side of the ridge line and there was debris and wreckage and stuff
on a string about the area but mainly this thing was intact I would estimate its size from an adult
perspective to be something like 35 feet in diameter I've heard other other people who were there
say they thought it was like 50 feet but as an adult I would say about 35 feet in diameter quite large
when we got up to it there were four bodies there not human there was two of them who were obviously
dead one of them that was obviously very badly injured and one of them that apparently suffered
no ill effects or it didn't appear to be injured and was was ambulatory was mobile I was just sitting
there next to the one that was still alive were they right next to the vehicle right next to it right
under the edge of it and this craft had apparently come in from the east bounced off one ridge line
went plowing through this arroyo area and then crashed into the ridge line and embedded itself and
they were sitting back under the edge it was kind of tilted up like this and they were sitting back
under the edge here and I'm assuming that this one creature that was all right had laid this material
on the ground but it looked like unrolled the tinfoil that these other three creatures were laying on
like it was trying to like you do a person that shot you and put them on a blanket kind of a thing
and apparently it has some boxes there around it and had apparently been trying to
give first aid or help these other creatures when we first got there and as we approached
the creature drew back like this like it was in fear of us like we were going to hurt it
and it wasn't very long you know and trying to communicate with the adults were
it seemed to calm down and just sat there and kind of looked back and forth watching them
apparently trying to figure out what was going on like what did it look like a little bit more these
creatures all of them were all about four foot tall four four and a half feet tall they had very
large heads that were shaped larger on the top and they kind of tapered down not to a real sharp point
but just tapered down to where they were thin and they had very large very large oval shaped or almond
shaped I guess you could say black eyes that had they were so shiny they had almost a bluish
tint to them when the light reflected off of them their skin coloration
i think the best way i could describe that is kind of a bluish tinted milky white
it was uh it looked like someone in shock and the ones that were laying on the ground were really
really looked more that way more blue how about ears nose mouth no there was there was no visible
ears on the creatures except like if you was just to cover your ear like this to where there was just
a riser and then a hole without you know your earlobe and the rest of the ear there how about nose
it was the nose was very very small almost imperceptible uh just like two holes straight in and the lips
were just a straight line it was like a cut and you couldn't see any visible lips like we have it was
just a slit and we never made a sound pardon what hair color there was no hair they were completely bald and no sounds i never heard a sound of one not out of any of the creatures
including the one that was didn't you see fingers yeah they had uh they had fingers like this they
didn't have a little finger they just had the thumb had three extra digits except the center digit was
longer and the other two were about the same size they were very long and slender it looked very delicate
and i've made the statement before and i'll make it again i think it would have made an excellent violinist
because of the the structure of their hands um they were wearing one-piece suits all of them were
dressed exactly the same and it was sort of a real shiny silvery gray color no zippers buttons no i saw
no zippers no buttons insignia no no insignias the only thing that was different you know they all had this
but the only thing that was different from the the silvery gray thing suit was that down like the
seam on like it was a seam on the shoulder and around the collar it was trimmed in what appeared to be
maroon like cordy then the suits were continuous with their foot gear you could see right about this
area down it seemed to be less pliable than it was up here like this was a stiffer area like they were
boots or shoes or something but they were all dressed exactly the same okay so you and your family are
talking back and forth wondering what was going on what did your family say i mean well say anything
yeah my brother one of the first remarks i heard made was uh that's a goddamn spaceship uh you know
there was bodies up there and you know i was told not to go up there which i did and uh how old was your
brother at the time he was in his early twenties i think 20 20 months he was a lot older than you
were oh yes considerably uh we when we got out there i kind of meandered off to one side this thing was
cocked up and i was standing here the bodies were here and everybody else was kind of down here except
my cousin victor was over here playing looking in this gaping hole on the side of this this disc and it
it's shaped just like a discus except for a round dome was up on top and there was this big gaping
gash in here where you could see inside it looked like a double hole how big uh length the dome well
it uh covered the greater majority from the center of the craft out it was just like a gaping hole in
there and i'm thinking you know it's like about 30 feet 35 feet diameter so we're talking like 17 feet
maybe and most of most of that one side was ripped open like that and you could see inside
and you could see another double hole like uh in there and there was these rows of components
that was on there and there was lights that flashed
on off some of them were steady some were flashing there was a lot of debris and stuff hanging out of
the hole there was uh evidence that there had apparently been fire it looked like it had been burnt
along the edge there the gash now this wasn't a gas that could have been caused by the thing coming
into the ground it wasn't at the leading edge of the vehicle no no this was in a side like it almost
appeared it was elliptical it almost appeared as if something the same shape as the disc we were
looking at had hit that that same you know it hit the disc and left an imprint that pretty closely
approximated the outside diameter of the disc itself and uh it appeared to be caved inward okay and and
kind of like you'd hit it like this and just crumpled it caved in and ripped it open uh okay so you're
you're there you you take all this and everybody's mystified what were the circumstances outside hot
cold very very hot incredible to me being the first time in new mexico and coming from back east
that dry heat was just like being inside of an oven it was unbelievable to me and that was the odd
part about this thing the closer you got to it the cooler it was and standing under it in the shade
there next to these creatures bodies it was like uh refrigerated air conditioning and did you feel
air coming out of this thing or no it was just like it was ambidian and i remember reaching up and
putting my hand on the side of it and i think i was afraid it was going to hit my head because
there was enough room for me as a small child you know i was approximately the same size of these
creatures to to walk up under there and stand there but i i kind of did like that put my hand up against
this thing what did it feel it was ice cold it felt like it just came out of her uh the freezer was it
smooth was it uh it was very smooth it had a very smooth texture to it was obviously made out of metal it
was very solid and it was very cold ice cold and there was a smell in the area it smelled uh volatile
acrid like acetone and that seemed to be coming out of that gash that smell
but the closer you got to this thing the cooler it was so you know i kind of remained there and i
guess that while they were over here my father and my uncle ted and my brother and uncle ted was trying
to talk to this thing in spanish and of course it didn't understand what he said and dad tried to
talk to him then they tried you know sign language and that didn't work and uh i don't know for some
reason i just uh i reached down and touched it this one that was laying next to me and when i touched it
i realized you know i jumped back it scared me and startled me because i suddenly realized that these
weren't dolls i thought they were plastic dolls and i you know i was still in my mind that these are
moving dolls until i touched it and i realized you know this was a dead thing i'd been i'd seen dead
relatives before and i unfortunately had made the mistake one time touching a relative it was in a
casket and i just knew this is a dead thing and it scared me and i ran around behind my father and my
uncle and um this thing was sitting there on the ground and it kept looking back and forth and it
just had its hands like it's in its lap and it just kept looking back and forth between the three of them
and like it was trying to understand and all of a sudden it just turned it looked right straight at me
between my uncle ted and myself and this is when it was just like an explosion of things in my head
things i started you know feeling just terrible depression loneliness and fear and uh just you
know awful awful feelings it just suddenly burst into my mind and i don't know if that meant that it
was communicating with me and i was the only one there i could communicate with because i was a kid i
i don't know i turned and ran and i ran across the arroyo and up on the area that it had bounced off of
during the crash and we're just standing there looking down at the scene you know and my family
and off in the distance i could see cattle grazing i could see a windmill and i could see dust trails
out on the playa out on planes out there and uh oh i was there for a while and then i came back down
and i guess we were there you know victor was in when i got back down there victor was up in the crack
ted yelled at him to get out of there and glenn went over and grabbed me by the belt and jerked
him off that's your brother yeah and jerked him off and said get out of there you could cause this
thing to explode and kill us all you know and then of course he went prowling around in there
uh i was kind of standing off to one side looking that's why i knew that there was i could look off
these rocks that i was standing on right into this thing that's why i knew you know about the lights
and the components and stuff and then uh i don't know i heard other people talking and i turned and
there was a group of people coming up the arroyo from out on the plains from the south they had come
up there and of course they walked up and was talking and uh how many uh there was uh an older man and
five younger students boys girls there was three boys and two girls and they were all you know
introducing talking to uh my father and my uncle and my brother what the older one looked like
the leader of this group of men he was a he was a very tall man very big man he uh he was wearing a
pith helmet when he first came up one of those kind of explorer helmets and uh he was bald and i know
that because he had taken it off and he had done this you know a couple times with a handkerchief and put
it back on he was a balding man and he had a round face he was very ready complected he's a big man
uh and he apparently was a doctor because he's they kept calling him doctor and as i understand it
was an archaeological group that was out there on some kind of summer thing and uh they they talked
and he apparently was able to speak several foreign languages and he tried to talk to this creature
several times in different languages again to no avail how did that happen to be there had he seen the
thing well they claimed that they saw they said they saw this thing come down the night before
flaming you know and they thought it was a meteorite and they had uh talked about well in the morning
you know well we'll go over there and see this where this meteor came down because that's what they
thought it was and when the sun came up the next morning you know and they got about their business
and got up and somebody looked over and said you know they saw the shiny metal and stuff across the
planes there and they realized it wasn't a meteorite it may have been an airplane and
and christ so they all decided to go over there and see if there was anybody who was alive you know
that was hurt that needed help they had driven on no they walked over apparently the way i understand it
and it's quite a ways across that plane so it hadn't taken a very long time to do this
or they may have had a vehicle i don't know that's an assumption i think on my part
okay so they're around with but they came across the the planes nonetheless i'm not sure if they drove
or not i didn't hear any and then somebody else showed up yeah they were down there just oh 15 maybe
20 minutes at tops you know and they were picking up things some of the students and uh this doctor
buzzkirk that they called him this one girl went up and said look doctor wouldn't this make a beautiful
ring and she was holding one looked like a red rod a red tube of some kind of kind of a silvery red
and he kind of snapped at her you know and put that down agnes you don't know what that is i think
it hurts you just don't pick this stuff up and she kind of said well yeah okay doctor and then he went
back to what he was doing and she walked away and put it in her pocket and a lot of them were doing
this sort of picking up things and feeling things i was picking up things and feeling things there was
all kinds of material metal and stuff laying around then we heard it i heard it well we all heard it
and the sound of a motor coming like a truck and i went back up the the incline there to the to the
ridge line and i could see out there and there was a truck coming up it was an old pickup truck
it was sort of a a beige color or a tan colored thing and it had a whip antenna on it and it stopped
and this guy got out and he's wearing brown clothes he's got boots on and he's wearing a straw hat just
like the kind harry truman always wore and he had wire rim glasses he was a big man and he looked exactly
like harry truman to me and now you know i'd seen in the movie tone news that the he was president then
yeah i was well aware who harry truman was so everybody was he's kind of a hero you know
and this guy looked like him except bigger bigger and i don't think and he didn't look as old either
his hair was kind of light gray and uh he walked over there and they got to talking you know with
everybody and he told them that he worked out on the planes out there and that he made maps and that he
had seen the the wreckage from out there on the plains and he saw the people and he thought it
was a plane wreck and you know just something was going on he came over there to see and he hadn't
been there but just a very very few minutes when we heard all kinds of motors and engine straining and
stuff and uh here comes a military car with a big white star on the side of it followed by a
six-by which is a military truck with a kind of canvas wagon type canvas thing over it and it's
full of soldiers it got guns and right behind that was what we call a four-by which is like a medium-sized
jeep truck situation and it had two big high wood bandanas all kinds of radio gear in the back and a
guy back there with earphones and stuff on and he's you know working these radios and they all pulled up
and stopped and uh which direction had they come from they came from from the north from the horse
springs area right so they could have come off the highway there oh yeah i'm sure that's exactly how
they got there they come off the highway same way we did well in the meantime that when it stopped the
this black soldier the sergeant and the reason i know he was a sergeant my brother told me he was
and he got out of this uh this car and then a guy got out on the other side and he was glenn said he
was a it was a captain he told me later he was a captain and this guy had orange red hair and uh
all the soldiers then we keep running over there pointing guns at people and tell them get away get
away get away you know and when this creature saw these people the military he went nuts he went into
an absolute panic worse than what he did when he saw us uh did he move around or just his eyes uh he
he just he just oh crazy and it was like he was here for yeah like he's looking for a place to run and
hide but he never got up never got up he never left the one injured one next to him and uh this
redheaded officer this guy was a real butthole uh he made all the threats he threatened to have people
shot they didn't move to everybody oh yeah get away get away you know well shoot get away from there this
is a military secret you know just screaming and hollering and he told my my uncle and my father
that if they didn't want to spend the rest of their life in prison they would never say anything
about what they saw there if they ever wanted to see us kids again they'd take the kids away and
they'd never see the kids you know meaning me and and victor that we'd better keep our mouths shut
if we did not this is what was going to happen uh they were threatening people and pushing people and
the students as well oh yeah they were they were hustling everybody and one of the soldiers uh
pushed my my uncle he had a rifle like this and he shoved him back like that well that was something
you don't do to my uncle ted ted had a violent temper and he grabbed the rifle and reached over top
smacked this guy and dropped him right there and ted had dropped a fight and dropped the hat this guy's a
cowboy he'll hit you in a minute and of course when he did that there was bolts opened and
i guess cocking you know they were cocking your rifles and they're pointing guns at people and
everybody busker and glenn and dad grabbed him you know pulled him back and got him away don't
don't man they're going to shoot don't do that you know trying to stop this and i think we came very
close to having someone shot uh then they really started threatening you know and they interviewed
did the redhead do all the talking pretty much too pretty much except once in a while the sergeant would
would you know would chime in and make statements like that to other people in response to the red
mainly it was the redheaded was there a name tag yes there was and his name was armstrong and i'm not
sure if i know that from having read it or know that from remembering and now being able to read it
in my memory or someone said that to me but his name was armstrong was right here on his uniform now
they chased you guys away pretty quick yeah yeah they did and uh they herded us up on cattle and they
moved us up the arroyo back in the direction we come from over the protest of this dr busker who said no
no we've got to go the other way we came from i don't care where you came from get your ass up the the
arroyo and they ran us up the arroyo and uh so you'll get to your car right now they take us up
the arroyo and just below the hill that we came down they broke us off and moved us up the hill
now this whole time no one has ever frisked us down no one has ever checked our pockets to see if we
picked up any of this material and this girl agnes still has that stuff in her pocket and some of the
other students had stuff to my knowledge at the tough to that point they had not been searched
whether they did so afterward i don't know they never searched us ever they run us back up the hill
and when we got to where the car was parked where dad had parked the car up there there's a jeep
with a guy sitting in the back and there's a mounted machine gun in the back of this jeep and all these
soldiers the jeep pulls out we're told to get in the car we follow the jeep and the soldiers go with
us all the way back out to the highway and when we get back out to the highway they set us right there
they wouldn't let us out of the car they wouldn't let us move forward i don't know whether they're
making a decision or what when we got out the highway this place was absolutely full of military
personnel military equipment there was airplanes sitting out there that they had landed on the highway
did you see any airplanes when you were back at the site yeah there was airplanes in the sky but
nobody thought much about it you know i didn't think anything about it i was used to airplanes
being in the sky having you know been raised in indianapolis indiana the home of the northern bomb
site you know the sky was always full of military aircraft i never thought nothing about it and when
we get back onto the highway there's observation aircraft you know high-winged aircraft and there's one
what i know now to be a c-47 sitting there and how we didn't hear that lands beyond me
and how you land well of course i guess you could land if you're a good pilot out there
and it was they had torn the fence down on the north side of that highway and all this equipment
was setting back up there that plane was up there they were taking stuff out of the plane
there was military ambulances and there was trucks with like uh wreckers cranes on them and there
was tankers like maybe had fuel or water in them it was just everywhere you looked there was military
and a major recovery operation yeah it looked like an invasion force it really did and they were all
wearing these these light light khaki uniforms they didn't look like you know holly drafts they were
light khaki and they all had the same patch over there that kind of blue funny patch with the
the circles on it was was on their shoulder and a lot of any clue as to where they came from did
your brother or your no i i don't know where they came from uh i don't think anybody ever
ascertained that there were a lot of them had np patches and they were and some of them were wearing
nightsticks off of these uh webbed utility belts they had nightsticks and they had 45s and holsters you
know the the automatics and the full roaster and these were the people who were given most of the
orders they had the road barricaded off out there and we sat there for a very long time and you know
we're getting thirsty and everything and we asked you know if we could go back to horse springs and get
some water oh no no you can't go through there and right after that they said no you just turn around
and you head out of here now and you go to socorro and you and this is a redhead again you keep your
mouth shut just keep going and don't look back well and so we drove away you know dad and i said hell
with it we'll get we'll go to magdalena we'll get water in magdalena you know because that's where john
trajillo is at their relative intent and uh so as we drove away i was looking out the back window and
i could see dr busker and these kids and that guy that got out of the pickup was standing there
and this dr busker was doing just like this in this redheaded officer's face and he kept pointing
back behind him and i guess that meant you know we got to go back that way and he was fed up with
this guy or something he was shaking his finger in his face while they were yelling at each other
and that's pretty much the last i saw the whole situation i don't know what happened after that
because we just kept going did you get home before dark oh yeah yeah it was before dark of course it
was in the summertime so we didn't get dark until way late and we stopped in in magdalena very briefly
and you know and they just kept going and uh the adults were really funny you know they were really
scared and i had very rarely you know of course i didn't know him that well but over the years i knew
that ted was not much of a disciplinarian he really didn't discipline the kids that much
but he really knocked the fire out of the world victory and victor will want to talk about what
we just saw i just saw ted get telling shut up don't talk about i don't nobody's talking about this
finally he just turned around and knocked a living hell out of uh victor for shooting his mouth off
did ted work at sandia then yes he did he was uh he did something out there in the technical area
i don't know had a clearance yes and uh later your dad worked out at sandia yes he did at security
and he worked there for years until he retired until he retired and dad had some very high clearances
okay um when we got home we mom was over at uncle ted's house and mom perceived instantly that
something was wrong and said what's wrong glenn and he's like and they decided to tell him well
when he did then of course isabel oh my god you saw demons you saw the devil because isabel was ted's
ted's wife devoutly religious catholic person who thinks anything that isn't a vision of say the
virgin mary or jesus is quote unquote demons and that's what we saw and of course ted you know he's
put her off and we really never talked about it much in the family because of the reaction it got and
my dad was really afraid and so was ted there and glenn especially because glenn made the statement
about when he first saw the military he told my father he said uh and ted and everybody there
don't let them son of bitches know i'm a marine don't let them know and of course nobody did and
he was in civilian clothes so you know he had a pair of uh blue jeans on you know and he was in civilian
clothes so you know he didn't look like military or i'm sure his ass had been in real trouble uh and
they never checked they just assumed yeah i guess that we were did they ask your names oh yeah they
took our names uh they got all that from my dad and and my brother just very cursory wouldn't you
know it was hard to talk to him at all he let dad and ted do most of the talking which was pretty smart
everything under the circumstances and of course they never really asked me any questions at all
you were just a kid yeah i was just a kid and uh well you first went public with this now let's first
square away all the other four that you were with are dead yes yes that's been some time my brother died
of a heart attack in mexico city my dad died of a heart attack in 78 and ted and uh victor were killed in
an automobile accident in the mid 60s and i assume i was 65 right now there's a strange diary that's
turned up how did that happen well when i went to my father's funeral in 1978 a lot of dad's belongings
were personal belongings were given to us you didn't live in the area at the time oh no you've gone off
to the military yeah i've been in the military and subsequently on the return of the military moved
to colorado immediately and uh your dad had remarried a couple of times and oh yeah this was uh so dad
was on his third wife and uh he his personal belongings and stuff you know are kind of given to my two
brothers and myself and my cousin belly jean was there at the funeral that's ted's daughter yes and she
came up and was talking to me and she said uh here uh you were there you need to have this too
and she handed me these photo copies and at first you know i thought well you know what is this
dad's diary she said no it's my dad's diary but you were there you need to have this and then it
dawned upon what i was looking at and uh you know because i read a little bit of it and so i said yeah
okay you know and i didn't want to talk about it at the funeral because ross's side of the family god
bless her that's your dad's third wife god bless her i loved her but they were very religious and
they would have viewed this exactly the same way as isabel had as evil and i really didn't want to
have any problems with them you know that we were kind of shaky terms we didn't see eye to eye religiously
so we're not quite you're active in religion now oh yes yes you're a deacon in the episcopal church
right okay that means you actively participate well yeah uh lay eucharistic ministry okay so i
yes i actively participate i serve on the altar what do you do for a living now i'm a security
officer in the state of missouri and you've been doing police sort of work for several years oh yes yes
about nine years and you also are going to college to be a nurse and you've already got a couple of
associate degrees from community colleges right yes one associate of science and one associate of
general studies and i'm working toward my bachelor's of nursing in roughly two years i will have my
bachelor of nursing i'll be out now to be a security officer you have to be licensed by the state of
missouri yes you have to be a certified law enforcement officer which means that you have to have gone to
the state academy the department of public safety so that's not just a pickup thing oh no no you have
to as a professional yes it's definitely okay um and you have to to to work for the state under these
conditions you have to not only be certified but you have to have prior law enforcement experience now
when we get back to the diary for just a minute uh when you were hypnotized by john carpenter a psychiatric
social worker and he was asking you questions about the diary apparently you've been told that there
were a number of copies of that around uh yeah something buried out maybe there too yeah as i understood
well in fact in conversations with valley gene after the fact after i got involved in this thing through
the unsolved mysteries thing uh i was told that that wasn't the only diary that what i had was it was
a copy what was a photocopy okay and uh that there were a lot of these copies around and apparently uncle
ted or someone had had put these out through different people in the family and friends and stuff
uh for reasons i don't know to keep her from getting lost or something like that okay now when i asked
you for the original you contacted who well yeah valley gene that was valley gene okay she was in a convent
right and she was reluctant to do anything you had to call a number of times as i recall that's correct
and you talked to the bishop somebody talked yeah i talked to a bishop
and he convinced her to send the stuff to me yes apparently okay because i got it directly from
colorado with a cover letter that strongly indicated that she didn't want any more to do with this
that was part of the agreement but that she considered this the work of the devil or worse
to that effect anyway is that i think she's in the same opinion that her mother was
okay so you see all i ever had of this was the was the photographic copies
that i had showed you originally and as i understand it you received i received the original
from which those have been made they were partly burnt she mentioned she had intended to burn them
but because of your persistence and with the agreement that i never contact her
she would send them to me and as you know when i had forensic analysis done it showed that the ink
dated from the early 70s the paper could have been available in 47 so it was clearly not an original
but it was also done before there was any publicity about this case anyway because i know i was the
first one to get involved exactly now as you know we have discovered not i but you had identi sketches
done by a police artist of the various people involved in this right and as you know there is a picture
several pictures that seem to indicate that dr buskirk uh was dr winfred buskirk who had received
his phd at university of new mexico and you had described him as in his late 30s early 40s it turns
out he was 39 in 1947 he was bald and involved most of his life even up to then uh did was there other
contact between you and he at that time as far as you know your family and him or uh i don't know i don't
i don't not to my knowledge i don't i don't believe my dad had ever contacted him there's a possibility
that ted may have and i'm not sure why i i think valley gene had alluded to the fact that ted had been in
contact with him and uh that they had corresponded and this kind of thing but as far as any personal
knowledge of it no okay now you didn't tell your story really until the unsolved mysteries program
was rerun in january of 1990 that's right that's when you contacted them got my address wrote me yeah
kevin randall and were they upset that the program wasn't quite accurate well yeah that was the whole
thing it started off as a fluke to begin with because everything that i saw didn't didn't jive with what
i had seen personally i guess i was kind of missed you know here all these years i had been
primarily forced you know by not only by others but by you know my own sense of uh survival to
keep my mouth shut and wow here it is it's on tv and you got it wrong that's yeah i just impulsively
called the number and told the lady wait a minute you know no the thing was wrong
well how do you know that sir and i said well because i was there that's why and boy that
really had apparently pulled somebody's string yeah and the key thing that was wrong of course there
were a few mistakes in an otherwise excellent program was that they had that uh the barney barnett the
civil engineer story over near corona and you knew that it was over in the in the plains right there's a
lot more well yeah and then the fact that the thing looked like a tint flat or a tint top hat and it
didn't it was dish shape and barney barnett or whoever the guy in the truck was did not drive right up to
it on a road it wasn't parked conveniently next to a thoroughfare you know and there was it was just
things like that and i i don't know i just for some reason i thought well you know geez look it's
already public yeah the story's out and let's get it right you know of course i didn't i don't think
i realized at the time you know how involved this was going to be but what kind of you live and learn
now i got you together with uh john carpenter the psychiatric social worker and you guys had several
sessions and then we flew out to the site uh you're reasonably convinced now that the second
time around out there we did find the exact location yeah the first time in i you know it
was like 43 years and we're in a helicopter yeah i was in the air this time and the last time i was
on the ground and so you know the landmarks were a little confusing i was positive i was in the right
place but until we actually got on the ground john and i and retraced the route in there that we had
come in in the car uh i wasn't absolutely sure there was two ridge lines there and i wasn't really sure
of which one it was and i had the feeling that the first one that i had pointed out was the correct
one but once i went in on the ground on foot with john i knew instantly that it wasn't that one it was
the other one and i'm absolutely positive that that's where i was at there's no question in my mind
and you will recall that you described the woman who sold you the pop on the way in right and we found
the older woman there who said that was exactly what she looked like that's right and i'll never forget
that lady because i uh well i had it with the heat i'm telling you back seat of that 40 plymouth
down those dirty old roads and stuff and for mile after mile of course my dad was one of these kind
of people when he got in a car it was point a to point b non-stop i don't know why he just never
stopped to smell the roses along the way and uh so you know i was pretty sad shape and yeah i remember
that lady quite well what kind of response have you had you went public i mean john talked to a
newsman you both talked he called me in the springfield newspaper paper paper carried a very
straight very large article and that got spread around by lots of people so suddenly you're a
celebrity if you will what kind of reaction from the people who knew you on campus where you worked
your friends oh very very few negativists there there's the noisy negativist you know we have those
but in general is that generally supportive 99 of the people were incredibly supportive uh only one
professor at the university uh was of the negativist type that was vocal about it everybody else is just
100 percent supportive the majority of these people are absolutely convinced even without this story
that extraterrestrial uh life forms exist and that the people are flying around out there and moving
between systems and stuff and it was just it's just an unbelievable amount of support you didn't lose
your job oh no boss didn't give you a hard time absolutely not in fact uh i think it's i can i can
publicly say that my boss was extremely supportive because he is a avid uh ufologist himself he is
fascinated by the subject and you won't have any problem convincing him either and my boss has a
master's degree he's not someone that's untrained observer that's given to hallucination most of the
people who are the most supportive of me are people with very high educations very very solid education
very solid upstanding degree in people not given to hallucination you went you attended a ufo conference
with john carpenter and he gave a paper i guess and introduced you i'm sure and you've got a response
from that audience too yeah 100 percent supporting i was really quite relieved and made very very welcome
well you've been interviewed by a number of other people uh linda howe working on a documentary and so
forth seems to have bought the story now uh how much contact did you have with kevin randall
uh a very brief telephone call uh i came home from work one day and there was a message on my
answering machine and as you well know i have a tendency to be hard to get a hold of yes
and they he'd left his number and of course i had his address and i i and yours and i had sent
cards to both of you and something to the effect if you want to know what really happened after he
called me yeah and uh he had called and i wasn't there and he had left his number so i returned his
call now uh i talked to him very briefly uh primarily because i didn't like the man's attitude
i don't feel comfortable with people who call other people liars and charlatans and phonies
and say that they rigged their research to make it come out the way they want when someone starts
telling me this kind of thing then the first thing i want to do is i want to get away from them and this
is exactly what i did now i understand that this man claims that i talked to him for two hours and that
he has a two-hour tape of one contradiction after another of me and that's not quite true okay there's been
no other contact with no other contact i won't give the man a time of day and uh has any other
investigator any of the noisy negativists approached you directly no none at all the only other
investigators you yourself are don berliner and bob biglow and john carpenter okay and of course you're
quite familiar with our involvement and you agree that uh on that first trip to the plains it was you
i bob biglow and a pilot in the helicopter yeah uh joe channing the pilot was in the front seat on the
left side i was in the front seat on the right side you were directly behind me
no you were directly behind the pilot on the left side and bob bigelow was directly behind me on the
on the passenger side right and then we met up with eventually with don berliner and right carpenter
you spent the next three days they drove to datil they drove the jeeps and stuff to datil and were
waiting for us at datil when we landed in the uh highway island out there right and as you recall
where did we refuel the helicopter uh springerdale arizona because it's not far to arizona that's
oh no no it was just a matter of a few minutes actually third 25 25 minutes maybe at the max uh west of
where we were located all right i think uh we may pick this up another time but i think that'll do
us for now i really appreciate the time and trouble and effort and all the rest of that and on the bigger
and better things