People were noticing, all throughout this time, that Forrestal seemed like he was unraveling.
He started developing these weird, nervous tics.
He said, I'm being followed by strange, foreign-looking men.
He started dipping his fingers into glasses of water all the time and just wetting his lips.
I drink only distilled water or rainwater.
I'm glad to see what you're getting at.
A couple of big, tough Navy guys grab him and throw him the hell out the window.
I'm absolutely convinced that's what happened.
And in the 80s, it felt like maybe the U.S. moved from a strategy of secrecy and denial to flood the zone.
And flood the zone doesn't mean put out BS.
It means put out partial truths and put out a lot.
People did see it emerge from the water, circled their transport ship twice, totally silent.
He said there were high winds.
This thing should have been bouncing around in the wind.
It was rock solid.
He writes in his diary at 3.30 a.m. on August 12, 1825.
The Night Watch reported this orange spherical object rise from the ocean.
Let's get down to the fundamental reality here.
We are dealing with a phenomenon.
Yes.
It is a reality-shattering phenomenon.
I do believe that there's a good reason to think that we have been monitored or observed for a long time.
It's not that we're being too crazy and too fringe.
We're not being, we're not going out there enough.
I think that's right.
Here with the great Richard Dolan, we just did this amazing kind of live show for a bunch of people.
It was a lot of fun.
I told you afterwards, I think you're the easiest person to interview because I just have to tee you off and then you just go.
It's an honor to be here.
It's a long time coming for me.
Maybe what we should start with here in this kind of private setting is I'm curious to know how you got into UFO research to begin with and who your inspirations are.
Yeah, I have a lot of inspirations in my life, some in this field, some beyond.
This is a story I've told a few times.
I don't want to sound like I'm rehashing it, but I want to try to do it fresh.
I was always a very driven young person and I always felt like there was this very intellectualized destiny that I wanted to pursue.
I didn't really know what it would be.
I've always been drawn to history and politics, discovered a real deep love of literature when I was in my early 20s and that's remained with me.
But as a young person trying to make a professional life, I thought, well, I would finish a PhD in history and teach at a university.
When I was in my youngest portion of that, I was totally unqualified to try to do what I ended up doing.
I was studying German history.
My German language was minimal at best.
And here I was studying basically the J. Edgar Hoover of Otto von Bismarck's 19th century Germany back in the 1850s and 60s, a man named Wilhelm Stieber.
And I'm like, oh, this is an interesting guy.
And I'm diving into his career and I thought, I'm going to do a dissertation on him.
I wrote 150 pages or whatever and it failed.
I was unable to crack Wilhelm Stieber.
He's an interesting guy.
He blackmailed people.
He created a brothel in Berlin in 1870.
He would take pictures, all of his stuff.
He literally was the J. Edgar Hoover of German unification.
Absolutely.
Interesting.
And it was amazing.
But anyway, so I bailed out of that.
That was when the Berlin Wall came down.
I was there.
I was in Berlin during that whole period, 1989.
I was trying to wrap this thing up and it just failed.
So I go back to the States and I left for about two years.
I was studying at the University of Rochester in upstate New York.
And then I went back and I thought, you know what?
My German sucked.
So why don't I just do like American history?
Because I know that language.
And I went in and I focused on United States diplomatic history.
And I did great.
I was really, really into it.
I was very deeply.
And by this time I was in my early 30s.
So I was a bit more mature.
And I was studying Harry Truman and his presidency.
And I was doing a lot of Soviet stuff too.
But I ended up studying 1950 national security strategy just before the outbreak of war in Korea.
And, you know, I was like, who cares?
But that was what I was doing at the time.
And I wrote another 125, 150 pages of a dissertation on that, which I did not finish.
So I had two unfinished dissertations.
And I was in a bookstore, just like an ordinary bookstore one day in Syracuse, New York.
And I saw a copy of Timothy Good's very classic work, Above Top Secret.
Oh, yeah.
And it was the subtitle of that book that caught my attention.
It was the Worldwide UFO Cover-Up.
Oh, wow.
So here we are.
It's like 1994.
So I'm about 32 years old.
And I flipped through the book.
And I'm like, I know that name.
I read his diaries.
I know that department.
Wait, what?
UFOs?
What is this?
Like it was this great cognitive dissonance.
And I thought, this looks like a fairly serious book.
He's got a variety of documents.
It looks like his research is at least halfway decent.
And my question wasn't, are UFOs real?
My question wasn't like, are there abductions or are there crop circles?
I wasn't down that road.
My question was simply, even if this was a mistake, like if they were mistakenly interested
in this UFO thing back in, or the flying saucers back in the 40s, how come I never read about
it in any academic history book, like ever?
Even if it was a mistake, like would you not think that's kind of interesting?
You go back to 1947, 48, and I'm reading here in Tim Good's book, like the Air Force and
the Navy, like they were totally into this.
And you're in the early Cold War.
Yeah, that's damned interesting.
And so I thought, well, I bought the book and I just went down that rabbit hole.
And I thought, I'm going to just spend like two or three months.
And I just want to resolve for myself, like, was this a thing or not a thing?
And that was it.
And then I figured like I would just leave and go on to my life.
And those are my favorite, famous last words.
So I read Tim's book and it was like, this is a very good book.
Started going online, back with the baby internet as it existed.
All the news groups, you suck.
No, you suck.
I'm going to kill you.
You know, the bulletin boards as they existed in the 90s.
But there were some good UFO bulletin boards.
And I went down that.
And the next thing I knew, I just, I left.
I left the University of Rochester.
And it was a real crisis in my life because I'm in my early 30s.
I'm like, I've got all this ambition.
I wanted to do something.
I wanted to teach at a university.
But I just lost the belief.
I lost the belief in that whole system.
I lost the belief in academia.
I lost the belief that I wanted to do that anymore.
And I was totally obsessed with UFOs.
I would remember for an entire year, I'd lie in bed, staring at the ceiling, thinking
all of these if-thens.
Like, if this is real, then was I totally wrong about everything I thought I knew about history?
What is the truth then about the Truman administration that I was studying?
Or Eisenhower or Kennedy?
Like, there had to be this whole subterranean reality that I was oblivious to.
And when you think you're a smart person and you think you're well-educated, that's the
hardest because you want to, like, you've got your ego there.
I had my ego.
Like, absolutely.
I want to be like, I'm a smart guy.
I think I know everything.
But wait, oh, wow.
I missed this whole thing.
That's not easy to admit.
No, it's not when your identity is so tied up in the system.
The system's giving you positive feedback until that point to just accept, you know, that
sort of crumbling and finding something new, I think, is really tough.
But you do.
You read something like Timothy Good's, you know, Above Top Secret.
And you're like, this is a whole ontology separate from, you know, the reality that I know.
And it's so well-researched.
And it, you know, if you associate, you know, psyops around UFOs with, like, you know, American
intel, like he's coming up from British Ministry of Defense.
He starts with the Battle of Los Angeles, but he goes through, like, really the UK history.
And...
I'm impressed that you just can roll right through that.
I mean, I just tossed Tim Good out there.
And you're like, yeah, yeah.
Well, he's amazing.
I mean, you got to, you know, like, you got to pay respects to your stuff.
You got to pay respects.
You got to know that these are canonical, I think, you know, works.
Today's episode is sponsored by Incogni.
You ever Google yourself and realize how much of your personal info is just out there?
Your address, your phone number, old jobs, even your relatives, all online for anyone to see?
There are these companies called data brokers, and they make a living collecting and selling
that information without you ever knowing it.
They sell it to marketers, recruiters, even risk assessment firms.
Worst case, it ends up in the hands of scammers or identity thieves.
That's why I started using Incogni.
It's a service that automatically contacts over 230 data brokers and demands they delete
your personal data.
And if your info ends up online again, Incogni keeps going, resubmitting removals on your behalf.
I didn't have to do anything after signing up.
It's just set it and forget it.
I also learned something wild.
In the U.S., people search sites are a separate problem.
They publish these creepy dossiers on you, property records, family info, even political
affiliations.
Incogni has a custom removals feature that targets those too.
So if you care about privacy, which if you're watching this show, you probably do, give it
a try.
Go to incogni.com slash AmericanAlchemy and use my code to get 60% off an annual plan.
Thank you to Incogni for sponsoring this episode.
In UFOs and the National Security State, you bring up this idea of a breakaway civilization.
And you have Catherine Austin Fitz, this former housing and urban development employee, who
then went on to be a consultant, who's uncovered trillions of dollars worth of fraud.
Discrepancies in accounting, yeah.
Discrepancies in accounting.
Yeah, there you go.
That's a nice euphemism.
So what is a breakaway civilization and what is the nature of the contact that we're seeing?
Yeah, I haven't really thought, I haven't talked a lot about the idea of a breakaway
civilization in a little while, but I still think it's probably true.
And just to give a background, it was a phrase that I coined, I don't know, about almost 20
years ago now.
I do a lot of reading of other types of historians and I was reading a story named Arnold Toynbee.
Some of you know of him.
He writes meta histories of civilizations.
And I was kind of in that headspace and I thought, you know, what is it that actually
makes a civilization distinctive and unique?
And I thought, well, there's a lot of things.
There's like your social structure and your economy and your ideology, your cosmology.
And I thought, you know, if you really think about the classified world, especially like
assuming like the Roswell event or other crash retrievals happened, you have this very, very
deep classified structure that keeps the technology and the science classified away from you and
away from me so that we can't really look at it.
And I thought, well, what do they do with those breakthroughs in their technology?
Well, they're going to learn new things and they're going to privately maybe patent them
and keep them away from the rest of us.
And they're just in danger of running more and more away from this.
Will they have functional flying saucers one day?
Can they go off world?
Can they encounter other beings and all of this?
And I thought, well, they're really actually kind of like a separate civilization when it's
broken away from our own.
And it was a totally theoretical idea.
It still is, I guess.
But I think there's evidence for it in a lot of different ways.
And so that's what I was talking about.
And I think it's a kind of a breakaway group that has its own legal protections and all
of that.
So I've known Catherine Austin Fitz for many years.
I absolutely admire her work.
She's a brilliant financial expert, you could say.
She did.
She served with the first George Bush senior administration back in the late 80s, early 90s
as assistant secretary of housing and urban development.
She told a story.
It should be funny, but it's actually really tragic.
She said, when I went into HUD, I said, I want to look at the accounting.
I want to look at all the books.
And they said, well, no, you're not authorized to see that.
She says, hell, I'm not authorized to see that.
So she finally got her way.
And she said, what happened when they brought in the financial records?
She said, you know, the old library carts with all the books on them, she said, they
wheeled in one after another filled, stacked with papers, like organized, disorganized.
And she's like, God could not pull this apart.
She said, you'd need the greatest accountants in the world to undo this god awful mess.
And she concluded, like, this whole system is designed so that it is impossible to audit.
And that was her start.
And then she goes through four years of that.
And she had her own amazing tumultuous journey dealing with analyzing U.S. government.
And then eventually looking into, she wrote a really great paper called The Myth of the
Rule of Law.
I highly recommend it.
And then she told a really interesting story about, I think, in 1998, she was invited by
a gentleman named John Peterson of the Arlington Institute.
John Peterson was on many, many short lists for DOD Secretary of Defense position for years.
And she wrote about this.
And he said, we're doing a little get-together of a mini-conference to discuss what it would
be like in a world where extraterrestrials are openly acknowledged as living among us.
And she said, the biggest regret in my life was not doing that.
She was afraid.
Because she, at that time, she was looking at connections of the U.S. government and drug
trafficking, intelligence communities, and all of this.
And she knew that they were after her.
And she was afraid that this was like a setup.
And so she didn't do it.
But she, I think she came to regret that.
But anyway, that's Catherine.
And she's come to look at discrepancies in financial doings of the Pentagon and the federal
government in general.
So back in 01, Donald Rumsfeld famously, before the House Armed Services Committee in, I think,
July of 01, just before 9-11.
Now, the Bush administration were brand new at this time.
So in a sense, what he's about to say was no skin off their nose.
This is really indicting Clinton years.
He said, yeah, we've looked at the Pentagon records.
And there's 2 point, I think he said 2.3.
Well, he kept revising it.
But originally, it was $2.3 trillion in unaccounted expenditures.
He said, if you can believe that, chuckle, chuckle, laugh, laugh in the House.
And that became $2.1 trillion on September 10th.
And then came 9-11.
And then you never hear about this again.
That was kind of like gone.
A few months later, there was a guy named Dov Zachheim who took over the accounting of
all of that.
And he, this is like in 2002.
And he's like, yeah, no, we got to figure it out.
It's all done.
We've just, you know, had to look at the books a little more carefully.
And it's down to zero.
We have no more discrepancies.
Literally, that is what he said.
But anyway, so Catherine's been on top of this all these years.
And then the question arises, does this mean the money's missing?
Or is it just you've got accounting discrepancies where you're not getting your books right?
I do think a lot of it is that.
It doesn't mean that $2.3 trillion got stolen.
But it does mean there's a lot of opportunity for money to just go missing.
And one thing she has always said is our accounting, our global financial system, she says, is like
an open window.
It's not a closed system.
It's an open system.
So in other words, the money goes out somewhere.
And this is where she and I really connected because she's like, I think that this idea
of a breakaway civilization is really right on.
And I think some of this money is going, a lot of this money is going to that, to support
and fund and, you know, keep that whole thing secure.
And I believe in her Tucker Carlson interview, she mentions your work.
And he's like, where is all this money going?
And she goes, well, talk to Richard Dolan.
And she goes, space, very vaguely.
But like, you know, the implication is almost like they're using this in some of these, you
know, some of this off the books UFO research.
I believe also that Jordan, not Jordan, John Peterson story, where they're doing a simulation
of, you know, extraterrestrial contact at the Arlington Institute.
This is from a researcher named Linda Thompson.
She's very active on Twitter.
She's great.
She said that John Peterson promised to show Catherine Austin Fitz a UFO if she would stop
engaging in her research.
I don't think I caught that one.
That's interesting.
I don't know.
Yeah.
Interesting.
Do you think...
By the way, John Peterson and his wife, along with James Woolsey, CIA director at the time,
and his wife were the people who invited Stephen Greer to a dinner in the early 90s in which
Greer has many times talked about this.
So I'm not really spilling any beans here.
Just kind of interesting connections going on here.
And I think you interviewed him.
I did.
Yeah.
I don't know if that ever came up.
I don't know if it was an interview.
But so you have all the trillions of dollars off the books.
She's talking about deep underground military bases and facilities.
Do we have documentation that this exists?
And how far have we made it?
Presumably some of this might be getting siphoned off.
You know, we all probably believe that there's some reality to the UFO story.
Is some of this money being spent on reverse engineering UFOs?
Well, all we can say is, I think so.
We think so.
Is there proof?
That's a hard thing for me to say.
I don't know what I can say in terms of proof.
There's a tremendous amount of good research showing that we have these so-called DUMs,
deep underground military bases.
I don't think there's any question that that's real.
We all know that there are such things.
I used to work kind of closely with a gentleman named Richard Sauter, who's done a lot of work
on underground base construction.
He went through the documentation.
I think he made a very, very strong case that even back in the 40s and 50s, we were looking,
the military was looking strong about how to go deep.
You know, partially, a lot of it's legit.
You know, if they're worried about like nuclear war, nuclear exchange,
how do we have secure underground facilities that are not, that are impervious to attack?
But, of course, a lot of other things can happen.
In those things.
Not just underground, but potentially in the oceans.
This is, I don't think this is necessarily impossible.
If you have the ability to go under the ocean floor, at least in maybe the shelf areas,
where they're a little more shallow, there's a lot of possibilities here.
In terms of proof, it's difficult.
You know, a lot of this stuff is hidden very, very well.
Hidden in plain sight, perhaps.
But to answer your question, I don't know if I can answer it.
I think all of these are somewhat unanswerable questions, but you're as qualified as anybody.
What is your opinion of these new sightings of unidentified objects?
With all due respect to the Air Force, I believe that some of them will prove to be of interplanetary origin.
My mind just went here, and it's somewhat of a non sequitur.
But mid-century UFO stuff.
I remember watching a video of you talking about a letter that FDR had written about a very destructive weapon that America had acquired.
And that had come from extraterrestrials.
And you thought that that was maybe a valid letter.
Am I getting this wrong?
So, well, I'm trying to think, you might, there's the so-called majestic documents.
You know, one of the people at this conference where we are is Ryan Wood, who's a very good friend of mine.
I've known Ryan for years.
He and his late father, Dr. Bob Wood, of course, are the curators of the majestic documents,
which are kind of related to the MJ-12 documents to some extent.
And Ryan and his dad did extensive forensic analyses of those.
Those are not just photographic negatives.
Those are actual pieces of paper that you can study them.
But what you can say with the MJ-12 documents.
So they first appeared in 1984.
They were probably sent from somewhere near Kirtland Air Force Base.
And so we know that.
That's a connection to the notorious Richard Doty.
And they were sent to a filmmaker and friend of a Bill Moore researcher, a guy named Jamie Chanderay,
who has his own, had his own very interesting intel connections, I believe.
So that's how we get them.
Now, the thing is, you set the stage for this.
So in the late 70s and the early 80s, the UFO field is being rocked by two major developments.
So one was the recently strengthened Freedom of Information Act.
So in the late 70s and through the 80s, early 80s, UFO researchers could petition the government for documents.
And they were getting thousands of pages of documents related to UFOs.
This was a shocking thing.
You know, all through the 50s and 60s and most of the 70s, the government agencies, CIA, FBI, military agencies,
said, look, we don't really do this.
This is not an interest of ours.
We don't really give a damn.
And then suddenly, thousands of pages of military failed interceptions and CIA memos and FBI investigations.
Like, it's all there.
It's like they were clearly lying.
So that's one thing.
And so from that perspective alone, if you're on the side of the secrecy, you're thinking,
are they going to shake the tree just enough and then the right document is going to come out and now we're screwed?
Like, is that going to happen?
So that was a concern.
The other prong, the other threat to secrecy were the researchers who were engaging into looking in crash retrievals.
People like the late Leonard Stringfield, who was the true pioneer of crash retrieval research, but also Stanton Friedman, also Kevin Randall and Don Schmidt and the late Don Berliner and then Tom Carey and all these people.
So like there, but in the late 70s, there was a lot of this was just slowly building.
It wasn't, we didn't really know a lot about Roswell at that, just, we're just starting to talk about Roswell.
But that was a threat, so these two things.
And then in the wake of all of that, we get these MJ-12 documents, which are allegedly memos to Harry Truman or letters signed by Harry Truman describing the formation of this organization to manage the UFO secret, referring to crash retrievals and Roswell and all of this.
And so it, you know, you had a lot of skeptics, the late Philip Klass, a man that I think was deeply, deeply connected to the U.S. intelligence community, in my opinion, not just mine, said, well, you know, Truman's signature, that was not his actual signature.
It was identical to another one.
Well, I think they were using auto pen then as well, actually, if I'm not mistaken.
I don't really know if that matters, but that was supposed to make it like fake.
It was a fake, so it was a hoax.
New York Times was very happy to support that.
But, and there are, you know, legit strong researchers who do think it's a hoax.
Robert Hastings, who you mentioned, very strong, very strong.
And he and I in the past had some disagreements about that.
And I very much respect Robert's research, so don't get me wrong there.
But he does not, he does not believe that they're legit.
And a lot of people don't.
I don't know.
I don't feel that way.
I think that, I don't know about those MJ-12 documents.
I don't really know where I stand on that.
But I think when I look at the majestic documents that Ryan and Bob collected, you print them
all out.
It's this thick.
It's like an inch and a half thick.
And you just try reading them sometime.
I did this, you know, 20 years ago.
I was afraid of looking at this for the longest time, but I thought, all right, I have to read
them.
I printed them all off.
I put them in my own little comb-bound collection and I just started reading them page after
page.
And they are highly sophisticated, extremely sophisticated, frankly.
And so if you're thinking of this as a hoax, you have to ask yourself, who's creating this
as a hoax?
All right.
You have documents that are through the decades, the 40s and in the 50s and in the 60s, all
in a very, like, seems exactly accurate format.
The data that's in them is written in exactly the correct way.
So it's not some guy in his basement doing it all by himself, that's for sure.
Yeah, there's documents in there.
And actually, my memory is a little more fuzzy on this, maybe, than yours at this moment.
But FDR did have some statements or letters, I believe, where he expressed an awareness
of this phenomenon.
There's another letter, supposedly, from Albert Einstein, Robert Oppenheimer.
Very interesting document.
Yeah, I mean, those are debated.
And I don't spend a lot of my time really fixating on them, but I go back to them every
once in a while.
And I suspect that there is a lot of truth in them.
I do, too.
I wonder if they, you know, you know the name James Jesus Angleton, of course?
Oh, yes, yes.
So, you know, one of the founders of the CIA, kind of an Alan Dulles acolyte, very deceptive
and devious.
He ran U.S.
counterintelligence for several decades.
Several decades and seemed very involved in the UFO issue.
And this is really interesting.
He was actually stationed in Italy at the time, or his father was, Hugh Angleton, at
the time of the Magenta crash in 1933, which is really crazy.
I only recently learned this.
Maybe they get that with you in Malmgren's interview.
I think maybe that's where I picked it up.
But there are rumors that the Knights of Malta have something to do with the UFO story as
well.
Well, what I'm saying is, yeah, they did, because Angleton was there.
And so it's interesting, you know, I've heard, and I don't know if this is true, that maybe
he had something to do with the MJ-12 leaks.
And in the 80s, it felt like largely maybe the U.S. moved from a strategy of, you know,
secrecy and denial to flood the zone.
And flood the zone doesn't mean put out, you know, BS.
It means put out partial truths and put out a lot of truths.
That is the way disinformation works.
This is something we, I'm really glad you bring this up, because what is disinformation?
It's not the same as lies, you know, like, so let's say we're on the inside and we've
got this secret to protect and we are afraid, like at some point this is going to come out.
So how do we deal with this?
So maybe you put it out, but you sandwich it between things or you stick at least one
thing in there that can be factually demonstrated to be a hoax or a lie.
And that's, you know, that's an inoculation.
It's like you get inoculated against a disease by getting part of a virus, but it's deadened and
your body recognizes it and can fight it.
So it's like you become inoculated against the truth.
The truth is put out there, but it's sandwiched in such a way that it's, it's not credible.
I love that.
You say you're, you're immune to it.
And, uh, you know, it's interesting.
I think you have blue book where it's just kind of rationalized, explain the whole thing
away.
The Condit committee sort of kills it.
And then in 74, Hynek seems to flip and they create, you know, UFOs past, present and future.
And from then on, there seems to be this kind of outward openness on the part of the DOD
around, you know, UFOs.
And in the, in the eighties, it feels like you, you know, you have Rick Doty doing all
his stuff and you have, you have this sort of flood the zone.
Like we're actually going to actively promote and see if this is peak Cold War era.
I would say yes and no.
I mean, you know, officially the Pentagon throughout the seventies and eighties and nineties was
like, no, this is nonsense.
I don't do this at all.
So officially speaking, there was never any, uh, to my knowledge, a genuine promotion of
a UFO reality coming from that institution.
So I just say that, but there were, let's call them shenanigans going on.
And, you know, we've learned about Richard Doty, which is a really weird topic for me because,
um, I actually met Richard Doty once.
Okay.
Uh, he's extremely gracious, genuinely, like he's a nice guy when you meet him.
Yeah.
And I, and I know, I'm sure he's extremely likable.
That was his job.
He is.
Yeah.
So, so you gotta be, but right.
That doesn't mean he's truthful, of course.
Yeah, yeah.
Um, but I do know for a fact that he has very high respect from within, um, a lot of his
colleagues from the intelligence community and from the, you know, the, the peripheral,
um, like scientists and people who've worked with him, they like him.
Um, they respect him.
His own father was, uh, I don't know all the details, but was deeply involved in Area 51
and with UFOs.
I didn't know that.
Yes.
And Richard Doty was kind of brought into that as a young, uh, office or young military
person.
So he, like when he says these days, like he knows it's true, which he says many times,
like, I, I think he's telling the truth on that.
And I think he is saying he knows it's true because he does know it's true.
Um, you know, in the early eighties, late seventies, early eighties, and I'm not here
to defend this, but he was doing his job.
Look, he was in the military.
His job was to, um, I assume protect certain secrets that were wrapped by Kirtland Air Force
Base and the like.
Paul Benowitz was very highly intelligent man looking at some of them and, and that's what
Doty did.
So he, he did kind of lead Benowitz astray there.
Doty also first shows up.
This is kind of a little known thing about Doty in 1977 Ellsworth Air Force Base.
Mario Woods has an experience where he is, uh, according to his hypnotic regression abducted
at the very least, he ends up 10 miles away from Ellsworth Air Force Base with marks on
his body and his, his partner, Michael Johnson in a catatonic state.
He then goes through this whole debrief session and guess who's there, Rick Doty.
And so it is interesting that I, I think a pretty, at least if you're into UFO stuff, you
know, the Mario Woods case seems pretty legit to me.
It's an, a line of, you know, all the Robert Hastings, UFOs and nukes.
Yeah.
And then you have Doty show up, you know, a couple of years later and he's definitely
psyoping, you know, Benowitz.
Yeah.
And there's an Ells, there's a document about Ellsworth there, which has been manipulated
and that's been traced back to Doty.
So at least I'm pretty sure.
So, you know, the thing is, well, I'm not, I'm, I'm, I'm not going to like condemn and
I, I try not to wag the finger too much at people.
Like it's easy to do that.
Um, everyone's got a job to do.
Yeah.
Uh, we have a job to do, which is to get past the BS and to try to understand the truth.
And, um, well, I always say it's, it's, it's dangerous enough just going for the truth.
So don't go ad hominem against like, yeah, there are people who it's like, it's obvious
that they're sort of counter and tell or whatever.
Right.
But like, it would be one thing if they were clearly leading you astray on a single thing
consistently.
And you're like, come on, dude, stop doing that or whatever.
But I think, you know, some people want you to stop your pursuit of truth in order to
just antagonize those counter and tell people or whatever.
And then you're, you're sort of losing, you're going to get less close to the truth and you're
going to nuke yourself.
And it's just like, so it's like, what do you, what do you want?
Like we all, we've all grown up.
We all know the government does all kinds of stuff and lies and lies.
I've started saying this probably before many other people.
I've been on this for a long time.
Of course, I did a whole study on the history of false flags a few years ago.
And so yes, we know there's shenanigans and they never stop, but is every single thing
and up and, and what I'm hearing are like some, some people out there, like they, it's
almost like there's the implication is the government wants us to believe in UFOs.
Now, therefore they want, and they want us to believe in aliens.
Now, therefore it must all be black budget, special ops.
That's right.
That the whole alien thing is a ruse.
And I'm like, that is so wrong.
Yeah.
You are so wrong.
If you do that and you're going down a very incorrect path.
Yeah.
Well, it's this reflexive, if the government says something, I'm going to put a minus sign
against it.
Right.
And so you're going to be totally thought controlled as a result.
If you have some, and maybe there is some, it is important to have the hermeneutic understanding
of where the government stands on a thing.
But, but there is no, the government is the whole thing.
That's true.
They're talking like, Oh, the guy, but what you have is, I mean, look, the Pentagon alone
is a trillion dollars a year is a mountain of labyrinths and fighting bureaucracies.
And I can tell you for a fact, you go back to the earliest UFO history, and there's always
been factional wars on this subject within the military, within the intelligence community.
They don't all agree on policy.
They have never agreed on policy.
In the 1940s and early 50s, there were factions that wanted openness on UFOs from within that
military.
We know that read, read the old books by Donald Kehoe.
He actually lays it out very well.
So that was the case then.
It is the case now.
And there are people, I'll just, we'll just mention Lou here again, who within that system
who support openness.
And there are other people who absolutely do not, and they will fight to the last, you
know, the last battle that they can.
So that's the fact.
And so when you're getting messages coming out of there, it's not, it's not like a unified
system.
It's like, who's the faction that's speaking there?
Yeah.
It's a war that is going on.
And, and we need to understand this.
Yes.
Do they understand that there's a war going on inside our establishment right now, which
is in real trouble?
Yep.
Like, okay, there's a lot of desperation on a lot of fronts, UFOs and beyond.
That's going to breed factional disputes galore and hard, you know, battle plans from within
to, to disable the other side.
Totally.
I don't understand that.
I couldn't agree more.
And I think, uh, there are probably less outright liars in the space than people trying
to front run the truth.
So you see disclosure is going to happen.
You, maybe you have to get in front of it or something.
And so I think there are all sorts of, you know, factions battling on that front.
Speaking of secret science, which I agree with you, I think the second you look at this
topic for a week plus, you realize that there probably is secret science going on.
And there's a real UFO phenomenon going on.
And those two are two disparate threats.
We spoke on the phone once about Thomas Townsend Brown.
I don't know if you remember this.
Oh, a little bit.
Yeah.
And you told me an interesting story.
What the hell did I say?
I can't remember what I said.
I talked about how his work might've made it into the B2 stealth bomber.
And then you got an interesting anecdote.
Oh yeah, I do.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I'll tell this.
This is true.
Yeah.
So back in 2008, I was at a conference in, uh, was it in Vegas or in Denver?
I think in Las Vegas.
So yeah.
And I met with a brilliant, very cool, retired air force colonel with a PhD.
So, uh, he had a very strong knowledge of the UFO topic.
He, uh, we had a lot of interesting conversations.
I met him and I met his wife too.
He's really nice lady.
So we sat down and he's, one of the things he said is he was part of the B2 stealth bomber
project.
And I said, Oh, I was so like young.
I was so enthusiastic.
And I just read a paper by, um, Paul Lavoillette.
Yes.
Who is a researcher on electrogravitics and had things to say about the B2 stealth bomber,
uh, having incorporated essentially, basically principles of electrogravitics to give it a
form of lift, um, an additional kind of lift.
So, uh, yeah.
So I'm sitting with this colonel and I'm like here and he's like closer to me than you are
right now.
Um, and, uh, and also we were in a pretty crowded area.
So there's like people milling about, you know, and I'm not recording anything.
I'm just, we're just talking.
And, uh, I said, see, have you heard this paper by Paul Lavoillette talking about electrogravitics,
uh, as part of the B2?
And he, he was so nice, but at this moment he literally put his hand out like this.
Stop.
And he looked this way and he looked this way and he leaned forward and he just whispered,
that's bullshit.
And, and he wouldn't talk anything more about it.
And as soon as he said that, I thought, all right, that's gotta be true.
Yeah.
That's a kind of a telltale sign.
Uh, definitely.
Yeah.
It was very interesting moment.
I didn't think I would hit a sore spot like that or something that's sensitive, but it
was clearly very sensitive.
Yeah.
It's so fascinating.
And, um, as a good segue to, you know, your current work on a USO submersible objects,
Thomas Townsend Brown was actually a Navy guy.
Yeah.
And, um, it seems like, you know, he was in the Navy, I think from like 1933 to 42.
And it seems like the Navy knew a thing or two maybe about UFOs before the air force actually
did.
It's totally possible.
Yes.
Um, absolutely.
For example, one USO account, which is actually the account that started me on, on, uh, this
book project that I've, I'm in nearly done.
I did the first volume.
That's out two and three are coming out.
Uh, was an account, uh, right by the Aleutian islands, uh, near a little island called Adak
Island, uh, in the summer, excuse me, of 1945.
So it's, uh, the Pacific war was still happening.
Uh, the European war was done by then.
And there was a US transport ship called the Deloroff, which was coming back from Japan
to Seattle.
And it was passing by, it's still in the middle of ocean, but North of it, the closest Aleutian
Island was this place called Adak.
You can look it up on Google earth.
Um, and according to the primary witness who was interviewed, a man named Robert Crawford,
he, and he spoke with a number of researchers, including Dr. James McDonald, who's kind of
a legend himself.
Anyway, Crawford said, yeah, we, uh, the crews, we, they saw this.
He didn't see the object come from the water.
He saw it right after that.
But other people did see it emerge from the water, disc shaped object, about 200 feet in
diameter, circled their transport ship twice, totally silent.
He said there were high winds.
This thing should have been bouncing around in the wind.
It was rock solid, totally stable.
And then it zipped off, uh, to, I think the East or Southeast so fast.
And he said, you could see this, uh, flash of light as it left.
So that's, that's US Navy.
You have just documented 670 something, uh, unidentified submersible object cases.
You've created this whole database and taxonomy around them.
Which case shocked you the most and why?
There's some very excellent ones.
One of the early ones did shock me.
It was from 1825 and it was in the South Pacific.
So it was a British vessel called the HMS Blonde.
There's a naturalist on board.
I liken it to, you know, in the movie Master and Commander, there was that great buddy of
Russell Crowe, the doctor.
And so I think of him as this type of a guy.
So he's the naturalist.
He wrote a diary.
His name is Andrew Bloxham.
And he kept a very detailed account of the, of the travels of this ship during this.
They actually went from, uh, from Hawaii to the UK, back to Hawaii, and then down to the
Cook Islands and on the way to South America.
And so on the return trip from Hawaii, they're passing the Cook Islands.
And he writes in his diary at 3.30 a.m. on August 12th, 1825.
It was about 200 years ago.
He said the night watch reported this orange spherical object rise from the ocean at seven degrees.
He said it lit the, the deck of the ship so bright you could pick a pin off the deck.
It then descended back into the water and then rose a second time and then descended into the water.
And what's interesting, you could, you could find this as a PDF online.
You could look it up.
And he, you know, before all of that, this is like just really detailed account of the travel.
It's very meticulous.
And after that, it's very like conventional, very meticulous, interesting.
He published this as a diary, uh, at the time.
So it's, it's been, it's been in publication for 200 years.
And there's just this one entry of this, this, he said it was red hot, like a cannon shot.
It was, I think about the size of the, of the moon or the sun.
Although there was no moon out that night.
So there's no commute, no, uh, confusion with that.
And that's it.
It's just this bizarre thing.
I read this and like, holy crap.
And what I, I like to pair it with another encounter from 150 years later involving a
United States aircraft carrier, the USS John F. Kennedy, which was in July 2nd, 1971.
It had just finished doing, um, a series of, of, uh, uh, qualification tests, which they
do periodically to stay, you know, current.
And we have this account from, uh, the man who ran communications at that time.
His name is James Kopp with a K and he wrote about this several times around 2000, 2001.
Uh, he spoke to the disclosure project in, in 2000.
So he's on record for that.
So anyway, this is what he says.
July 2nd, 1971.
It's eight 30 at night.
He's running the comms and he said, all the in, inbound communications start spouting gibberish.
He's like, Hmm, what's going on?
And then he, he's on the, the, and he hears on the intercom some, some sailor like freaking
out, screaming, it's God.
It's the end of the world.
That's what he hears.
Yeah.
So that gets his attention.
So he goes out, uh, and outside to see a glowing orange, like roiling orange, yellowish, reddish.
Um, I think he's, I'm thinking he said it was the size of a beach ball at arm's length, which
would be kind of big.
It was just above the ship or maybe off to the side.
It wasn't totally clear.
He said, I'm standing there watching this for about 20 seconds.
A lot of other people.
He said sailors were, uh, one guy, he said he had to be sedated.
This was a really intense moment.
Um, and then the ship goes to battle station, uh, general quarters, battle station.
So he had to go back to his comm and he didn't see it after that.
But for the next 20 minutes, the ship was on battle, uh, on general quarters.
And he, uh, stated that the weapon systems went offline.
He learned later.
And, um, trying to think what else.
That was essentially it.
So no communications, no weapons.
And, and then that ended.
And he doesn't know how this departed because he didn't get to see it.
But that's his story.
And then he actually said, by the time we got into port a few days later, uh, the only,
the only discussion about this at all was from the ship's captain.
He got on the ship's intercom and said, well, as you all know, uh, certain things happen
aboard a U S naval vessel that have to remain on the vessel and not to be discussed anywhere
else.
I hope I made myself clear, you know, something like that.
And that was it.
That was it.
So, but, but what was interesting made me think of it is that this was, I mean, it sounded
like it could have been the exact same type of thing that Andrew Bloxham back in 1825 was
describing this spherical object.
And, uh, I guess I'll just say, you know, we hear a lot of people talking these days
about orbs and spheres.
And I, I have to say and noticed a large number of USO encounters do involve these kinds of
orb like spherical objects, uh, which frequently, and certainly I think in the case of the JFK,
uh, engage in some kind of lecture magnetic interference.
And there's a lot of that.
A lot of that goes on.
Um, I guess I'll just add when I finished doing all of these, uh, cases and hunting them
down and all of these disparate sources and just generally wanting to breathe life into
them.
Most of these were completely forgotten cases, but, uh, had a long, a lot of long conversations
with my wife, Tracy about this.
And she said, you know, you should really look at, pull out some relevant categories for
each of these cases.
And I did that.
I pulled out each case like 15 different categories, like, uh, special effects from there.
Was it at daytime or at nighttime?
What, what was the shape of the object and all of this.
And what I noticed after looking at all of the statistics and I, I put a very amateurish
spreadsheet together, but large, large, but amateurish spreadsheet, but it helped me to see patterns.
And, um, I noticed about 10% of all the cases involved EM interference, about one out of
10.
It's quite a lot, but one, that, that percentage has doubled when I looked at the military cases.
There was one, so there was a, a, a two X likelihood that a military encounter would
have electromagnetic interference.
I'll just add one other thing about that in the, in the few cases where people reported
missing time with the USO encounter, and there are such, or sightings of a being in connection
to a USO.
And there's a few of those, those, those instances are four times as likely to report
electromagnetic interference.
And when I looked at these numbers, I mean, maybe my data sample's small, I don't know,
but it's as large as, as, you know, whatever it is.
But it makes me think that these EM encounters, they're not accidental.
They're, they're kind of a tool, maybe a weapon.
Like they're not, it's not a random thing.
So, um, I'm getting a little off track here, but it's just, it was fascinating going into
all of these, uh, uh, looking at these, uh, trends and these relationships that exist
within these sightings, uh, there's an intelligence and they, those guys, they know what they're
doing.
They know exactly what they're doing.
Do we have a USO crash retrieval program?
The thing that comes to mind for me is I think Howard Hughes had like a, it was like a front
company for the CIA.
It was called like global Marine corporation.
And out of that came the Glomar Explorer.
And, uh, you know, we know that we've retrieved exotic technology from the
ocean floor.
So have we possibly retrieved the USOs?
I think, yes.
Uh, I believe it's probably a yes.
The Glomar Explorer, yeah, this huge corporation, they actually recovered a, a sunken Soviet submarine
in the 1970s.
And it was an incredible feat because they went down something like three miles down to
the Pacific floor.
They got it, it broke, um, but they, they recovered half of it.
They actually gave a proper military burial to some of the Soviet sailors that they recovered.
So that was an incredible thing.
And, um, in terms of recovering disks, I once, I received a, a communication from a, um, a
gentleman who was former US Navy.
He told me about having attended a conference, uh, not this one, but another, another excellent
one, the International UFO Congress, a really great place there.
And he said, you know, I'm, I'm hanging outside and I run to this other Navy guy between lectures
and we're just chatting.
And this guy was, um, aboard the USS Nautilus submarine.
So that was the first nuclear powered submarine.
And he said, you know, the Nautilus went through a retrofitting or a refitting, excuse me, in the
mid sixties, which is true.
We know about this.
And he said, one thing that, um, that we did is we had like this, we created this hatch,
this side hatch to be able to acquire objects that were, uh, disks, uh, unknown, unknown objects,
um, in the ocean.
Now, I mean, uh, this guy, the guy like wrote to me and then, and then he, he never really
was able to follow up with this Navy guy.
So he lost that whole thread.
So he wrote to me and we went back and forth on it.
And, um, I, I reported that it's in, it's in my first volume here.
I don't know if this is true or not, like, because a Navy submarine is not going to be
able to go down to the ocean, the bottom of the ocean floor.
That is way too deep, but it can, you know, about 10 or 15% of our oceans are basically
ocean shelf.
And that might be a different thing.
And you might be able to, um, have a submarine kind of work, work that area.
You know, if, if this is a true thing, um, definitely look, we have a long, long history.
Crash retrievals is a really strong interest of mine personally.
And there is no question we've had a number of crash retrievals or recoveries of these UAP.
We could do a whole interview on that.
Frankly, there's just a lot to say about that.
And now those are retrievals that we know about from land.
Um, you know, the waters of this world are, are much more remote to us and much more mysterious.
And I don't think a lot of these stories come through.
I did, um, there is one gentleman that, uh, I did speak to many years ago.
His name is David Noble Whitehorse.
And he was, uh, did you want to talk about this?
Yeah, we did.
I thought we did.
Yeah.
So, and did you interview him?
No, but it made its way into the Malmgren thing that I did.
And then I realized it was actually, you know, I think there, yeah, it was a whole can of worms.
But this, I think it was a year before Malmgren.
I think that was actually a little off.
It was one year because it was, it wasn't Bluegill Triple Prime.
I think it was one year before.
Yeah.
62.
And he's a really interesting character.
He's a great guy.
I, you know, I interviewed him, uh, I don't know, 15 years ago and, uh, I can't even remember
how I found him, but we talked extensively and he was a member of, uh, aboard a U.S.
ship called the Finch back in 1962.
They were involved in what became Bluegill Triple Prime, part of what is called Operation
Dominic.
You can look this up.
And, uh, there's a series of high altitude nuclear detonations.
Uh, this is at the peak of like, we were just going crazy detonating these hydrogen, massive
hydrogen bombs.
It was crazy.
So he said it was, uh, October, this is like right around the time of the Cuban missile
crisis, October 25th, 1962.
They were off a little place called Johnston Island, which is about 500 miles off of Hawaii
out in the Pacific.
And he said, we did a detonation.
He said, we often would have bogeys in the atmosphere before we would do a detonation.
Like, that is UFOs.
And they would always disappear just before we would detonate the bomb.
So they're hanging out, checking it out, evidently.
He said on this occasion, so, uh, we, we had to do the debt, the detonation and we were all
ordered below deck.
This is protocol.
And then to his surprise, um, some of the officer or some other guy comes down and says,
you, you, you, and you, and you, I want you out now, uh, out on the, I think the port side,
one of the sides.
He says, you are now to face forward.
You are not to look to the left.
You are not to look to the right.
Just look ahead of you and observe.
And they're like, oh, okay, whatever.
Orders are orders.
And so a, what they see is this long cigar shaped object zooming by horizontally.
And that's all he saw.
Then he was doing a cross train with radar.
So later that day or evening, he's talking to the radar guys and they're all talking about
the bogey that was, seemed to be shot out of the sky.
And, and this is clearly what he saw.
And it landed, uh, at some point in the Pacific and they were sending a series of ships to go
and see about trying to recover it.
Fascinating.
So actually I, I, I did a little research.
I think the Finch might've been an earlier operation, Dominic test.
We can workshop this live or I don't know.
Anybody could search, but, um, there's, I have a lot of reason to believe that there
were anomalous objects that came out.
Actually Bob Jacobs, 1964, uh, you know, Vandenberg case.
He was stationed at Johnston at all a few months before the Vandenberg case where he saw, he was
a photo instrumentation specialist.
He was on big Sur and he saw a UFO wraparound Atlas 8F missile.
That's right.
And only two years apart.
And he said it was, you know, ubiquitous water cooler conversation that a UFO shoot down was
being used as a cover for shooting down a Soviet nuke.
The scuttlebutt at the time, by every single person on that Island, when I got there, this
was engineers, technicians, um, my airmen who had been down there before me.
Um, we were told that what happened is the, the Soviets had launched a nuke into orbit
up above us and JFK told Khrushchev, take that down.
So I found that to be an extremely interesting, uh, another firsthand testimony.
That's wacky.
And this was around Bluegill triple prime.
So this was, that was, you know, what this detonation that had happened a year earlier.
And then you have the whole Malmgren testimony, which I think is very important as well.
Um, I want to ask you, so this begets all sorts of questions around secrecy.
You know, everybody talks about the air force.
You have, uh, in 1947, uh, uh, Twining writing this memo, you know, he's the head of air material
command for the air force.
Uh, and he's expressing kind of earnest confusion as to how UFO, how UFOs work, but he says they're,
they're, you know, uh, real and not visionary or fictitious.
The office of Naval intelligence is the oldest, uh, uh, Intel, uh, organization in the U S you
know, 1890s.
Um, you know, they call it the silent service, the Navy.
Um, what does the Navy know and how deeply embedded are they in this issue?
Even the reports that came out, I think in 2020, 20 and 2021 were office of Naval intelligence
led.
Yeah.
Navy, I think has been deeply, deeply involved in this from the beginning.
It took me a long time, even, you know, researching this for years to fully appreciate just how
deep their involvement was.
If you go back and look at some of the original, uh, books that were published by people like
Donald Kehoe, he's one of the people that kind of was my springboard.
Uh, he kind of talks a lot about this.
Uh, Kehoe was a Marine, so associated with the Navy.
And so he knew a lot of top Navy brass.
He was friends with many admirals.
And, uh, so he had a real ear to what was going on there and described quite frequently
the rivalry between the Navy and the Air Force.
This is very well known.
I mean, after the second world war, the Air Force was the new organization.
They had a lot of prestige.
They were the only, uh, uh, branch that had nuclear weapons.
The Navy wanted their own nukes.
They eventually got it.
There was something around 1949 or so called the revolt of the admirals.
This was a big political, uh, fight between the Navy and the Air Force.
So there's all, there was all this kind of bureaucratic institutional rivalry that already
existed.
But it happened, it also had to do with this, the flying saucers, as they were being called
back then.
Uh, the Air Force was getting all the attention.
But one thing that Kehoe wrote about, even back then, was, like, Navy people were having
UFO encounters.
And the Navy personnel would get really angry because, uh, Air Force people would come on
the Navy ships and throw their weight around and take over the investigations.
And the Navy guys were really resentful of this.
The Secretary of the Navy in 1950 was a guy named Dan Kimball.
He had his own UFO sighting.
So he was, he was flying in duel, uh, with, uh, Admiral Arthur Radford, who's quite famous.
They were flying out from California to Hawaii, uh, in 1950.
I think it was 1950.
Yes.
And, uh, Kehoe wrote about this.
So what happened was, Kimball's plane and Radford's plane were both accosted by an object
that circled around their aircraft.
They were, like, a number of miles apart.
But they both had this happen.
And as a result, Kimball decided, we are going to have our own separate investigation of this.
The hell with the Air Force.
But, uh, at least according to what Kehoe learned, it didn't seem to take off.
It didn't really go anywhere.
But their, the rivalry was always there.
I think Ross Colthart is, is somewhere here.
And he ended up having a conversation with Nat Kobitz, who is Director of Science and Technology
for the Navy.
And, um, this is the end of Nat's life.
I think he was dying of cancer.
And he said that he had seen UFO technology at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base.
And it was involved these sort of, you know, um, bonded metals that were fabricated at the
atomic level and said all sorts of other interesting stuff.
So, yeah, I've, I've heard about this.
I've not actually listened to it yet.
And I'm, I'm kind of really excited about doing that.
General Eisenhower is called back to duty, meeting Defense Secretary James Forrestal to
discuss many vital questions.
So, uh, one other kind of interesting axis around that time, Navy, uh, James Forrestal.
So, James Forrestal was the Secretary of Navy before becoming, uh, Secretary of Defense,
meeting a very mysterious, untimely death.
He was murdered.
Okay.
Let's hear that.
He was absolutely murdered.
Did he have anything to do with the UFO issue?
Maybe.
Yeah, probably.
Okay.
Probably.
Yeah.
So, uh, Forrestal, this was one of my real pet projects when I broke into this field.
And, uh, Forrestal was a fascinating, very brilliant man.
Of course, uh, kind of a financial wizard.
Uh, I think he played football at Princeton back in, you know, as an undergraduate.
Just, so then he becomes, um, after he makes his fortune, he becomes one of those so-called
dollar a year men, uh, under FDR for the war, basically to support the war effort.
He becomes undersecretary of the Navy and then secretary of the Navy at the end of the
war.
And he, um, he was actually one of these guys who fought against a strong secretary
of defense position.
When, when, um, we were going through the reorganization in 1947, National Security Act,
uh, kind of a total, let's like, we're done with the Republic.
We're creating the empire now, people.
And we got to reorganize the whole military system.
Forrestal fought tenaciously for naval independence under a unified secretary.
And, and the real issue was, does the SecDef have budgetary authority over the independent
services?
That was, that's really where the power is.
And, and, and Forrestal particularly fought so well that he won that battle and the secretary
of defense, uh, originally did not have the authority to tell the army and the Navy and
the air force what their budget would be.
He didn't have that capability.
So he was a weak SecDef.
And then irony of ironies, Forrestal ends up in that position as secretary of defense.
So he, uh, for his entire two and a half year tenure in that role, one of the biggest problems
he had with Truman, we tend to forget this, was that the, uh, that Truman wanted to cut
the military budget significantly.
At the same time, he wanted to expand U.S. military presence globally.
So it's kind of a disconnect there.
And the, uh, the joint chiefs were saying like, $15 billion a year out of your mind, which of
course that's nothing today.
But at the time it was also not very much.
They wanted like 30 billion, I think.
And Forrestal sided with them, but he was kind of stuck because Truman's just like, just make
it happen.
And so they had a very unhappy relationship over that.
Then at the same time, we have the flying saucers making their appearance in, in the military
world and in the American psyche.
It's like we're talking about it.
And this was something that he was definitely very aware of.
It was impossible not to be.
Um, I read Forrestal's published two volume diaries, uh, which were published after his
death.
We'll get to his death in a second.
And of course, there's not a, not a mention of, of UFOs or flying saucers in there.
But anyway, so what, what ended up happening?
So, uh, Forrestal and Truman, their relationship became rocky.
Truman's up for reelection in 1948.
Everyone's like, sure, he's going to lose.
Thomas Dewey, the Republicans, sure, win.
And, and, and Forrestal, bad move, had met with Dewey and it got out and Truman was pissed
and like, you betrayed me.
Uh, but anyway, so Truman wins, shocks the world, tells Forrestal shortly after that, you're
done.
I think in January 49, he says, you're out, you're out.
And they give, but you know, publicly they give Forrestal this nice, uh, going away ceremony.
It's like, you're a great American and all this stuff.
And this is the crazy thing.
So for, it's January 49, Forrestal leaves this ceremony and gets into a limousine.
And in the limousine is the secretary of the air force, Stuart Symington.
Now Symington was like one of Forrestal's major political enemies.
Forrestal was convinced, and I bet he was right, that he was being followed.
Uh, Symington was probably involved.
There was a journalist back then named Drew Pearson who was writing stories about Forrestal.
And people were noticing all throughout this time that Forrestal seemed like he was unraveling.
He started developing these weird, nervous tics.
He said, I'm being followed by strange, foreign looking men.
He's looking around.
He's very paranoid.
He started, uh, dipping his fingers into glasses of water all the time and just wetting his lips.
Like there's some weird thing going on with him.
So, um, so he gets out of this meeting and he goes into the limo and there's Stuart Symington, who they hate each other.
And all that we know is that Symington said this, I want to talk to you about something.
No one, to my knowledge, knows what actually happened on the limo ride back.
They were going back to Forrestal's office.
And, but what we do know is that when Forrestal got out of that limo, he was, he goes into his office, closes the door.
And he's shut in there for, like, hours.
Finally, his secretary knocks on the door and she opens the door and he's, he's sitting in his chair.
He's just staring ahead at like this blank wall.
And he's repeating one sentence.
What is it?
You are a loyal fellow.
So, he's out of it.
So they start making the phone calls, you know.
And suddenly the team comes and they collect him.
And they fly him down to Hobie Sound in Florida.
And he's there for, I think, six weeks, five, no, maybe less than that, a few weeks.
It's been a little while since I've remembered, since I got into all of this.
At one point down there, he apparently, we're told, tried to hang himself with his belt.
That failed.
They bring in an army psychiatrist by the name of Menninger.
I think William Menninger.
He was kind of famous.
He had a clinic.
And then one of his friends, Robert Lovett, a future secretary of defense himself, goes to visit him.
And, and apparently Forrestal's first things to Lovett, first words were, Bob, they're trying to kill me.
So then they fly him back up to Maryland, to the Bethesda Naval Hospital there.
I think it's 16 floors.
Against all the advice of the attending physicians, they take him to the top floor.
Because they're like, if this guy's suicidal, that's the last place you should take him.
He should be on the ground floor.
But no, national security people said top floor.
So he's sequestered there.
Now he's visited by a few interesting people.
We all know.
Truman, yeah.
Oh, one thing they certainly did is they grabbed his diaries.
Like, that's not making it out.
They expunged the shit out of those diaries before they were ever published.
But Truman, Forrestal's successor, Louis Johnson, Lyndon Baines Johnson, a young guy named John Fitzgerald Kennedy.
And who else?
Forrestal's own brother, William, was not, did see him, finally was able to see him after a long, long time.
Forrestal was never allowed to see his spiritual advisor, a chaplain by the name of Sheehy, Father Sheehy.
What guy in a hospital is not allowed to see his priest or rabbi or spiritual minister?
Like, that's kind of weird, right?
Forrestal wasn't allowed.
So anyway, he's there for, I think that's six weeks.
Yeah.
And he's getting better.
He develops a friendship with a, one of his Navy corpsman guards.
Like, they're in eight-hour ships outside his door, you know.
And one of them, they just strike up a really good relationship.
And Forrestal says, you know, when I'm out of here, I want you to be my assistant.
So this is really a good thing.
So he's thinking about the future.
And, but his brother, William, was it William or Henry?
Yeah, Henry.
Yeah.
He is, he is angry.
That the Navy's not letting his brother out.
Yeah.
Oh, and meanwhile, over in that whole last week, Forrestal's main attending physician was
out on, at a conference.
So the, the hen house has no protection here.
Really.
So anyway, Henry, uh, calls the hotel, the, uh, hospital and he's staying, I think at
the, uh, Watergate hotel.
Okay.
Wow.
Is that where it was?
Yeah.
Or the main, I think that's where it was.
Anyway, he calls them and he says, if my brother is not out by tomorrow, God damn it, I'm going
in and I'm, and I'm going to raise holy hell and you're not going to like what I have to
say.
Mm-hmm.
So that was the, that was May 21st, 1949.
And, and on the night of May 21st, going into the 22nd, that's when James Forrestal did his
16th floor bungee jump out the window.
So what happens?
So what we know is that Forrestal's Navy corpsman, who he was pals with, who had the midnight
shift, somehow went AWOL and was gone.
Uh-huh.
No explanation.
New guy comes in.
And at 1.30 to 1.45, we are told, he opened the door to check in on the secretary on Forrestal
and he sees Forrestal up in his bed and he's reading a book and he's, looks like he's taking
notes, this type of thing.
Mm-hmm.
He asked, would you like a sedative?
And, and this is according to his testimony.
Forrestal said, no, I'm good.
And, and according to the replacement corpsman, he said, the next time I went in there, he was
gone.
Well, he'd gone out the window.
So what apparently the official story is that Forrestal is transcribing, uh, ancient, an
ancient Greek play, uh, The Death of Ajax.
Mm-hmm.
It's a, it's actually really amazing stuff.
But.
Sophocles, right?
Or, or who is it?
Is that, that's Sophocles, yeah.
Yeah.
That's a Sophocles one.
And he stops transcribing in the middle of one word, night, nightingale, I think, stops
in the middle of it and decides apparently that he must kill himself at this very instant.
Wow.
So he, he, according to the official story, gets up and I think in the, there's a shower
where he could have done this more easily, but he didn't do that.
He leaves his room, goes out into the hallway.
Anyway, there's a little, uh, a little window there, uh, behind a radiator, you know, the
radiators that were ubiquitous back in those days.
And he takes his bathrobe cord, ties it, uh, very tightly around his neck, ties the other
end, not so tightly, I guess, around the radiator and think of this as a weird way to
kill yourself.
Tries to hang himself outside the window.
Yeah.
No one, no suicide.
I don't think anyone's ever tried to do that.
No.
So, uh, according to the official story, the cord slipped off the radiator and he just
plunges to his death.
Right.
Now let's look a little more realistically here.
How difficult would it be?
I mean, Forrest still had been very athletic as a younger man, but he was small, a lot more
frail.
He wasn't really doing great.
A couple of big, tough Navy guys or big, tough young guys grab him and throw him the
hell out the window.
Then tie the bathrobe, the radiator after the fact.
Yeah.
That sounds pretty.
I'm absolutely convinced that's what happened.
Yeah.
And then this is 14 years before the assassination of John F. Kennedy.
So you have a country that is, they're going to believe every single thing the military says.
They just won World War II.
Yeah.
They're national heroes.
And, uh, what they said, they immediately said it's a suicide.
They followed up with a, uh, a kind of investigation.
I, which I read the transcript, uh, most of it anyway, the Willicuts, uh, review or I think
it's called, they actually interviewed the Navy corpsman who was on duty.
You think like, this is your main guy.
You're like, you got to really grill this guy.
I think he was in for like 15 minutes and gone.
Like, wow.
Like, thank you for your testimony, young man.
You can go.
Whoa.
There was no, no, no, no investigation, no critical examination.
I believe Forrest on JFK actually knew each other from the Marshall plan, uh, much earlier.
Actually, they had had some interactions, which is, uh, interesting throughout history.
You know, well, I'm not sure how much I knew about that.
So I believe that though.
Uh, uh, it's so fascinating.
Another, another Forrest all thread possibly related to UFOs is I believe one of his direct
reports was Admiral Richard Byrd.
And so you have Operation High Jump.
Yeah.
Right.
You know, that would be Byrd.
Yeah.
And 46 and, and you have, you know, off the coast or down the coast of Argentina, you have
this, this big fleet of American ships going for, I don't really understand what the story
is.
Like it's a very weird story.
It's kind of weird.
Yeah.
I don't even know if I believe the high jump thing.
I think I don't.
Do you believe, like when you say you believe the high jump thing, you believe it was even
a mission to begin with?
No, no.
I think it was, but I don't believe they ran into a basic leg.
Space laser, Nazi flying.
I don't think I do.
No.
Yeah.
And, and, um, cause I remember I read Byrd's full statement that he gave.
And if you really read the whole thing, I don't think he's really talking about flying
saucers.
There was a, was a death or more than a one death, a couple.
I mean, it's very difficult conditions down in Antarctica.
So that's one thing.
Like, but my, my thing is like, if they ran it, if they were chased away by super advanced
technology, well, like a year and a, and two years and three years later, like we went
right, we went back to Antarctica.
It's not like we didn't go back there.
Right.
So maybe there are details that I'm missing and I will fully like, look, if someone is
able to show me a really strong case for it, I'll change my mind in a heartbeat.
I'm not committed, but I, uh, to like thinking it's prosaic, but I just don't know that I'm
convinced it's, um, that they ran into not.
Yeah.
It's really, it's really spotty.
It's like, I think he came back and he gave a speech, but it's unclear.
The problem.
He said, we're, we're living in a new world now where from pole to pole, uh, danger can
come.
Right.
I'm paraphrasing probably badly, but he, he's talking about the fact that we have nuclear
weapons and, um, and there will be delivery systems.
Everyone knew it was all going to happen.
Yeah.
And that's a small, we're living in a smaller world in a dangerous world.
I don't know that he was talking about, uh, aliens or, you know, whatever.
We choose to go to the moon in this decade and do the other things, not because they are
easy, but because they are hard.
You have Danny Sheehan in the audience here, the great Danny Sheehan, who's done incredible
research around this.
Um, do you think, you just actually did a great show on this, on your podcast.
Um, do you think there is a connection between JFK's assassination and UFOs?
I do.
We just had an 80,000 document drop that was less helpful than, I mean, it's like, well,
I'm more confused, you know, afterwards than going out.
Like, I'd rather just listen to Danny on it.
I likened to JFK's murder to, uh, Agatha Christie's murder on the Orient Express in which, spoiler
alert, everyone killed the guy.
There was, there were more than one motive.
There were many, many motives to, to assassinate President Kennedy.
Many.
He was, he was a threat on every level you can imagine.
You know, my wife and I just rewatched JFK, Oliver Stone's great movie.
Great movie.
It was like less than a month ago.
I'm really glad back into the left.
Remember that.
Um, but that was, that was a great movie and see, he brought up the Vietnam connection,
which I think is legit.
He also brought up operation Mongoose.
That's the whole Cuban operation.
That's absolutely part of it.
Uh, he didn't bring up some other things like there's the whole federal reserve connection.
Penn Kennedy was a threat on that.
Uh, and, and the whole nuclear connection where I think that this was brought up in the movie,
uh, where Kennedy really was interested in a kind of a nuclear reduction and maybe disarmament.
Uh, to some extent.
So, so Kennedy was the guy who made the mistake of thinking just because he's president that
he was actually running the show.
He goes up against this national security establishment that was like, no way.
We're not going to let, you're not, you are like a traitor communist.
That's how they saw him.
And we're going to, we're going to have to kill you for our, to protect this country.
That's their rationalization.
Uh, but the UFO subject, yes, this is, I think absolutely must be brought into it.
Um, the, the interview that you're referring to is with a gentleman who's here.
His name is Philip Lavelle, and he's a very good friend of ours.
He's not a published, uh, author on JFK, but he, he knows that assassination as well as
any person alive.
Uh, no lie.
And, and he's a great friend.
And so we talked about it, uh, and about the potential UFO connection there.
And, uh, he's, he's on board with it as well.
I think he believes that this is absolutely, uh, part of the picture.
You know, there was a memo JFK, uh, did sign on November 11th.
So 11 days before he was assassinated.
It was November 11th, wasn't it?
Or the 12th, 12th, 12th.
Yeah, thank you.
Where he's, uh, directing, uh, the Central Intelligence Agency to coordinate UFO data with
the Soviet Union for, for, you know, laudable reasons, I would say.
So that was part of his psyche right there.
He was going against the system.
You look at the majestic documents, which you referred to, and there's, uh, something
called the so-called burned memo where, uh, Lancer, and that was the code name for Kennedy,
was described, oh, I wish I could remember the exact wording of this, but an operation
has to be done on him if he's too dangerous and that, and it must be wet.
And that refers to wet, wet work, which is assassinations.
So, um, and that was, that was, uh, written shortly before the assassination.
I can't remember the date of that.
So, yeah, I mean, I think Kennedy, but I, I don't think it was only the UFO situation.
I mean, John F. Kennedy is, is complex.
There's a lot to, um, to see there.
And as I, I mentioned Philip Lavelle, but the reason is Philip said, you know, you talk
to JFK researchers and they absolutely will not go there.
They will not, even to this day, they will not want to talk about the UFO connection.
You see this in all aspects of the alternative community.
It's like, well, I'm already taking slings and arrows from the establishment for this.
I don't want to talk.
I don't want to wear this other albatross around my neck, but, but it, it is true.
And the UFO phenomenon, look, it is, it is the elephant in the room of United States and
world history of the 20th century.
And, and all the academicians, all the mainstream historians and analysts, they ignore it over
and over again.
You know, the first director of the CIA, Roscoe Helen Carter was into UFOs big time.
Yeah.
Why does no one, why did none of the historians talk about this?
And he, he joined, uh, NICAP.
Yeah.
He was a board member.
Until he resigned suddenly at the moment where in 1962, Donald Kehoe, his friend, they were
trying to get congressional hearings.
It looked like it was going to happen.
And a week later, Helen Carter says, uh, yeah, I'm at a NICAP.
Look, the air force is doing everything they could.
I think we should lay off.
Yeah.
And that was the end of that.
So there's a story here that, uh, establishment historians ignored for years and years and years
and years.
It is the elephant in the room.
If we do not understand, uh, the impact of, of the UFO or UAP phenomenon on world history,
we're not going to understand a whole lot.
We're going to miss a big part of the picture.
Reports of flying saucers are nothing new from the beginning of recorded time.
Men have been seen unexplainable things in the sky.
Can we go, uh, rapid fire through some crashes?
Okay.
I just want to get a real or hoax.
Oh, wow.
All right.
Well, I'll see.
Okay.
Roswell.
Oh, real.
Uh, Kingman.
Yes.
Real.
Um, Kecksburg.
Yep.
Um, that's a good one.
Uh, I don't believe it was the bell.
Some people say it's, it's the lock.
Okay.
Uh, just because it looked like it superficially.
Uh, first of all, the bell was not a flying device.
It was, it was, yeah, it was like some sort of torsion chamber thing.
Yeah.
Voltage electricity thing.
It was.
And it probably did use, uh, rotating mercury, um, you know, like pressurized mercury and
all of that, which is very important for electrogravitics.
And you want to get an anti-gravitic lift, not my specialty.
I should stop right there.
But it was not a flying device by any means.
Um, according to the legend, uh, you know, Cook, I think wrote about the hunt for zero
point.
That's a really good book.
Amazing.
And he, he broke this out a little over 20 years ago.
And he, he said, according to, I think this was brought out in a, a post world war two
trial of Nazis in Eastern Europe, in Czechoslovakia, where they talked about this.
And the claim was like, you had a bunch of scientists, like 60, a bunch of them died from
the effects of this.
And then the rest were executed at the end of the war.
So they wouldn't talk.
Yeah.
That that's the, that's the story.
The D-Glocket thing is fascinating.
Do you see a rig there now where maybe like a bell shaped thing?
What?
I mean, it looks like that shape.
It's, it's really fascinating.
And then I think he's also documented through this Polish journalist, Igor Witkowski, who, uh,
documented that, uh, Ernest Growitz, who, um, was basically that this SS medical chief who
worked with directly with Joseph Mengele and, um, another guy named Walter Gerlach, who is
a gravitational expert in physics, uh, were working on this project.
And so you have a gravity guy and then you have a guy working with like biological, you
know, specimens doing, and we know the Nazis did like experimental cell block nine, like
they were doing weird stuff.
They were.
And they were doing a lot of like off, off the, off the main stream of physics.
Totally.
Yeah.
They really were.
So there's a, I love hearing you talk about this, uh, back to Kecksburg.
I just, I guess I'll just say, uh, there's something very bizarre came down there and I
don't think it was a Soviet, uh, satellite.
I do not believe that.
I do not believe that at all.
Uh, you know, there's Stan Gordon, who's still around.
I love Stan.
He's really dove into this and I think he's got the goods on it.
There were, uh, there was a local radio station guy.
I think Frank Murphy was his name.
He goes in there.
It wrecked his life.
It destroyed his life, uh, uh, on many levels.
Anyway, so Kecksburg, I don't know what that was.
I think it was important.
It wasn't just a satellite and maybe it was something more.
Maybe it was a craft.
I have a, I don't know.
I have a weird one for you.
Uh, Aztec.
Oh, oh, I'm, I'm on the Aztec train.
I believe that one.
Aztec was, you know, it was the first case that was, uh, written about.
Yeah.
In 1950.
And it was viciously, viciously smeared and debunked a couple of years after that.
Uh, by a guy named Considine.
I think that was the one.
J.P.
Khan.
Oh, J.P.
Thank you.
I'm getting all of my people mixed up.
It gets tough to be an older man.
Well, you know a lot of stuff, man.
That you're, yeah.
Yeah.
J.P.
Khan.
And, and, um, but this story, what there's, I have two very dear, wonderful people, uh,
Scott and Suzanne Ramsey, who've really done the work on this, but they revived and
resuscitated this case.
And, and what they showed was that, that Khan's expose was utterly mendacious and just
driven by resentment over not being allowed to do the story.
Yeah.
He was going to break it.
With Scully to begin with.
And he lost it to Scully.
And then it was kind of this pit pit.
Yeah.
And then the, the, the other weirder thread is he was family friends with J. Edgar Hoover
as well.
Oh yeah.
I heard that.
J.P.
Khan.
I did hear that.
So, and then you have these FBI files on Silas Newton and Gebauer going way back to
the, uh, I think the thirties or something.
And they're, they're totally redacted.
Like, so it's like, why would you have these crazy FBI files?
This whole thing of smearing them as these, uh, shysters, you know, sleazy real estate
investors.
That's not, I don't think that's true at all.
Yeah.
Um, in fact, I'm just going to give a shout out to Richard Geldreich, who, uh, I love his
research and, uh, I talk with him and he, he's got stuff on this.
Yeah.
He's going to come out with more information.
Amazing.
I would love to hear from him.
So Silas Newton was worth $20 million at the time, which just for inflation, like it's
like that guy doesn't need to hustle people on a doodlebug oil thing.
He was very successful.
No, absolutely not.
Yeah.
So anyway, I think Aztec was real.
Uh, I think that actually did happen.
You know, unfortunately with a lot of these crash retrievals,
Roswell was the anomaly in the sense that because Roswell made the newspaper at the time.
And so it was harder, like they buried it right away, but it, but there were always researchers
like, Oh, remember that newspaper headline?
Yeah.
Like, so it was always kind of there.
And then it wasn't until the late 1970s that a few people, especially like the great late
Leonard Stringfield.
He's he, you asked in the beginning, like who are some of my heroes?
Yeah.
He's one.
I never met the guy.
Yeah.
Um, he was amazing.
Amazing.
But anyway, so Stringfield starts collecting and dredging up these.
And he was one of the first people to interview and publish his interview with Jesse Marcel
Sr.
And, and by the time that happened, you're really looking 20, uh, no, 30 years after
Roswell.
So those people were, a lot of them were still around, some were gone and researchers kind
of jumped in and they found many, many, many people like in the case with Aztec, uh, it
just didn't work out that way.
Kingman, you've mentioned that before.
I just want to say that, that there's no question in my mind that Kingman was the real
thing.
Raymond Fowler still alive in his nineties, I think, uh, was involved in, uh, contacting
the, uh, the primary witness of that.
And so I think there's some good information on Kingman, but the problem with all of those
other cases is compared to Roswell, we have like a small fraction of the number of people
to be able to talk to.
And, uh, that makes it, that makes it tough for them.
It shows you how managed this subject could have been in the Cold War secrecy era too,
because with Roswell, nobody really knew about Roswell until 1979, 1980.
That's right.
Friedman helped popularize it.
Jesse Marcel came out.
Yeah.
Uh, but between 47 and that time, it was not in any of the UFO books.
Not only that.
Yes.
So the UFO, you know, um, this applies to us today in our community and in the early decades
of the flying saucers.
So it was really not an easy career move to like, you know, write and study flying saucers
or UFOs.
Bad career move for the most part.
So everyone stayed away from it.
And so the people who were in it were often like hyper conservative in a way.
Like it was very surprising.
So like abductions, like no way they're not going to get into abductions.
That's like, that's crazy talk.
You're talking crazy talk.
Uh, crash retrievals of UFOs.
Pfft.
Keep that away.
Yeah.
They would, and they'd been scared off of it by the JP Conn, uh, hit piece.
Certainly.
Uh, despite the fact that how is it illogical that with all of these flying discs, the United
States military might've gotten one.
It's really not that illogical when you think about it, but it was absolutely off, off the
limits.
And when, when Stanton Friedman and Stringfield and others started looking at these crash
retrievals in the late seventies, they got a lot of pushback from established, you know,
UFO researchers at that time.
This was not an easy sell.
It's still not.
I mean, if you Google Aztec crash, it goes Aztec crash hoax.
That is the Wikipedia page of this thing.
And yeah, you have, uh, Scott and Suzanne Ramsey.
That's not UFO researchers managing those pages.
Of course, those are hardcore skeptical, skeptical organization, but then you, you give them first
principles points as to why actually maybe something did happen at the time.
And there's never anything to say back.
It's, they always, well, it's been well established that it's a hoax.
And it's like, you're, you're, that is just received wisdom.
You're literally just repeating some party line.
You've done zero research.
No, I think Aztec really, that was the real deal.
I agree.
I've been there and I've been there with Scott and Suzanne and you see the trees have been,
you know, where the UFO was dragged out.
You see that the trees are like, you know, have been bent over in this awkward shape.
You have FBI files of the two guys who reported on it, you know, through Scully or whatever,
going back to the 30s.
So they were clearly kind of tracking these guys, which is really strange.
What they were thrown, Newton was thrown in jail over this.
Um, so yeah, I think there's a lot.
And then Scully, people say with Scully, oh, it was like written in this sort of flowery,
artful way or whatever.
But he was the guy a lot of celebrities would go to, to give, uh, really kind of, um, you
know, to tell stories where, you know, they didn't want everything out necessarily.
They want it told in a delicate way, but he was approached by this possibly consortium
of scientists that were kind of, you know, consolidated into Dr. G or whatever.
Yeah.
And it would make sense that he would have been approached.
And you have all these people mysteriously dying around Scully.
You have Carl Flock, you know, who's the, probably a three letter agency guy.
I knew Carl Flock.
So it's like, you do a little digging.
I think about Scully.
Yeah.
You read, read that book.
Read just like the introduction.
Yeah.
If nothing else, 1950, this is a guy who really knew things really well.
He was deeply skeptical.
Yes.
Of the United States establishment in the military.
Which is an unusual thing for a journalist in 1950.
Yes.
Uh, Scully was no one's fool.
He knew things really well.
It's, I would recommend anyone find the book.
Just read that.
Yeah.
It, it reads about as fresh today as when he wrote it back.
I agree.
And you have a recording of Silas Newton speaking, uh, that was the university of Denver or some,
some Colorado or some.
And, um, so there's so much documentation from the time, but as, as, as soon as you say,
this is a hoax, people just kind of, kind of look away and, and, and, and forget about
it.
Yeah.
Um, well, because again, the whole thing about being in a fringe field like this, it's like
the last thing you want to appear is, is gullible.
Right.
It's like, that's the kiss of death.
Like you don't look like you're stupid.
I'm going to leave every single thing.
And so there's this overcompensation that has always happened in this field.
Yes.
Which is too bad because let's face it.
Um, let's get down to the fundamental reality here.
We are dealing with a phenomenon that is beyond us.
It is a reality shattering phenomenon and it breaks everything.
It breaks absolutely everything.
And the, the reality is that we, it's not that we're being too crazy and too fringe.
We're not being, we're not going out there enough.
I think that's right.
That's the thing.
This is a very, um, it's a very powerful subject and reality.
What we, UFOs, UAP, whatever we want to call them.
This, the, but even more than that, like UFOs or UAP, that doesn't really even touch.
That's right.
That's nothing.
Yeah.
The, the truth is there is an other intelligence, society, civilization, whatever they are.
They're here.
They are established.
They have bases.
They have a presence.
They are global every, every day.
The nationwide sightings of mysterious drones.
Weeks of mysterious drone sightings.
You're telling me we don't know what, what the hell these drones are in New Jersey are?
Can you make sense of the Jersey drones?
I know you covered these in various contexts.
Uh, it's so confusing.
You have, you know, Rogan and Sean Ryan being like, they're looking for loose nuclear material
on the Eastern seaboard.
You have other people saying, you know, we found some, uh, uh, uh, Chinese nationals like
around there.
Uh, and then I think there's a lot of reason to believe there was possibly genuine anomalous
aerial stuff going on.
But yeah, everyone's always like, I've solved it.
I've solved it.
Like everyone's like figured this thing out.
But really the thing that strikes me about the mystery drone phenomenon was it's like
every single other UFO wave you ever studied.
In other words, this thing happens.
No one seems to be able to explain it.
Everyone's got their own theory.
Thousands of theories are out there.
And then it goes away and you have no resolution, no resolution.
Well, you know, join the club.
This is how this has been going on for many, many years.
Um, there's still a lot of unknown things about this that I'm personally, I would like
to get more information about.
And I don't know if we ever will, uh, the reports of these things supposedly coming out
of the water, um, and harassing us coast guard vessels.
That's one.
There was apparently a swarm that supposedly came from the ocean out of the ocean.
Do we know?
I don't know, but it swarmed a coast guard vessel.
And you have Trump saying it came from a garage and we, you know, these are, it's very
strange place.
Biden knows where they're coming from.
Our military knows where they took off from.
If it's a garage, they can go right into that garage.
They know where it came from and where it went.
I can't imagine it's the enemy because it was the enemy that blasted out.
Even if they were late, they'd blasted.
Uh, something strange is going on for some reason.
They don't want to tell the people and they should.
With Trump, it's always hard to know because he speaks in such a overly simplistic sing
songy way where it's like, dude, I don't know what you're saying.
But, uh, you know, uh, what do you think?
It's entertaining, but, you know.
It is entertaining.
But that is sort of, it seemed to imply something kind of anomalous, right?
Yeah.
I don't really know if Donald Trump actually knew what these were.
I mean, I presumably after he became president, he might've figured out.
And by the way, notice, you know, the Trump and Biden teams, they hate each other.
and yet when they talk about this phenomenon
it's not exactly the same
yeah that's right
there's no difference
it's the only thing that gets like AOC and Matt Gaetz to agree
and then simultaneously like the power structures
that are clamping down to agree
so I don't know if we have an answer to that
and I don't have an answer to it
I was very unpersuaded by the argument
that they were looking for nuclear material
I didn't find that believable at all
because first of all
you had these mystery drones over
Rammstein Air Base in Europe
you had them over Lakenheath
and in the UK
and there are a lot more reports of them having sightings in California
one of the problems with this is
it's really hard to know
are we looking at the same phenomenon
when you look at all the massive UFO or UAP reports
it's really hard to know
like are all of these legit
so how do you actually see the patterns here
is the European aspect of this related
to the New Jersey tri-state area aspect of it
and is that related to the California
I don't know
because it's
who is doing the actual sure shot research
and nailing these cases down
getting field investigators out there confirming
we have a lot of stories
a lot of people throwing videos out there
and I was in as much confusion as anybody else on that
where do you think disclosure is going
because you know
you've been in this field for decades
I'm sure when you get into the field to begin with
you start to gather data
and you start to probably think
like why is no one earnestly
like why isn't the mainstream media
taking this seriously
and then you probably think
oh disclosure is maybe right around the bend
or something
and so now I hear maybe a slightly more pessimistic
Richard Dolan
or where are you
oh well yeah
sorry
like I have wonderful brilliant friends
who say Richard you know
look on the bright side a little more
and I do
I do
once a week
I actually will look on the bright side of things
so one out of seven days
and I'm there
no seriously
you mentioned our media
so one thing that I have
definitely concluded a long time ago
like we you know
we like to think of our media
media is supposed to be the watchdog
they're the press
they inform us
and you know
we all kind of know a little bit better now
but really what
when you look at the media
it's part of a system
that must maintain itself
you have a system
that is
we have a very complex society
with a lot of interlocking parts
that really do kind of need each other
to make them go
not just to keep the lights on
but you need that
and you need all the logistical systems in place
and you need all the financial systems
to be working properly
and that's how we live
that's how we eat our food
and that's how we make our money
and disclosure
to a lot of those interests is a threat
it is a threat
it may not be a threat to you
or to me
in the immediate sense
but think about someone
who's sunk trillions of dollars
into a military infrastructure
or an energy infrastructure
or a transportation infrastructure
disclosure could upset a lot of that
it could make some of those investments
maybe worthless
or at least lose a lot of money
we don't really think about this enough
and so it's a danger
to that established society
some people may say
well the hell with it
I don't really care
okay well I get that
but those guys who own it do care
and they're going to fight
every step of the way
to protect their financial interests
and also everything else
the political stuff
and so
and the media is part of that system
media is part of that system
it always has been
you know
earlier today
I was doing a lecture
and I quoted late Catherine Graham
who was the owner
of the New York
Washington Post
for many years
and she famously said
you know look
this is in the 80s
late 80s
she's like
yeah yeah
we work with the intelligence community
all the time
to manage information
and it was
it was known
it was not even apologized for
so that's
that's our media
and that's not even for me
to criticize the media
that's just for us to
like see it for what it is
so I don't think
we're going to really see a media
I mean
just think about
since 2017
so you have Leslie Kane
Ralph Blumenthal
and Helene Cooper
they write
the really breakthrough article
for the New York Times
two of them
and
and we were all like
is this disclosure
this was
kind of an amazing thing
I was blown away by it
I was
I was really
caught off guard
it was amazing
what happened in the aftermath
really nothing
nothing
nothing at all
no
no deep
in journalists
like investigations
by journalists
of the mainstream
you had this very moderate
measured
controlled
often skeptical
response to that
where months and months
and months would
would pass
before another article
would come out
sometimes it would be
like a skeptical editorial
in the New York Times
and things like this
that's the nature
of their investigation
so they clearly
were not interested
in following up
there were no
primetime news specials
on this
like none of that stuff
so you have to wonder
this we've always said
even the skeptics
would say
well this would be
the biggest story
of all time
okay so now
we've got a glimmer
of it
where are you guys
and I think we know
that's not a
actual area
that they want
to open up
because it's too dangerous
so back to disclosure
I don't believe
that we are going
to ever see
an honest voluntary
disclosure
from the U.S. government
it's not going
to be voluntary
it could be
if their backs
are pressed
to the wall
by let's say
powerful revelations
that become
too unrealistic
to deny
let's say
a senior level
recent or active
U.S. government official
maybe
maybe a Pentagon person
Matt Kovitz
would be an interesting
one
but he's
now he's gone
yep
so
but something along
that level
maybe
but those
those people
are tough to get
they're very
they're very tough
to get
yeah
I'm with you
in the frustration
I met with
one of the lead
op-ed people
at the Wall Street Journal
maybe a year ago
and I was trying
to convince her
that she should
write about
this topic
and that this was
a very worthwhile
important topic
I was telling her
about the nuclear
connection
she did express
some interest
and I think
she was
you know
earnest
I don't think
she was like
dogmatically opposed
to the subject
and it's funny
she said
oh we have a consultant
for this stuff
she said
this guy's name
is David Spergel
and this guy
did the NASA UAP panel
in 2023
he's probably associated
with the whole
secrecy
and then
he said
he said to her
apparently
he told us
that it was all
light reflections
and temperature inversions
and I was like
oh my god
Don Menzel
was saying
the same thing
in the 50s
and it was probably
working on the same
mainstream media
proponents back then
and where it's like
literally snapshot
to today
so you think about it
so the Washington Post
one of the establishment
publications
has a deep system
deep state
scientist you could say
who's managing
this topic for
so she has to defer
to him
basically is what
it sounds like
so that's how
the whole thing's managed
you got your talking points
after having researched
this topic
for as long as you have
Richard
is there a science fiction
book or movie
that most accords
with your world view
I'm looking at my wife
well there's a few
movies and shows
that I think
are really neat
hey you know
I co-authored a book
with Bryce Zabel
we did After Disclosure
about 15 years ago
and he of course
co-produced
the TV show Dark Skies
which was a really great show
they did one long season
in the late 90s
it's tough to compete
with the X-Files
but they did a good job
of the kind of
inside machinations
of an MJ-12 group
I actually really like
what they did there
that's almost 30 years ago
Steven Spielberg
20 years ago
did Taken
which I think
was a very very good
good work
on that
I'll just put this out now
because I'm a fan of him
and I talked to this man
there's an author
named Lou Balden
who I love
I love Lou's work
and he's
it's crazy to read him
because he is
a self-described contactee
and I don't
I don't usually hang out
or work with contactees
that's really not my thing
but Lou's work
fascinates me
absolutely
and I have no problem
saying this
so he in the 90s
mid 90s
he writes a book called
In League with the UFO
it's a weird title
what does that mean
and then he subtitled it
The Roswell Incidents
like this book
has nothing to do
with Roswell
but he was trying
to like market it
1997 it gets published
Roswell was
the 50th anniversary
so fair enough
but you read this book
it's insane
he says well
I got the material
for writing this book
from a gentleman
who gave me some papers
totally cagey about
like this
and he writes
an insider's story
of how the committee
studied the flying saucer
that came into their possession
after Roswell
the scientists
all the crazy stuff
about the alien ship
how surreal it was
all the crazy
conscious
genius level
alien gadgets
as he calls them
that baffled
these scientists
the political arguments
and I'm thinking
this is fiction
this is the best
damn fiction
in UFOs
anywhere
it would be
and is it true
and well to this day
people discuss it
I've communicated with Lou
I've talked with him
and he's still around
and I really like him
and I think I believe him
I think I believe this man
somehow he gets this information
he can talk about it
I'm going to try to interview him
one day
you should too
he's worth it
and then 10 years later
he writes this even crazier book
it's insane
it's called a day with an extraterrestrial
who has a name
the extraterrestrial's name is Milton
whoa
that guy has a good name
so Lou writes it
and he's like
yeah I'm doing my daily walk
in the park
where I live
and this crazy guy
accosts me
and says
hey
I remember me
he's like
I don't know you at all
yeah yeah
you know me very well
I don't think I know you at all
get the hell away from me
next thing you know
he's been paralyzed
he's floated
levitated into a ship
no one sees it
and he goes for an entire day
on this crazy
Alice in Wonderland adventure
this is Alice in Wonderland
for ufology
this book
a day with an extraterrestrial
if Lewis Carroll
were to write
about UFOs
this is the book
he would write
people do not realize
just how wild it is
is it true
I don't know
it's a great read
and I find myself
returning to it
over and over again
Lou you're welcome
yeah that's what
I've never heard
a better plug
it's a great book
I want to pivot
a little bit
you've been on this
interesting kick around
China and UFOs
to many of us
I think China
is somewhat of a black box
when it comes to this
this topic
you know people talk about
the three body problem
this famous
you know science fiction trilogy
or I guess that's the first book
of the trilogy
and there are a couple
of journals from China
that people are aware of
but you've done
kind of a deeper dive
I did yeah
I did actually this
for the members
of my website
so I like to do
special projects for that
we've got richarddolanmembers.com
great people there
and I'm always like
working on those projects
as well as what I do
on YouTube
and in my books
so I thought
you know
I've always been interested
in understanding
all international dimensions
of this phenomenon
and that includes
international research
and China was as much
a black box to me
as you're just saying now
and I thought
I don't really
what can I learn
I mean I want to do
the same dive
on Russian ufology
as well
but I started
with a better knowledge
of that
and with Chinese ufology
I felt like I knew
next to nothing
and I thought
why is that
why do I know
so little about
what the Chinese UFO
history is
well yeah
I just discovered
it's really quite fascinating
so there's still a lot
that I don't know
but what I can definitely
say to you
it you know
everything revolves around
the death of Mao Zedong
in 1976
so there's pre-Mao
and up to that point
you could not
absolutely not
no way ever
research UFOs
in that country
it was absolutely no way
the whole subject
was off limits
because I mean
it seems to me
it was a challenge
to the authority
of the communist party
and a challenge
to the fact that
the party was in control
of everything
and so what are these
things flying around
are you American
are they extraterrestrial
whatever it is
we don't like to
acknowledge it
and they did not
Mao then dies
and of course
with many aspects
of Chinese society
certain floodgates
did open up
one of them
was a massive
absolutely massive
almost national interest
in UFOs
to this day
I think this is a very
very popular topic
in China
but it's managed
very differently now
than it was in the 70s
so when Mao
first died
you had Chinese researchers
a number of different ones
you had a kind of
very scientific materialist
you could almost say
Marxist
version of understanding
this subject
but
what you find
is that culturally
among the grassroots
Chinese people
they are into
like contact cases
big time
into like metaphysical
aspects of
this subject
in ways that
you wouldn't think
for a communist country
where spiritual beliefs
are not particularly
encouraged
or even tolerated
at times
but yet this became
a huge thing
so all through the 80s
you get the
development of
on the one hand
very like solid
like
MUFON type
you know
Chinese research
where they're
they're researching
sometimes military encounters
and publishing
some of these
so I was able
to find some of these
there was a Chinese
researcher
by the name of
Paul Dong
who wrote a really
great book
in the early
early 1980s
on this
and I think
you can find
a PDF of that
it's out there
but anyway
and there's a few
other like
random Chinese journals
that you can get
some of the information
here in the West
but basically
long story short
through the 80s
and 1990s
China had an organization
known as the Falun Gong
many of you know of this
that grew
so massively
so the Falun Gong
was essentially
doing
kind of like a
version of
Tai Chi
movement
with a very
like almost like yoga
but Tai Chi
it's
you know
you could probably do it
outside on your mat
and that's what they would do
but it was such a massive
national movement
millions and millions
and more millions
and the Falun Gong
had very explicit
UFO extraterrestrial
related beliefs
so it made them
a little different
and this movement
became so big
the Chinese government
really became afraid of it
this is
you know
you had Tiananmen Square
remember that
where all of the openness
that had been happening
through the 80s
became
kind of grew
and grew
and morphed
into a public demonstration
wanting
you know
open and complete
freedom of expression
and that was
very very severely crushed
so all through the 90s
in the aftermath
the Falun Gong
goes on their rise
and they were
ruthlessly shut down
in the late 90s
in almost the exact same way
Chinese
the Chinese Communist Party
decided
this is
way too much of a threat
we absolutely cannot allow this
and we must crush this
and they did crush it
absolutely completely
the whole thing
that my biggest takeaway
from all of that
was
that
we talk about disclosure
here in the United States
disclosure in China
is
I really am sure
would be perceived
as such a major threat
to the government
vastly more
vastly more than
anyone in Washington DC
would perceive
to the United States
structure of power
so
it had to be
suppressed in China
and Chinese ufology
to this day
is
basically
has its teeth
taken out
I mean
it's very
very tame
it's very managed
it's very controlled
and it's also
one thing that
you would have to add
is the People's Liberation Army
the Chinese Army
Chinese military
they are
very sophisticated
in tracking UFO reports
very very sophisticated
they are integrated
I think
in all of like
the Chinese research
civilian organizations
they're collecting everything
and they have a multi-tier system
by which they organize
these reports
so they
they collect
then they have
they bring them to like
a central
clearing house
where they study
and analyze them
and then they bring them
to a final repository
where they keep these
we don't get
any of that information
I don't think
any of that
really comes out
but they
they're very
very sophisticated
they have got
they are on top
of managing
their UFO data
and that's really
one reason
I think why
we don't really
get anything out of it
I tried
you know
looking
we can do
Google Translate
you can translate
website pages
but you cannot
get to
the Chinese cases
it's
I don't think
maybe some people
can but I can't
it's so fascinating
and it does beg
the question
you know
why is the
this Dark Forest
you know
trilogy
the three body problem
allowed
you know
they can clamp down
on whatever
literature they want
and it doesn't
exactly paint
the cultural revolution
in the most
you know
the rosiest
of ways
it's sort of
well
yeah
I want to respond
to that
because I think
what we're seeing
is
nothing is black
and white anymore
we're in a world
and China is part
of this too
where things
are in change
we're in the midst
of an AI revolution
of all of the kinds
of tech revolutions
going on
and a global
communications revolution
has been occurring
it continues to happen
so just because
the government
whether it's the US
government
the Chinese government
the Russian
just because they say
we don't
we don't want to
recognize this
doesn't mean
that they're able
to prevent it
they can't really
prevent it 100%
I think what
we're seeing
is a series
of adjustments
being made
by all of the
governments
in all these ways
I think you see
them fighting
defense
as it were
that's certainly
the US as well
people will say
you know
this guy says
he's taken
all these NDAs
and all of this
and yet
he's talking
about crash
retrievals
isn't he breaking
classified
security regulations
and what I
what I suspect
I mean
I don't know
but I think
what happens
is you've got
factions all over
the place
you've got factions
in the US
Pentagon
probably multiple
fact
not just two
probably many
and some people
have supporters
who are enabling
them to say
certain things
other people
in that same
structure
who will probably
be dead set
against it
but they didn't
win that battle
and so certain
things get out
and I guarantee
it's probably
very similar
with China
they have to
play the game
they can't just
slam down
all the time
and say
this is how
it is forever
we're in a world
that is in flux
we just have to
recognize
there are
there are other
sides of this
and I'm not
advocating for
one thing or
another
I'm just saying
it's a little
complicated
but when you
have a system
that is designed
to support
like media
the media is
part of this
system
so it's been
captured
we all know
long ago
it's been
captured
like there
you know
you had some
watchdog
journalists
that maybe
some of them
are still out
there
you're one
but in terms
of establishment
journalists
everything's
captured by
the system
because it
must protect
itself
the system
must protect
itself
so you know
when you get
the skeptics
out there
they fit
right in
perfectly
they serve
the system
as well
it's funny
you have
people like
Vannevar Bush
talked about
in UFO lore
kind of all the
time
Robert Starbacher
said he was
part of the
program
it would make
sense
if we had a
UFO program
it would be
adjacent to
our atomic
program
he was
head of
you know
the office
of strategic
research and
development
at the highest
level for
FDR and
Truman
and he wrote
a paper called
the endless
frontier
and I almost
think if you
read that
that that
paper that
essay through
the lens of
UFO technology
maybe it's
like oh
the frontier is
actually super
endless and
this thing
needs to be
you know how
this tech gets
developed needs
to be managed
by you know
these central
groups like
and they are
convinced like
they're the
guys to do
it right
they're smarter
than we are
they know
better right
we can argue
whether they do
or don't but
that's their
position and
so they're not
they're not ever
gonna like
voluntarily just
say oh yeah
here you go
yeah it's not
gonna happen
yeah I have a
weird crash for
you I don't know
if you're familiar
with this one but
South Haven
Long Island
uh-huh
in the 90s
yes yes
okay
do you think
that happened
yeah by Brookhaven
National Lab
that's right
by Brookhaven
National Lab
there's a man
named John Ford
okay
who I'm sure
you know this
maybe maybe
some listeners
do too
yeah I mean
I I actually
think that's
that's a real
possible one
okay
yeah there's a
Long Island
UFO group
uh
he headed it
and they
actually there
there may be
more than one
of those that
may have happened
on Long Island
I grew up on
Long Island
okay
my backyard
there
I didn't know
about it at
the time
yeah
that was kind
of
you think
there were
more than
one
well I think
they believe
there were
more than
one
well that's
fascinating
because that
was the first
particle accelerator
in the US
which is the
Cosmotron
at Brookhaven
National Labs
and you hear
you know
definitely UFOs
are definitely
attracted to
nuclear
and then
I wonder
if you could
generalize that
to tip of the
spear science
and to high
energy physics
and particle
accelerators
I have to think
yes
I think so
the Long Island
crash I think
was supposed
to be 1989
by Morish's
Bay
okay
I think
that's when
the year
and um
yeah I believe
I'm a little
fuzzy on this
but I do
know like
there was a
lot of
there were
eyewitnesses
who talked
about massive
security
yes
presence around
that area
at that
time
and uh
John Ford
looked at
you know
he was
they really
destroyed his
life
so John
Ford
I used to
be um
on
sometimes
some good
terms with
the late
Elaine Douglas
who was a
very close
friend of
John Ford
Elaine Douglas
in her own
right was a
really cool
lady
tough
smart
uh
someone you
know
screw around
with
she could
get angry
like I
remember that
but toward
the end of
her life
she and I
were were
much closer
but anyway
she knew
John Ford
very well
and I
know she
was a strong
believer in
this uh
reality of
the Long
Island crash
but Ford
was it
really does
look to me
that he
was totally
set up
uh with
this kind
of wacky
plot to
kill a
member of
one of the
uh I think
the Nassau
County or
is it Suffolk
County uh
city uh
council whatever
whatever uh
governing body
by poisoning
his toothpaste
with uh
radioactive
material
Jesus
like are
you kidding
me man
so he gets
accused of
this and
he's I
don't even
know if he's
alive anymore
oh my god
he was incarcerated
for decades
oh that's nuts
he might still
be alive
that is so
messed up
it's um
it just
seemed
I haven't
really dived
super deep
into this
but it
really looked
like they
just went
after him
and that's
now was
he was
he just
that unstable
and he was
like getting
kind of crazy
and I don't
know but I
don't I
don't think
so it seems
really wrong
what they did
to him
so wrong
you hear of
these historical
you know
Galileo type
case people
who seek
truth and
then they
get persecuted
by the
establishment
and then you
hear stories
like that
modern stories
and ufology
we like to
think oh
we're so much
better now
like we're
not any
different
yeah
the problem
with our
country
our world
is that we
like to tell
ourselves we live
in a democracy
and we like to
tell ourselves
oh yeah we've
got natural
rights
and government
and so the
problem then
becomes for
those people
who've always
controlled things
it's like
how do we
deal with
this
let's do
some good
public propaganda
create public
relations
you know
Edward Bernays
nephew
of Sigmund Freud
who creates
that whole
industry for
massive public
manipulation
so that's
okay check
and then all
these other
things to get
around the
formal restrictions
on their
untrammeled
pursuit of
power
and so it's
just a game
you know
it's like
all right we
have this
pretend democracy
that's really
what it is
and both parts
are true
like we
we have
certain democratic
elements to
our world
okay
but ultimately
we all kind of
see it's
it's very
tightly guided
yes
manipulated
and
in
a
naturally
hierarchical
social
organization
and ours
is
it always
has been
anytime you
have
concentrations
of wealth
that are going
to be unequal
and since we
12,000 years
since we both
started collecting
ourselves into
societies
it's always been
the case
you're going
to have
hierarchy
sorry
but it's
inevitable
and those
people
with the
money
are going
to control
things
and so
they never
give up
and they're
just
it's like
how do we
work our way
through this
system now
how do we
manipulate the
system
to keep it
going
all right
let the
people
think they've
got freedom
good for
them
yeah
that's what
they do
yeah
it's like
the
and we're
surprised
when we see
that there
are these
injustices
happening
today
it's like
that shouldn't
be
yes
yeah
it's a
weird
you know
it's like
the left
is always
talking about
you know
government
overreach
and then
the right
is talking
about
you know
corporate
overreach
and
yeah
it used
to be
the opposite
yeah
it used
to be
the opposite
the left
used to
talk about
the government
overreach
oh no
the corporate
overreach
and the right
used to talk
about government
overreach
exactly
they have
and now
it's just
a sort of
seesaw
where
the only
constant
is the rich
gets richer
and the poor
gets poorer
but it's
the sort
of hypnotic
like
you know
rearranging
the deck
chairs
in the
Titanic
or something
but I was
thinking about
our conversation
yesterday
we talked
about
you know
this amazing
history
of unidentified
submersible
objects
you have
this
incredible
chronology
one case
that you've
covered
before that
which I think
connects
to USOs
is the
Pascagoula
case
where you have
these two
fishermen
who were abducted
I didn't realize
this until
recently
Pascagoula
was right
next to
the largest
production
of nuclear
submarines
at the time
yes
that's
right
I don't
know if
it still
is
but
that's
right
and
actually
well that's
a good
case
and
in the
second
volume
of my
study
which will
cover the
1970s
and 80s
so
there's a
you know
maybe I'll
make more
of a
reference
I might
throw a
little bit
more about
Pascagoula
in there
it's not
in my
opinion
technically
USO
case
necessarily
but a
week or
two later
there was
a genuine
USO
incident
right there
oh wow
and that
is in my
book
and it's
a good
it's a
really good
case
it's really
really good
so
but I do
make a
reference to
Charles Hickson
and Calvin
Parker
they were
the witnesses
for that
they were
the abductees
for that
and
yeah so
basically
what you
had with
that
they are
seeing
they're
fishing
Hickson
at the
time was
in his
40s
Cal
Parker
was like
years old
and they
were doing
a fishing
thing
early in
the morning
and they
see this
dome
shaped
kind of
crack
like a
almost
cone
maybe a
shaped
crap
I guess
and it's
hovering above
the water
it's off
the coast
of Mississippi
and they
are
they're
abducted
and for
the longest
time
it was
only
Charles
Hickson
who was
supposedly
abducted
but Calvin
Parker
years later
I think
indicated that
he was
too
the thing
about that
is a
couple of
things
so the
being
that they
described
is very
bizarre
looking
it's got
like a
carrot
ears
and like
it's a
weird looking
creature
very bizarre
look
I wouldn't
think of an
alien looking
it looks
like
like a
1950s
version
of an
alien
like in
one of
those bad
movies
which is
the one
thing about
it like
you just
don't want
you look
at that
and you
cringe
oh guys
like is
this what
you saw
but look
it's what
they said
they saw
but what's
interesting
about it
is they
reported this
to the
police
local police
which many
people know
and the
guy the
deputy sheriff
on duty
is like
he's kind
of suspicious
of them
so he leaves
a recorder
in the room
where they're
alone
they don't
know this
know they're
being recorded
and they're
just talking
very honestly
with each other
like in Cal
Parker's
freaking out
they're like
holy crap
how do we
do this
process
this is
and so
they totally
convinced
the law
enforcement
there that
they were
honest and
sincere
so it
and you know
and for many
years Cal
Parker just
kind of
disappeared
for a while
he reappeared
toward the end
of his life
but Charles
Hickson
did lots
of interviews
and like
you know
I've watched
the guy
I've listened
read his
interview transcripts
he's
I think he was
telling the truth
you know
it's fascinating
do you ever
does naval
surface warfare
crane ever
come up for you
are you familiar
with that
facility
not related
to the
Glomar bit
is it
or
I don't know
well you actually
reported on it
you did
as part of
Richard Dolan
intelligent
disclosure
like and subscribe
maybe I use
different terminology
you
you talked
about
why I think
this guy
Randy Anderson
who I
interviewed
right
who went
deep into
an underground
military base
which you've
you've covered
yes
no he's
he's fascinating
guy
he is fascinating
and you know
that was not
really on a lot
of people's radars
that complex
at the time
I think it's still
there's very
you're talking
about the thing
down in Puerto Rico
in the
no I'm talking
about this thing
in 2014
it was taken
down underground
to this
and then
taken to a
skiff
that said
off planet
technologies
oh I never
took notes
on it
so I should
probably revisit
this
well yeah
I don't know
it's a complex
that's very
interesting
I have a couple
of Navy friends
and they say
some spooky
stuff goes on
there
I'm going to
data mine you
about this
when we're done
talking
yeah yeah
we'll do it
well Richard
this has been
an absolute
honor
I can't thank
you enough
for your time
and yeah
I mean
you're just
an absolute
wealth of
knowledge
I love
talking
to you
man
you are
you're
very easy
to do
this
with
and
you're
a wealth
of knowledge
in your
own right
like your
knowledge
of 1940s
like World War
II era
stuff
very
very impressive
well
I really
enjoy hearing
you
standing
on the
shoulders
of giants
and
that's
what we
all do
yeah
we said
that
before we
started
or
but it's
true
like that's
all we
ever do
we stand
on
you asked
me
who some
of my
inspirations
I'll tell
you right
now
so
when I
started
with
before
before I
got into
UFOs
I was into
a couple
of academic
guys that I
really love
Max Weber
great sociologist
from a century
ago
was very very
important to me
still is
yeah
his ideas
still resonate
with me
his whole idea
of rationalization
of the world
I think about
this a lot
age of disenchantment
yes
exactly
yeah
absolutely
yes
in fact
that whole thing
I was 21
years old
when I first
read Weber
and I read
him talking
about disenchantment
of the world
and that's
what that
hooked me
so it's
kind of cool
that you
mentioned that
yeah a lot
of other
kind of
important
thinkers
of the past
I guess
but within
UFOs
I'm like
an admirer
of a lot
of all the
OGs
you know
Donald Kehoe
was probably
number one
in that
I went through
all of his
books very
carefully
James and
Coral Lorenzen
of APRO
very huge
admirer of them
and Edward
Ruppelt
his whole
story has
just been
interesting
oh yeah
very early
death of a
heart attack
at age 37
are you
conspiratorial
about that
or his
death
Ruppelt
possibly
okay
some people
are like
no no
he died
he had
he did
have a
previous
heart attack
before that
okay
but the
thing about
Ruppelt
that's weird
he
absolutely
was pressured
to basically
debunk his
own book
yeah
and there's
no question
about this
so you read
he does the
report on
unidentified
flying object
which was
flew in the
face in many
ways of the
official air
force position
he ran
project blue
book
he was in
a position
to talk
about this
and he's
making it
clear throughout
the book
it's like
yeah we were
baffled by this
this scared
the hell out
of us
this was
amazing
that blew
my mind
like again
and again
very uncomfortable
so what ends
up happening
Kehoe is the
guy who writes
all about this
he brings this
out because he
was in touch
with Ruppelt
and Ruppelt
was on board
with all of
the kind of
pro-UFO
public statements
right up until
around I think
the middle of
early 1958
so for 56
and 57
he was
gung-ho
starts to become
a little cold
in 58
and Kehoe's
noticing
what's up
with Ruppelt
and other people
like what's up
with Ruppelt
well he was
working at
Northrop at the
time
and he was
under pressure
and he ends
up in 1960
publishes his
second revised
version of his
book which all
he ended up
doing was he
tacked on
three chapters
at the end
of it
and the
chapters are
I mean
written in a
completely different
manner
they're very
like the
original book
is very like
it's measured
it's mature
the three chapters
tacked on
is like
sophomoric
and goofy
and he's
smearing people
including Kehoe
and he's
it's just like
very unlike
the writing
that preceded it
as if he was
coerced or
pressured
yes
that's right
and he publishes
that and he
trashes UFOs
at the end
calls it
I think the
space age
religion or
myth
myth of the
space age
and then he
dies
37 years old
it's crazy
well you
there are other
cases like that
you have
you know
Philip J.
Corso
you know
he had 24
hours to edit
the day after
Roswell
written
co-written
by William
J. Burns
and he had
written another
thing you know
Dawn of a New
Age or whatever
and so you have
this like managed
version
and this more
pure version
and we talked
about Aztec
earlier
William Steinman
he was a
Skunk Works
employee
he was an
at Lockheed
yeah and
he was pushed
out because
of his
UFO research
and could
never get a
job in
aerospace
after writing
that book
which I
would love
to vindicate
I think that
is a great
UFO research
book
yes it is
it is
because
Wikipedia
says the
you know
Aztec thing
is a hoax
you know
he
you throw
the baby
out with
the bath
yeah before
the Ramseys
rehabilitated
Steinman
did a
wrote a
really big
fat book
on it
an amazing
book that
covers all
sorts of
interesting
stuff around
MJ-12
you sure
did
yeah
yeah so
I talked
with Steinman
one time
and I
really
I liked
him a lot
all kinds
of stories
like all
kinds of
really crazy
stories that
come out
other people
I've admired
and continue
to admire
one of them
still alive
her name is
Linda Moultonow
oh yeah
Linda
Linda is a
one-off
there's no one
else like her
she is one
of a kind
and
she's brave
she puts
herself out
there all the
time
she's
investigated
I just
admire her
and by the
way if you
ever get to
hang out with
her just
let the
lady talk
she has
got
the
like
more
amazing
personal
stories
yeah
because the
thing about
Linda is
all the
older guys
always like
Linda
like all
the military
guys
well she's
brilliant
no BS
about her
but they
feel
that they
can talk
to her
and she
listens
and she's
brave
and so
she's
collected
all of
these
amazing
encounters
like some
of them
are just
kind of
crazy
and I
I just
like
I sit
and I
just listen
I've been
really lucky
that I can
get to
do that
with her
I mean
she's
one of
a kind
amazing
resource
a gem
of a human
being
in our
field
I don't
know a lot
of other
people I've
really
truly
admire
Tim
Good
is one
I got
to know
Tim a
bit
and
he's
not
well
these
days
and I
wish him
the best
he must
be a
little
over 80
at this
point
yeah
about that
and
he's
just
retired
but
Tim
was a
real
gentleman
and a
really
gentleman
and a
smart
guy
this is
a field
of UFOs
like
I
look
back
and I
think
what an
amazing
little ride
I got
to have
just
because
I
thought
I got
the bug
and I
thought
I would
write a
book
and I
get to
meet
these
people
Stanton
Friedman
was another
one
although
Stanton
I'm just
going to
say this
I always
liked him
always respected
him
Stanton was a little
bit of a gatekeeper
with me when I
first broke into
this field
really
I will say
that yes
you know
he didn't
sort of
just give
you
it was all
about Bob
Lazar
because you
expressed genuine
interest in
Lazar
in 2001
so I
still had
nice black
hair
big round
glasses
I had a lot
going on
so I did
my first
public
appearance
was actually
in Laughlin
Nevada
in March
of 01
and my
second one
was right
after 9-11
and it was
in St.
Louis
and Stanton
was there
we had
like
honestly
probably
like 15
people in
attendance
at this
whole thing
like I
flew out
there
Stanton
was there
a couple
of other
folks
how old
were you
at the
time
I think
okay
I just
turned
okay
yeah
so
and you
know
we didn't
there's no
social media
so things
were slower
you know
I had two
appearances in a year
I was like
wow that's great
yeah
so anyway
I'm there
and Stanton
like I'm
sitting alone
with him
and he's
checking me
out
he's like
who is this
guy
because I
had just
written a
book
big fat
and
he's like
so
what's your
opinion on
Bob Lazar
and the fact
was I didn't
really have
one
I mean
I didn't
know enough
I had spent
the last five
years just
trying to
figure out
from 1941
to 1973
it was like
Lazar
are you kidding
me man
I didn't
really know
yet
and I was
by the way
I was scared
out of my
mind
entering the
UFO field
back then
because
I knew
I wrote
this
like it was
a good
book on
the early
part of
the cover
up
but like
when I
published
that book
I knew
nothing
about the
1980s
and 1990s
I didn't
have time
so I was
afraid like
people are
going to
ask me
all these
questions
and I
don't know
what I'm
going to
say
and Bob
Lazar
was one
of them
I was
aware
this was
a big
thing
but I
hadn't
really spent
enough time
to know
and so
and I
resented
those Stan
like I
knew where
he was
coming from
he wanted
me to
come down
against
Lazar
and I
was like
you know
don't
I think
I said
like I'll
decide to
send my
own time
and I let
him know
you can't
don't bully
me man
I'm not
going to
take to
it
we always
had a
fine and
cordial
relationship
I wasn't
really close
with Stan
like other
people were
but you
know I
think he
learned to
respect me
over time
it took him
a little
while
one thing
was he
realized
like because
everyone's
attacking him
over MJ
12 and
he realized
oh Dolan's
kind of like
okay with
MJ 12
so he
suspected I
was kind
of an ally
there
the other
thing I was
just going to
say about
Stan though
and this is a
bit of a
problem
the fact that
he was so
hardcore against
Lazar to me
signified a
larger problem
yeah
which is that
look you're
going to
research
Roswell
good
great in
fact
and it's
really good
that you
did that
but why
in God's
name would
you think
the story
stops there
yeah of
course
all right
so you
have the
craft
it's
obviously
going to
be studied
yes
under
great
secrecy
yeah
that's a
given
yeah
let's look
for some
stories here
and and
he just
always seemed
to like
shoot them
down
well it's
kind of
intellectually
disingenuous
to say
simultaneously
I believe
they're
see covert
reverse engineering
programs
and then
also say
the one
guy with
probably
the most
coherent
story around
having worked
on a craft
is a hundred
percent wrong
you have to
think probabilistically
and so
give it
give it some
probability
above zero
if you think
the first thing
yeah
and he fixated
like on the
education
on the education
because he was
educated at MIT
and it was
personal I think
I think he was
like what did I
do to get my
degree at MIT
I think that's
exactly
it was a little
ego
yeah
yes
I think so
and he kept
using the word
fraud over
and over again
and I'm just
like this is
not helpful
right
and there is
something that
happens with
UFO research
too where
by that time
I think
Friedman
he had gotten
in with
I don't know
probably a lot
of you know
interesting characters
in government
but he was very
good friends
with Bill
Moore
William Moore
he's good
friends Bill
Moore who
admitted at
MUFON in
the late 80s
that he you
know helped
with the
mess up
Paul Bennewitz
Moore
I'm not going
to defend
or attack him
but Moore
always said
and Greg Bishop
wrote about this
in a really good book
called Project Beta
that's amazing
Moore said
I allowed
myself to get
involved with those
people because
I believed
I had the ability
to separate the
shit from the
candy
as he put it
so he thought
at least this is
his explanation
that he was going
to deal with
these people
because he wanted
to get to the
holy grail
himself
and Bill
Moore was
the hot shot
UFO researcher
of the 1980s
people so often
forget
and it was
Robert Hastings
by the way
who in my
opinion is
probably more
than anyone
else responsible
for the
takedown of
Bill Moore
because Hastings
you go back
through the old
MUFON journals
of the late 80s
I wasn't involved
in the field
but you know
you can read
the journals
Hastings
was on
he was on
he knew
that Moore
had intelligence
connections
he knew it
and he sniffed
it out
and I
personally
think
I'm sure
others know
this better
than I do
but I think
that Moore
by July
of 1989
when he was
at the MUFON
symposium there
the gig was up
like he couldn't
there was no way
he was going to
keep this going
anymore
so he just
kind of came out
that's what I think
that's fascinating
yeah
yeah you also
have you have
the guy
Chase Brandon
he wrote
Cryptos
I think he was
working on a script
at one point
with Stanton Friedman
and so you have
these interesting
oh yeah
with Stan
right
with these
interesting sort
of overlaps
where in the
beginning you start
off super irreverent
and iconoclastic
and then maybe
you get softened
over time
or something
yeah thanks for
bringing me back
to Stan
that was all
I was going
a little off there
but yeah
I mean I
having said all
of that
look I admire
and always
respected
and liked
Stanton Friedman
and his
contribution
to where we
now are at
is extremely
important
yes
and
but you know
like I once
read Marilyn Monroe
couldn't cook
you're going to
hold that
against her
you know
she's Marilyn Monroe
sure
everyone's got
their things
where we're not
we're not 100%
perfect
yeah
of course
and
and so
but yeah
Stan was someone
that was important
to me
and
anyway I'm
kind of tailing
off here
no I love it
this I could talk
to you for hours
well
Richard this has
truly truly been
an honor
and hopefully
hopefully we can
do it again
at some point
and thank you
for doing
everything
go subscribe
to Richard Dolan
Intelligent Disclosure
on YouTube
this is on
Spotify
and Apple
too
I think so
you know
I'm not that
good at
organizing
wherever it is
on social media
but I know
it's on YouTube
I check it out
on YouTube
buy his new book
on USOs
volume one is out
two and three
are coming
it's amazing
and buy all
his other books
too
he's written
some incredible
I don't know
UFOs in the
National Security
State
yeah they're all
like little babies
of mine
I love them all
and the thing
I love most
is probably
writing the books
yeah
I mean YouTube
is fun
conferences
talking with people
is fun
but I actually
mostly enjoy
just writing
well keep going
putting that out
keep doing what you do
thank you Jesse
thank you Richard
yeah
then about
all in
Ikea
I love you