He's frightened. He's really frightened.
He's screaming into the phone.
They said, sir, we got all the guards out.
They've got their weapons pointed at this red-orange pulsating light.
It's huge.
I went over to talk to my commander
because now I'm thinking there's something serious going on out there.
Before I could tell them about the phone calls,
we'd get a big horn go off.
One of the missiles went off alert status,
or it went from green to red.
No go.
Can't launch it.
And right after that one went down,
all of them went down, one at a time.
I had already been trying to get in touch with you and interview you,
and then this kind of ridiculous Wall Street Journal piece comes out
by this guy named Joel Schechtman.
It just seems like a really botched kind of attempt
at discrediting you entirely.
Why would they come after me?
Well, nuclear deterrence is the backbone of our national security.
A short time ago, the U.S. military carried out massive precision strikes.
You have Xi and Putin closer than they've ever been.
Iran and Israel is really a proxy war for this larger global conflict.
You have Pakistan having nukes.
Think about the amount of Al Qaeda still in northern Pakistan.
That could be a failed state at any moment.
I am gravely concerned about the situation in Pakistan.
If there was ever an explicit disclosure moment,
it might occur around us being on the brink if you have another kind of Cuban missile crisis.
Between September of 66 and March of 67, we lost 30 missiles to UFO activity.
30.
Our next guest was a witness of one of the most spectacular UFO nuclear-related cases we've ever had.
He was stationed at Malmstrom Air Force Base in Montana.
He was a missile launch officer there deep underground monitoring a group of 10 Minuteman missiles.
In March of 1967, while on duty, he received a call from an extremely frightened top side guard
reporting unidentified flying objects.
Glowing red lights hovering above the base.
You won't believe what happened next.
But the UFO appeared to interact with the nuclear weapons.
If this were an isolated incident, it would be one thing.
It's not.
It's a repeating pattern.
UFOs show up constantly around nuclear weapons in civilian energy grids.
The great journalist Robert Hastings has documented 167 Q-cleared witnesses
in his great book, UFOs and Nukes.
The link between UFOs and nuclear weapons is ubiquitous and widespread.
And our next guest's sighting at Malmstrom is one of four different sightings that I
am aware of in and around this particular Montana base.
This isn't an anomaly.
It's a real scientific pattern for those earnestly engaging with the data,
for the ones who won't just reflexively look away due to the stigma.
Just last month, the Wall Street Journal wrote a hit piece attempting to discredit our next guest.
They claimed that this whole event he witnessed was due to an experimental test of a non-nuclear EMP.
They cited an EMP model that wasn't even operational in 1967 and claimed that this
device was used on our own nuclear weapons with officers like him present.
The article made no sense and it really didn't even make an attempt to make any sense.
But it was written by a journalist that says that conspiracies around JFK's death are now
fueling a belief in the quote unquote deep state.
This journalist also just wrote an article railing against a psyop that marginalized Chinese COVID
vaccines.
Suffice it to say, I think we have very different worldviews.
But as you'll see in this interview with my next guest, history might not repeat, but it
certainly rhymes.
In 1967, they also tried to cover this case up using some very bad faith tactics.
Luckily for us, our next guest has documented the hypocrisy the entire way.
And even though the Wall Street Journal wouldn't let this 85 year old veteran publish a full
response to defend himself, he does so very eloquently here.
So without further ado, I'd like to welcome this week's American Alchemist, First Lieutenant Robert Salas.
I'm here with Bob Salas.
I'm so grateful to be here.
I appreciate you having me.
Um, I've been kind of citing your experience for the last two or three years on my show.
And so it's really cool to finally be in person and be able to, to, you know, hear it directly
from you.
And this couldn't be more timely because I had already been trying to get in touch with you
and interview you.
And then this kind of ridiculous Wall Street Journal, uh, piece comes out by this guy named
Joel Schechtman.
Clearly, you know, he's collaborating very closely, probably too closely with a guy named
Sean Kirkpatrick, who's the former head of the Aldo name, Aldo main anomaly resolution office.
And it just seems like, uh, a really botched kind of attempt at, uh, discrediting you entirely.
And basically saying that there was an EMP that was wheeled up to Malmstrom Air Force Base,
where you were first Lieutenant, you were working in the, you know, launch control facility.
And that is what explains these 10 nuclear missiles going down.
So anyways, it's very timely and I'm very grateful to be having this conversation with you.
I'm, I'm happy to talk about this. Uh, yes, I think there was a deliberate attempt to discredit
my story. Um, and, um, I've got some theories as to why that was done.
Yeah.
What are your theories as to why, or why don't we do this? Why don't we just get into the core
details first of what happened? And then, you know, a lot's going to be referencing that.
And then from there we can get into theories as to why people are trying to sabotage.
Uh, so in 1967, uh, I was assigned to a two man crew. Uh, my commander was, uh, Fred Mywald. Uh,
we were both lieutenants at the time and we were assigned to Oscar flight, which is near Lewistown,
Montana. No, I take that back. It's near Roy, Montana, which is about a hundred miles to the
east of Great Falls and Malmstrom Air Force Base located near Great Falls. So at this, uh,
site, we, we go underground to, uh, what we call the launch control center. And that's where we have
all the equipment down there to, uh, monitor and launch missiles if necessary. Uh, so on this
particular evening, March 24th, 1967, um, my commander, uh, was taking a rest break. We had a little
cut down there and I was in charge of the entire facility. Um, I get a call sometime in the evening.
I don't know when, uh, uh, uh, exactly. I was probably close to 9 PM or so. It was dark out
and the top side guard, which we call a flight security controller called down and said, uh,
sir, I've been seeing some strange lights in the sky, uh, overhead directly over us. Um,
they're strange because, uh, they're flying very fast, stopping in midair, reversing course,
doing 90 degree turns. Um, no engine noise. And sir, these are not airplanes. Uh, airplanes can't do
what this, these lights are doing. So, um, I even said, you mean like UFOs? Because we had actually
had, um, newspaper accounts in the Great Falls Tribune, uh, of people and, uh, like farmers and
citizens seeing strange lights in the sky at night that week. Yeah. Wasn't there a, there was a truck
driver and a police officer, if I'm not mistaken, who would also. Yeah. We'll, we'll get to that.
That's, that's an important part of this. Um, we can talk about it now if you want. On the same
night, um, and this I think was about seven 30 to eight in the evening, a truck driver was driving
through the town of Belt, Montana, which was about 35 miles to the Southeast of, uh, Great Falls. And,
uh, he looks over out his, his window and sees a bright light that's pacing him.
Going the same speed. And it's actually blinking at him. And he finds it a little strange. Um,
uh, it was just a big white ball of light to him. He stops a truck and, uh, and gets out and watches the
light, um, land, um, land in a ravine, uh, large ravine. Uh, he goes over there and takes a look,
sees it. And then, uh, then he calls the highway patrol and he wants to get somebody else to look at
this thing. And, uh, uh, the highway patrolman comes out. He also sees the light. The light comes
back up, flies off at high speed, and then comes back while the highway patrol was there.
Uh, they then call the, uh, uh, uh, county sheriffs. They come out, they see, uh, uh, they inspect a
little bit of the area where this object landed. They find some broken branches. They all decide to
call the air force base. We happen to have what was called a UFO officer at the base at the time
because of the Condon investigation. One of the air force to identify certain officers at certain
bases, uh, to help them with their investigation. And so they identified this particular guy,
a man by the name of Lieutenant Colonel Lewis Chase, who was also a base operations officer.
Uh, so Chase comes out. Um, I don't know if he saw the object or not, but, uh, at that time,
uh, but he decides that they can't bring a helicopter in that night, um, because they're not trained for,
uh, night operations in that area. And so, uh, he wait, he wants to wait till the morning.
Uh, and in the meantime, there are reports at Malmstrom Air Force Base. Objects are seen on radar. Objects are
seen by airmen at the base. Uh, again, bright white light, uh, flying around Malmstrom Air Force Base.
Um, and so, uh, Chase decides he needs to report all this. Uh, and he does in a, uh,
telegram to air force headquarters and also reports to Edward Condon. I writes a couple of reports.
I've got copies of them. Um, and they take the statement of the truck driver, et cetera.
And by the way, in the meantime, my missiles are shut down.
So you have missile security officers who are topside. They're calling down and they're saying
they're seeing. No, no, no security officers. These are airmen, you know, the non-commissioned
officers, uh, NCOs. Okay. Uh, and they're responsible for the security of the launch control facility.
In other words, and that's what I told him. So after the first call, we just hung up because it
was no point in talking about lights in the sky. I didn't think.
So you were like, what are you talking about? And you hung up and you were like, uh, you know.
Basically, yeah, I wasn't too interested in what he had to say after that. Uh, because, uh,
you know, he could have been seeing little stars, uh, there, I don't know. Uh, but then five minutes
later he calls back and this time he's frightened. He's really frightened. He's screaming into the phone.
He's babbling. Can't, I gotta calm him down. And finally I calm him down. He says, sir,
we got all the guards out. Uh, they're, they've got their weapons pointed at this red, orange
light, uh, pulsating light. It's huge. It's, uh, you know, I think he said 40 or some feet long. Um,
um, it was hard to see inside. I said, try to look inside the light and see if there's a
solid object in there. Uh, he said, it's, it's really difficult because it's so bright,
but it looks like there's some kind of a solid object in there. Old shaped is what he said. And I
said, uh, uh, and then he said, what do I do, sir? You know, I basically told him, I don't remember
the exact words, but I basically told him to make sure the secure, uh, the facility is secure,
that nobody enters the fenced area. Um, you know, basically it's your responsibility, right?
Uh, and so he hung up. He first said, uh, a guard got injured and I got to go.
The injury I'll talk about later, but it had nothing to do with the UFO. Um,
so he hung up. First thing I did is I looked over at our board, our status board that showed the
status of each missile. Right. And yeah, all the missiles were green at that time. Ready to go.
Ready to launch at any time. I went over to talk to my commander, uh, Fred Milo was taking a rest
break. Woke him up and started to tell him about the phone calls. And because now I'm thinking
there's something serious going on out there. Uh, that guy was really scared, really frightened. And,
um, before I could tell him about the phone calls, we'd get a big horn go off. One of the missiles
went off alert status or went from green to red. No go. Can't launch it.
Had that ever happened in your career thus far?
I was there for three years. One of them may have gone down for some power problem. Uh,
we had triple power redundancy, but anyway, uh, but nothing like multiple shutdowns. And right after
that one went down, all of them went down one, one at a time. As you know, I'm always on the hunt for
things that helped me stay sharp, focused, and full of energy while I'm diving into life's
mysteries and making this show happen. And I've got to say mud water has completely transformed
my mornings back in the day. I used to struggle with that post coffee crash and let's not even
get into the caffeine jitters. Mud water gave me the smooth, steady energy. I was missing.
It's packed with functional mushrooms like lion's mane chaga and reishi plus turmeric and cacao all
working together to keep me focused, calm, and grounded. Honestly, it's like coffee went on a yoga
retreat and came back Zen. What I love most is that it's not just about replacing coffee. It's a whole
new ritual. It's a simple nourishing way to start the day. And I actually look forward to it every
morning. Every ingredient is USDA certified organic, vegan, non-GMO, and there's zero sugar.
It's energy that doesn't mess with your sleep or make you question your life choices at 3am.
Ready to make the switch to cleaner energy? Head to mudwater.com. That's M-U-D-W-T-R.com
and grab your starter kit today. Right now, our listeners get an exclusive deal up to 43%
off your entire order, plus free shipping and a free rechargeable frother when you use code
JESSE. That's right, up to 43% off with code JESSE at M-U-D-W-T-R.com. After your purchase,
they'll ask you how you found them. Please show your support and let them know we sent you. Keep
your energy natural and refreshing all year long with mudwater because life's too short for anything
less than clean, delicious energy. So what do you do at that point? So we jump up, go through our
checklist. And we also had two of the launch facilities. The launch facilities are where
the missiles are actually located. They're about a mile away, mile or two. But at two of them,
we had incursion lights, meaning it's possible someone or something was trying to enter those
facilities where the missiles were. So I got on the horn or the phone and called upstairs. First thing I
asked about was this bright red glowing object. And he said, it just took off so it's gone. But it was
there when the missiles went down. But anyway, I sent guards out there and they again saw an object
above two of the launch facilities. Again, bright light hovering just above the facilities.
Uh, we brought those guys back to where we were. Uh, and they lost radio contact on the way back.
Strange. Anyway, uh, my world called wing command post report the, our incident, a shutdown, you know,
requesting maintenance screws to come out because we had a way of querying the system. Uh, we would get
an audio feedback of, uh, what was wrong with each missile. They were all reading guidance and control
system failure. So we thought, well, okay, we got to send a team out there to restart the missiles,
each one and retarget them. We had to check the targeting again. Uh, but after that call, he hangs
up, he turns to me and he says, the same thing happened at another flight. Now I thought he meant
that evening, but what he meant to say was that it happened before, uh, eight days earlier.
And that was what we've referred to now as the echo flight incident. We were at Oscar flight.
Uh-huh. And so before, before we get into the, uh, echo, yeah, go for it.
Yeah. But the, the reason the belt siding was important, uh, was because, uh, when Robert Jameson was
called at home to come in to the base, he was asleep, he was called, he sat around
10, 10 30 in the evening, uh, told to come into the base, uh, because there were, uh,
missile shutdowns that you need to work on. Yeah. In March of 1967, I got a call saying a missile
went off alert in Oscar flight. Well, that's all the information was given. They said a missile
went off alert. So I had called my team together. We went down to the hangar. I no sooner walked
into the hangar and a friend of mine walked up to me and says, have you heard what happened?
No. Uh, I just got here. He says, well, a missile, a UFO was reported over Roy, Montana,
which is where Oscar flight was. And all missiles went off alert. And I said, it's not possible.
Couldn't happen. So I went to a place called job control just to see, just to confirm this.
And sure enough on job control, they have a wall and they have green lights where all the missiles
are on alert. We had 200 missiles at the time, except for one corner, all 10 missiles were off
alert. All 10, whole flight was off alert, all red. And so then I said, yeah, they were off alert.
It doesn't happen. And he was also told that we are on lockdown right now because there's too much
UFO activity going on. I, like I mentioned, there are overflights of Mels from Air Force Base.
He assigned me four missiles to restart. He says, go ahead, get your team ready, but stay here.
Don't leave the hangar yet until we're sure that all the activity out there has ceased
and there's nothing else going on. Then we can release you. So I stayed around for the hangar
for a couple of hours. And then just before we were released, we had to go into a special briefing.
Normally we go into a briefing where they give you your, what your job is, like road conditions at
the time, weather conditions, anything else we may need to know. This time they brought us into a special
briefing and they told us there's UFOs out in the area. Here's what you have to do. If you're on your
road and you see a UFO, let us know by radar and go to the nearest launch control facility.
And okay, if you're breaking into the site, just break, just withdraw from the site. Let us, give us a call
and let us know what's happening. You see a UFO. However, if you're in the site and you're doing your work,
I was to take myself, my team members, and all our targeting tapes, take them downstairs into the
silo, close the silo, and we all take a guard with us. We have to leave him on top. Nothing happened on
the way out there. And targeting or the restarts, I had four of them. They went rather smoothly.
Missiles went right up as if nothing had happened to them. And I came back and then I was given
another briefing. I was told I wasn't supposed to tell about it, talk about this, but I am coming
out now. But Jameson was told about the belt incident. The same person that told me that all
Montana missiles went off alert also told me that there was a UFO that went down into a canyon near
a little town not far from Armstrong called Belt, Montana. There was a canyon there and there was a
UFO trapped in a canyon. And yeah, yeah, right, right. But he told me I'd go to the command post.
He set up a command post in the colonel's briefing room. So I went over there and I heard what they
were looking at. They had a radio contact with the people out in the field and they were telling me
about the lights. And now there's blue lights, now there's green lights. I was looking at the
UFO down at the bottom of the canyon. Now they were going, the canyon is too steep to send men down
in a night. This is at nighttime. Walls are too steep to send men down at night or even a helicopter
down through that. So they're going to take, and as soon as daylight comes, they're going to take
some helicopters and go down in there. And I found out later, yeah, as soon as daylight came,
they sent the helicopters and this UFO just went right through the helicopters and out, between the
helicopters and the helicopters and out. That's amazing. So you have Bob Jameson, who is a, he's a
targeting officer. Is that right? Right. And then who else came out publicly alongside you to test, to
testify to this UFO event? Well, eventually I got ahold of my commander who was down there with me. He was
the crew commander, Fred Mywald. He had retired a full colonel, um, had a distinguished career in, uh,
strategic air command, uh, headquarters. Uh, but of course he verified the essentials of the story. He
didn't remember at the time when I first contacted him exactly how many missiles had gone off alert,
but he remembered we did lose missiles, uh, during UFO sightings.
Did you record that conversation or is it public or is it just, you went to him?
I recorded it. It's on my website.
That's amazing.
Spiralgalaxy.org.
Check it out.
All right. Here's the sequence I remember. I remember receiving a call first and, and the security guard said, uh,
I've seen some UFOs up here flying around and I said, uh, forget it. You know, I didn't believe them.
I kind of hung up on them. And then a little while later, I don't know how long it was, maybe five,
10 minutes, maybe longer, uh, they called back and the guy sounded real scared and said there was one just
outside the front gate. And, uh, he's, and he also said, I recall that, uh, one of the other guards had
gotten injured in some way. I, I don't, I don't think it was from the UFO. I think it was from, uh,
trying to climb the fence or something like that. Uh, and then I hung up or he hung up because he had to go,
this guard got injured and then, and then I believe you were either getting up or I woke you up
and then some of our missiles started setting down. Is that right?
Mm-hmm.
Is that about how you remember it?
Right. We had security alarms and, uh, problems at a couple of the, uh, sites.
Yeah. Okay.
So I remember the two guards that had gone out to one of the sites, uh, finally got back scared to
death. We had relief from the junior.
Yeah.
Oh, you mean, uh, our guards?
Oh, I didn't know that.
Yeah, robot patrol type.
Oh, I see.
They had gone out to one of the sites, uh, on the LF there.
On the way back, they lost radio contact and we ended up having to send them back to base earlier.
I'm not sure what happened, but I don't think they ever returned to, uh, guard duty.
And what were they scared about?
Well, they had seen these some crazy things then.
Oh, they did?
Yeah.
So they reported that to you?
They reported it to the topside guy.
Oh, the topside guy. That's right. Okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay. Okay. Well, interesting. What's that?
Yeah.
Um, does anybody at the time after this experience come up with a prosaic explanation as to what's
happened? Or is everybody basically, uh, on the sort of consensus view that there was
UFOs appearing and that ostensibly there's some connection between the UFOs appearing above
the base and these 10 missiles going down?
There were, uh, one of the documents we received from the air force was a telegram or
telex about the echo flight shutdown, right? It names two individuals by name that worked for
Boeing aircraft. Uh, the SAC headquarters, uh, wanted people to do a complete investigation of
what happened. They used the words, this is a grave concern because we don't have any idea what
happened. I've got that telex, you know, this was no test. There was no test involved here.
SAC headquarters, uh, demanded that Boeing do an investigation.
And SAC for everybody is, is, is strategic air command.
That's right.
Yeah.
No.
So they had, they viewed this as a genuine UFO event taking down.
Well, because there were witnesses, uh, to the objects, uh, being seen over, over the echo flight.
And also in the case of the echo flight, they had security guards and maintenance people already on
site. They had stayed the night because they were going to work on those missiles.
Uh, and they reported to, uh, Fiegel, Walt Fiegel, uh, UFOs overhead or lights that they couldn't
explain overhead, uh, when the missiles went down.
The strike team that went out, one of the two, claimed that they saw something over the site.
How did they describe that?
He just sent a large round object.
Directly over the LS.
Directly over the site.
Let's talk about a guilt-free alternative to alcohol that's perfect for your dry January or
any time you want to unwind. Cornbread's organic CBD gummies. These gummies are an absolute
lifesaver for my evening routine. They're a natural way to relax, celebrate, or wind down without the
hangover. I've cut back a lot on my alcohol consumption over the last few years. For a lot
of you trying out dry January or cutting back generally, it's not always easy. But swapping
that glass of wine for cornbread CBD gummies is a total game changer. It's a simple upgrade to your
evening routine that leaves you feeling great the next day without sacrificing the fun. Plus,
with all natural ingredients, they're the perfect way to stay balanced. Cornbread hemp isn't just a
product. It's a small way to bring balance into your life. Whether you're journaling, meditating,
or simply enjoying some downtime, these gummies elevate the experience without any of the guilt.
It's like having a moment of calm in your pocket ready whenever you need it. Alcohol doesn't have
to be the default anymore. Whether you're cutting back for dry January or just looking for a healthier
way to relax, you've got to try cornbread CBD gummies. Right now, American Alchemy listeners can save
30% on their first order. Just head to cornbreadhemp.com slash jesse and use code jesse at checkout.
Again, that's cornbreadhemp.com slash jesse code jesse. Cornbread hemp, this is the good life.
Yeah, there were many witnesses. In fact, I mentioned the name of Ray Fowler.
Ray Fowler was a manager working under Sylvania Corporation. Sylvania had the contract for electrical
systems at Malmstrom, and he had people working there, contractors working for him, who reported to him
that they had seen these objects and that they were involved in the missile shutdowns.
So Fowler got this information from his people. He contacts Roy Craig, the chief investigator for Condon,
tells him all about it, gives him details, gives him names, dates, places, etc., phone numbers
of his people that can confirm the UFO's connection. And Craig says, okay, I'm going to go out to
Malmstrom and check this out. So he goes to Malmstrom, and I've got this on audio tape also, by the way.
He talks to Lewis Chase, the base ops officer, the base UFO officer, the same guy that went out to
Belk, Montana. He went to Belk, Montana, saw the object out there, wrote two messages, one to
U.S. Air Force headquarters, and another one to Condon, about the activity. And in one of those,
he says, I went to the base command post, or the wing command post, rather, and talked to the
officer in charge. This was the same officer that we had reported our incident to. And he said,
I coordinated with him on the UFO activity. In writing, he's got this in writing. When Craig goes
out there to talk to him, Chase, he denies it. The following interview, conducted by Roy Craig,
is with Lieutenant Colonel Lewis D. Chase, who is Chief of the Operations Division at Malmstrom Air Force
Base Base, Montana. The interview is being conducted at Malmstrom on October 19, 1967.
Now, right about that same time, we heard rumbles from other areas that something happened here on the
day, related to the failure of a flight of a minute man. It's just about the 24th of course. And this,
has this any connection with the UFO business? The rumor, the rumor mail has that there was a UFO socket
by one of the SAG maintenance crew who went out to check out why the flight had lost power.
As far as the status of the missile site was concerned here, I can't discuss this, Dr. Craig,
because what is on alert, what is not for all periods of time, I shouldn't refer you to other
people on that. All I can tell you is that the time that we had the reported landing,
the whole area here, we had lots of reports on them. But I'm not privy to knowledge of what the status of
the missile sites are. As you can see, this of necessity must be classified, and I'm not privy to
this type of knowledge. I think the comment that came to us was that some of the maintenance crew who
had to check out sites that had lost power, that's unexplained, had said they saw a white light come
down and circle the base in broad daylight or something like this, and then this would be
nice the next day after it had been, you know, and then a big hush-up sort of thing. You're not
aware of anything of this sort? No. No, this I'm not, because I wouldn't know what the status of the
of the missiles were. Now, I understand that it's common for us to have a commercial power failure
or something like this. This happens repeatedly, such as commercial power does anyway.
So, and I just have a suspicion that some of the commercial power people have to, there happened
to be a power outage someplace, and they tried to tie the two of them together. But this, I would
tell, but I would respect this as a real strong possibility.
He didn't know anything about it. Why did he do that? He did that because he did not want
content investigators snooping around and putting in their report that UFOs had shut down missiles.
Do you think somebody got to him? Like, did he have some ulterior motive? Why would he want,
why would he want to deny, you know, the committee that he's supposedly working for access to an event
that seems like it's their mandate to investigate?
Because the Air Force organized this whole content investigation as a whitewash.
It was whitewashed even before they got started. There was a famous letter written by the deputy
de Kahn and Robert Lowe, who wrote a memo stating that there was going to appear to be a scientific
investigation, but indeed they would find nothing. And then there was another letter that Chase had
written after having a big meeting in June of 67 with other base UFO officers,
and the Condon investigative team, um, uh, stating that the, um, the wording of the final
wording for the Condon investigation would read, you know, nothing to see here.
Yeah. I believe there are letters too, between, uh, Colonel Robert Hippler of the Air Force
and Condon. And basically, uh, Hippler's saying like, I want you to show that this was all a waste
of time and money. He's talking about blue book and Condon sort of complying with that. So it seemed
like a kind of a hit job. It was a whitewash. Yeah. So in fact, it was Hitler when, uh, after this
meeting, which I've, between Craig and Lewis, Craig went to Lowe and said, maybe we ought to get the
report on their investigation. And, uh, Lowe said later on, he replied, he said, I've already talked
to Hippler. Hippler said, this is probably going to be too high, uh, highly classified for us to look
at. And plus Hitler told him he, they think the Air Force thinks that EMP from nuclear testing was the
cause of these shutdowns. Really? Yes. Really. Back then? Back then. Back. Oh. Uh, I've got it in
writing. That's wild. Interesting. Any specifics on like the, the model or anything or? When I read
that, when we read that, my investigator, James Klotz, who's a coauthor of that first book we wrote,
uh, uh, gentleman still living, uh, um, we, uh, checked with the Department of Energy, who was in
charge of, well, cognizant of nuclear, uh, testing being done in the Nevada desert, right? Time. There
were no, there were no nuclear tests on June or, uh, March 16th or March 24th. So it couldn't have
been EMP from a nuclear test. Yeah. And that's, I think, you know, I got into this whole squabble
online or whatever, where people are saying there were EMPs at Starfish Prime in 62 or whatever. And
there, there are EMPs that are caused by nuclear detonations. Yes. But my understanding is that
operational non-nuclear EMPs weren't, maybe at most, they were, you know, undergoing extremely
preliminary investigation at DOE sensitive sites, but they weren't being used, let alone on our own
nukes, live nukes. There's no way. Absolutely not. In fact, um, in our book, again, Fated Giant,
we talk about, uh, references. We list the references, actually. People can look them up of, uh,
testing that was done, uh, on our kind of equipment, but it was done at a base like, um, uh, Space
Missile Systems Organization in, uh, San Bernardino Hill Air Force Base in Utah, but it was, uh, not
operational equipment. I mean, it, the equipment wasn't operational, but it was the type of equipment
we had, right? They did want to do authentic tests and to see what impact was. Now we're talking about
something like the production of 6 million volts of electricity in EMP, uh, discharge.
We're also talking about, uh, equipment that was not mobile. In order to produce this EMP,
they had to set up, uh, a superstructure to hold the, uh, the generating device that would,
that would, uh, fire 7, 6 million volts.
And that took time to build. I mean, it took at least three days from what I understand.
Yeah. You can't install that in secret. Even in the diagram in the Wall Street Journal,
it was like a 60 foot test stand or whatever was required to uphold the EMP. And the idea that that
would get wheeled up to the gate without, you know, any of these, you know, officers understanding that
the EMP was there and not being freaked out about some UFO.
Well, they would have reported it. The guards upstairs would have reported any activity like
that.
Yeah. It makes no sense. And it's interesting to see the Wall Street Journal use the same
cover story as Robert Hippler used back then. That's, you know, kind of interesting.
Kind of. Hippler stated to Lowe, apparently, and I've got this in writing, a handwritten note
by Robert Lowe, that he talked to Hippler and Hippler told him the Air Force thinks that EMP
from nuclear testing was the cause of the shutdown.
That's even better because that's like, it's like Roswell where they have, you know, it's like a
weather balloon and then it's like these, you know, Huntington's disease children using, you
know, an experimental Nazi craft. It's like they changed the story like five times. So it sounds
like back then it was a nuclear detonation. Now it's a test EMP. The exact model of which cited by
the Wall Street Journal wasn't actually tested until 71 and ready until 1973. Right.
So it's absolutely crazy. Interesting. Yeah. They got to get their story straight. They're
going to debunk well.
Boeing also did a bench test on what's called the logic coupler. Okay. The logic coupler is,
think of it as an onboard computer that would take data from onboard instruments after the
launch of the missile, Minuteman 1. Again, an inertial guidance system. We didn't have GPS
satellites up there guiding this thing on target, right? It had to compute how well it was doing
to get on target, right? In flight. And this logic coupler would help with that processing.
So Boeing took that piece of hardware and did a bench test and were able to momentarily cycle
it off by injecting a certain energy or electrical input, certain frequency, voltage, duration.
and, uh, uh, basically cause it to malfunction, uh, momentarily and cause the guidance system
to shut down. Interesting.
So, uh, they suggested it as a possible cause of the failure mode, guidance and control system
failure. However, they had no idea on how that could be injected into this, each missile separately
within seconds and shut each missile down, uh, so quickly. Um, because number one, we had, uh,
what's called a, um, these large cable, about eight to nine inch in diameter. They were triply shielded.
They went from the location we were, the capsule, uh, underground, uh, for another mile or so,
but they were triply shielded against EMI, electromagnetic interference.
And so they did say in this report that, um, they think it was an externally caused, uh, it was an
external signal that caused the shutdowns, but they could not explain how that signal got into the system.
Yeah. So Boeing goes in, they test it and presumably they're using whatever state of the art methods exist at
the time, as far as shutting down nukes. And they're going directly after the accelerometers, these inertial
mass units, and they can show that they could do it in one, but that doing that simultaneously in 10 is
impossible. Right.
And they admit to being puzzled afterwards that they're, they're brought in as consultants.
They are paid presumably to, you know, success for them is explaining it in a prosaic fashion.
That's how they're judged. And they're unable to do that.
Yeah. They were identified. These two, the individuals that did this testing were identified by
SAC headquarters by name. They wanted those two people to do these, uh, you know, to do part of the
investigation, but we were in contact with, uh, James Klotz and I, uh, made contact with them and
talked to them. Um, and they said that, um, they couldn't explain how that signal could have
possibly have gotten in there. Hey everyone, Jesse here. Let's talk about something a lot of us
quietly deal with hair loss. This is something that messes with your confidence more than you'd expect.
Okay. You might be wondering, Jesse, you clearly don't suffer from this. It's true. The biggest
issue I face is hat hair. I actually have very thick hair, but one of my good friends deals with
hair loss. So when I restore sent me their, I restore elite, I gifted it to him and I've been
amazed at the results it gave him. The first thing that stood out to him is it's comfortable and easy
to use. You just pop it on while reading or working and it does its thing. This isn't some gimmick.
It uses 300 lasers and 200 LEDs to deliver clinically backed red light therapy straight to
the scalp. This is the best way to stimulate hair growth. Over the past few weeks, I've seen noticeable
improvement with my friend. He says that his hair feels thicker and healthier and it's improved his
overall confidence in life. The iristore elite uses triple wavelength technology and lumatech red
light therapy. It's engineered for deeper penetration and broader coverage. That means more stimulation to
hair follicles and better, faster results. And look, if it doesn't work for you, they offer a 12
month money back guarantee. I've never heard of a money back guarantee that lasts that long.
Try it consistently. And if you're not happy, they get you your money back. Of course,
the restocking fee applies. That made it a no brainer for my friend. So give yourself the gift of
hair confidence this spring. For a limited time only, our listeners get a huge discount on iristore
elite. When you use code Jesse, J E S S E at iristore.com. Head over to iristore.com and use
code Jesse, J E S S E for our show's exclusive discounts on the iristore elite. Please support
our show and tell them we sent you. Hair loss is frustrating. You don't have to fight it alone.
Thanks to iristore. How did you, after that, did you live your life differently outside of having
experienced this highly anomalous event and probably being questioned about it and wanting
to get the message out that maybe we're, we're not alone? Uh, you know, outside of that, did
it change your perspective on life or, you know, change your view, your worldview in any kind
of profound ways? Well, um, I lost confidence in the integrity of the air force after that for
sure. I, you know, I had planned, uh, a career in the air force. And after this, I wasn't quite so
sure I wanted to do that. Uh, and so it changed it in that way. Yeah. And, uh, Malmstrom is no
stranger to incidents like these, right? So the eight days before you mentioned the echo flight incident,
what, what exactly happened there? I echo flight, um, Walt Fiegel again, a lieutenant at the time,
later a colonel, retired. Uh, as far as I know, still living, talked to him about a year ago, I think.
But, um, he was in, he was, uh, in charge of the facility. Uh, and one of the missiles gets shut down.
One of the missiles where, um, he had guards and security, uh, well, uh, maintenance people and
security people out at two of the launch facilities. They had stayed overnight because they were going
to start early the next morning and do some kind of modification to these, uh, missiles. Um,
he calls out there and says, you guys aren't supposed to do anything without my permission. And
they said, we didn't do anything. Uh, by the way, the, uh, these objects are hovering just above us.
And, uh, at first he couldn't believe what they were saying, but, uh, very shortly after that,
uh, all 10 of his missiles went down. Wild. So very similar. Similar. Yeah. And then I want to tell
you about an incident that happened in 1966, September of 1966 at Minot Air Force Base,
North Dakota, not in Montana. This is just North Dakota. Uh, again, another witness has come forward,
a man by the name of David Shindell, um, who relieved the crew. Uh, but before they relieved the crew,
they, uh, he talked to the security people upstairs who told, who told him that UFOs were seen over
the facility the night before. Uh, when they got down to relieve the crew, all 10 missiles had been
shut down. After entering the capsule, our eyes were immediately transfixed on the launch control
council, which showed that all missiles were off alert and unlaunchable. We had never seen such a thing
before. The outgoing crew briefed us on the wild events that transpired overnight and indicated that
the missiles malfunctioned at the time the object was hovering directly above the capsule and next to
the main gate. And again, uh, this was as a result of the UFO activity above the facility. So we're talking
between September of 66 and March of 67, we lost 30 missiles to UFO activity.
It's wild. Yeah. 30, 30. That's pretty, pretty insane. Um, and, and Malmstrom itself. I mean,
even Robert Hastings who wrote this, you know, probably the authoritative chronicle of all of the
UFO events when it comes to nuclear weapons, UFO and nukes, great book. Uh, he was a janitor at
Malmstrom air force base, I believe in 67. And he, I guess this like radar operator had taken him under
his wing and was teaching him about radar theory and brought him over. They said they were tracking
unknowns at the time. One night. And as best as I can tell, it was the second half of March of 67
was emptying trash cans and pushing a broom. And he motioned me over to his scope
and he pointed, he said, we're tracking. And he probably said unknowns. That's the formal term for
unidentified objects. I saw five blips in the sort of Northeast quadrant of his radar scope.
And then he thinks that that might've been around the same time as, as your incident.
It could have been, uh, I believe his father worked in that facility.
That's right. Yeah. Yeah. Uh, this was part of the NORAD organization, right?
Yep. That would monitor the skies, uh, for possible incoming, you know, bombers or whatever
heading for the U S. But, uh, yeah, that's, that's true.
And then I believe, um, in 1993, there's a, a now retired missile technician, a guy named John
Mills, who was headed, I think with, you know, some four other guys, they had left the base
and they're headed towards Malmstrom. They saw a UFO hovering around Malmstrom. They get back to the
base and apparently everybody there said that the base had been swarmed. Um, and so, and then there's,
there's even their other, there's a guy named Chris Langan, who's known for having this sort of theory
of everything in physics, which, you know, maybe take that with a grain of salt. I don't know how real
that is, but you know, maybe he's got a big ego. I don't know if the theory is real. I don't think
he's lying about the fact that he said he was driving past, you know, um, uh, uh, uh,
near, uh, Malmstrom and he sees a UFO right ahead on the UFO thing. I was working for the
forest service, not too far from Malmstrom air force base. One day I was up there in a
forest service pickup truck at a certain campground. And, uh, I was there and suddenly I look up
and I say, suddenly it was just in the sky. I became aware that it was up there. And I looked
up and there's this huge spheroidal, you know, but elliptical, not, not a perfect spheroid,
like a saucer that was turned partially on its side.
So it just seems like there's a real pattern over time with Malmstrom.
Uh, even though the air force tried to get out of it in 1969, they even quoted the Condon
investigation and said that, um, we have no evidence that, uh, UFOs cause of, or cause of
national security concern. And, uh, therefore, uh, we're going to shut down blue book. We're
not going to be reporting to the public on UFO sightings, and we're probably not going to
do much investigating ourselves. Well, uh, incidents continue to occur, you know, again,
in, uh, uh, 1975 at Malmstrom, uh, there is a NORAD report of UFO settings, uh, again, over
Malmstrom, uh, missile basis, 1968. Uh, I've listed about 13 in my book.
Uh, incidents involving nuclear weapons and UFOs.
And when you did come out and go public, you've, you've done interviews with Larry King and
you've spoken at various conferences all over the world. Um, did you receive any backlash
and did you, uh, experience any resistance about your testimony?
I never have.
That's pretty remarkable. Do you have a theory as to why? Cause some of your colleagues who
have come, gone public, people like Bob Jacobs, photo instrumentation specialist,
at Vandenberg in 64, he's experienced obviously a lot of reprisals and, you know, took a career,
such a career hit that they denied he ever even worked at, at Vandenberg and was, you know,
uh, uh, even involved, you know, in the air force.
Yeah. My, uh, I'm just speculating again. Why? Because I did sign a non-disclosure agreement,
which basically I violated when I started going public about my incident being at Oscar flight. I
didn't find that out until 1996 when I finally contacted, uh, I was able to contact my commander
friend, my world. And he told me we were not at echo flight. We were at Oscar flight. I've been
speaking that about the echo flight incident as though it was mine because it was so similar to
what I had recalled. But once he told me that I realized I was in violation of the NDA and I had
to make a decision as to whether I should shut up, no longer talk about it or keep going, keep talking
about it. And I decided to keep going.
Did they make you sign an NDA around this specific incident or just working really?
Yes. And that's what everybody says. That's what Mario Woods says. That's what, you know,
everybody who experiences the incident right after they make you sign an NDA.
Right. And do you remember what the NDA said or like what, what that was like,
like who came up to you and said, you have to sign this?
Yeah. Uh, right after we were relieved by another crew, after our incident occurred,
we were ordered back to the base to our squatter commander's office, walked in there,
and, uh, first thing I asked, by the way, uh, my squatter commander, who was an ex-World War II
B-17 pilot, tough as nails. He was white as a sheet. And I asked him what the hell happened there.
I, you know, in our incident, was this some kind of an Air Force test to see, you know,
how we'd respond or anything like that? He said, absolutely not. There was no test involved. He
didn't know anything more than I did. And by the way, he introduced me to a man from AFOSI,
Air Force Office of Special Investigation. It was in the office with him. And all he wanted was
to have us sign a non-disclosure agreement. I complained about that because, um, we already
had above top secret, you know, if they told us not to talk about this, we wouldn't, you know.
But that seems like a recurring pattern is an Air Force office of special investigation
agent always shows up around nuclear UFO incidents and then swears you to secrecy.
Right. Right.
So that's, yeah, it just seems like this, uh, pattern. That's fascinating.
They want to clamp down on witnesses.
Are you familiar with, have you heard of the Pentacle Memo? Do you know what that is?
No.
So this was Jacques Vallée, who was kind of Jalen Hynek's assistant, you know, Blue Book. Obviously,
Jalen Hynek is this, you know, Northwestern professor, astronomer. So Jacques Vallée is looking
through the Blue Book files and he finds this thing called the Pentacle Memo, which is this guy
named Howard C. Cross, who is a guy who works at Battelle Memorial Institute. And he is writing,
basically, uh, saying like, we have, uh, all these sensitive sites around which UFOs are showing
up regularly. And we know that these hotspots exist and Battelle is going to do a more surgical,
real investigation of these things while basically, you know, Blue Book is going to go on doing its
front, front facing kind of BS PR job. And Jacques Vallée, and apparently this couldn't get brought
up around the Robertson panel. Like there's, you're, you were not supposed to bring this,
this memo up. And so Jacques Vallée goes to Jalen Hynek privately and says, did you know about this?
Like, you know, are you, um, are you kind of complicit in, uh, uh, basically concealing,
you know, are what's supposed to be this earnest UFO inquiry from this actually real vital investigation
that's going on around, you know, nuclear sites across the U S and Jalen Hynek kind of plays dumb
and says, you know, I didn't know about it and stuff. Uh, but I do wonder sometimes, you know,
especially when you hear this very coordinated effort that involves Air Force offices, special
investigations agents, was there something underneath Blue Book, underneath the Condon,
you know, commission that was very real about, you know, there was a real UFO investigation
going on at the time. Oh, absolutely. No question about it. Uh, I mentioned that, uh, you know, since
probably 47, there's been, um, an attempt to, uh, seriously cover up, uh, anything, um, that was
found related to UFOs, you know, such, such as craft that were retrieved or non-human intelligences
that were retrieved. Uh, and those were studied and worked on in secret.
Well, like you say, organizations like Blue Book were just kind of, uh, a way to, uh, quell
public excitement over this subject. Yeah. At what point do you think the Air Force made that
decision to split off kind of, you know, the, this front facing facade, Blue Book, and then more
vital investigations of UFOs? Was it around the Robertson panel in 1952, maybe, or?
Okay. So in, uh, 1948, there was a, um, uh, and this was the precursor to Blue Book. It was called
Project Sign, right? People that were working on that had come up with enough information,
pilot reports, et cetera, uh, to conclude that these were extraterrestrial objects. They were not
manufactured on Earth. And they wanted, and so, uh, the Air Force Chief of Staff, Hoyt Vandenberg,
uh, wanted a briefing. And so they produced a briefing for him, uh, called the Estimate of the
Situation. It was a real document. It was seen by Ruppelt, uh, who would be the next, uh, head of
Blue Book, the first head of Blue Book, really, uh, after Project Sign. And he read the thing, and,
and he confirmed in his book, I've got a copy of his book that he wrote, uh, Ruppelt wrote.
It was Report on the Unidentified Object, yeah.
Yeah. And, um, he confirmed that, uh, they had strong evidence that these were not
aircraft, uh, that we knew how to build, uh, because of their abilities to maneuver,
maneuvering abilities. And he confirmed this must have been from elsewhere, off Earth.
Yeah, well, you had Nathan Twining writing in this 1947 memo to this guy, Brigadier Shulgren,
and he's saying, you know, UFOs are not visionary or fictitious. He even says in the postscript of
the memo, we have within our means, or within our knowledge, the ability to build these crafts.
But if we were to do that, if, if, if directed, you know, these would need to basically look like
the Manhattan Project. They'd need to take place in a wholly separate compartment from existing
projects and, you know, kind of exist very, you know, sub-Rosa and, and this sort of secret.
But anyway, uh, Vandenberg, uh, didn't buy this estimate of the situation and, uh, basically
informed Blue Book that, you know, they're full of it. They're, they're going to tamp down on,
uh, any, any, any idea that, uh, these could be extraterrestrial. And, and so they changed
the whole fabric of, uh, Blue Book, um, after that. That turned into a Project Grudge, I think
it was called, after Blue Book. Um, and that's when they started, uh, doing more disinformation.
And, and, and again, from the Robertson panel too, the, the directive was, um, let's keep
an eye on UFO, uh, groups that are looking at this, these reports, uh, let's infiltrate
them. Uh, let's, you know, do whatever we can to keep the public from getting too excited
about all this. Yeah. To this day. Right. So we just talked about the Condon Commission,
which was very interesting, you know, supposed to be this impartial study that the Air Force
was supposed to have no involvement with. And, you know, they were going to objectively evaluate
the results of Blue Book. I think we both know that might actually not have been the case.
It might've been sort of a bad faith effort. Talk, talk to us about that because that's,
I didn't even realize, you know, I've, I've been talking about your story for a while because
it's such a remarkable case and I didn't even realize how much the Condon Commission kind
of tied in, you know, with the officer there and yeah. Uh, well, let me, let me just start
with this. Um, in 1949, I believe it was, um, J Edgar Hoover wrote a letter, um, to, uh, Congress.
I'm not sure it was McCarthy or not, but, uh, in that letter he identified Edward Condon
as, and I'm paraphrasing nothing less than a Russian spy. I've got a copy of that letter.
And so Condon, who had been, um, actually part of, uh, the Manhattan project, he was number
two man under, um, under Oppenheimer, but there was a security issue. I don't know the details
of that, but, uh, he was asked to resign for the Manhattan project from, because of some
security issue. And so he did resign, but later he was appointed, um, um, um, um, not sure
the agency, but, uh, by Truman, he was appointed to some head of agency. And then this letter
comes out from Hoover. And, um, um, so he was questioned by, uh, during the McCarthy hearings
and, uh, eventually he lost his security clearance as a result of that. And so he went to work
for the University of Colorado, uh, as a physicist. He was a very good physicist, well respected.
Um, and at some point, um, uh, I think this was, uh, uh, someone who knew him, Lou Branscombe?
Lou Branscombe, yeah.
Yeah. He came to visit Condon and said, you know, uh, and this was in the, uh, around 1966,
I think it was. Um, he said, you know, it's been a while since, um, since you lost your
security clearance. Maybe it's time you reapply it to see if you can get that clearance back
because I know you want to do some research, uh, um, and get some government funding for
it. And, um, he said, um, well, he wasn't sure this would be a, um, successful,
but Branscombe told him, uh, you know, the Air Force needs someone to head up this UFO study
and it would help if you accepted that. It would probably help you get your security clearance.
Anyway, that's, that's the background. I don't know what actually happened there, but, uh,
uh, Condon actually gave an interview to the, um, um, physical society or physical
American Institute of Physics.
Thank you. American Institute of Physics. He gave a long interview. Uh, and I think this
was discussed in that interview.
Yeah. Well, it's funny in that interview, he talks about Lou Branscombe just randomly goes
up to him. He says, Hey, maybe you should get your security clearance back. No explanation.
And Branscombe is deep in the, uh, kind of defense, you know, elite apparatus of the U S at the time.
He's a part of the Jason advisory group, which is, you know, this group that's meeting in Santa
Barbara talking about the most kind of elite frontier weaponry, you know, uh, uh, defensive
and offensive. And so he, he goes to, to, to con and says, maybe you should get your security
clearance back. The interviewer in this American Institute of Physics interview with, uh, Condon
then says, why'd you need your security clearance? Like if all of this stuff was bogus, were
you, you know, reviewing any sort of classified material as part of the Condon, you know, commission
and he gets very awkward and he says, you know, maybe there was a video or two. I don't
really know, you know, sort of like walking back, you know, his stuff. Um, and it's interesting
about, I didn't know that about the J Edgar Hoover letter about him, but I D I did know that
a guy named Guy Hoddle, who's an FBI field agent in Washington is basically, uh, creating
a dossier on Condon throughout the fifties after he loses his queue clearance. And he did
clash with Leslie Groves six weeks into the Manhattan project because he wanted, you know,
more openness around nuclear stuff. Uh, and so that's why he was fired. And so that brings
up this line in, uh, the movie Oppenheimer where Leslie Groves, his character, he says, you
know, I didn't hire Oppenheimer in spite of his communist sympathies. I hired him because
of them. And I think about this guy in Condon who's been marginalized, you know, he's lost
his queue clearance. They said that, you know, he had labor, labor sympathies in the twenties
or whatever. And then they just randomly give him his clearance back, you know, they, and
they have all this compromise on him through Guy Hoddle. I mean, who, I couldn't pick a better
person to do your dirty work as far as kind of doing a hit job on, on the whole UFO
thing. Right. Fascinating. Also, he, you know, he wrote the McMahon secrecy act, which
was in 1946. A lot of the language in that act worked its way into the atomic energy act
of 1954. And so he's kind of laid out the secrecy protocols for UFOs. And then, so it's
this weird history with Condon. It's just fascinating. Yeah. Do you think that that's
going on at all today? Cause you, you know, you have this wall street journal article coming
out saying that an EMP was, you know, somehow wheeled up to, you know, Malmstrom in plain
sight of all of these people who claim to witness a UFO. They don't even report on the witnessing
of the UFO. They just discard that entirely. It just seems like a hit job. Like this doesn't
seem like an earnest, uh, impartial accounting of the facts that you relayed to them.
Yeah. Let's talk a little bit about that. Why would they come after me? Uh, well, I can
think of, uh, the rationale, uh, that would go this way. Um, the basis of our national security,
so says the department of defense on a yearly basis when they, they put out their, um, nuclear
posture review, it's a, basically a, a statement, um, about nuclear weapons is that nuclear deterrence
is the backbone, the basis of our national security, nuclear deterrence. So if I start, you know,
coming forward and speaking about strange objects that are able to, uh, disable our nuclear weapons,
uh, of course, um, that's going to require the department of defense to explain what they're
doing about it, if anything, whether they can do anything about it. And they've also already said,
no, uh, nuclear deterrence, which is the concept started in the fifties, by the way, that says,
uh, if we have a preponderance of nuclear weapons more than any other nation, or at least as much,
um, no nation will attack us with nuclear weapons or even non-nuclear weapons. Um,
and so we've used that rationale, that rationale caused, uh, the arms race during the cold war,
right? To the point where in 1967, uh, the world, uh, nuclear powers at a 32,000, 32,000 nuclear weapons.
Now, uh, these weapons range, you know, in the kiloton range to, uh, to megaton or a million tons of TNT
equivalent, um, but certainly enough to, uh, destroy every living thing on earth if we use them in a nuclear war.
And we still have 20,000 today total. Uh, we've got nine, uh, nuclear nations and, uh, everybody's afraid now that Iran will get one.
That's right. And, uh, um, um, the fact is that, uh,
you know, with, uh, uh, uh, uh, an effort, it's nuclear weapons are probably, could probably be accessed by any country that really wants them.
Uh, because the technology is out there. How to build a nuclear bomb is out there. In fact, I, I once saw a website that went through all the details on how to do that.
Jesus. Yeah. Yeah. Uh, anyway, um, so I don't think, uh, the, the, the reason they would want to discredit people like myself, Dave Shindell,
and many other witnesses to this phenomenon where UFOs have been interacting at nuclear weapons facilities, um, I've only touched the surface with those 13 that I mentioned in my book.
There have been many, many others. I've been in touch with witnesses who are afraid to come forward or can't come forward because of, uh,
non-disclosure agreements and fear of losing their jobs or their lives or whatever. Um, but there are many other witnesses out there that could come forward, uh, to talk about incidents that happened, um, where they were involved.
Have you met any witnesses who have not been public and kind of fear for their lives or reputations and confide in you around this stuff?
Yes.
Have you met any that also have nuclear incidents, nuclear related?
Have you met any that have seen craft in hangers in on the ground or are they all aerial witnessings of UFOs?
Well, uh, what I can tell you is that, uh, I had, um, uh,
something happened to me where I met, uh, one of my friends from the Air Force Academy, um, who indicated to me that he had actually flown, um, um, um, a craft similar to a UFO, uh, that operated under similar principles.
Wow.
Was it in his belief it was of non-human origin or it was like in some sort of gravity by defying craft that we had built?
Uh, we didn't get into those details, but, uh, let's just say I believed him.
Uh, and, uh, so I think we have back-engineered, uh, craft that had been recovered.
That's wild.
Did he say anything about the experience of flying it, like the G-Force or the way the back-to-end?
He was pretty excited, but, uh, the way it went down, it was very quick.
Uh, he was, um, he didn't want to go into details.
Obviously, this was highly classified.
Um, and he was concerned about my knowing about it after he said it.
But you feel like he was trustworthy?
Absolutely.
I spent four years going through the academy with him.
Wow.
Well, that, that's always been.
I knew, I knew him very well.
Yeah, yeah.
So it's not, not your, uh, limited hangout, you know, at a UFO conference, you get targeted with some, some info or whatever.
It's, this is a long trusted friend who opens up to you towards the end of that four year period around this?
Oh, it was after.
It was after.
Oh, yeah.
I was out of the Air Force at the time.
So how long had you known him before he confided in you around this?
Well, I, uh, I'd say, uh, well, we went through four years together and this was about 10 years after graduation.
Well, I won't push you farther, but if he wants to go public at any point, I would talk to him.
That is fascinating.
Yeah.
Um, but I, let's just say I know other witnesses who could come forward and validate some of these things.
It's so interesting.
I mean, yeah, clearly even you look at Robert Hastings book and you have 167 queue cleared guys who all had to sign NDAs immediately after their sightings.
Many of whom face career reprisals.
You have to think if 167 people who are coming out, despite all the disincentives to come out, it's got to be thousands of actual witnesses and people who, who, you know, in reality have experienced things around nuclear specifically alone.
Um, there've been many, many.
And it's so interesting too, to, you know, sometimes you'll hear about a UFO story in the lore, like the aerial school sighting in 1994 with you have 60, you know, school children in Zimbabwe.
And you learn that there's a uranium mine right there or the Pascagoula, you know, the fishermen in Pascagoula, you know, in, in 74.
And then you realize that all the, you know, Navy nuclear subs were being built in Pascagoula, Missouri.
So there's often this kind of unknown connection too.
Do you think that it's, um, you know, we were talking about theories before the cameras were rolling.
Do you think that they are trying to save us from ourselves and make us realize our sort of brutish ways?
Do you think that it generalizes beyond nuclear to like, you know, advanced science, like particle accelerators or AI or, you know, any other things like that?
Or do you think it's just nuclear?
What do you think?
Uh, well, what I think is, uh, uh, they see us as very warlike and, and with nuclear weapons, um, we could,
we could have a nuclear war.
I mean, it's not out of the realm of possibility now.
I think, um, what's happening in, currently with Iran and Israel, um, um, you know, we can, we can all visualize how that could escalate into the use of, of, uh, nuclear weapons.
I, yeah, go for it.
Now we're going to say, uh, yeah,
we also have Pakistan and India who are at war with each other, both nuclear powers.
Russia has threatened to use so-called tactical nukes against Ukraine.
Uh, but even if a small nuke like a, and by that we're talking about, uh, these tactical nukes are 15 to 20 kilotons equivalent, uh, TNT.
And that's the same size nuke that was used at Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
Yeah, it's a scary state.
We're in a multipolar nuclear world.
That's like, you know, it's funny.
I feel like cold war, uh, tensions have died down in some ways, uh, as far as like the zeitgeist, you know, that sort of dive, duck and roll.
Like we're, we're not mentally prepared, but it's actually worse than, you know, maybe pre, you know, uh, Berlin wall falling where all of a sudden you have Xi and Putin closer than they've ever been.
Then, you know, Iran and Israel is really a proxy war for this larger kind of global, global conflict.
You have Pakistan, you know, having nukes, which like, you know, think about the amount of, uh, Al Qaeda still in Waziristan, Northern Pakistan.
Like that could be a failed state at any moment.
I think Obama was quoted as saying that keeps him up more than anything at night, that Pakistan becoming a failed state.
So the amount of threat vectors around nuclear specifically are growing.
And sometimes I think, I don't know if you think this too, that like, if there was ever a, an explicit disclosure moment, it might occur around us being on the brink.
If you have another kind of Cuban, Cuban missile crisis or an event where nukes are about to go off and you have more explicit intervention, like the intervention you saw at Malmstrom in 67, but around missiles that are maybe about to go off or something that might bring.
The, you know, kind of collective world into a greater understanding around these things.
I don't know.
So in 1914, H.G. Wells wrote this book called The World Set Free.
And in that book, he talks about, uh, the construction of an atomic bomb.
Yeah.
And not only that, but he talks about, um, in different terms, but the generation of, of energy or electricity from, uh, a nuclear reactor.
He even predicted dates, which are close.
The first nuclear reactor went online in Russia in 1954.
And I think he, he, he mentions in his, this novel, The World Set Free, um, it happened in, uh, 55, I think, in, in this book.
Um, but he even talks about the first time on, uh, uh, the splitting of the atom and something like the transmutation, uh, which occurred, creating, uh, two different elements by the splitting of the atom.
Um, you know, which actually happened.
That was, uh, uh, uh, happened to be a Nazi scientist by the name of, um, um, Hahn, I think, uh, who did an experiment in 1938 and, uh, was first, uh, to split the atom.
Um, and plus they detected a certain, uh, uh, amount of energy from, from that reaction that could be enormous if, uh, many atoms were split, uh, in very short order, which was the chain reaction, right?
Which was later done.
But anyway, this book became, uh, um, the reason that, uh, was, it was brought to the attention by Einstein and, and another fellow who's a name I can't remember right now.
Um, but they wrote to FDR for a meeting about the possibility that Germany could build an atomic bomb.
Um, and that's what started, uh, the process of, uh, having our own program, the Manhattan Project, uh, to, to beat Nazi Germany to the bomb.
And, uh, so fascinating.
Yeah.
The history is so amazing.
And, you know, the Germans really seemed ahead of us for a while.
They were worried.
Heisenberg was known as this genius at the time and he was running the German program.
Right.
And then Luis Walter Alvarez at the Livermore lab, you know, figured out that, you know, maybe, maybe we could do this too.
And then it seems like they went off on the wrong path and really started experimenting with this heavy water engine, you know, sort of deuterium.
Um, and, uh, and that ended up.
They're not working out, but, um, who knows, you know, this is really trippy and weird, but it's just a connection I made is, um, a lot of the rumors around, you know, UFOs and how they fly involve a deuterium reactor, you know, in the middle, like a heavy water engine.
And so I wonder if, you know, one timeline is like super destructive where we figure out the nuclear bomb.
And then maybe, maybe Heisenberg was like onto something that involved civil side propulsion or something.
And then, and then that's where the, that's what the ETs or whatever these beings are, the non-human, you know, beings are, are flying around.
Right.
Well, you know, I like to conjecture that, um, since these are very advanced beings, if they were able to travel intergalactically or, you know, from another star system, um, that they've been, uh, they've been through this process of, uh, developing weapons of mass destruction, maybe fought wars themselves.
And, and, and, but we're finally able to determine how to live in peace with their neighbors and they want to see us accomplish the same thing and get rid of our nuclear weapons and try to learn how to live in peace.
Yeah. Is there a science fiction book that most accurately describes your worldview or do you think, yeah. What, do you have a sense of the intention of the non-human intelligence? I mean, it sounds like you think that they're trying to kind of wake us up a little bit, but.
Well, I mean, uh, to me, I'm, I'm just using logic. I'm, you know, I'm, I'm thinking if they're so far advanced than us, they must've been through the same evolutionary process or a similar process, uh, where they had difficulty dealing with other groups, you know, other life forms.
And, uh, and, uh, possibly had wars like we have had. And, and they can see what, where we're headed. If we keep down this path.
Like I said, uh, the Department of Defense uses this idea of nuclear deterrence or having a nuclear weapons program that's greater, better than anyone else, uh, as a means to protect our national security. That's the basis.
And so they want to keep the nuclear program going with nuclear weapons, you know, and put the fear in everybody else that might try to attack us. And that's, but that's not sustainable. That's not a sustainable program. If other countries feel the same way, right. Because they're going to want nuclear weapons too. And they have.
Yeah. It's a scary time. Right. It's hard to say where this all leads or goes, but like probabilistically, if you don't have non-human intelligence in the mix, then you'd assume some sort of nuclear calamity, you know, near term.
Like, it's hard to say that, like, if you have, what'd you say, 20,000 nukes now and, you know, uh, and, and, and increasingly kind of balkanized complex web of alliances, you know, and with tensions rising, right. Uh, it doesn't feel good.
No, it's not good. Yeah. And so that's why we have to make the effort to try to abolish them, uh, worldwide. The salt, I think it was, uh, no, it's called a new start treaty when president Obama was in office, actually signed a treaty with Russia.
And to reduce the number of operational weapons, nuclear weapons, I think it was 1500 each. So each country would have 1500, um, and then work towards reducing them till we got to zero, both the U S and Russia.
Um, and of course there was a inspection regime where they would, they would send inspectors here. We would send inspectors there to see, um, what was going on in each country with the reduction of nuclear weapons.
So there was an active program to go to zero between two of the major players in nuclear weapons. Um, so we, we can't just assume this can't be done.
As Oppenheimer said in one of his last speeches that he gave, um, to his scientists, uh, we can't afford to think that we can't abolish all nuclear weapons.
Well, yeah, you had the salt talks as well in the seventies and you had, uh, back channels that JFK had established with Khrushchev where he was trying for detente and trying for, you know, denuclearization.
And you had guys like Alan Dulles, who he had fired director of the CIA, who basically wanted to take him out, whether he did or not, you know, I think he might've, but, um, you know, around, around that issue.
And then, yeah, like you said, Obama had that initiative, but then you look at the same forces kind of behind Obama and you had this Ukraine peace deal in April of, you know, uh, 2022 right after it started.
And, uh, you know, we have not done Ukraine any favors by telling them not to sign that deal.
You know, they've lost hundreds of thousands of people and maybe it's some strategy to like tire out, you know, Russia or something, but it doesn't seem like Putin's very happy with us.
You have Medvedev, you know, former president on Twitter saying, you know, uh, this is good, you know, this is going to get really bad, you know, like really suggestive videos that he's posting and stuff.
And so, yeah, it's a weird time.
So, this is a kind of a crazy segue, but, you know, Medvedev was interviewed actually, and it was on April Fool's Day and, uh, an interviewer asked him about, um, UFOs and thought that, you know, he would not take it seriously.
And then he goes, oh yeah, no, we have an extensive file about this stuff.
You know, absolutely everything.
Well, like, for example, you flew to the planet, the same green human being.
Mariana, значит, рассказываю вам первый и последний раз.
Вместе с передачей «Чемодан с ядерными кодами» президенту страны приносят специальную папку.
На ней написано «Совершенно секретно».
И она целиком и полностью посвящена пришельцам, которые посетили нашу планету.
Одновременно предоставляется доклад от абсолютно закрытой спецслужбы, которая занимается контролем пришельцев на территории нашей страны.
Значит, две эти папки передаются вместе с ядерным чемоданом.
После прекращения полномочий, соответственно, эти папки передаются новому президенту.
Более подробную информацию на эту тему вы можете получить, посмотрев известный хроникально-документальный фильм «Люди в черном».
Вышло несколько версий.
Сколько их среди нас рассказывать не буду, потому что это может вызвать понятие.
And he talks about a nuclear connection.
No doubt.
And it's so fascinating.
You're like, and maybe it's plausible deniability for him because it's on April Fool's or whatever.
But it's wild that he's, you have this former, you know, Russian president talking about this.
Crazy.
Right.
And there have been other Russian officials that come out and say, yeah, we've got people studying the UFO questions.
So, no doubt that these incidents have happened all over the world.
All over the world.
You have a Russian general, Vasily Alexeyev, coming out in a German magazine in 2000 saying this stuff.
And then the one, one of my favorite ones is there's Marconi, you know, the radio engineer, famous radio engineer.
So, he is rumored to be part of, you know, this majestic 12 equivalent, quote unquote, in Italy called the RS-33.
I actually, I don't know if you remember this.
I met you briefly at the San Marino event, which is this global UFO conference held there in Italy.
And so, you have Roberto Pinotti and other guys, you know, Paolo Guzzardi, you know, who do research on this out there.
And Marconi's grandson, in an interview that's, everybody can see the video of this.
He's speaking to Ogo Magazine, which is, I guess, their People Magazine equivalent.
So, it's sort of a gossip magazine.
But he says, yeah, my grandfather had a lot to do with the UFO and ET issue.
He's a part of this select committee with, why am I blanking on the?
Mussolini.
Yeah, there you go.
He's part of a select committee with Mussolini to study this stuff.
And so, it's just fascinating.
This was the Magenta crash, Magenta, Italy.
In 1933.
1933.
You mentioned Roberto Pinotti.
He just finished a book about the Magenta crash and shows documentation that, yeah, it really did happen.
Marconi, who invented radio, was assigned by Mussolini to head up the group that would investigate this and study the craft, et cetera.
And that craft may, you know, it's reasonable to see where that craft was taken to Germany, to Nazi Germany, where studies were done with that craft.
In fact, Wernher von Braun, who we know was later taken under, you know, taken back to the U.S. after World War II under Operation Paperclip, right?
And he worked on the Apollo program.
He knew a lot of the astronauts.
He used to have astronauts over to his house on weekends for barbecues.
And, in fact, Gordon, let's see.
Gordon Cooper?
Gordon Cooper wrote a book.
And in that book, he talks about von Braun telling him that they actually worked on UFO craft in Germany, in Nazi Germany.
Wow.
And actually had a flying model.
That is fascinating.
I didn't know that Gordon Cooper wrote that.
That's really amazing.
Absolutely.
And—
Wow.
I got to check that out.
That's wild.
Yeah.
You get a hold of his book.
I can—I forgot the name of the book, but he did write it in there.
Uh, so chances are, yeah, the, uh, back engineering of UFOs goes way back.
That is fascinating.
Gordon Cooper is no scrub, you know.
No.
He spent more time in, in orbit than anybody before him as an astronaut as part of the Mercury missions.
Right.
These were before the Apollo missions.
That's amazing.
I didn't know that.
I had—I got to research.
That's—that's fascinating.
Look into it.
I will.
Yeah, because Wernher von Braun pops up in these stories, you know, he—Edgar Mitchell says that he, you know, comes to him and says, you know, he has knowledge of this stuff.
And apparently he was involved in Edgar Mitchell actually doing these sort of remote viewing parapsychology experiments, you know, in space and stuff.
So there's tangential there, all these anecdotes.
But that's maybe the most interesting anecdote of them all, that he said he was directly involved in reverse engineering craft.
Right.
Fascinating.
In fact, other of the, uh, paperclip scientists from Nazi Germany confirmed this, um, again, during these weekend meetings with some of the astronauts.
Well, you know, um, Wernher von Braun's mentor is a guy named Hermann Oberth.
And Hermann Oberth is on video speculating about UFOs.
He says, you know, the existence of UFOs should make anybody question reality.
And then he's, he talks about, you know, um, uh, time manipulation involved in UFO travel.
And he was openly very interested in this stuff.
So, and then he actually, as part of paperclip, comes to the U.S. to work as part of Convair Bell as well.
So, yeah, it's fascinating.
How do you evaluate?
Because you obviously are very high conviction on your own experience.
You have all these, you're, you're kind of, you know, brothers in arms with the nuclear experiences where I'm sure you have to slap a pretty high probability on those being real, given your own experience.
You have a bunch of new whistleblowers now coming out in other contexts saying they've worked on programs or seen things.
How do you evaluate those?
Well, like I said, I, uh, from personal contact with a friend of mine, I'm, I'm convinced that we have back engineered, uh, recovered craft and, um, even flown, uh, some models of that.
Uh, so I have no doubt about that.
Um, um, the, uh, uh, uh, genetics studies or the, uh, studies that have been done on tissue of these beings that have been recovered.
Uh, I think that has been done.
Uh, that's, there's, there's, there's been reports of that, good reports and by individuals.
And so, yeah, and all that's being hidden from the public.
Do you think, do you have any hope of any of this stuff coming out at any point or do you think it's just so locked down and tightly controlled that we never get to see what a craft looks like?
We don't understand its flight principles at most certain things leak in sort of these limited, you know, managed ways.
You know, what, what, what do you think?
Well, let's just say I'm hopeful.
I'm hopeful.
But we still have this committed organization that I call the UFO cabal, uh, secrecy cabal, uh, which is determined to maintain the secrecy for a multitude of reasons.
You know, greed and power and, uh, you know, these secrets are very valuable, um, and can be used as, you know, bartering chips.
Um, but it's a worldwide organization, well organized, well funded, and, uh, it's going to be tough to break through.
Do you have any final things to say to the wall street journal, to Joel Sheckman, to Sean Kirkpatrick?
I mean, yeah, I'd like to know what evidence arrow has, uh, so that they were able to tell Joel Sheckman that this was some sort of EMP test.
And, uh, and if they have no evidence, in other words, uh, then they're obviously, um, intended to discredit me in some way for whatever reason.
And, uh, it shows the modus operandi of the secrecy cabal, and, in that they want to discredit witnesses like myself.
And by the way, I'm not the only one, only witness to these incidents involving UFOs and nuclear weapons.
There are many, many out there, including Dave Schindel, I mentioned, uh, uh, Walter Fiegel, uh, et cetera.
I, I could name others, but some don't want to be named.
Yeah, no, I mean, it seems very, very common.
I was, I was diligencing, cause I, I invest in companies.
That was my day job.
I was sort of not doing that too much anymore, but a month or two ago, I was helping out a friend and he wanted, uh, help on an investment.
And it was actually this like, uh, way to create an artificial ozone layer to, you know, I thought it was a little harebrained, honestly.
I didn't think it was the best, best deal to do, but it was this Israeli entrepreneur and he came from the Israeli nuclear program.
And so I was like, at the end of, you know, speaking to him, of course, about the company, I was like, look, do you think that there's any, you know, UFO connection when it, when it comes to this stuff?
You know, high meshed, you're, you know, the head of your space force equivalent has said all these kind of really interesting things about UFOs, but also like, uh, you know, this kind of secret space program and, um, you know, it's galactic federation or whatever.
And he got very kind of uncomfortable and he was like, we should talk in person or so, you know, we should, we should talk, you know, he's like, and he was just kept deflecting.
And I don't know.
I think you get a lot of that when it comes to the new, the nuclear thing clearly is if you were to pick a starting point for empirical grounded inquiry into all this stuff, there's just so much bullshit out there.
But the nuclear thing seems like this really clear.
Well, uh, you know, after I read the article, the, uh, the hit piece, disinformation, uh, I wrote, um, a rebuttal and it was, uh, I listed 14 reasons why, uh, it couldn't have been EMP testing that shut down my missiles.
And it was, uh, by 1100 or 1200 words.
I sent that to the wall street journal.
They wrote back and said, we can't accept this because it's too long.
We have, uh, a limit of between 250 and 270 words for any kind of, uh, op ed or opinion piece or, um, they didn't use the word rebuttal, but anyway, they rejected it.
And they said, if you can condense it to 270 words, uh, then, uh, we'll consider it.
What is that?
Like a half a page or something?
That's not a lot of words.
Yeah, that's about a half a page.
That's wild.
That, that doesn't make sense to me.
Also, it's like you have this, what his thing was like 11 pages or something, the original piece.
And then you're, you're, and then you're only allowing, you know, um, an air force veteran.
You're, you're in your eighties now.
Is that right?
Or that's right.
That's amazing.
And, and they even mentioned in the article, by the way, that I'm an octogenarian.
I don't know what that has to do with anything, but.
Well, what a, what a sucker punch though, to somebody who served, served their country to
say that, you know, this is bullshit cover story about an EMP, not include any of the
details around people topside actually seeing UFOs, all of the other cases, the Oscar, you
know, the, um, uh, you know, the echo flight case eight days before and all of the cases
since at Malmstrom, just ignore all of that and then allow you to publish something that
is literally 5% the length of their original piece.
That's absurd.
I agree, but I made the effort and sent them a 270 word rebuttal.
Uh, and just yesterday, no, just this morning, I'm sorry.
Anyway, uh, they said they were going to consider it, but they probably have to edit it.
It's crazy.
I, I wrote back and said, why should you edit my rebuttal on your article, which was full
of errors?
No, they, they clearly have some vested interest in, in destroying this topic.
I don't know what it is, but I, did you hear about, I had a story too.
That last November or something in the fall, I spoke to them about getting an op-ed published
between Carl Nell and, uh, a cabinet, a former cabinet member.
So somebody who's like a presidential cabinet member and not a low ranking cabinet member,
like one of the more important positions in the cabinet.
And that guy is saying he's expressing frustration about lack of civilian oversight around UFO programs
and lack of his own access to these programs.
And, uh, they, they rejected it out of hand with no, you know, reasons as to why, why they
would reject it.
And then they go on to write this hit job, you know, discrediting you and stuff.
But they didn't mention that a cabinet member had submitted an op-ed to them last fall.
It's just, I think that's all you need to know to say that they're acting in bad faith.
I mean, you could maybe make some argument around bad bureaucracy.
The left hand, the op-ed sections, not talking to the other.
It's just, it's, it's nuts though.
Yeah, but I think this is an opportunity for Congress to get involved because they created
Arrow, right?
Arrow's not performing because one of their jobs was to investigate reports like, like mine
and follow through, get some answers.
And in my case, I gave them a two and a half hour talk.
I, I gave them documents to support what I was saying.
Um, they complimented me, uh, in writing and verbally on the job that I did.
And then I, at the end of it, I asked, are you going to check with the air force and see
if I'm, you know, what I've said is, is, uh, you know, they can verify it.
And they said, no, why wouldn't they do that?
Exactly.
I said, you know, no, because, uh, he said, because we haven't had cooperation from the
air force on other witnesses.
Well, yeah.
I mean, look, I think again, all you need to know is, you know, the crazy story of them
not, you know, not involving the cabinet member submission, but also the fact that Colonel
Robert Hippler is saying that this was due to a, you know, an EMP fallout from a nuclear
detonation, which is obviously bullshit.
And then, and then they come up with some new, you know, EMP simulation thing.
Right.
But they name an exact model that hadn't been, you know, ready until the early seventies.
So it's just, it's, it's, it's even if you're trying to discredit something, it's, it's a,
it's a lazy job.
It's just not, it's not very good.
Right.
Um, so yeah, I don't know.
It feels like to me, Kirkpatrick, who has always been kind of, it feels like a fly trap or something.
Like he's just trying to get the info and then, and then squash these stories is spoon feeding
this information to Joel Sheckman, who probably knows nothing about UFOs, but he's a national security
reporter and he's just taking it face value.
You know, you have this, this guy who seems like to be, you know, a normal credentialed
physicist telling him that all this stuff is a hoax, which if you don't have the data
set that, that you have, or I have around UFOs and nukes, you're just going to believe.
And then you're just going to publish the thing, not going to fact check.
Well, again, like I said, at some point, Congress has to do the job of getting to the bottom
of this issue, this UAP.
What is it?
What have we been doing about it?
What studies have we done?
What have we learned?
Um, and they, they can start with bringing the air force in and asking them questions about
incidents like mine and others.
That would be great.
Well, Bob Salas, really appreciate your time.
Thank you for having us and, uh, yeah, this is a fantastic discussion and, uh, I hope that
it, it opens people's minds and also, uh, allows them to look a little deeper when it
comes to kind of just, uh, taking at face value, some of these mainstream media headlines
and coverage of this very important topic.
Thank you, Jesse.
I really appreciate your taking interest in, in my case and, and, uh, well, the whole subject.
Absolutely.
All right.
That's our show.
For more information about the ubiquitous link between UFOs and nuclear weapons, please
watch my comprehensive documentary with the great journalist, Robert Hastings.
And if you want to watch my comprehensive takedown of the Wall Street Journal, I will link that
video too.
Finally, speaking of hearing out patriotic whistleblowers and veterans, please support my friend and past
American alchemist, Randy Anderson, who came on my show earlier this year to expose a possible
off-world technology division at Naval Surface Warfare Crane in Indiana.
He described seeing a levitating orb and a gauntlet emitting alien-looking hieroglyphics.
My friend UAP Gerb also did an amazing deep dive on Randy that you can check out on his channel.
Randy is setting up a very cool program called Alpha Rising.
It's a group specifically for veterans, first responders, and anyone who wants to get their mind
right and regain purpose in life.
I'm linking his GoFundMe for that project in the description of this video.
Until next time, I'm Jesse Michaels, and this is American Alchemy.
Thank you.
You