The president's car is now turning onto Elm Street, and it will be only a matter of minutes before he arrives at the trademark.
It appears as though something has happened in the motorcade route.
The JFK files were just released.
The National Archives released thousands of new pages of declassified records related to President John F. Kennedy's assassination.
80,000 pages of documents is a lot to sit through. Can you just tell us who killed Kennedy?
Who should be held culpable?
I don't want to point my finger at anyone in a case like this.
There's numerous people running up the hill alongside Elm Street.
Who were the two men on the grassy knoll? Who were they?
This guy's like a radio man. He looks like a Cuban. He's out of place, and he's sitting right next to the umbrella man.
There's Rip Robertson, photographs of Rip Robertson, who's the field operations commander for the S-Force.
Standing right there in Dilly Plaza, you've got Ed Lansdale.
Photographs of Lansdale sitting right there, and his wife identifying him.
The thing that I find to be so special about what we now know is the relationship that Oswald had with all these guys.
Back up, man!
I'm just a patsy!
All of this is a side product of deception and duplicity.
And to think that he was alone, taken completely by surprise by this.
Nonsense.
It's nonsense.
Man, it was all set up by the highest levels, and they got away with it for 62 years.
You know, the JFK files were just released.
The National Archives, a short time ago, released thousands of new pages of declassified records related to President John F. Kennedy's assassination.
You have 80,000 documents that require a lot of, you know, artificial intelligence overlay, optical character recognition to make any sense of.
Even then, I think very few people made any sense of them.
I think they left more confused.
There's a great quote by Brett Weinstein where it's like, looking through the JFK files is like looking for a needle in the haystack where the needle is missing.
And even President Trump, when he was asked point blank who killed JFK after the file drop, he said, we released the files, we did a historic thing or whatever.
80,000 pages of documents is a lot to sit through.
Can you just tell us who killed Kennedy?
Well, you know, I was given the task of releasing that because many presidents have gone through it and they haven't released.
And I said, release. We even released Social Security numbers. I didn't want anything deleted.
They said, sir, what about Social Security?
But he kind of sidestepped the, you know, point blank question is, who should be held culpable?
And I don't think anybody has a good answer to that after that file release.
I'm here with Jeremy Riss, alien scientist.
Um, you've been making epic videos for 20 years on not only UFOs and aliens, but often the science, the secret science behind all this stuff, along with sprinkle in some of your favorite conspiracies.
And, uh, it's, uh, I can't wait to speak to you, man. We've, we've had some phone conversations.
We don't agree on everything.
No, I don't have to.
We don't have to. That's the point of having conversations.
And, uh, I'm excited to have you, man. Thank you for being here.
For sure, man. Thanks for having me.
Thanks for having me.
It's great to finally be here.
Absolutely.
All right.
Well, there's so many jumping off points.
There were just these JFK disclosures, right?
Like what?
$80,000?
How many documents?
Like a whole bunch.
And then there's, you know, how many, how many things that didn't write down, you know,
you gotta think like you're planning to murder somebody.
You don't write stuff down and keep a log and a whole bunch of incriminating evidence on
yourself.
So there's a lot of cool stuff in the documents that have come out so far, but you know, really
you learn more, uh, from talking to long-term assassination researchers who've been way more.
I feel like people come out, came out of this way more confused than a lot of people did.
Yeah.
There's a lot of the, the media use it as an opportunity to once again, you know, hype
up this, uh, idea that, oh, there's nothing in the documents.
There's nothing new here.
This is all just conspiracy theories, you know, the typical operation mockingbird mantras
and whatnot.
But, uh, yeah, the, really the JFK research community has cracked this case and they've
cracked it for, you know, number, number of years.
I mean, Jim Mars was one of the first with Crossfire.
That was the book that Oliver Stone's JFK was based on.
And that really laid the foundation, uh, for a lot of the investigations that followed.
And there's been decades and decades and tons of people have dug into this from every possible
angle.
And now it's, it's just come out that, you know, Priscilla McMillan, who interviewed, uh, Lee
when he went to Russia and also befriended Marina Oswald and wrote her autobiography for her.
Um, she's CIA agent.
She's like witting CIA asset.
And that came out in one of the things that was revealed in the documents, which shows the
level that they went through to get ahead of the sources and the story and be like, all
right, we're going to, we're going to put our people in so that anyone getting information
about this from the sources has to go through us basically.
So I know you to be, uh, you know, as deep on the topic as maybe anybody alive and you have
a very coherent narrative.
So what do you think happened?
Who, who killed JFK?
They actually, the shot that was fired from the knoll that killed him was, uh, was Morales,
uh, David Morales.
And, and he was called the Mexican.
They're kind of different nicknames they had for him, but he was the crack shot, uh, out
of the team, the S force team that had been put together to kill Fidel Castro.
And it was a triangular, uh, a fire team, uh, plan, you know, to have three gunmen, uh,
crossfire at a moving target.
That was the plan.
That was the structure that they'd set up and that they trained down in Oaxaca, Mexico,
you know, uh, at the, uh, ranch of, uh, of Clint Murchison Jr.
And they trained them up down there to do that, to kill not, not only, uh, Fidel Castro,
but Raul Castro and Che Guevara and five other commandantes they had on the list.
So this was the 5412 committee, which was run by Nixon under Eisenhower.
He's setting up these sort of covert operations to take out Che Guevara and Castro.
Yeah.
But then they get used in the assassination of JFK.
How, how does that occur?
Well, what happened, what happened is that the, the, the, the people on the task force,
the people that were recruited to be on the, the S force to kill Castro, uh, in short Castro
and Che Guevara and the others that they were rabid anti-communist, uh, Cubanos that had fled
from Cuba in January of 1959 when Batista was overthrown and they all fled up to Florida and camped
out basically in Miami and Tampa, uh, primarily.
And the, a lot of them were mafia gunmen that worked for Santos Traficante, who was the don
of the mafia, uh, in Havana and ran the gambling casinos, the houses of prostitution, but most
importantly, the heroin smuggling that was coming in from Southeast Asia, because that was critical
because the, a portion of the profits from the heroin sales that were going on through
the mafia run by Santos Traficante and the Gambinos, that they were running the, the heroin
into the United States and a portion of the profits that were being skimmed off that sale
were being used to purchase military equipment and explosives to, to smuggle to the Kuintang
in China.
Whoa.
So this is pre-Iran Contra, but the same sort of architecture.
Oh yeah.
Same thing.
Same move.
And, and, and that they were in, that's where they got the idea to keep doing it, you know,
so that they, they had the whole thing set up for the, the portion of the heroin income
was being used to purchase the explosives and weapons.
There was a company set up, uh, with offices in Havana and in Miami that was the C Supply Corporation,
they called it.
And on the face of it is the SEA, oh, it's the C Supply Corporation, some kind of maritime
thing.
It was a Southeast Asian supply company run by Paul Halliwell, uh, the full time central
intelligence agency employee running the operation.
Uh, getting.
So he was getting the money to the Kuomintang?
He was getting, he was actually using the money from the heroin smuggling, a portion of
it to purchase the weapons and explosives here.
Uh huh.
And then they would fly them from here.
And that was that whole Terry and the pirates thing, what they call flying the hump.
Uh huh.
That they, they had this whole operation that a fellow named William D. Pauli, uh, was,
it worked for Prentice, uh, aviation and they were providing the airplanes and they were smuggling
them and flying them into China.
Uh, so there was a, and you know, uh, uh, Claire Booth Luce was involved in it.
Uh, Henry Luce.
Henry Luce's wife.
That's right.
And it was in Dulles was involved.
They were all involved in it.
That's what they call the China lobby.
Uh huh.
That was that whole group that right from way back had figured that they were planning
to really turn the, the development operations of their economic investments into Asia.
And, and Henry Luce then starts life in time magazine, which publishes the Zapruder
film with the missing frames of the JFK assassination.
That's right.
So that's a very interesting connection as well.
Oh yeah.
Which is, as you know, I mean, I know the guy that got the film.
Dick Billings.
Yeah.
Dick Billings and knew all about how they, they brought it to Rochester and doctored it.
He, he sat and told me about the whole thing.
That's wild.
So he talks about them doctoring the film and, and taking certain frames out and stuff.
And did the frames involve David Morales and the other men on the grass?
No, it just, it, it, it, it made it clear that he was being, he was shot from the front.
Okay.
You could tell from the thing so that they reversed the actual, uh, frames of the, of
the film.
And then the guy who let out the Zapruder film is a guy named Charles Douglas Jackson,
who was, uh, basically ran psychological warfare for the United States.
He was, uh, in the psychological strategy board with Gordon Gray and some of these other
guys.
Yeah.
And, um, he let out the Zapruder film in life magazine, which he was involved with, but with
missing frames.
And so.
So.
And that was a big thing.
The other guy that ran the psychological warfare program for JM wave station was George
Joanides.
And it recently came out that, you know, these files prove that he lied about his involvement
with the program.
Cause they asked him who ran the program.
He said, I don't know.
I'll have to look and check for you.
And he never got back.
They never got back to that question.
Never resolved that.
Well, he's the one that ran the program.
How do you not know who ran the program?
You ran the program.
And he lied about it to Congress and in front of it and the whole entire of America.
So that one, that one came out.
That was it.
That was a huge one.
Anslinger to that, uh, not Anslinger, um, Angleton, James, Jesus, Angleton.
And, uh, he was running this whole, um, spying program and the male intercept program.
And this guy, Ruben Efron was in charge of that.
And, um, Ruben Efron is in the, in the files and they asked him about, do you know, Ruben
Efron?
And he says, no, that's a lie.
You hired Ruben Efron.
And he ran the, the spy program for you.
That was reading Lee Harvey Oswald's mail.
And, and, and spying on this dude for years.
Cause he had a 201 file in the CIA since 1959.
So they were, they have a massive file on Lee Harvey Oswald following all his actions.
And to think that he was alone, not, and that we didn't know, we had no idea.
And we were taken completely by surprise by this nonsense.
It's nonsense, man.
It was all set up by the highest levels.
And they got away with it for 60, 62 years.
But it's, it's, I don't want it to be too confusing to everybody.
It's, it's easier kind of having in a chronological structure to understand how this thing happened.
Because it's a, the, the entire operation was set up way back in 1960.
You know, when, when, when, when Fidel Castro and Che Guevara and the guys overthrew Batista and drove him out in January of 1959, Richard Nixon, as the vice president under Eisenhower and the chair of the 5412 committee, the supervised covert operations.
He sent all kinds of communications to Fidel Castro saying, look, you are fine.
You've overthrown Batista.
Okay.
It's a deal.
What we want to do is make sure you don't have any diplomatic relations with China or Russia.
You can't have, and he said, you can't have any kind of relations with him at all.
And Fidel Castro said, screw you.
Who do you think you're talking to here?
You know?
Uh, and you know, they, they, you know, wave the old Monroe doctrine flag at him.
And so, which he didn't give a crap about, you know?
And, and so Nixon got really PO'd with him.
And, uh, so he then set up this covert operation, which was called originally operation 40.
Okay.
And then he recruited naturally enough.
He recruited a whole bunch of, uh, a whole bunch of Batista supporters, uh, who supported the fascist authoritarian regime down there, uh, and worked directly with Santos Traficante because Santos Traficante was the business partner of Batista and Paul Helliwell.
Uh huh.
In running the heroin operations.
And it was just a means of covert funding for the operations to oppose China, to oppose Mao Zedong.
Uh huh.
This is amazing.
Yeah.
And, and they didn't, they didn't want to tell Congress about it at all because they didn't think they could muster enough support from Congress to actually support covert operations against Mao Zedong.
So they did it totally covertly.
They, the CIA sent up this entire operation, uh, to be supporting, uh, Chiang Kai-shek, uh, in the so-called nationalist forces.
And the chief of security for, for, uh, Chiang Kai-shek was the head of the green gang, the major heroin operation in, in China.
No way.
Oh yeah.
Whoa.
Yeah.
That is wild.
Okay.
So in 5960 timeframe, you have the 5412 commission and committee rather you have of which Nixon is ahead and he's sort of, you know, running kind of national security.
He, uh, partners with, uh, mafia dons like traffic Conte.
Well, actually, actually he avoided that one by one step.
What he did is recruited Howard Hughes.
Yeah.
He called Howard Hughes because Howard Hughes was a consultant to the 5412 committee.
Uh huh.
He would, he had designed the Spruce Goose, which became the prototype for the C5A cargo plane that could fly, you know, major covert operations in and equipment and stuff.
Uh, and he also, he also designed the Goldmar Explorer, uh, that ship that could pick up Russian submarines off the bottom of the ocean and stuff that they fell through.
And a couple other extraordinarily sensitive programs that he was working on.
Like what?
Yeah.
I can't tell you.
I can't tell you that.
Uh, cause of the way I know.
You've said this before to me about Howard Hughes.
And then I always goes at the UFO stuff.
You go, no, no, no, it wasn't that it was.
What else could be the so sensitive?
Is it like time travel or something?
No, no, no, no.
Nothing esoteric like that.
You're a man of the people, Danny.
We need to know.
Yeah.
As evidenced by Tim Dillon's recent and masterful interview with CNN, legacy media can be a bit problematic.
It's more sensationalist and divided than ever.
They ask leading questions brainwashed by their social milieus.
And that's why people are flocking to podcasts.
But podcasts have their own limits.
They're often three hours long.
They're not super efficient.
They aren't always fact checked.
They're sort of a hybrid of entertainment and news.
So how do I stay informed amidst this backdrop?
I started using my new favorite service, Ground News, a tool designed for both skeptics and truth seekers like many in this community.
Ground News is an app and website created by a former NASA engineer to tackle a problem we all face.
How distorted the information is that we consume every day in the modern post-truth era.
Ground News gathers coverage from over 50,000 sources worldwide, organizes the stories by topic, and even breaks down the bias and ownership behind each perspective so you know what you're getting.
With features like the bias bar and factuality score, it's easy to see how different outlets frame and spin the same story.
When you eat certain foods, you want to see the ingredients list.
This is the same thing, but for content and news.
For example, when I was researching those mysterious drone sightings in New Jersey in December, Ground News gave me instant access to over 200 articles helping me uncover every angle, from the facts to the spin.
Spoiler alert, I don't think they were just FAA-approved research drones.
So if you're tired of echo chambers and one-sided narratives, Ground News is your ultimate tool for staying informed and making better decisions.
You can follow your favorite topics and compare coverage to find the most credible sources.
And for a limited time, you can get the same plan I use every day for nearly half the price.
Just go to ground.news slash Jesse Michaels, Michaels with no A, or scan this QR code to save 40% on their unlimited access vantage plan.
Or gift it to someone you know and have more informed discussions and hopefully chill out about those drones.
I only promote brands I vet and I think you'll find them just as valuable as I do.
Ground News, the truth is out there.
You just need the right tools to find it.
It's one of those kind of things that one of the very rare things that I tend to agree that it would be good to tell people about it.
Sure.
It would generate all kinds of damage and it wouldn't really benefit anybody.
Got it.
The bottom line is, but because of that, he trusted Hughes.
And so he contacts him using the red phone, the secure phone, which he had for the 5412 Committee Communications, called Howard Hughes, and Traficanti told us all this.
This all came directly from Traficanti about how the whole thing happened and actually told us the day on which Richard Nixon called on the phone, Howard Hughes, was the day after Nelson Rockefeller withdrew from the 1960 Republican presidential primary race against Nixon.
Because as soon as he withdrew, Nixon knew he was going to be the nominee for the Republican Party in 1960, and he was sure he was going to win.
Right?
So he then took upon himself the authority, basically, of the incoming president to contact Hughes and ask him to put together an assassination team.
What's the...
Why did Rockefeller step down right then?
I don't quite...
He just withdrew.
He withdrew from the primary race for the...
Was that a coincidence or...?
No, no.
But what it did is it freed up Nixon to realize he was going to be the nominee for the Republican Party.
And so he was therefore confident he was getting ready to be president.
Yeah.
And so he started exercising the kind of a power that a president might do.
And so he took onto himself this kind of authority to actually reach out and have Howard Hughes set up an assassination team.
He said, but you've got to keep it completely away from the White House.
So you can't...
You've just got to do it yourself.
Mm-hmm.
And so what Howard Hughes did is sent for one of his lawyers that he had, Bob Mayhew.
And had Mayhew...
He assigned Mayhew.
He said, here's the job.
The president kept...
They started referring to him as the president in their communication.
Traffic County said so.
Oh, my God.
They kept referring to him as the president.
To Nixon as the president.
Yeah, they kept referring to him as the president.
And now he was the VP.
Yeah.
Wow.
He wants this done.
He wants to keep it away from the White House.
And so Bob Mayhew went to see...
Because, you know, Howard Hughes was in Las Vegas.
Mm-hmm.
He was hanging out at the...
I can't remember whether it was the...
The Flamingo or the Sands.
Or the Sands, one of the two.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But anyway, he was up in the big penthouse there.
Uh-huh.
And it was one of the mob hotels.
Right?
And so he knew that they were there.
And so Bob Mayhew went to see Johnny Roselli, who was the bag man, you know, for the mafia,
the mafia skim, the skimming of the cash off those casinos to be used, right?
Mm-hmm.
And so his principal, the guy in charge of him, was Sam Giancana out of Chicago.
And so when Bob Mayhew went to Johnny Roselli and said, look, you guys have your own reason
for wanting to get rid of this Castro dude.
Mm-hmm.
You know, you shut down all your casinos, shut down your whorehouses, he said.
And very importantly, they've cut off the whole heroin supply.
Okay?
And so that you've got your own reasons for wanting to get rid of him.
So, you know, that Nixon is assuming that you'll do this for us.
And so Johnny Roselli said, well, you know, I don't have the authority to make a decision
like that.
We're going to have to talk to Sam Giancana.
Mm-hmm.
And so they went together.
You know, Johnny Roselli and Bob Mayhew went to Chicago and met with Sam Giancana and pitched
the proposal to him.
And Sam Giancana realized that, you know, doing a favor like this for the president was going
to get them a lot of potential goodwill.
Mm-hmm.
Right?
And so, and keep them, keep the feds off their back.
Mm-hmm.
So he was agreeing in principle to do it.
He said, but you know, but this isn't up to me.
Mm-hmm.
That's Santos Traficante's territory.
That's down in Havana.
He's the mob boss in Havana.
He's, even though he's up in Tampa now, because he left Cuba, he said, so we have to go talk
to him.
So they went down.
Mm-hmm.
They went down to see him.
Now, they were down there about September or so.
This all started around June, around June 7th.
Mm-hmm.
That was when Rockefeller withdrew.
June 7th of 1960.
So between that and it's now early September, Johnny Roselli, Bob Mayhew, and Sam Giancana
went down to Florida and at the Fontainebleau Hotel, met with Traficante.
And they had two meetings in which finally Traficante tells us that, he said, you know, I agreed
in principle to do this.
He said, but I wanted to make sure that, you know, he said, it wasn't some kind of brain
fart, he said, you know, on the part of Bob Mayhew or even Howard Hughes.
I wanted to make certain that this was coming from the president.
That's how he termed it, he said.
And so that they had a third meeting, and a guy, another guy comes to the meeting at
the Fontainebleau Hotel using the nom de guerre Mr. Ed.
And it was Sheffield Edwards, who was the chief of security of the Central Intelligence
Agency under Dulles, okay?
And under the Eisenhower Bush administration.
But so he comes to the meeting and gives them the green light to go ahead and do this.
So that's, so what Sam, what Traficante did is he recruited guys from his people that were
from Havana, these gunmen that he had down there that were enforcers who had fled with
him to Florida in January of 59 and had gotten recruited by Richard Nixon and the CIA to run
covert operations against Cuba.
Because when Fidel Castro just finally thumbed his nose at Nixon and said, you know, screw
you, I'm going to have relations with anybody I want.
And so I'll have diplomatic relations with Russia and China, you know, therefore, quote,
violating the Monroe Doctrine, you know, of allowing a foreign power to start having influence
inside our hemisphere, you know, or our zone of influence.
And so what happened is Richard Nixon had mounted this covert operation.
And he recruited all of these people that were Traficante gunmen and mobsters, basically,
but virulent anti-communists, you know, and were all in around Miami.
They had the 2506 Brigade.
They had Alpha 66.
There were a bunch of these kind of, well, it's unfair to call them covens, but I mean,
they were these gangs, like, that were there that were engaged in covert operation.
And so they thought that they were kind of invested with kind of a certain kind of authority
on the part of the federal government because they're paid by the CIA to do this.
And they set up these bases.
They set one up on No Name Key.
They set one up on Swan Island.
They put one in the Everglades.
Then they had two of them at Lake Pontchartrain over in Louisiana, one on the southern coast
of Lake Pontchartrain, one on the northern coast.
And they set up these paramilitary bases in these rabidly anti-communist, pro-Battista,
you know, Traficante gunmen, a lot of them, you know, were covert operators working under
the auspice of the CIA to run these covert operations.
So Traficante says, okay, Nixon wants me to put together this assassination team.
I'm going to take my people who are working with the CIA, but in a completely different capacity
just to run covert operations.
What I'm going to do is recruit 15 of them.
I'll hand pick them and we'll put them into this special S-force, they call it.
And that's what they did.
And they would send private planes to go pick them up, you know, at these five different paramilitary bases.
They would pick up a couple of the guys at each one and they would fly them to Fort Huachuca in Arizona
and big electronic surveillance operations that they've got going there in Fort Huachuca.
And so they'd bring them there and then they would sign in and then they would just disappear off the records.
And then they were flown down to Oaxaca, Mexico, to the ranch of Clint Murchison, Jr.,
very wealthy, uh, skion of the, this, uh, oil fortune, uh, down there who his father,
his father owned the Dallas Texans football team, you know?
Cowboys.
Yeah.
Well, later Cowboys.
It was Texans at the time.
Yeah.
And that's, that's who they were in the, you know, horse racing and rich people and something.
And so they had this big ranch down in Oaxaca.
So they set up a triangular fire team base down there to, to practice a shooting, a moving target
from three different locations to get a triangular crossfire onto the site, uh, onto the target.
Uh, and they were training them.
And Carl Jenkins was, uh, was brought in, uh, from the CIA to train them on this under ZR rifle.
It was the code name for the program, but they, this was a whole separate thing.
And it was not even known to many people at all that this was going on because they were
trying to keep it away from the white house.
So that operation is going on.
And the way they funded it was from the skim of money off the casinos.
Uh, and they would skim the money off the casinos.
They would, uh, put the cash into these brand new big expensive suitcases and put them in the trunk
of brand new Cadillac automobiles and they would drive them.
And I know the guy that sold them the Cadillacs cause he had the big dealership in Vegas.
Anyway, and anyway, then I interviewed him at length about it, you know, and so that they
drive, they drive the cars, uh, through, uh, New Orleans, uh, and Marcelo was there and they
did the audit on all the money to keep track of how much money they were moving.
And then they would repack it and they would drive them into Florida and deposit it in the
Miami national bank of Meyer Lansky.
Uh, and then they would wire a portion of the money down into the Banco Internationale,
uh, down in Mexico city.
Uh, and they put it into this account by, uh, this lawyer named Mavogario had the account
down in the bank.
Uh, and then they would pay the costs for the whole triangular fire team training base down
in, in Oaxaca.
And that's the.
So how do you go from this systematic drug running covert operation that ultimately is
in support of the resistance in China, the, the, the Kuomintang and the, uh, you know,
uh, Chiang Kai-shek, how do you go from that?
Um, and then this plan initially to take out, you know, Che Guevara and Castro or, you know,
uh, impinging upon the Monroe doctrine to killing JFK.
Well, what happened is that the, that whole operation was going when suddenly Richard Nixon
didn't get elected.
John F. Kennedy of the state of Massachusetts has received for president of the United States
303 votes.
Richard M. Nixon of the state of California has received 219 votes.
This is the first time in 100 years that a candidate for the presidency announced the
result of an election in which he was defeated and announced the victory of his opponent.
All of you work in a cause that is bigger than any man's ambition, greater than any party.
It is the cause of freedom, of justice, and peace for all mankind.
And it is in that spirit that I now declare that John F. Kennedy has been elected president
of the United States and Lyndon Johnson vice president of the United States.
Uh, and Kennedy comes in, uh, and they, they briefed Kennedy now about the Bay of Pigs plan
that they had going, but they didn't tell him about the assassination team at all.
Hey guys, I want to tell you about my new favorite piece of apparel.
These are called the perfect jeans.
They're literally the perfect jeans.
I used to wear jeans all the time and they're kind of rough and not super stretchy or breathable.
These are extremely comfortable.
They work in casual environments.
They work in work settings.
They come in six different sizes from 26 inches to 50 inches.
And they're all around just amazing.
For a limited time, our listeners get 15% off your first order.
Plus, free shipping at theperfectgene.nyc.
Again, that's theperfectgene.nyc.
Or just Google the perfect gene.
Use code JESSE15 for that 15% off.
Again, that's code JESSE15.
That's 15% off for new customers at theperfectgene.nyc.
After purchase, they'll ask where you heard about them.
Please support our show and tell them that we sent you.
Fuck your khakis.
Get the perfect gene.
And so they lure him into allowing the invasion to go on, the attempted invasion at the Bay of Pigs.
But he tells them right from the very beginning that he won't provide air cover.
He won't provide any air cover.
And he won't provide any kind of U.S. military intervention.
You know, they wanted to be able to land on the beach and basically raise the flag of free Cuba
and then ask for U.S. intervention and do it the old-fashioned way.
You know, just send in a paramilitary operation.
And Kennedy wouldn't do it.
And they said, oh, he said, look, if you're telling me that the people of Cuba want to rise up against Castro
because they're so unhappy with him, if they land on the beach and they raise the flag of a free Cuba,
if the people all rally and toss out Castro, good.
If you're telling me the truth that they're going to do it, you go ahead and do it.
Yeah.
And what happened is they had two or three, you know, B-25s of these old bomber planes that were down in Nicaragua, actually,
that the Somoza, Anastasio Somoza, was supporting them in doing this.
You know, it was this kind of right-wing fascist dude.
And so the bottom line is that they were going to provide their own air cover for this.
And what happened is they were in a different time zone.
And so they got there an hour late after the landing.
And the guys had been knifed, whacked already.
They sank their ammunition boat and everything, you know.
And so they were trapped on the beach and they all got arrested.
And the whole thing fell through.
Wednesday, April 19th, resistance ends.
All those who are not killed are taken prisoner.
And then Kennedy took responsibility for it.
And this is where the thing starts.
Kennedy took responsibility for it.
And the Cubano guys that got all arrested were upset at him for refusing not only to provide air support, but they had, you know, that, in fact,
General Curtis LeMay and other folks from the Joint Chiefs had actually moved U.S. military forces into place.
They put naval ships with marines in them, you know, staged them contrary to the orders of the president, you know, ordered in marines.
There was so much at the time that Curtis LeMay felt the liberty to do by himself.
Like, he put, apparently, I didn't even know this, during the Cuban Missile Crisis later, obviously.
He put us into DEFCON 2 without the president's permission.
He did.
It's crazy.
And launched the U-2, ordered the U-2 to fly over Russia to do the final retargeting, which was, and did it at a low altitude that he knew the Russians would pick it up to send them the signals.
He was trying to goad them into trying to initiate a nuclear war, you know?
So, the bottom line is that all that was going on at this time, and what happened is Kennedy took responsibility for it, of the snafu, and what he did is he apologized to Khrushchev for having allowed that thing to go down,
and gave him, gave Khrushchev, Kennedy did, his solemn promise that he would cease and desist from efforts to undermine the government in Cuba.
And he went down to Cuba, went down to Miami at the Orange Bowl, actually, and convened, you know, a whole meeting of all these kind of right-wing Cubano refugees that had fled from there in the whole stadium, and he apologized to them all in person.
He said that he gave them his personal guarantee that the free flag of Cuba would be flying over the island by the end of his second term, and he said that to them.
I can assure you that this flag will be returned to this brigade in a free Havana.
They said, okay, we got you.
And then he turned around and had lied to Khrushchev and actually converted Operation 40 into Operation Mongoose.
That's all it did.
It set up the big operation on the University of Miami campus called JM Wave, this great big gigantic airplane set of hangars, and they had all the operations going on there.
It was a full-scale war operation going on against Cuba.
And so he continued doing that.
And so Khrushchev said, screw you, then, and started moving missiles in.
And so all this was happening all right in that first period from 1961.
He's elected in November of 1960, comes into office in January of 1961.
You know, he does all this apologizing and stuff because it was in April of 61 that the Bay of Pigs thing came down.
And so he apologizes, but he's totally pissed off, you know, at the CIA for bungling this whole operation.
And the days of Alan Dulles were numbered.
And so he waited all the way till the fall, September, October, you know, of 61, and then pushed Dulles out.
But Dulles didn't leave.
He didn't leave Washington.
He had his whole setup over in Georgetown in his big brownstone over there.
And all of the guys from the CIA were going over to meet with him like every day.
He had like a social club.
Wasn't it called the Georgetown Set?
Do you know what I'm talking about?
Yeah.
Georgetown's a very, we won't get too far, but it's a very interesting place, you know, with every administration.
You've got these very wealthy, social people.
Beautiful brownstone.
Yeah.
Kind of old houses.
I've been in a bunch of them.
Yeah.
You know?
Yeah, yeah.
And again, recently, the new administration has got people over there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I remember being in Michael Pillsbury's house, which I think was JFK's old house.
Yeah.
In Georgetown.
And just being like, this is amazing.
Yeah.
So cool.
I mean, he's been a kind of lead China expert in every administration since Nixon.
Yeah.
It's a very elite group over there.
So the bottom line is that, so the whole operation shifts over to Operation Mongoose, being run
out of JM Wave, and crew chefs are sending the missiles in to Cuba, and then they discover
the missiles in there.
The whole Cuban missile crisis comes down, right?
Within the past week, unmistakable evidence has established the fact that a series of offensive
missile sites is now in preparation on that imprisoned island.
Goes all the way through into late October, right?
And then this bizarre thing happens with the UFO, right?
That, and we'll just set that aside for a moment because it's a very kind of comparable
new piece of information.
But the bottom line is that by the time they get to October 26th, the night of October 26th,
they come to within like two minutes.
This whole thing with General Curtis LeMay trying to instigate an actual nuclear exchange with
Russia saying that, look, the most, the Russia, if they launch nuclear missiles against us,
the most, they'll kill maybe 40 million people, you know, but we'll wipe them all out and we'll
get rid of that entire scourge of communism coming out of Russia and then we'll win because
we've only lost 40 million people and we'll have eliminated Russia as a threat.
And that was his whole thinking, right?
And the bottom line is Kennedy is so completely horrified at how close they came to the nuclear
war.
This is where it starts now.
And what happened is he reached back out to Khrushchev, said, okay, you're right.
I lied to you.
You know, we, we, you're right.
We kept on doing the Operation Mongoose, you know, but you shouldn't have put the missiles
in there.
Uh, we're going to make a deal, you know, that I'll take the missiles out of Turkey.
You take the missiles out of here.
Uh, and he ordered the, all of those, those, uh, bases, those paramilitary bases to cease
and desist from any further operations.
But, but he didn't know about the assassination team that had been deployed that, uh, but he
ordered this shutting down of all the bases.
And what happens is in December, December of, uh, of 1962, uh, Frank Sturgis, who is the CIA
liaison to the Cubano, uh, guys, uh, out on, uh, uh, no name key.
Uh, uh, he, he decides he's going to, even after getting the orders from the president
that they're all to stand down and to discontinue their operations, he, in complete defiance with
the, with the Cubans launches an assault into Cuba and sinks a Russian ship.
Whoa.
Which like nobody knows about, you know, that anymore, but they, they sank a Russian ship.
When was this?
It's December of 1962.
Whoa.
Uh, sinks a Russian ship.
Kennedy freaks out over the fact that, you know, he'd already lied to, to Khrushchev once
and he couldn't stand for doing it again.
You know, the whole thing would fall apart.
And so what he does is he, he sends in, he and Bobby, who's the attorney general, uh, they
send in six helicopter gunships, uh, with U.S.
marshals, uh, sends it because he couldn't trust FBI because of Hoover.
And so, and so he, he sends in U.S.
marshals and they burn out the base, uh, at, uh, at no name key and arrest all those guys,
including Sturgis and charge them with a violation of the neutrality act, mounting military operations
against a country with whom we have diplomatic relations.
Right.
Uh, and hold them for almost a week and then let them go.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
But it's kind of shot across the bow.
The president's serious.
They geez in on it.
You know, you're not going to do this anymore.
Mm-hmm.
Then a second group, the ones in the Everglades, the, under the liaison of, uh, E. Howard Hunt,
start planning another attack into Cuba in complete defiance of the president, even after the,
what they had done over on, uh, on no name key.
And so Bobby and John send in the same six helicopter gunships and burn them out too and
arrest them and charge them with the neutrality act violations.
Uh, and the heads of the, the 50, the, the, uh, the 2506 brigade and Alpha 66 resolve, they're
going to kill these guys.
They're going to kill John and Bobby who are complete traitors that they've lied to them.
They came, he came down and promised they were going to, going to support them and overthrowing
the government.
Now they're chickening out and they're, they're, they want to kill him.
Uh, but they know that they can't get away with it, you know, but they've got the S force
that's capable of doing something like that.
So they're all kind of, you know, just pawing away like a charging bull wanting to get at
the president and kill him and the attorney general, both, you know, uh, and, uh, but
they can't get away with this.
And so what happens is Kennedy turns out starts secretly.
This is the key to this thing.
He starts secretly exchanging letters with, with Khrushchev, uh, through Norman Cousins.
Uh, this guy is running letter, 18 different letters back and forth off a completely off
channel.
No, no state department oversight, no CIA coverage, anything completely secret communications.
Uh, and in those letters, they're deciding that they're both so totally traumatized by what
happened, uh, and how their military forces can get out of control, uh, and the, the nuclear
weapons that threat the total annihilation of our whole human species, so they can't let
this happen.
So what they do is they start discussing how they're going to order.
Each of them is going to exercise their respective executive authority to start ordering the disassembly
of the nuclear warheads in their respective arsenals and destroy them, not just take them and put
them on a shelf somewhere where they can just screw them back on another week or so, you
know, but destroy them.
And they, they reached this agreement in principle.
So he was, JFK was really going for it.
He was trying to denuclearize.
Totally going for it.
And there's a, there's this book, um, I think called Mary's Mosaic.
Oh yeah.
About, you know, Mary Pynchon.
Yeah.
Mary Pynchon, who was the wife of, uh, Kord Meier.
Kord Meier.
Kord Meier, you know, World War II veteran who I believe came back with, uh, I think an eye
patch and, uh, you know, he turned him into a pacifist and then he sort of got in with
the Dulles, Alan Dulles kind of Intel cabal and became this kind of warmonger who I think
believe later was in charge of Operation Mockingbird.
So like, yeah, incepting journalism world with, with Intel assets.
Yeah.
Um, but also, uh, was, became this kind of, kind of bloodthirsty guy.
And so his, uh, wife, uh, Mary, Mary Pynchon Meyer, she murdered, she was an artist and she
was kind of a little more kind of spiritual hippie dippy.
And she, so yeah, so she had an affair with JFK.
Even more than that.
I mean, it was, it was a prolonged.
Ongoing.
Relationship.
She, she became in a certain sense, his actual sort of mistress.
And they did LSD together.
Yes.
And I don't know.
Provided by, provided by Tim Leary.
That's wild.
Provided by Timothy Leary.
Timothy Leary actually provided it to him.
I know the guy that knows it.
Of course you did.
Did it.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
So, yeah, okay.
Um, are you still lugging around one of those bulky, worn out wallets?
You know, I am.
Like, your posture's not great due to that wallet.
Yeah.
Are you aware of that?
I'm, I'm currently now more self-aware of my posture.
It might be time for an upgrade.
Oh, what do you suggest?
My personal suggestion is Ridge Wallet.
Look at this sleek design.
Do you see it?
Oh, wow.
So sleek.
Yeah.
Pretty sleek.
Uh-huh.
This thing holds up to 12 cards, plus cash.
All in a slim, durable, and stylish package, too.
You took the words right out of my mouth.
Ridge Wallets feature RFID blocking technology, so digital pickpockets won't stand a chance.
Plus, with their AirTag attachment, you'll never lose your wallet again.
Where'd it go?
I lost my wallet.
I was just checking my AirTag.
Easy.
Brilliant.
Yeah.
I was recently in the Colorado Mountains, and if I had lost my Ridge Wallet, I would have
no problem tracking it down, even in the Rockies.
Right now, Ridge is having their once-a-year anniversary sale.
So get up to 40% off at ridge.com slash cosmic.
Just head to ridge.com slash cosmic to see their biggest sale of the year.
After you purchase, they will ask about where you heard about them.
Where did they hear about Ridge Wallet, Chris?
They heard it here first on American Alchemy.
Yeah.
Please support our show, and tell them our show sent you.
Upgrade your wallet.
Thank me later.
And then I think they do LSD together, JFK and Mary Meyer, and this is sort of rumor mill
stuff, so I'm curious to get your take.
After that, JFK, because she has this mission of like, I need to stop these guys.
Like her husband, Gordon Meyer, and all of his associates are going to like blow up the
world.
Yeah.
And she is like, we need to reign these guys in, and she does LSD with JFK, and then JFK
kind of, he was already more pacifist than them, but he becomes more hardcore, like we
really need to kind of denuclearize.
He saw the light, you know, and he went through this metanoia, as we refer to it, this metanoia
experience about how incredible this was, you know, and how extraordinarily outrageous,
you know, Curtis LeMay and the Joint Chiefs have been, you know, and they'd already proposed
to him this Operation Northwoods, you know, of, oh, okay, because they were so desperate
wanting to get Castro out of there, that they were so dedicated in their mission to preserve
U.S. complete domination and control of the whole Western Hemisphere, that they viewed
this as an absolute horrible affront to have these guys in Cuba.
So they were just desperate to get that island overthrown, and so they kept trying everything
to do it.
So the bottom line is, when Kennedy is exchanging these letters, and very important thing that
people don't know about, is that Khrushchev recommended that in order to verify that they
were both complying with the actual, not only the disassembly, but the destruction of the
nuclear warheads, is that they were going to have Pope John XXIII broker the whole deal
and oversee the whole process.
No way.
That's all true.
Are you serious?
That's absolutely right.
Khrushchev wrote about this in his letters back?
They were, yes, they did it in the letters.
And these letters...
Have you seen these letters?
No, but I know what the content of that.
How do you know?
From Jesuit headquarters, because of John Paul XXIII, or John XXIII was going to be
the broker.
But he dies.
I need to get in with the Jesuits, Danny.
I don't know.
Yeah, right.
Right.
You know, but he dies.
Yeah.
He dies in early June.
So they were working on trying to get this done.
So he dies in early June.
And what Kennedy decides is that in order to make up for the massive disfunding of the
whole nuclear weapons programs in both countries, in order to have a massive economic stimulus
to replace that, that he wants to...
And he proposes to Gorbachev, or to Khrushchev, that they have a joint Soviet-U.S. space program,
that they completely combine their forces, and they overcome the whole threat of the Cold
War, and that they join forces and going into outer space together.
And he, on June 5th of 1962, or 63, rather, now, of 1963, what he does is he contacts McCown,
the new CIA director, because he'd already forced into retirement, Dulles.
And he says he wants to get fully briefed in on the UFO stuff.
Now, this becomes important, because I didn't know, and when I found out all that stuff,
I didn't know about this other thing.
Yeah, the Harold Malmgren stuff.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah, so, yeah, he asked to get briefed about UFOs and wants to know more.
And this is really an important fact.
John McCown, before he became director of CIA, after Dulles departed, was also the lead
of the Atomic Energy Commission.
He ran the Atomic Energy Commission, so he definitely would have been privy to all of
the secrets when it came to UFOs, given the nuclear connection.
Yes, yeah.
And so, he's asking for that, and then I can give you the little Malmgren piece, which
is, so, Malmgren, Harold Malmgren was a presidential advisor for JFK.
He was the youngest of presidential advisors.
He was one of McNamara's whiz kids.
Yeah, yeah.
And McNamara's, you know, secretary of defense at the time.
Malmgren is 27 years old, and he's in the situation room around the Cuban Missile Crisis.
Mm-hmm.
And at that same time, the Cuban Missile Crisis, McNamara had put him in charge of cost assessments
for these new X-ray-based missile defense systems.
And so, they're doing these tests in the Marshall Islands, specifically at Johnston Atoll.
Mm-hmm.
And you have these test series called, you know, Starfish Prime Tests.
And one of the tests is the Bluegill series.
And this is this kind of X-ray projection in the nose cone of these ICBMs meant to take
out incoming nuclear warheads.
Yes.
Which we didn't have great nuclear defense at the time.
Yeah, right.
And so, this was this really exciting experimental thing.
And the RAND Corporation had a paper on it actually earlier.
And so, Harold is in charge of doing all the cost assessing for this.
And he catches wind that in this test, a UFO gets knocked out of the, comes out of the
plume of the nuclear blast.
Yes.
And he freaks out.
And he says, well, I need to know about this.
And they used to call them tag-alongs at the time.
Yeah.
Because they were so kind of, you know, immune to, or was so casual.
And, you know, Cold War kind of intensity was so, you know, I don't know.
So, it kind of just made them think it was just, yeah, like normal thing that you have
a UFO coming out of the plume.
And he said, I need to know.
I have like all, I blink at Q clearances.
And they said, no, you don't.
You know, this is Office of Naval Intelligence and the Atomic Energy Commission stuff or
whatever.
Yeah.
And so, they say, okay, you can know, but you have to, you have to come to, you know,
Sandia complex, Kirtland Air Force Base, Sandia, where Lawrence Preston Geis, who's the maternal
grandfather of Jeff Bezos, can show you these UFO, you know, they didn't say, we're going
to show you these UFO pieces.
We'll brief you on it.
Yeah, yeah.
And then he goes, they show him the UFO pieces.
He feels the debris.
He feels this anomalous debris.
It speaks to him telepathically, which is remarkable.
Then he insists on getting briefed or he, I don't know, maybe Bissell reaches out to
him, but Richard Bissell, who was number two, went on to become number two at the CIA, but
at the time, he was deputy director of plans at the CIA.
And he was known as the mayor of Area 51, goes in and briefs him on, quote unquote, other
world technologies and all of these kind of past crash retrievals, including Magenta of
1933.
And so Malmgren knows about this stuff.
And then JFK, I think a couple of weeks later, a few weeks later, ends up at Los Alamos, getting
briefs, getting briefs.
Yeah.
So it's like, is that a coincidence?
Probably not.
Well, what it is, is that then Kennedy realizes that if he can give this information to Khrushchev,
that'll seal the deal, that Khrushchev will know that he's completely, he's dropping this
kind of nationalistic, competitive thing with Russia, and that they can have a genuine
joint space program.
And of course, they need to know about what this extraterrestrial dimension is if they're
going to be venturing out into space together.
And so he, so, but what happens is when he demands the briefing from McComb, Bissell and
the other guys tell Dulles about it.
Yeah.
Because Bissell and Angleton and the other guys kept going over to see Dulles all the
time.
Yeah.
In the Brownstone, over in Georgetown, because he never left town.
He just stayed right there.
Because the fact of the matter is, is that the reason he'd been appointed to be the first
civilian director of the CIA is the fact that he was legal counsel for Brown Brothers
Harriman.
This is Dulles.
That's Dulles.
Allen Dulles.
And that's where the China lobby is.
That's the group of people that had decided long ago that what they would do is secretly
fund the rise of Hitler in Germany after World War I.
Through the Union Bank.
To the Union Bank and all that stuff that they set up to have them be raised up to be
the bulwark against Bolshevism in Europe.
Yeah.
And since the investors at Brown Brothers Harriman, these two dozen-
And that was the initial feeder for the CIA, came out of the Brown Brothers Harriman.
That's right.
It was Robert Lovett who actually wrote the initial memo to Truman saying, we've got to
reinstitute a major agency like the OSS.
We've got to have it in peacetime.
And it came from Robert Lovett, senior partner at Brown Brothers Harriman.
And so that whole group was the seat of the China lobby who saw the future of investment,
capital investment in the Asian markets.
Because they already owned a controlling stock interest in most of the war industry in Germany,
which they'd extracted through the Versailles Treaty Agreement, long involved in process they
did it.
But the bottom line is that when, at the end of World War I, at the end of World War I,
when the Treaty of Versailles was being signed, Robert Lansing, who was the Secretary of State
under Wilson-
Dulles' uncle.
Was the uncle of Alan and John Foster Dulles.
He had married the eldest daughter of John W. Foster, who was the maternal grandfather for
both Alan and John Foster.
So there was John W. Foster was the guy.
And he was an arch-imperialist.
He's the guy that overthrew under his, when he was Secretary of State, he overthrew the
island of Hawaii and started taking Guam and that whole thing, focusing on moving into
Asia.
That was the whole idea of that.
And so what they did in the Versailles Treaty, he got Robert Lansing, who was the son-in-law
of John W. Foster, had Robert Lansing, his son-in-law, bring his two grandsons, John Foster
Dulles and Alan Dulles, with him to the Versailles Treaty.
And actually, as lawyers at Sullivan and Cromwell, to draft into the Versailles Treaty
Agreement, the war reparations requirements.
Whoa.
That Germany had to pay war reparations for all the damage they'd inflicted on other industries.
So that made them dependent on the Union Bank.
Well, what happened was just even pre-Union Bank.
This is in 1918.
And so what they did is they said, look, that you're going to have to pay these war reparations.
They imposed that financial obligation on them, but they didn't have the money to pay
them.
And so what happened is the investors in Brown Brothers Harriman, these 20, 24, you know,
robber baron families, you know, the Rockefellers and Harriman Railway people and Carnegie and
all of these guys, the Mellons, all of them were there.
Uh, and they saw their future is going, uh, westward into Asia because what they could
do is they could secure control over Europe through Germany.
Uh, and, and what they would do is they would loan the money to Germany to pay the war reparations
and they would take as security for their loans, the controlling stock interest in like a corrupt
ball bearing factory and, and IG Farben and all these other major war industries making
the explosives and chemicals.
They would, they would have this stock interest.
A lot of these were kind of operation paperclip based companies, right?
Like they were, they were in some cases started and run by Nazis.
Well, the Nazis weren't there really yet.
Okay.
This is only 1918.
Right.
And, but so, so what happened is what, what they did is, is they set up that mechanism
by means of which the stockholders or the investors in Brown Brothers Harriman called
these two dozen wealthy, super wealthy families.
What they did is they had the controlling stock interest in those companies.
And then what they did is they additionally loaned additional money to Germany to rebuild their
war machine so that they could be the bulwark against Bolshevism because at the very end
of the, of the, of the, the first world war in October of 1917, the Bolsheviks had overthrown
Tsar Nicholas the second and overthrown him and withdrawn them from, from World War one.
And so what happened is this, this, this seat of kind of a socialist alternative to the kind
of investment ideas that were housed at Brown Brothers Harriman, that they viewed them as
this terrible adversary.
So what they did is they leaned in on Robert Lansing, who was the secretary of state and
sent a foreign military expedition into Russia that almost nobody knows about it.
Now the full scale U.S. financed U.S. military foreign expeditionary force into Russia to try
in 1918 to try to crush the Bolshevik revolution.
Wow.
Really?
And they recruited the white Russians, all those kinds of Tsarist Russians that were in
St. Petersburg, that whole crowd.
Was Dulles involved?
That, that, that, that Dulles, Dulles was involved with Germany.
He was, he was appointed to be the legal counsel for Germany as well as the legal counsel for
Brown Brothers Harriman.
Wow.
So he was, he was negotiating both sides of these, these financial agreements so that they,
they had them owning.
He was the legal counsel for.
For Brown Brothers Harriman.
But for Germany is what, what he meant?
He was appointed by Robert Lansing, his uncle, to be the legal counsel for Germany as well,
so that he was on both sides of the negotiations.
He was counseling Germany to accept these loans, you know, and, and to rebuild their, their war
industry.
And he, he ended up being the, the, basically almost the legal governor general, you know,
working for the German government.
Whoa.
And so that, that, that's what he did.
He choreographed that entire thing.
And so what happened is they got that all set up in 18, 19, 18, 19, 19.
Yeah.
Then they, then Robert Lansing sent the foreign military expeditionary force into Russia to
try to crush the, the Bolshevik revolution in the cradle.
Hey everyone, Jesse here.
Let's talk about something a lot of us quietly deal with, hair loss.
This is something that messes with your confidence more than you'd expect.
Okay, you might be wondering, Jesse, you clearly don't suffer from this.
It's true.
The biggest issue I face is hat hair.
I actually have very thick hair, but one of my good friends deals with hair loss.
So when iRestore sent me their iRestore Elite, I gifted it to him and I've been amazed at
the results it gave him.
The first thing that stood out to him is it's comfortable and easy to use.
You just pop it on while reading or working and it does its thing.
This isn't some gimmick.
It uses 300 lasers and 200 LEDs to deliver clinically backed red light therapy straight
to the scalp.
This is the best way to stimulate hair growth.
Over the past few weeks, I've seen noticeable improvement with my friend.
He says that his hair feels thicker and healthier and it's improved his overall confidence in
life.
The iRestore Elite uses triple wavelength technology and Lumatech red light therapy.
It's engineered for deeper penetration and broader coverage.
That means more stimulation to hair follicles and better, faster results.
And look, if it doesn't work for you, they offer a 12-month money-back guarantee.
I've never heard of a money-back guarantee that lasts that long.
Try it consistently and if you're not happy, they get you your money back.
Of course, the restocking fee applies.
That made it a no-brainer for my friend.
So give yourself the gift of hair confidence this spring.
For a limited time only, our listeners get a huge discount on iRestore Elite when you
use code JESSE, J-E-S-S-E, at iRestore.com.
Head over to iRestore.com and use code JESSE, J-E-S-S-E, for our show's exclusive discounts on
the iRestore Elite.
Please support our show and tell them we sent you.
Hair loss is frustrating.
You don't have to fight it alone, thanks to iRestore.
But let's get back to, okay, so 63.
So he's aware of UFOs and trying to do some joint space program with Khrushchev around
that.
Yes.
He is trying to defang the American nuclear arsenal, but also have-
Also the Russian arsenal.
Soviets, yeah, denuclearize and tie the mutual disarmament.
Yes.
And he is trying to take the country back, the U.S. back from this kind of military.
And China agreed.
China agreed that they would not pursue any nuclear program at all.
Do we have records of that?
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
Really?
Oh, yes.
Where are the records of that?
That there's, they can dig them out because they reached out to China.
China only had like-
He reached out to Mao.
They had a real early interest in kind of trying to deal with the nuclear weapons issue,
but they hadn't really mounted a program.
And he agreed to forestall the entire thing.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
No way.
At that point in between basically January of 1963 and June of 1963, at least prior to
when John XXIII died, that that was still a kind of totally viable operation that they
were planning to do.
Mm-hmm.
And then when John XXIII died, I think Kennedy leaned forward into it to try to make sure
that the thing kept on going.
And so he decided he was going to get the information for Khrushchev and give it to him as a further
sign of good faith so that they could not only have a complete open and honest relationship by putting
some skin in the game, by coughing up the information we had about this, but also prepare for who they were going to be
encountering, you know, out in extraterrestrial civilization, you know, and what happened is on June 5th,
when he asked for it, the Bissell, it's almost certainly it was Bissell, you know, found out about it, you know,
and told Dulles.
And so Dulles and the guys started really, wait, they can't allow the nuclear missiles to be disassembled
because they have to have them to deal with China, you know, because China had demonstrated already
in Korea that they could put a billion men in uniform and just melt your gun barrels down by just pouring
them on you like they did up at Incheon and at the reservoir, you know, that that's what they did.
They just sent in like a billion guys, you know, and just stormed them.
And so they realized that they could not take on China in the future in a conditional land war.
So they needed the nuclear weapons.
That's why MacArthur kept saying, what we got to do is show them, bomb them, you know, that whole thing,
that fallout with Truman.
So the bottom line is that China lobby freaked out about potentially losing their nuclear option
against China.
So that can't be, that we can't allow that to happen.
And we can't wait a year for the elections, you know, I mean, you know, they can probably figure
out how to get rid of him in the election, you know, uh, but they couldn't wait the year
because he would order to start ordering the disassembly.
And so what happened is that, uh, when he, when, uh, on, uh, that June 5th, that, uh, he ended up, uh, issuing the, uh, the, the demand
for the, he did the same thing the same day.
He did this weird thing, which I've never been to quite figure out yet about the printing these, uh, these silver certificates.
Mm-hmm.
He did that on June 5th too.
Interesting.
He did a whole bunch of these things.
I met Oliver Stone once and he connects the printing of the silver certificates with JFK's assassination.
Like that was somehow undermining of...
Well, he was, he was doing a lot of radical things right there, you know, because I think that what happened
was when, when John the 23rd died, you know, Kennedy, uh, he was hoping to, to bring, uh, John the 23rd in
and kind of Catholic support for what he was doing, uh, the ethics of what he was doing, the whole speech
at, at, uh, George Washington University and all that stuff, you know, he was going through this real
metanoia at that time, you know, and, uh, but the, the, the act of, of disassembling and destroying
the nuclear warheads was viewed by Dulles and the guys as a, as an act of treason, you know, uh,
and now that, but it was eliminating their ability to actually quell China, you know, and to, to be able
to have access to the market, the Asian market. So what he did is just green lighted the S force.
Mm-hmm. So this is this kind of sleeper cell. Yeah. They're just select group of
trafficante Cuban exiles who are these kind of killer assassins that were originally
commissioned to, uh, take out Che Guevara and Castro and he re-operationalizes them to take
out JFK. Just all he had to do was just get up off their neck. So who were the three, who were the,
uh, they're the two men on the grassy knoll. Who were they? Well, the, we, we know that Morales was
the shooter. Okay. Because he was the guy. Uh, we, we know that the Rip Robertson was there.
Were they the two men on the grassy knoll or was Morales on the grassy knoll or?
Morales was on the grassy knoll. Okay. So he took the shot from the grassy knoll.
He took the shot from the grassy knoll. Wow. That was, that was he. Wow. The, the thing that I,
I find to be in a certain sense so special about what we now know that actually happened is the
peculiar aspect of this is the relationship that Oswald had with all these guys. And then you look
at the, what's come out about, um, Oswald's landlady. She's a super curious character.
She's still alive, bro. She's like 93. No way. Ruth Payne is her name. Ruth Payne. That's right.
And she somehow was connected with Dulles's mistress, Bancroft. Am I making that up?
Yeah. No, this is correct. Um, she actually vacationed the summer of 1963 at a place called
Nashawn Island, which is right up near Martha's Vineyard in Massachusetts. And Nashawn Island
is owned by the Forbes family. That's John Kerry Forbes, the guy who ran against Bush in 2004.
Yeah. Right. They're both skull and bones. They both went to Yale secret society. Um, the Forbes
family hosted this summer retreat at their mansion. Ruth Payne's there with Alan Dulles,
Alan Dulles's mistress. What they discussed is, again, that's not going to be in the JFK files.
It's not going to be in the Kennedy. What year were they together there? 63. That's so right there.
So right after she leaves Nashawn Island, she, I think she either before she went to Nashawn or after
she visits her sister in Virginia. Turns out her sister works for the CIA. That's, that's come out.
Whoa. Then she goes, picks up Lee and Marina in New Orleans and dry and brings them to Dallas,
gives them a home, hooks Lee up with his job at the school book depository building,
which by the way, the school book depository building is an interesting, it's owned by D.
Harold Bird. Dry hole bird is, uh, David Harold Bird is his real name, but they call him dry hole bird
because he was against something called the oil depletion allowance. He's an oil, oil man. And,
uh, Kennedy wanted to get rid of this oil depletion allowance, which would have made all the oil
people have to basically pay a ton of money. They wouldn't get this government tax break from Uncle
Sam. So they were all, they all hated Kennedy. They wanted him gone for that reason. That's where
you have the, the oil, big oil element and big oil goes back way long in history. There's a whole book
by Daniel Yergin called the prize. And there's a prize part two, where he talks about the whole history
of oil with John D. Rockefeller and how he bought out all the railroads and, and would only ship his oil
through the railroads so he could basically have a monopoly over the oil business because he, or none
of the other oil companies could ship their oil because he owned all the railroads. And that's
why you, you know, in Monopoly, you own all the railroads. It's, it's part of the game. And, um,
again, he, he shut all the business and competition out and, uh, they were eventually disbanded with the
Antitrust Act, um, that, you know, broke up all the monopolies supposedly. But, um, a lot of these oil
people have a real dangerous history of murder and conspiracy going way back to then, you know,
and just doing terrible things. Uh, so yeah, those guys are involved. And then D. Harold Byrd,
addition to being an oil man, he's also, um, buys a bunch of stock in this company called LTV,
Ling Temco Vought. And he's part of, he owns this big share in, in Vought Aerospace. Well, it turns out
Vought Aerospace built all the flying saucers for Wright Patterson in the forties and fifties under a guy
named Alfred C. Loading. Wait, wait, what? Yeah. Really? We've built, what do you mean when you
say built the flying saucers, like built the Avrocar project, which is on record as flying saucers?
Well, the Avrocar project was Canada. So that was, that, that's. But then it got moved to Wright-Patt
as Project Y or Silverbug. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. But, but like, so what do you, when you say built
flying saucers because. So the Vought Flying Pancake is a, is a Vought aircraft and it's a, it's literally
an attempt to, it's an early attempt to build a flying saucer with propellers. That was before Avrocar in the
40s. Yeah. It was way before. This was, or this was even predates that. That's so interesting. I
didn't, I didn't even heard of this. Yeah. That's so, wow. It's, it's, it's, it's very obscure. It's not
well known. And then T, LTV, Ling Tengko Vought, he, Ling, he gives a bunch of money with Ling and they
invest in this right before the Kennedy assassination. And of course, aerospace and, and all those people
made a ton of money off the Kennedy assassination. And then you have deep space, aerospace
connections, deep state aerospace connections to Lee Harvey Oswald, because he worked at
Sugi, which is where the CIA was running the U2 spy plane program. Whoa. You know? So.
Well, also I believe Harold Byrd, who owned the Texas Book Depository, he was, I think had
some connections with LBJ. And then he was also connected with Curtis LeMay. Curtis LeMay gave
him an award for the Civil Air Corps when he was younger. Yes. And Curtis LeMay hated JFK.
Absolutely. Hated him. And, uh, you know, thought that he was, you know, kind of a
traitor. LBJ, LBJ too. And there's pictures of LBJ and D. Harold Byrd together, like going
to football games and, and, and they were, they were good friends. So they're definitely
knew each other. Definitely. Um, maybe the craziest thing of all, I mean, JFK, we're painting
a picture of him just being 360 surrounded by these like, you know, spooky people. Um, the
mayor of Dallas was a guy named Earl Cabell. Yeah. And, um, his, his brother, Charles was
Dallas's number two at the CIA. And, and the Bay of Pigs. There you go. Yeah. And, and
Earl rerouted JFK's motorcade. Yeah. So like that. They took it right by D. Harold Byrd's
building. It's like, come on. Yeah. Now it gets, it gets even deeper. Yeah. It's, it's
crazy, bro. Cause, uh, you know, D. Harold Byrd, you know, that he has, he's a big
hunter, right? He, he went after JFK got assassinated, he went to Africa on a safari
and shot a bunch of elephants, brought their heads back and had them mounted on
the wall in his big trophy room, a big trophy room full of all the animal heads
that he, of all the animals he killed and shot. You know what else he did? He took
the window out of the six floor depository building and he put it in his trophy
room at his house. What? Why? What, what reason for that? No.
No way. That's crazy. That's fucking weird. Whoa. That is like, dude, that's red
flags. That is huge, huge red flags. And the fact that Ruth Payne knows D. Harold
Byrd, she brings the Oswalds to Dallas, gives him this house to live in. And then
all after the assassination, they go to Ruth Payne's garage, find all the evidence
that, that, and then about a month after the assassination, after the FBI has already
searched the home extensively, Ruth Payne comes and says, Oh, me and Marina found
this other note that he left for Marina, supposedly where he, he wrote Marina a
note when he supposedly went to go shoot General Walker and left her a note. But
they found this all after the case. So, and then, then they've used that to blame
the shooting of Edwin Walker on Lee Harvey Oswald. He's, oh, he's, you know, he's
killing this, you know, anti-communist general, which is really weird because, you
know, it, it doesn't make sense with the narrative of, you know, what is he just
trying to kill someone to get famous? Is that, is that Lee, who, who we think Lee
Harvey Oswald is? You know, the people get, oh, poor Oswald, you know, was just this
innocent guy who was just a weirdo and he was just a fall guy, you know, and didn't
have anything to do with it. It's not true at all.
He was CIA trained.
Well, he was actually trained by the Office of Naval Intelligence. It wasn't CIA.
Interesting.
And he was in this thing called Operation Redskin. It was a whole different
operation. But the bottom line is he ended up being part of this thing that was
called, uh, the, in the field intelligence. Uh, and it was, it was a kind of a
private, uh, spying operation, the political spying operation that was going
on. The William D. Pauly and, uh, and, uh, uh, Hunt, uh, E.H. Hunt and a lot of
guys, they were funding it. And that was a Willoughby, George Willoughby, Charles
Willoughby rather. Uh, cause at, when, when Truman got not fired, Truman wasn't
fired. He was, he was redeployed.
So what were these operations Lee Harvey Oswald was involved in?
He was doing spying. He was doing spying on progressive groups, uh, in, uh, in
around the, around New Orleans, working with Guy Bannister. It was true.
Guy Bannister is the FBI guy who's known as like the head of the X-Files, like he's on
the weird desk of the FBI. And so he was 555 Camp Street. Is that right?
555 Camp Street. And so, and so Lee Harvey Oswald is working out of that building. That
building mysteriously gets burned down, right? By, by, by Novell.
Gordon Novell is the guy that was arrested and prosecuted by James Garrison in New Orleans
for burning down 555 Camp Street, the office where, where, uh, where, uh, uh, Lee Oswald
Wow.
Had the office along with, uh, uh, what was his name? Uh, the guy that was the hardcore right
wing guy that was the head of the Latin American, uh, uh, anti-communist league. Uh, one of the,
uh, the guy that was the former FBI guy that was down in New Orleans, the heck was that
guy's name? But anyway, he had an office in the same, the exact same building on the exact
same floor. Whoa. With him. And, and Gordon Novell was prosecuted and convicted for burning
down that building in the midst of, uh, in the midst of the investigation.
Crazy. Okay. Who ends up later in the U of a, in the UFO conversation, uh, you know,
and tried to hire me as his lawyer, Robert Bigelow and stuff. Okay. So, so he's just all
so crazy. Yeah. So what is Lee Harvey Oswald doing exactly? He's inserting himself into like
he's, he, he is, he is, uh, in addition to spying on the different liberal groups like ACLU
and other things that he's doing and filing reports with this field intelligence operation
going on that, that what he's doing is he's infiltrating the, the free Cuba group, uh, and
pretending to be a Marxist, you know, uh, just like he, when he went to Russia and did all
that stuff. And so what he was doing is he was designing a character of being, uh, involved
with Russia and with, uh, with Cuba. Uh, and what, what the, the plan was is to coax him
into taking a shot at the motorcade, not hitting anybody, but taking a shot at the motorcade.
Uh, and then he would, uh, he would, uh, escape, but they would have, they figure out who it
was. There's the gun and there's who he is. And that they would blame it on Cuba and they
could get back to invading the Island. You know, again, it was the same guys, the same
guy, hardcore right-wing guys that are into this. And so he's, he's all put into place to
take the shot at the motorcade and then run and escape. Uh, and what happens, he takes
the shot at the motorcade, hits the curb and chips the, you know, the curb, the pieces
of the cement flying. And immediately these other shots ring out, uh, and kill the president
right in front of him.
So you think Oswald missed?
Oh, he didn't miss. He wasn't intending to hit him.
He wasn't even. What was the point really?
The point was to have a fire, a gun, uh, shot fired at the motorcade to be a, a bungled
attempt to assassinate the president and blame it on Oswald, who was a Cuban operations
guy so that they could then justify invading the Island.
Yeah. Got it.
That's, that was the whole plan. A very subtle plan. And he was involved in that part.
And when he finally fired the shot.
Why didn't they end up using him as, oh, like he was this Cuban operative? Cause they
didn't, that didn't end up being the narrative. Like we need to retaliate against Cuba.
Well, B, because, because he killed, he killed, uh, uh, uh, Tippett, the police officer was
sent to kill him, you know, cause the whole idea is there's a dead guy. There's a lone
gunman, dead guy, you know, that he took the shot at the president. You rotten bastards,
you know, you're a Cuban, you know, spy. And, you know,
And what was his association with Cuba prior?
He was, uh, he, he was part of the, uh, uh, free Cuba group. He, he infiltrated the group.
That was when he got arrested on the street. Remember by, by, by, you know, sitting on the
street corner championing Cuba.
Where, what year is this?
In, uh, 1963.
Okay.
1963.
And he's, he's chanting free Cuba like in New Orleans or where?
In, uh, in New Orleans.
Okay.
Yeah.
This is amazing.
Yeah. So he was, he was creating this character who was a, who was kind of a zany guy who'd been
to Russia and it was in favoring Cuba. And then he was going to take a shot at the, uh, thing. And
he thought he was supposed to help get escaped.
Yeah.
The whole theory was he was going to, they were going to help him escape.
Uh, and then, but they were going to blame it on him, but he's already in some safe haven.
But in reality, they were just going to take him out.
They were going to kill him.
And then he killed Tippett.
That's right.
Sort of fumbled the plan.
As soon as he saw Tippett, he just killed him.
Wow.
You know, and, uh, and got arrested for it.
Yeah.
You know?
And, uh, so that's why he kept saying, wait a second, I'm just a patsy here. Something's
wrong.
I'd like some legal representation. These police officers have not allowed me to, to have any.
I, uh, I don't know what this is all about.
I work in that building.
Were you in the building at the time?
Naturally, if I work in that building, yes, sir.
Back up, man.
Come on, man.
No, they're taking me in because of the fact that I live in the Soviet Union.
What are you talking to me about?
I'm just a patsy.
You're just a president.
And he tried to place the call.
Yeah.
He asked for the telephone call.
To Nag's head.
Yeah.
Which is Redskin.
That was, that was the whole operation where he was dipped.
That's what he was dipped.
Ship dipped.
He was erased.
Yeah.
And so, so the bottom line and that whole thing, the role of him, you know, it really
disappoints half of the, the Castro or the, the Kennedy assassination community.
Oh no, way of saying it.
He's supposed to be a completely innocent guy.
Didn't have anything to do with it.
You know, wasn't involved with these people at all.
And they're just these weird things, you know, that, that, uh, Garrison in, in, in New
Orleans was way off base, but he wasn't, you know, that that whole crowd was part of
that, you know, in Guy Bannister and that whole crowd.
Bannister was the head of the, the Central American chapter of the World Anti-Communist
League.
Wow.
You know?
Uh, you know, that's, that's who they are, you know, and that's what he was part of.
Uh, and, uh, and so that, that's, that's how the, that's how the thing came down.
And of course, as soon as it happened, all the people that knew about the S-Force said,
holy shit, it's the S-Force.
You know, there's, there's, uh, Rip Robertson, photographs of Rip Robertson, who's the field,
field operations commander for the S-Force standing right there in Dilley Plaza.
You got Ed Lansdale, you know, the photographs of Lansdale sitting right there and his wife
identifying him, you know?
Uh, and so the, the, you got the S-Forces in town.
Wow.
I mean, you see a Philip, uh, Felipe Fidal Santiago on the grassy knoll.
This guy's like a radio man.
He looks like a Cuban.
He's out of place.
And he's sitting, he's sitting right next to the umbrella man.
And the umbrella man has never been really solved.
They, they came out with this guy they said was the umbrella man in the set in 74 at the
house select committee.
That's not the dude.
Come on now.
And there was a different guy there with the umbrella symbolizing, you didn't have the
umbrella to, of the air support to help with the Bay of Pigs.
And now we're going to get you and also being the signal man on the grassy knoll.
Did you know that there were three yellow painted lines right on the side of the curb where the
shot in, in conjunction where all the shots took place in the, in the kill zone.
And they were painted the night before because Beverly Oliver was standing on one.
She can be seen in the, in the Zapruder film, standing on the yellow curb on the edge of the,
edge of the sidewalk on Elm street.
And she got yellow paint all over her shoe because it was freshly painted the night before.
Now there's no parking on Elm street.
So there's no reason to paint the curb yellow.
Everyone, everyone knows there's no parking there.
It's an on-ramp to the freeway, to the Stemmons freeway.
You know, nobody, nobody pulls over there and parks.
So there's no reason to paint the curb unless you're marking the, the shots for the kill zone.
Were there any other actors or people worthy of consideration as far as the involvement here?
Yeah.
I mean, the, the, the, the, the question is to how many of the people in Brown Brothers
Harriman had to sign off on this, you know, other than Dulles and the, the, the real power
was sort of in Sullivan and Cromwell, that whole law firm, you know, that that's not a
normal law firm, Sullivan and Cromwell.
There was legal counsel for Brown Brothers Harriman, the Cromwell of Sullivan and Cromwell is the
guy that choreographed the, the, uh, overthrowing of the Panamanian government to build the Panama
Canal.
I mean, it's, it's sort of, it was sort of like, uh, uh, Williams and Connolly.
Interesting.
Yeah.
It's not like a normal law firm.
Gotcha.
No, that's like Sullivan and Cromwell was that back at those times.
So, so the, the bottom line is that's what happened.
And then as soon as the people realized what had happened, they said, shit is the S force,
you know, and so we've got to do everything in our power to cover this thing up because
anybody finds out it's the S force, they're going to track it all the way back through
to the agency and they're going to blame this on the agency.
Uh, whereas it wasn't the agency as such that did it.
It was Dulles, you know, in his capacity as the consigliere, basically for Brown Brothers
Harriman, you know, in that whole China lobby operation.
And so the agency went to great lengths to conceal this.
Uh, and then they briefed LBJ, LBJ goes and gets ahold of Earl Warren and says, Justice
Warren, Chief Justice Warren, you've got to chair this commission because we've really
got to quell any of these concerns about a conspiracy.
And look at one thing that you got to do.
And he didn't want to do it.
And so he said, look, let me tell you why you have to do this.
He said, because it says, you've got to be sure to conceal the fact that there was an
assassination team that was, that was assigned to try to kill Castro.
And it was the Kennedys that put it together.
And if the word gets out that there was an assassination team that Kennedy put together
to try to kill Castro, everybody's going to believe that Castro found out about it and
killed the president.
And if that happens, you know, people are going to go crazy and they're going to try to make
us invade Cuba.
And if we do that, Russia is going to cause a world war.
And he, they lie to, to Chief Justice Warren, to, or Chief Justice Warren to get to chair
the Warren Commission.
And they put Alan Dulles on the, who was the de facto run, the guy that ran the Warren
Commission, you know, the whole thing to cover them all up.
So crazy.
To cover the, and, and what people do is people, when they get little pieces of the information,
they say, oh, this is the agency that killed him.
Yeah.
You know, and they kill him because he screwed up the Bay of Pigs.
Did they get Jack Ruby to kill?
What, what, what happened with Jack Ruby?
I mean, that's all the mob.
They said, wait, holy shit.
We, we've messed up here.
How did they, how did they manipulate Jack Ruby into killing Lee Harvey Oswald?
He was, he was a made man.
He was a made man of the, of the mob.
You know, when they tell you.
Do you think they MKUltred him because he says he didn't remember killing Lee Harvey Oswald
for a long time?
No, I don't think that's true.
You don't think so?
That's just a good story.
But that, okay, but so then, yeah, maybe, maybe not, you know, for the actual killing,
but then he ends up in jail and he's claims that he doesn't remember killing Lee Harvey
Oswald, but is pretty lucid.
And then he's seen court ordered by a psychiatrist who is on record as being part of MKUltra,
a guy named Jolly West, who is letters between him and Sidney Gottlieb.
We, you know, are fairly sure that he was involved in CIA mind control stuff.
And he sees Jack Ruby for 24 hours, totally not filmed, you know, and comes out.
Jack Ruby has a psychotic break and he starts, you know, saying that there are Jews outside
his jail cell screaming or whatever, and is never the same after that.
And Jolly West does a press conference saying Jack Ruby has gone crazy, you know, he's lost
his marbles or whatever.
And so...
So you can't depend on anything he says.
Yeah.
I mean, that's got to be pretty...
But that would imply that the first time around he wasn't, he wasn't MKUltra because
maybe he had something to share and they needed to scramble his brain to cover it up.
And the thing is, is that just following Occam's razor, you get a real simple line and narrative
of what really happened.
And then all kinds of activities that are undertaken to cover up and conceal this, you know, end
up being interpreted as your principal involved in making the plan to kill him because it makes,
it satisfies people's other more sinister worldview.
Right.
But the bottom line is that the threat that was going to come unraveled happened with the
Watergate burglary.
Because what happened is when, as soon as the Democratic National Committee chooses Larry
O'Brien to be the new head of the Democratic National Committee, it turns out previously,
20 years, he was the chief lobbyist for Howard Hughes in Washington.
This is an amazing part of your narrative, which is that Larry O'Brien is the number two,
or chief lobbyist for Howard Hughes.
Howard Hughes was responsible on behalf of Nixon for setting up, you know, the S-Force
and working with Traficante.
Yep.
And so Nixon is, because he was a longtime political opponent of JFK, is freaked out that
he's, because he's running for president later.
Yes.
Is in the, you know, so this is in the seventies.
He says, he's, he's freaked out that basically Larry O'Brien is going to out him as having
killed his longtime political opponent, even though he set up the S-Force not to kill JFK.
That's right, that's right.
It was to take out Castro and Che Guevara.
But he's freaked out that they have compromise on him.
That's right.
And if you look at what happened in the Watergate scandal, the burglary, it's James McCord
is involved.
You represented him, you know, in the, in the, afterwards.
Yeah.
McCord was known as Dulles's number two and his favorite guy or whatever.
It was just, you know, his favorite understudy.
Mm-hmm.
And they put it, they bug Larry O'Brien's phone.
And bug his office.
So clearly they were targeting him.
And Nixon was way up against McGovern in the polls in that election.
Oh, yeah.
So you always have to ask the question, was it like, he was paranoid, but was he that
paranoid?
Like, why would he do that if it weren't this sort of specific thing he was worried about?
That's right.
Because, because if O'Brien were to reveal the fact that he's the one that, that created
the assassination team that in fact killed the president, there's no way you can talk
your way out of that time in an election year from June, between June and November.
He's not going to climb out under, from under that.
And so he said, we've got to, we've got to find out whether, whether O'Brien knows about
it and is thinking at all about using it.
So we've got to not only wiretap his telephone, but bug his office.
That's amazing.
And that's what they did.
And they sent him in to do it.
So you were, you then are the lawyer for James McCord.
Well, it was Bailey.
It was Bailey himself.
Because Bailey, it turns out, was on index four for the agency.
Okay.
Which, which we didn't know.
You know, none of us knew it in the office.
Did you learn anything from those guys about like spooky Intel world or like, did, did any
of them sort of reveal any secret, like McCord, did you interact with McCord at all?
No.
Okay.
But, but I, I knew that McCord was, was, was, uh, didn't want to plead guilty.
He was refusing to plead guilty.
He said, why am I pleading guilty?
You know, that we got, because he had been told that they were going in to, to try to
find evidence that, that, uh, O'Brien and the other guys were, were coordinating and
financing anti-war demonstrators.
Yeah.
Uh, and he wanted to get that information.
So he thought he was involved in kind of a, a typical kind of, you know, uh, uh, I guess
meat and potatoes kind of covert operation by the agency.
Uh, and they've been instructed that if you get caught doing a covert operation for the
agency stateside, which is totally illegal, call one of the people on the index four.
You know, there's William Bennett Williams and then there's a Bailey and there was this
other guy Miller I knew about, you know, but, but I didn't know any of that when Bailey
contacted me and asked me to come over to his shop to, to be special counsel, uh, you
know, for the burglary case.
I want to pivot slightly.
It's the same sort of, uh, you know, world that we're talking about here, but, um, you
have a very interesting narrative about how some of maybe the initial financing occurs
for secret covert UFO programs in America.
Oh yeah.
And, uh, you, you talk about this Anderson trust and, uh, you know, billions of dollars
worth of lost gold.
1.2 trillion.
There you go.
At $32 an ounce.
Unbelievable.
Which is now $3,400.
So what's, what's the story there?
Well, it's the, the, what happened is back in about 19, about 2000, uh, it was just like
2000 or 2000 that, uh, Mr. Aaya, who is like the third richest fellow in the entire
Philippines, you know, uh, contacts the Jesuit headquarters that he wanted to, he wanted to
have somebody from the Jesuit headquarters because he'd gone to a Jesuit high school and college
and stuff and wanted them to come in brief the top 50 business people in the Philippines
about what the consequences of global climate change were going to be for the Island, you
know, with the rising sea levels is going to swamp parts of the Island and ruin businesses.
Uh, and so trying to see if they would mobilize the business community to do something about
it.
Right.
So I got designated to go brief him.
So I fly, I fly to the Philippines, uh, and Mr. Aaya puts me up in this, like 20 years,
20 star hotel, you know, with these, this sumptuous food everywhere, all this bizarre
kind of offensive, uh, kind of opulence.
Uh, and you know, I go brief these guys and I tell them that, uh, what they should do is
they should try to mobilize and get the government of the Philippines, uh, which they had some
influence with these rich business guys, you know, to lead a, the, uh, uh, association of
Island States, uh, in the United Nations to mobilize a, uh, a motion on the floor of the
General Assembly to have a uniting for peace resolution, to have the Island States all
joined together and accused the United States and, uh, and China and India of, uh, aggressive
activities, ruining their national security by the fostering and promoting of the fossil
fuels that are swamping their islands and ruining their country.
Uh, and if you can get, if I told him, if you can get two thirds of all the members of
the General Assembly, the 193 countries at that time, you know, to support such a resolution,
you can get an investigation done.
Uh, and if you can get three fourths of them to vote for a resolution, ordering those countries
to start cutting back on all of their, the use of petroleum, you can enforce it. And the
Security Council can't veto it. Okay. So I explained that all to them. Uh, and then Mr. Ayat
drives me up to his big mansion on the top of the mountain, overlooking Manila, and we're sitting
there, you know, sipping lemonade one afternoon. And he said, you know, uh, would you like to meet the,
the president of the Senate of the Philippines? And I said, yeah, that would be really helpful
if we could get right to them, you know? And he said, well, let me, let me get ahold of him. He
gets up and leaves, he goes in, makes a call. He comes back, he says, good, let's go down and see
him. So we go get in his big Cadillac. We drive down off the hill. He walks into the, to the office
of the president of the Senate, says hi to the secretary. And we just walk in, we sit down.
And then he introduces me to Senator Pimentel, who is the president of the, of the Philippine
Senate. And, uh, I'm briefing him on this, how to go about, you know, spearheading, organizing the
Association of Island States to bring on a motion under the Uniting for Peace resolution. And he's,
he's listening to me, but he doesn't seem particularly enthralled about it all. Uh, and so then he, he
casually gets up and goes over and he closes the door and comes and sits back down. He said, well,
I should tell you, he said, as the president, uh, of the, of the Senate, you know, I chair
a thing called the Blue Ribbon Commission. And the Blue Ribbon Commission is charged with
finding these 176, uh, troves of treasure that have been buried in the Philippines by General
Yakushima at the end of, uh, World War II. Uh, and each of them, uh, has like a hundred billion
dollars of gold and silver, uh, in the platinum bars and big 50 gallon drums of diamonds and rubies
and, and precious jewels that have all been pilfered by a special unit of the Japanese army
that was deployed all during the 1930s before World War II started, uh, as a treasure, a war
chest for the, the war.
Because they were, and they were worried about being invaded or taken?
Well, they, yeah, because they, they knew that, that once the Germans had surrendered in May
of 1945, it was just a matter of time that the U.S. was going to invade the island, you
know, and, and take them down. Uh, and so they, they were going to move all of the, the treasure
out of there, uh, out of Japan and they were going to bury it. And they were going to sign
General Yakushima himself to oversee all that. And they were going to send the, uh, the cousin,
I think of, uh, of, uh, Hiroshito, you know, uh, to a prince, a Japanese prince of the royal
family to accompany them. So he would know where all 176 of these treasure troves were. Uh, and
so they sent him into the islands and they started moving the gold out in the last months of the
war and they buried it. Uh, and they buried him in these, like, you know, like, you know, 500,
600 feet deep, you know, big wells, like that they drilled. Uh, and then they were using, uh,
prisoners of war to do the digging and then burying the team that dug that particular hole,
burying them with the gold so that no one would know, be around to tell.
So where did, where did this gold end up?
It ended up in the Philippines. There's 176 troves of these things.
Is it still there?
Still there.
Oh yeah.
So there is 1.5 trillion or $1.2 trillion worth of gold in the Philippines now?
Oh, 1.2 trillion was just about, just 12 of the troves. There's 176 of them.
And they're still there?
Yes. They're still there.
So who's guarding over them?
They, they don't, they can't find them. That's what the problem is. They're crazy people
running around the Philippines for decades trying to find these places.
No way.
But they don't, they don't know where they are.
But you, but we have documentation that there are a lot of these.
Oh yeah. That, that, that, uh, Marcos got two of them.
Yeah.
Uh, by, by, by capturing one of the guys who was, uh, uh, who, who, who found one of them
and, uh, they drilled the eyes out of his son right in front of him with a hot poker.
Jesus.
Marcos, Colonel Vare, you know, did it.
Who is, who's Marcos?
Marcos was the president of the, of the Philippines.
Whoa.
That, uh, that was.
Who drilled, who drilled?
Well, the, the, General Vare was his kind of chief torturer and, uh, he tortured this
guy's son right in front of him to get the guy to tell him where two of these little troves
were, you know, and, uh, they got two of them.
Uh, Marcos got two of them, each of a hundred billion dollars.
What?
But, but.
So what does this have to do with UFO financing?
Well, the, the, no, the, it doesn't as such.
What, what we know is that, that at the end of World War II, after they had done this,
after they'd buried them all and there were maps of, of, of them, that what, what happened
is that, uh, Lansdale, Ed Lansdale, who was in the OSS, when they disbanded the OSS after
the Germans, uh, uh, surrendered in May of 45, that Truman disbanded the OSS and reassigned
them all around.
And Ed Lansdale, who was an OSS guy, gets made the G2, uh, in Manila, right?
And he knows about the fact that this treasure has been buried around there.
And so what he does is when, when, uh, General Yakushima turns himself in, you know, at the
end of the war, after the dropping the bombs, you know, in, uh, in August, the 6th and 8th
of 45, you know, they all surrender.
Uh, so there's not going to be any kind of, uh, invasion to the, but, and what, what, uh,
Japan was hoping that they could get a conditional surrender, uh, and that they would be able
to keep custody of the Philippines so that they'd be able to then later go in and dig
these things up and have, you know, reconstitute the wealth of the Japanese empire, right?
That was the plan.
But the U.S. bombs them instead, uh, and says, you know, it's an unconditional surrender.
You don't get the Philippines.
We keep the Philippines, right?
And so, and so what happens is, is, uh, Ed Lansdale, Ed Lansdale, uh, knows that these
are here.
And so these, these treasure troves are there.
So what he does is he, he kidnaps the driver for General Yakushima, who would know where the,
some of them were, right?
And so he has him tortured, this guy named Santo Mario, uh, uh, Santo Mario, yeah, it's
his name, uh, this corporal that actually conducted the torturing of, of this driver, uh, and they
find out where 12 of the troves are.
Uh, so they punched the first one, uh, and find the hundred billion dollars.
Uh, I've seen photographs of the, I mean, it looks, it's like a football stadium down
underneath the ground, you know, that goes down like five, 600 feet, huge cave caverns
down there in stacks of gold bullion, you know, you know, armpit high, as far as you
can see, you know, and big barrels of jewels everywhere.
And the bottom line is they, they punch 12 of these things.
And so, uh, so Lansdale, uh, after punching the first one and verifying that, that it's
for real, he gets in a plane, he flies, uh, from Manila to Singapore to see MacArthur.
And he goes in to see MacArthur, uh, personally, he starts to tell him what they've got here,
right?
And MacArthur brings in his G2, who's Charles Willoughby.
Uh, and, uh, and so MacArthur orders Willoughby to go with Ed Lansdale.
In MacArthur's private plane, and they fly him from Singapore, back to Manila, back into
the, uh, the Philippines and back into the United States.
Right.
And they, they go to see Truman to tell Truman that they've got $1.2 trillion, uh, in gold
bullion and platinum and, uh, and, uh, silver and jewels.
Uh, and the, the, the chief of staff won't let them see him, uh, unless he, they tell
him what they want to talk about.
So they brief the chief of staff who is Clark Clifford.
So Clifford comes into the meeting, uh, with Truman, uh, with, uh, Ed Lansdale and with
Willoughby and start to brief Truman about what they've got.
Truman says, hold a second, I've, I've got to bring, uh, uh, Stimson in, brings in the
Secretary of War, uh, uh, Stimson, brings him in.
And as soon as Stimson starts realizing what they've got, he sends for his three deputies.
And he, he brings in Robert Lovett, uh, and Robert Anderson, both not only deputies, secretaries
of war, but senior partners in Brown Brothers Harriman.
And, and John J.
McCloy, and they bring them in, the three deputies.
They find out what they've got here.
And Truman decides that what he's going to do, he's not going to tell anybody.
He's not going to tell the Congress.
He's not going to tell anybody else about it.
They're going to set up this secret, uh, uh, trust, uh, they call the Anderson trust.
And they set it up down in Houston, Texas.
And they, they set up the, the Anderson trust and they have all this and they, they assign.
We, we now know we've got the, he's still alive.
The, the, the commander of the pilot that flew the, flew the gold out.
He's alive.
Yes.
Have you spoken to him?
No, I'm going to.
Whoa.
We're going to, we, we know right where he is now.
And, and I'm going to, I'm going to talk to him, you know, to get this thing on the record.
Whoa.
But so the, so they fly the, using U.S. military transport.
They fly these, these, this gold all out of there, you know, these 12 troves of it.
And they bring it to the international credit bank in Geneva, Switzerland.
And then they deposit it there.
And then they issue gold certificates on it, which are like bearer bonds, you know, and, and they, they make, they distribute them to right wing anti-communist candidates for mayors and stuff.
After World War II, you know, all throughout Europe.
Whoa.
And there, so there's this whole covert program.
So this has nothing to do with the UFOs.
No.
Oh.
Okay.
No, no, no.
But what it is, is it's a, it's a mechanism for secretly funding covert operations.
Yeah.
They're going on after World War II, uh, when the CIA is set up and they're all funding this stuff.
And that's Dulles knows about this money that's there.
Yeah.
So that they're, they're using this for covert operations.
Interesting.
You know?
And yeah, it's wild.
That's wild.
It's, it's, it's totally separate from the, the UFO stuff.
Yeah.
I think Chris Ramsey, who just did a great interview with you.
Told me maybe he thought it had something to do with UFOs.
No.
I'll use this as a, uh, opportunity to say, Chris, why'd you lead me astray?
But go watch your interview with Chris.
Cause I thought that was great.
I don't know if you've seen it, but it was fantastic.
It was really great.
Yeah.
I don't, I don't see, I don't see most of these things.
I just, you know, when I, with somebody that I trust anyway, that I can just tell you.
Yeah.
And so it's done.
I know that you guys will tell other people.
Check it out.
Area 52.
Um, yeah.
In that interview, you actually talk about, uh, an interview with a live alien being.
Yeah.
Uh, at S4 in Area 51.
That's right.
And, uh, yeah.
Care to go into any detail around that?
Well, yeah.
Uh, yeah.
I got, at Jesuit headquarters, uh, I mean, see, it must be about, uh, let's see when that
would be, uh, it was 94 that I'd already done the, uh, the John Mack stuff.
Uh, so it was, it was like 2000, uh, 2001, 2002, something like that, that, uh, I get a
call, uh, from a guy, uh, in Northern Minnesota and he's, uh, on his deathbed.
Well, he's actually in hospice.
Right.
Uh, and he wants me to come and see him.
There's something, and he says that he worked directly with Project Blue Book.
And so I said, uh, oh, uh, uh, okay.
So I fly there and fly into Minneapolis and rent a little car and drive up into this little
teeny town up in Northern Minnesota.
Uh, and there he is.
He's at this little hospice place with, he's got one of these little rollers with all the
little bottles on it and stuff in his nose.
And he starts telling me how, uh, he was a, uh, a clerk typist, uh, army, U.S.
Army clerk typist assigned to this special unit of Project Blue Book that was focusing
just on the 700 or so, uh, uh, cases of, of, uh, of incidents, incidents, which they couldn't
explain away.
They were just too credible.
The sources were too credible.
They had too many people had seen it.
What was his name?
That is, his name was, uh, Oscar, uh, Wolf, Oscar, Oscar Wolf or Oscar Lane, Oscar Wolf.
Yes.
Oscar Wolf.
Uh-huh.
That's who he was.
Uh, and, uh, and, uh, he, he starts telling me about it all, uh, and goes into detail about
it.
Uh, now it's one of these bizarre things because I, my, my, my office people said, you've got
to bring a camera, you've got to bring a camera to get this guy if he's going to give
you a death.
Did you record him?
Yeah.
I, I, I brought the little thing.
I set it all up on the little table and, and so I had the whole, the whole thing recorded,
uh, and it got corrupted somehow.
But I think Jeremy Corbell might've recorded an interview with this guy separately.
Later.
Yeah.
He did.
And he also, he also talked with Richard Dolan.
Okay.
So we have him on record.
That's right.
Oscar Wolf.
And, well, uh, they, but the thing is they didn't press into them as far as I know about
this incident.
Oh, really?
And he, and he told me about the fact that he, cause I kept, they missed the, they buried
the lead.
Well, yeah.
Cause I was interrogating the shit out of him, you know, and I was just pressing down on him
because I figured he was going to get his help.
He's on a dead bed.
So, so, so, so, yeah, don't, don't mess with me.
So shape up, you know, I could have said, you know, if you want any absolution, you
know, but I didn't do that part.
So, so, so, so.
Man, the Jesuits are thugs.
I didn't realize that.
That's being too tough.
You know, and so, so, so the, the bottom line, he tells me that, that, uh, that the reason
that he has developed this kind of special relationship with the commander of this unit
that is assigned specifically to investigate the, the, uh, the, the 700 other cases, right?
Is because he and the commander were both part of this really fundamentalist Christian sect
called the worldwide church of God.
I mean, and apparently really hardcore fundamentalist crowd.
And, and, uh, and so that he, he stayed there for years and when they were working on it, people
would come and go in the staff and do field investigations and all that, but he kept staying
there and keeping records.
And then his commander comes in and said that he is going to be going to area 51 and, uh,
wanted, wanted Oscar to come with him.
And so he did, he went with him, but it turns out it was not just area 51.
It was S4.
So they actually went all the way to S4, uh, and went down in the big elevators and went
in and he said he saw like three or four.
By the way, S4 isn't supposed to officially exist.
So it's important.
The only versions where it exists, you have Bob Lazar, you have a guy named Dan Barish,
and you have this story.
That's right.
And I think we're going to get some more corroboration soon that S4 does in fact exist.
I'm sure.
And then, and then all of a sudden you start asking questions about these specific stories
and it starts to blow your mind.
Okay.
So you're going down.
So, so he goes down and he says, and he sees like, there's three or four, uh, UFOs
that are just, they, they've got little, like, uh, little garages, like these, these little
chambers where they are.
So it's the same story as Bob Lazar.
And they're just, they're just hovering in there.
They're just, he said they were just, they're just hovering all by themselves inside these
little garages, like that were underground.
And he said, he saw them, uh, and then they went in and his, his commander was going to
be quote, interviewing a live ET guy.
Right.
So he goes with him, uh, and they come into this other area where there were military
guys there.
He said, but there was this room, like a standalone room with these big two way mirrors that,
that you could see through, uh, from the outside.
And he said, he saw the ET guy, but he was like, you know, five and a half feet tall.
No, it wasn't a little tiny shirt guy.
It was a kind of a kind of life size guy, big, big head, big eyes.
And he was in this kind of jumpsuit that they'd provided for him.
Uh, and he was, he was very cooperative that he wasn't being interrogated.
Was he speaking English or telepathic?
No, no, he was, it was all telepathic.
It was all telepathic.
So they just, he just saw them sitting across from each other.
And he could see, he could see his commander walk in, but he wouldn't go.
Cause he said, he said, I thought it was demonic.
That's what he said.
He said, I thought it was demonic and I didn't want to go near him.
Uh, and so he stayed outside and, but he could see his, his commander having this kind of
telepathic communication going on with him.
And his commander was a fundamentalist Christian.
Yeah.
And so, and so how, what was the communication like?
That, that he didn't say.
He just said that it was telepathic.
He could tell that they were having this telepathic, well, he, and he probably afterwards got it
confirmed by his, his commander that it was all telepathic.
They weren't talking.
He could just see that they were having this kind of communication.
Did he seem honest to you?
Oh yes.
So you think that happened?
Yeah.
I do think that happened.
I think that happened, you know?
And, uh.
So you think we have alien beings at S4?
Well, no, no.
All I, all I know is I think that there was one there at that time.
At that time.
And that he saw him, uh, and that he, he stayed outside and the, the military guys that were
there showed him these, these cards.
They had, he said they had these index cards that, uh, and it, it didn't say whether they
were typed up or printed, but they had the questions and answers that were there of things
they'd ask him.
Right.
And so they had a little record of interviews that had been conducted with him.
And then one of them, he said that, uh, they asked him, you know, so where are you guys
from?
What are you, what are you doing here?
And he said that, you know, he was part of a group, uh, of people, beings from different
star systems in our galaxy.
He said, and that their job was to go around monitoring where life had started.
And in different planets inside the galaxy, uh, and that that was what they did, uh, and
that's what they were doing here.
And he said, uh, they asked him, well, who's, who tasked you to do that?
You know, who's in charge of that?
And he said, well, it's what you people would refer to as God, but it's very different than
you think.
And how is it different?
He didn't say, he didn't say, and he said, but I didn't believe him, he said, because
I thought he was demonic.
And so I never told anybody, I never told anybody about this.
Have you ever heard the term Collins elite?
Yes.
Do you think that the, this kind of fundamentalist Christian commander was involved in the Collins
elite?
No, it didn't, didn't seem to be.
This was kind of an individual thing with him and this guy.
Cause they also thought that the, the alien stuff was kind of demonic.
Oh yeah.
No, no, it's that there's, there's a whole, a whole stream of that in the fundamentalist
world.
You know, I've got, you know, that, uh, Sarah's, uh, sister-in-law is a big fundamentalist,
you know, and she will, she thinks the whole thing is demonic.
It's a, it's a meme.
Have you ever interviewed, I mean, I'm sure part of it is, and part of it might be angelic
and, you know, it's like probably.
I think that it's because people don't understand that whole part.
People don't understand angelic.
It's probably good and bad is probably way too simplistic of a frame for whatever they're
operating on.
And I'm sure they're good ones that incidentally do violence to you because of their kind of,
you know, field or whatever.
Once you, you know, it's like St. Francis of Assisi has a vision of this, you know, um,
kind of, you know, winged angel being, it was a flaming torch in the original translation,
but as a seraphim and it does violence to him, but it's like, it's, that becomes part
of his conversion towards God and it ends up sort of killing him.
But I think the sort of good, bad, you know, dichotomy is probably a earthly one.
Yeah.
Well, there's, there's, I mean, an awful lot of, uh, anthropomorphic projection, you know,
onto these folks because they, because they're so much like us.
I mean, you know, that, that's a real challenge.
Have you ever met an alien?
No.
Would you want to?
Sure.
Really?
Yeah.
I'd like to sit down and chat with them and actually figure out, you know, how to kind
of represent us, you know, in, in a full way about good and bad stuff that we do, all of
us, you know, but try to figure out what the criteria are for trying to establish a relationship
of trust with them and how we could trust them.
What can they do to kind of assuage the concerns that people have about them in their kind of
secretive ways, you know?
Have you ever seen, so you've seen picture of a UFO, which was in the blue book files
and a skiff in DC and you even, um, traced.
It wasn't a skiff though.
Oh, it wasn't a skiff.
Okay.
No, it was just, it was just this room that they had downstairs in the Madison.
And you traced the, uh, symbols that were along the edge of the craft.
I did that.
Um, have you ever seen anomalous material?
No, I've seen photographs of the, of the thing that Hal had.
I've seen photographs.
What, what thing that Hal had?
That piece of metal that's got like 17 different layers of, of different elements.
Is that magnesium bismuth?
Yes.
Yeah.
I've just seen the photographs.
Layers thinner than a micron or whatever.
Yeah.
That's right.
That's the one.
I've seen photographs.
What do you think of, you know, Hal Puthoff's this sort of godfather architect of the space.
He's just, uh, you know, seems to have his hand in everything.
Um, what, what do you think of Hal and his role and kind of UFOlogy?
I think, I think Hal is, uh, is more knowledgeable, uh, in depth about this whole thing than most
any of the people that you would meet, you know, can, and know, uh, you know, in the, that, uh...
Do you think he says everything he knows?
No.
Oh, no, no.
He doesn't even pretend to.
Uh-huh.
No, he doesn't even pretend to say everything he knows.
Do you think he's worked on a craft or seen a craft?
Oh, I'm sure he has.
You're sure he has?
Oh, no, no, I'm, I'm completely sure he has.
Really?
Yeah.
Do you think he knows how they fly?
No, he has a better idea of how they fly than most anybody.
You know, there may be some technicians that, that know more about some details.
Do you think he understands a lot about sort of, um, I don't know, uh, mental networks
and that sort of thing?
Do you think he's sort of clued into that?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I mean, that's his major focus.
From Stargate?
Yeah.
What's the connection between remote viewing and, you know, so you had these guys in the
remote viewing program like Stargate, you know, which was formed by the CIA and later
running out of the DIA, 1972.
He, um, you know, some of these guys like Ingo Swann would like remote view alien bases on
the moon and things like that.
I talked to Ingo about it.
Did you?
Yeah.
I spent like a whole day with Ingo in an apartment in New York.
What did Ingo say about the alien bases?
It was interesting that, that, that my, my access to him came through the Church of Scientology
thing.
You know, that that's a big deal.
Yeah.
Uh, that Church of Scientology, that helped put off at Church of Scientology and, and,
uh, uh, Targ, Russell Targ was Church of Scientology.
All kinds of the guys were.
And to catch people up, you kind of won L.
Ron Hubbard's favor by, uh, you know, there was a case against them around, uh, you know,
special exemption, you know, as a, as a religious organization.
And, uh, there were, you know, I think they were, they were being bugged for a little bit
and they were sort of trying to bug the federal government.
They were trying to track the federal government.
They had, they had the, they had the door of their headquarters chainsawed off.
Right.
By the, by the IRS.
And then you, you were sort of helping them out and then you made it, you were about to
like sign on formally as their counsel.
And then you asked them for their.
No, no, that's wouldn't be the way to look.
I was asked to be their counsel.
You were asked to be their counsel.
And I said, look, as a condition precedent to even begin to talk with Ron Hubbard, because
he wanted to meet with me, uh, and try to persuade me to become the lawyer for him and
his wife specifically.
Not necessarily for the church, but for him and his wife.
Uh, and that, uh, the, the head guardian from the, from North America came to my office
at the Jesuit headquarters and said that, uh, that, uh, Mr. Hubbard would like to talk with
you about becoming the lawyer for him and his wife, Susan.
And I said, well, I said, look, uh, as a condition precedent to even being willing to meet with
him, to talk with him, I'd have to be given permission to have access to whatever records or
information there is anywhere in the world about the church.
Uh, and I said, that's, I assume that's a total non-starter, right?
And they give you their records.
Within a week, they came back and said, it's a deal.
No way.
What do you want to see?
And so I.
So you could query anybody's e-meter results?
Anything.
I could get anything I wanted.
And so, uh, they flew me down to, uh, to, uh, Florida, uh, and the big blue cube they've
got down there, this big, huge blue building.
Uh, and, uh, so I go in and there's the head of the guardian's office, U.S.
Guardian's office, and the international head of the guardians, you know, out of the
U.K., uh, and they say, uh, said, so what do you want to see?
And I said, uh, well, first, what I want to see is the file you've got on me.
Uh, and the American guy said, no, why, no, we've got, no, I don't, no.
You know, and I said, excuse me, I said, what do you think, I fell off some melon wagon somewhere?
I said, you know, you're going to have me to be L. Ron Hubbard's attorney, and you don't
have any file on me at all?
And the international guy says, go get him the file.
You know, so they bring me the file.
I'm going through it.
How deep was it?
How much stuff did they have?
Well, they had, they had, you know, pictures, pictures of me, what, you know, I was, I was
a Jesuit candidate.
I was at the headquarters.
You know, they would follow me around.
They showed me at different restaurants, you know, and, and meeting with people, you know, Mark Lane
and some of the other guys, you know, they, so Mark Lane, he was like, uh, Kennedy assassination.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Rush to judgment.
He was the author of that, you know?
So, you know, they had all these kinds of things.
And so I said, okay, good.
I just wanted to make sure that it was, that it was accurate, you know?
And then, so the international guy says to me, so, okay, so what else do you want to see?
I said, I want to see the three most sensitive files in the entire world, according to you
as the head of the guardian's office, you know?
And he just went, oh, fuck.
He said, I said, so.
So, so either you get him or not, you know?
So he gets up and he's gone and Revellins is around, comes back and he ends up laying
one of the files in front of me.
And I started looking at it and it was all reports by Ingo Swann.
Ingo Swann was filing reports with the head guardian office in the UK about the entire internal
operations of the Office of Naval Intelligence remote viewing program that they were doing.
He was just giving him all the information.
So he was a spy or something?
Yeah.
He was a spy for the Church of Scientology.
For the Church of Scientology?
Over and against the Office of Naval Intelligence.
Why would he do that?
Because he was a high-level clearer.
That was his loyalty group.
His fundamental loyalty.
He was loyal to them prior to...
That's right.
Over and above the country.
Because I always thought Puthoff was looking into that stuff because he was an NSA guy before
he was a Scientology guy.
So I thought Puthoff was just tasked to looking into this very para-governmental intelligence
organization that is Scientology that's seen as a threat.
And so you don't get put off in there.
No.
I mean, the Church of Scientology, you're not aware of it, that their highest principle
in the Church of Scientology is all to do with UFOs.
Really?
And so, yeah, they believe that there's a major confrontation going on between the human-like
people from the Pleiades over and against the reptilians from Zeta Reticuli.
And that there's a major confrontation going on over which of them is going to actually assert
major relations with our planet.
Do you agree with that worldview?
No.
I don't.
But Swan was, like, fully in with the Scientologists and was giving them information on the Office
of Naval Intelligence?
All of it.
And so you're also saying that there's a remote viewing program that was deeper than Stargate?
Because that wasn't Office of Naval Intelligence.
That was DIA after CIA.
No.
This was a program.
And Pat Price, I'll give you some idea how deep this goes.
Pat Price, you know, they had the file.
Ingo Swan had the file that Pat Price had gotten so good at remote viewing that they assigned
him a task of, they gave him the exact longitude and latitude down to the minute and second
of a location, and he was assigned an artist so that he didn't have to do these hen scratches
trying to show it.
But he was, and he was saying, you know, I, so what's there?
So there's this major building here, and there's a big, big fence up with razor wire on the top
of it and everything.
And his facilitator was Russell Tark.
And so Russell was saying, okay, now can, can you get inside the fence?
Can you see anything inside the fence?
And he goes, yeah, okay, all right, yeah, I can, I can see inside the fence.
There's just a snowman's land there.
Can you get to the front door of this place?
And he said, all right.
He said, okay, all right, I got it.
Yeah, okay, I'm in front of the front door.
He said, can you go inside the building?
He said, let me see here.
Okay, yeah, yeah, I can see, I can see inside the building here.
He said, so what do you see?
He says there's this big, long hallway, and there's some doors on both sides.
And Russell said, now go, go down to the third door on the left.
And he said, okay.
He said, can you go into the room?
Yeah, I can go into the room.
So what do you see?
Well, there's a big desk there and some chairs and stuff.
There's a big file cabinet over in the right corner over here.
Go over to the file cabinet.
He goes over to the file cabinet.
He said, second drawer, first file, read it to him.
And he did.
What was it?
Well, that's not the point.
The point is that he did it.
And he can do it.
It turns out it's an American facility.
It's a top CIA security facility.
Yeah, but that's insane then.
So anybody with remote viewing skills can get the nuclear codes?
Not anybody, but Pat Price could.
The best.
So that's Pat Price, right?
And in the same file, it points out that Pat Price had actually evolved to the point where they could take a full photograph of a boomer class Russian submarine, nuclear submarine, and show it to him and say, where is it right now?
And he would give him right down to the exact longitude and latitude, down to the minute and second of exactly where that is.
And he visualized the whole thing and told him exactly where it was.
But there was a huge UFO right over the top of the water where that thing was.
And it was tracking it and monitoring it.
And he had it in the file.
You know, I'm going, whoa.
I said, this is pretty wild.
And then I said, okay, so what else have you got?
You know, he says, well, here.
And I said, show me the second file.
And he showed me the second file.
And it was, again, from Ingo Swann.
It was a deep inside report from Ingo Swann that they had taken Pat Price in the program up to southern Canada, south central Canada, just north of the state of Michigan.
And he was, they brought him to this little facility.
It was like this little domed, little building.
And it had these big, huge dishes on top, these communication dishes on top.
And they brought him in and they set him down and they put this helmet on him.
And they had him think a particular message.
And they turned all the big antenna down to the northern peninsula of Michigan, that little section that's in there, and had him be telepathically projecting, you know, when it comes time for you to file your national, your U.S. income tax forms next year, file them in this little post office box down this little town down in West Virginia.
And 85% of the people did it next year.
No way.
Absolutely way.
That's insane.
You keep saying that.
So you're saying that Scientology had some sort of mass mind control technique.
That wasn't the Church of Scientology.
What was it?
This was the program.
That was the program, the Office of Naval Intelligence.
But that's like, the implications of that are crazy.
No, they're profound.
Yeah.
And so then I, from then.
Seeing Matt Ingo Swann.
Yeah.
I didn't say no to them then.
But as soon as I saw the file on the fair game, I knew I wasn't going to do it.
But I had the opportunity to go see Ingo.
So I contacted Ingo and said, you know, I'm being asked to be the lawyer for Hubbard.
And, you know, I want to chat with you.
So I went to see him at his apartment in New York.
And we go all the way upstairs up onto the roof of his apartment that he's got there.
And then I started talking to him.
And I didn't want to freak him out over the fact that he was clearly violating his security clearance, you know, by providing these reports to the Church of Scientology.
So he was using his remote viewing from Stargate in the reports that he was giving to the Church of Scientology.
Yeah.
He was filing not only about his work, but Pat Price's work.
You know, the other stuff, all the things that he was doing, he was reporting to the Guardians.
So he was basically like, he was a back-channel spy to the Church of Scientology on behalf of them vis-a-vis the federal government of the U.S.
It was clearly his major loyalty, allegiance, was to them.
Did you ask him about, because he wrote a book called Penetration about seeing bases, alien bases on the moon.
Yeah, I hadn't seen that.
You hadn't seen that?
Did you get into the alien thing at all with him?
Oh, yeah, because he, in one of his reports, had a report in there about, it was Hal Puthoff, no, it wasn't Hal, it was Targ.
Russell Targ had been facilitating a remote viewing by Pat Price when they stepped it up from him.
Being able to remote view things in real time, to be able to be shown a photograph of a Russian boomer submarine, and then he could locate it.
He could figure out exactly where it was down to the minute and second of longitude and latitude, I mean, which was the big deal.
You know, I mean, that's the big deal.
Yeah.
And when they found it, when they found it and verified that it was there through the remote viewing, others to find it, there was a UFO hovering right over the top of where the Russian boomer submarine was going into the water.
And it was monitoring it.
And when I saw it, I just went, whoa.
Did you see a photo?
No.
Okay.
No, they just told me about it.
It was a written report that it was there, and it was just, it was following right along where the Russian boomer submarine was going, you know.
And that was the only piece that was in there, except when I started interrogating people, you know, because I wanted to get as much advantage as I could of the opportunity that I had here to get information.
So I got to meet the guy who was legal counsel for the church to ask him to explain to me, you know, what the net net of all this was, you know, what were they up to here?
And what it is is that they considered themselves entitled to being considered a sovereign entity because the Catholic Church was.
So the Catholic Church has this kind of status of being a sovereign entity in a nation, basically, because they have Vatican State, right?
So they insisted that as a matter of First Amendment equal protection, that they were entitled to take unto themselves the same status.
And so that's what caused them to be engaged in this fair game program.
They believed that they had a right to engage in, like, wet operations, you know, like the United States does and Russia does and all of that, which they asserted, you know, the Vatican does, they said.
Do you think, do you think that the Vatican and that specifically maybe the Knights of Malta had anything to do with the UFO kind of reverse engineering or transport or oversight?
I think that an element of the Knights of Malta have something to do with everything.
And why do you think that?
Because of the people that there were in this, this Monte Carlo group.
There's a thing called the Monte Carlo group that is at the top, top of the entire Knights of Malta structure.
And I discovered that there were non-Catholics in it, which didn't make any sense to me at all.
Because the Knights of Malta is a Catholic men's club-like thing.
But there's this high executive council that turned out that Henry Kissinger was on it and George Bush Sr. was on it, who's Episcopal.
That's amazing.
But if I were to play devil's advocate, I could have said Council of Foreign Relations, Bilderberg, you know, like I could name five other organizations that those two guys were a part of.
Any other reasons to believe they had something to do with the UFO thing specifically?
No, just not specifically.
What I'm saying is that anybody who is at that level dealing with international things would have to be involved in this.
There's no way that you're not going to be involved in this.
Because, I mean, you could be involved in all the other stuff and it wouldn't make any difference ultimately.
You know, I mean, this whole thing could, to use the phrase, Trump, you know, everything.
What is the, is there kind of a mandate or, you know, constitution for the Knights of Malta?
I mean, the only references I really have are, you know, Humphrey Bogart, the Maltese Falcon.
They were supposed to be the guardians of this Maltese Falcon.
And I believe they're also the heirs to the Hospitaliers.
You know, there was the kind of Templars back in the day.
Yeah, yeah.
Sort of, you know, pre-13th century when they were, they were disbanded, I guess, 14th century.
And then they were kind of the guardians of these pilgrims that would go to the Temple Mount in, you know, Jerusalem.
And then the medic side of that was the Hospitaliers.
And so that sort of, there's some lineage between that and, you know, Knights of Malta.
But otherwise, I don't really understand, you know, what they do.
I know they have sovereign status and they can kind of.
They do.
They're a military, they're a military order.
And they're a sovereign, they're a sovereign military order.
And it's, it's, it's very clear that, you know, the guys like Reinhard Galen was in the Knights of Malta.
He was a former Nazi.
Yeah.
Reinhard Galen is the guy that was the head of the anti-Soviet and anti-Eastern bloc intelligence for the Third Reich.
And also became the director of intelligence for West Germany at the end of World War II, you know, at the behest of our OSS.
We got him put in there, you know, and Shackley worked directly with him, you know.
Yeah.
And, and, and also Otto Skorzeny.
Another former Nazi.
Yeah.
Otto Skorzeny, who ran the rat line, you know, of smuggling them all out of there.
And they were Knights of Malta passports that were used.
Did you, I mean, you're a Jesuit.
Did you ever use your Jesuit connections to figure out more about the Magenta crash, which was supposedly recovered, you know, according to David Grush.
It was recovered in Lombardy in 1933.
And I believe the Cardinal of Milan was also a Knight of Malta at the time.
And the UFO supposedly made itself to the Vatican, where it was held for a while.
And then I think Pope Pius VI, maybe, then, you know, transferred it over to the U.S.
It's the 11th.
Pope Pius XI, okay.
Transferred it over to the U.S.
So do you know anything about that?
No, no, I didn't, actually.
It's interesting.
Do you believe that's a real case?
I didn't know about it.
Okay.
I didn't know about it until comparatively recently.
Uh, so that one never came across the radar.
Yeah.
So I had, I had been pretty well locked down on.
You gotta hit up your Vatican contacts.
Yeah, right.
Those that are still alive anyway.
Uh.
You know, I mean, they're all dead.
I couldn't believe it.
I mean, virtually everybody that was there in the staff when I was there have all passed away.
Damn.
It's totally bizarre.
Yeah.
Uh, but, uh, but the bottom line is I didn't know about that one at all.
Mm-hmm.
And no one has ever said anything to me about it.
You know, and when I, when I talked to Johann Itx, who was the head of the Vatican archives,
Mm-hmm.
you know, he's just always just smiled.
I mean, and, and.
Has he given you a smile, a smile of quiet knowing?
Oh, yeah.
No, he knows because, because I sent the letters to them from Jesuit headquarters.
Okay.
To ask for access for President Carter.
So he doesn't give you a befuddled laughing smile or something?
No, no, no.
Okay.
No, it'd be perfectly easy for them to say, look, there's nothing to this.
You're crazy.
Okay.
No, but no, he knows, he knows that I know.
Interesting.
That stuff is there.
And he just isn't going to let me have it.
So you, you were the, um, lawyer for John Mack.
Yeah.
Who's the head of the Harvard Psychiatry Department and childhood friend of Bud Hopkins.
Towards the end of his career, he started to take very seriously these, uh, uh,
experiencers.
People would experience abductions or alien contact and often it would come out in hypnotic
regression or through holotropic breath work, which was one of his favorite kind of modalities.
That was, that was.
And, um, you have his final manuscript.
I do.
And he writes about, I heard at the end of his life, he started to get into reptilians and was like interested in reptilians specifically.
I don't know.
Is there anything interesting in that final manuscript that, um, sort of shows his overall worldview at the end of this, you know, decade plus long inquiry into the UFO alien question?
Yeah, he, he, he really views the entire UFO ET issue as a, as a, as a window opening onto the functioning of worldviews, you know, in, in, in our human family to really explain an awful, I had something to do with that because that's what I was talking to him about.
He and I, just before he got killed, we were planning on trying to set up a thing called.
When you say he got killed, was that, do you think it was intentionally or accidentally?
No, it was accidentally.
It was accidentally, yeah, yeah, no.
In Europe.
Yeah, I was on that within hours after it happened.
So, you know, dug it out and knew who the guy was.
The guy's still in prison that, that ran him down.
He was just drunk and, uh, you know, yeah.
And, uh, so, so the, uh, that John and I were talking about the fact that, that this was a, uh, actually the name of his manuscript.
Is When World Views Collide.
And, you know, all the Velikovsky, uh, all of that, you know, from When Worlds Collide.
So that's what he did.
It's When World Views Collide.
Yeah.
Uh, in the.
What was the Velikovsky, what was the When Worlds Collide, what was that about?
When Worlds Collide is an old, uh, classic, uh, piece that Velikovsky wrote.
It's a, uh, the theory that the asteroid belt, uh, is a, another planet that was here in our, in our solar system.
Uh, and the, it, uh, collided with the moon or something.
I, I just remember it.
And, and it believes that it blew up.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
It's like the Kyber belt or something.
Yeah.
The whole, the whole asteroid belt is really that planet all blown up, uh, into, into shrapnel, basically, all through the asteroid belt.
And so Mack was saying when World Views Collide, like the kind of Western materialist reductionist worldview and the animistic worldview or something, one that encapsulated life beyond humans.
If you want to shatter the Western mental structures, the, the Western mind, so to speak, which is now permeating the whole Earth in its materialist dualistic philosophy,
the way you do it is you take something that's supposed to be in the spirit world, because even in the West, we can make allowance for the spirit world,
and we can study it through mythology, through religion, through imagination, through poetry.
But the one unforgivable sin to the Western mind is when something that should be in the spirit world transgresses and shows up in the physical world.
That traffic is the cardinal sin for the Western mind.
So it has great power to shatter the belief structure of the Western mind when that occurs.
And that's precisely what's occurring in this subduction phenomenon.
And, and so he started really starting to perceive things because I, I was some assistance in that because I, I had, you know, done the master's degree work and then started the PhD work at Harvard, uh, on that very issue, uh, trying to under, trying to understand things.
When you get a really complex issue, what you want to do is figure out what the kind of operational pieces of it are.
So you can get them spread out in front of just like a plane wreck, you know, you want to kind of reassemble the pieces that you can recover and take a look at it.
And what this does is it tends to shake down into this octave of human worldviews, you know, that the, that, uh, only one aspect of which is their political manifestation.
You know, that, that, uh, runs from, from right to left, you know, from the authoritarian to the reactionary, to the conservative, to the moderate, to the liberal, to the progressive, to the utopianist.
You know, that there's, there's a, there are integrated worldviews that are internally self-referentially consistent, you know, and that they're all predicated upon the answers that you provide to these four pillar questions about the origins of the universe, the kind of end product, the teleological outcome of the universe is projected.
You know, what the analogical relationship between consciousness and the material manifestation, uh, of reality is the big one, you know, and the epistemological question is, you know, that what means do we have at our disposal as human beings by means of which you can possibly answer questions like that?
You know, are we limited to our five senses or do we have other faculties?
Do we have other kind of charisms that we have access to that have been hidden or suppressed?
You know, those are, those are, those are the fundamental questions.
Uh, those are the cosmic questions.
And since we don't have the definitive answer to any of those yet, uh, the way, as long, as long as you have a internally and self-referentially consistent answer to all four of those questions, you have a worldview.
It's a systematic worldview.
And if you can discern what the common principle is that makes all of them similar to each other, the answers are consistent with each other.
You apply that principle to any question that you confront, uh, in making your judgments.
Uh, and then you have a philosophy.
That's, that's what a philosophy is, is a consistent application of a single principle that is generic to all four of these fundamental questions.
If you can do that, uh, in that that's what a philosophy is.
And then you have a subcomponent of that, your political philosophy.
And then you have a mode of spiritual expression, which is generic to that.
That's where you get these major world religions that are generic to a particular worldview.
You know, and so I would, I was starting to explain all that to him that, that I discovered, you know, when I actually went back to talk to John Rawls, who's the head of the department of philosophy at Harvard, you know, when I was running into these conflicts that I was having with the different lawyers and the firms where I was, you know, they all seem to be functioning on some different ways.
So what did, what did, what did Mac think, you know, when, what would happen when worldviews collided and when, uh.
He, he, he, he believes, he believes that, that it's absolutely clear that there's, that the initial response that we have as human beings, as homo sapien to an encounter with an extraterrestrial being, uh, is that it, it, uh, kind of shatters, uh, the, the kind of, uh, walls, uh, of the room, uh, the mansion of our worldview.
You know, uh, that all of a sudden the things are so completely different than anything you'd ever assumed before that your world can fall apart, uh, as it were.
Uh, and so people, and people have this kind of cellular, uh, response, uh, when you find yourself actually confronted with an extraterrestrial being that your whole cellular system reacts, you know, in a kind of a fight or flight way, uh, that your subconscious doesn't have any control over.
It's just, you just freak out, you know, and, and so what we, so we started deciding that what we wanted to do is help train people, uh, that had consistent repeated encounters, you know, because we found that to be a fairly common theme that if you've been abducted once, you've been usually abducted more than once.
Right. And so that if it's going to happen again, to try to train a person through holotropic breathing, to kind of just calm themselves down and to get centered, to try to get mastery over that kind of cellular response that your body has.
You know, because all of us that are alive right now are the end of the chain of survivors.
I mean, that's, what's distinguished us, you know, that, that, that our, our lineage have all survived and gotten us through to where we are now.
That's fascinating though. He's talking about almost like a manual for being physiologically ready for contact.
That's right. Absolutely right. To try to overcome the cellular imprint that we have in us to react like that.
Allergic reaction. Yeah. And it is like, if you're, you know, like the three body problem, if you're in the dark forest and you are afraid of making contact, it's actually adaptive to sort of hide yourself.
You would want to know that the other side is sort of receptive and stable and going to be okay.
Yes. Yes. You know, when you, when you, uh, appear.
Oh, that's right.
Cause if you, uh, you know, cause this.
Oh, they get, they get in trouble. I mean, you know, Karen, one of the, they used to throw things at them. I mean, she'd throw lamps at them.
She was one of Mac's patients.
She was one of the ladies.
That's a little crazy. Yeah.
And she was one of the first people who really got the, the holotropic breathing training.
So are you going to release this book or what, what do you, what do you, what are you planning on doing this?
I haven't, I haven't ever, I, he just gave it to me cause he was getting set to go to England to do this lecture on T.E. Lawrence and wanted me to go through it because it covers a lot of the encounter we had with the, the faculty committee.
Yeah.
It's kind of his, his, uh, account of what, what happened.
He was such an interesting guy.
Well, he won a Pulitzer prize for, uh, his book called The Prince of Disorder, which is about.
The Prince of Our Disorder.
Prince of Our Disorder, uh, by, uh, about T.E. Lawrence.
He was Lawrence of Arabia.
Yeah.
It was a psychobiography.
Right.
Of, of Lawrence.
Who I believe was, he was gay and he had been sort of sexually assaulted multiple times and he had this sort of crazy and then he led this uprising, you know, and, uh.
He's a pretty fascinating character.
Fascinating, fascinating character.
And Mack himself was such a fascinating character.
Yeah.
I feel like his search for, uh, the UFO and alien question was kind of motivated by some autobiographical stuff with his mother, who I think, did she die during childbirth or when he was very young?
No, no, no, no.
In fact, his mother played this really kind of major role in that.
Okay.
Because he, when, when he first got dragged up, oh, when he first started encountering, uh, these high level military officials that were ordered to get a psychiatric exam to try to deter them from really pressing any further on this, it was the first thing that would happen.
They'd be ordered to get a psychiatric exam.
Because they'd seen an alien or something?
Yeah, because they wanted to file a report.
Uh-huh.
They wanted to file a report about, you know, a, a, a UFO encounter.
And they were always told that, you know, like, you don't want to do this.
This is not good for your career.
Did John Mack, was he kind of abreast of any of the UFO stuff from his Navy experience or, or no, it came later?
No, nothing.
No.
He was, he was a complete agnostic.
Yeah.
You know, to start with.
And then he got sent these, like, like, uh, Arnie Arnoldson, who was the, the, uh, the actual commander of the, the, the, the, uh, the Montana, uh, base, you know, the Minuteman base.
Malmstrom.
Malmstrom, Malmstrom, uh, that, uh, that he was the actual commander that filed the report with NORAD about it all.
Uh, and then they said, are you, are you trying to file a UFO report?
Is that what you're doing?
And he said, yes.
He said it was the most important moment of his life.
He just said, yes, I am.
He says, I'm not letting this one go.
You know, because they shut off all of us.
They shut off 10 silas.
10 independent, independently wired nukes.
Yeah.
Minutemen.
And so he was adamant that he was going to get that filed.
And the, and so, you know, that he and a number of other high ranking military people had been sent to John Mack at Harvard as the head of the Department of Clinical Psychiatry to do the psychiatric workup on these guys.
And after a half a dozen of these folks, he started saying, wait a second, this doesn't make any sense at all.
He said, you know, these are high ranking military people.
There's lawyers and doctors.
There's all kinds of people that are coming to report these things.
It doesn't make any sense.
And so he started this actually kind of like a little investigation.
And he would train them to do the holotropic breathing and get them calmed down and centered, right?
And then he was asking them questions.
Okay, now you're inside the craft.
Look around and tell me what you're seeing.
And he was getting them to give little reports on these totally esoteric things, you know, that nobody would really make up, you know, and then he would see if other people saw similar stuff, you know, and he was verifying.
And so he started, got to the point where he said, wait a second, there's something really happening here with these people.
And so he called his mother.
So she didn't die in childbirth.
So he called her and she said, oh, you ought to check with Bud, the Hopkins kid, you know, that he's into this stuff, you know, even though he's a sculptor and artist and all that kind of stuff.
But, you know, that our families are close and you ought to, he knows a lot about this.
And so that's how it happened is that he ended up talking to Bud Hopkins and Hopkins said, oh, look, let me show you, you know.
And he started giving him a lot more people.
And so by the time he contacted me, you know, he'd interviewed like a hundred people.
Wow.
You know, who'd had these experiences.
And so he ended up calling me.
And when he got confronted by this faculty committee and they called me and asked me if I would legally represent him.
And so I went there and confronted the faculty committee, you know, but very fortunately went with John to meet with Lawrence Rockefeller.
And Lawrence Rockefeller told us all about, you know, his best friend seeing a UFO.
That's why he was convinced it was true.
Yeah.
Lawrence Rockefeller was a patron for a lot of early UFO research.
He funded John Mack.
Yep.
He funded Stephen Greer.
I think Whitley Stryber has told me a story about meeting with Lawrence Rockefeller in Wyoming and the Tetons at his ranch or whatever.
Why do you think Lawrence Rockefeller was so interested in the subject?
So you mentioned that his friend had an experience.
That's interesting.
Whitley.
Is the Prince of Lichtenstein.
Hans Adams.
Whoever it was.
That's all it was.
He's apparently extremely interested in UFOs.
It was his best friend.
I think he thinks that Jesus is going to come down on a saucer or something.
It's like some eschatological worldview.
I don't.
I didn't know.
He just told us.
He gathered.
The guy named John Brandenburg, who I interviewed, said that Prince Hans Adams had gathered all of the Roswell witnesses.
I think in the 70s or something, or the 80s.
I don't know.
You know, and he wanted to speak to all of them and kind of, you know, understand what had happened.
Oh, yeah.
So he was very interested in this.
Well, that, and Lawrence told us that, you know, because he said that's why he was so convinced that it was true.
That his friend, who was the Prince of Lichtenstein, had seen one, and that had actually walked right up onto one.
Oh, that's so fascinating.
That was up in the mountains.
Very similar to an experience of one of the guys that I knew.
You know, the son of Bill Todman.
You know, Mark Goodson and Bill Todman, Mark Goodson and Bill Todman were the guys that used to produce I Love Lucy and the $64,000 question and that tune.
All those kind of quizzy shows kind of things back in the 50s.
It made millions, you know.
And I was out at the, we were, Mace Neufeld and Bob Ramey had contacted me.
The guys that do all the Tom Clancy movies.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
And they wanted to do the Iran-Contra movie.
And so they contacted me to talk with him down in L.A.
And I was down in the office with Bob Ramey, who was the president of the Academy of Virus and Science.
He was the head of the Oscars thing, you know.
And so we were talking with him and his executive, his exec, his name, I forgot his name.
But anyway, he contacts me and said, look, there's a friend of mine that wants to talk to you.
You know, would you, he told me not to say who he is, but would you trust me to take you there to him?
So I said, okay, we'll do that.
And so we went out and, what was the guy's name?
Anyway, we go out, get into this big red Cadillac convertible, and we drive off into Warner Brothers.
And we go over to the Warner Brothers lot, and we go in, and it turns out that it's Bill Todman's son of Mark Goodson and Bill Todman.
So here's his son, who's now an exec in Warner Brothers, you know, and he wanted to tell me about an experience that he had had.
And he had, he was in college, and he was on summer break, and he was in the Tetons, you know, outside of Boulder.
And he was climbing in the Tetons, and he came up into this meadow, and there was a UFO just sitting right, hovering right there in the meadow.
And he walked all the way over to it and put his hand on it, and it was like alive.
He said, this is alive, this thing, you know.
And then the whole thing started kind of shuddering and raised up, so he backed away from it, and it just went and shot away.
Whoa.
And he didn't dare tell anybody because he thought that it would ruin his whole reputation and stuff in the industry.
But it turns out that he said that his father, Mark Goodson Sr., or Bill Todman Sr., was best friends with, he's this big famous author that writes these romance novels.
Anyway, that, and he wrote a book about it, partly because Bill Todman Jr. told him that he'd had this experience.
He wrote a thing called The Doomsday, The Doomsday Plan or something.
Who's the author?
Sidney Sheldon, his name was.
And he wrote like 50 of these, you know, books, you know, made millions of dollars.
But he, too, wouldn't dare ever be public about it.
He said he wrote this book called The Doomsday Project, you know, a hypothetical of a saucer that had crashed in a tour bus over in Italy or somewhere.
It happened to be driving by when they were doing a recovery of it.
And so this young lieutenant colonel in the naval intelligence was assigned to find out where all the people were that were on the bus that saw this because they just wanted to explain to them that this was just an experimental thing, you know, so that they wouldn't be distressed.
Well, it turns out they all started getting killed, all these witnesses.
And so Sidney Sheldon wrote this book.
It's complete fiction about it.
And that's the only time he ever said anything about it.
Wow.
And then went right back to his normal life.
And so Bill Todman Jr. wanted me to know about this just to tell me.
And so I've been constantly trying to get him over the years.
I said, why don't you go public?
Yeah.
You got more money than the Pope, you know, now from your inheritance.
Why don't you?
He won't do it.
He still hasn't agreed to do anything.
Well, you've done it for him now.
Yeah.
Because he was perfectly honest about it.
I didn't have any doubt that it was true.
Sure, sure.
Yeah.
Well.
He's a real nice guy.
Yeah.
But he still hasn't done anything.
Danny, it's exciting times right now.
Do you have a prediction for the next three months of disclosure and the UFO truth?
Some of it's easy.
So, you know, the Senate bill is going to get repassed, you know, all 64 pages, exactly
the same.
Is the Senator Rounds?
Rounds is going to sponsor it.
Yeah, from South Dakota.
He's going to sponsor it.
And I'm sure that Schumer will co-sponsor it.
We don't have Marco around anymore.
Rubio.
Rubio to sponsor it.
But, you know, we're hoping to try to get State Department in on this.
Okay.
Because there's this whole State Department dimension that is totally inappropriate for
the State Department not to have been brought in on this.
I mean, you're dealing with an entire foreign power here.
And they're being X'd out.
So, I mean, now that Rubio's over there, you know, he ought to...
Yeah, he's very interested and on record on this whole topic.
Sure he is.
Yeah, one of his aides was probably as deep as it gets on the topic as well.
Yeah.
And it was sort of, you know, I think encountered a bunch of obstacles as a result of his involvement.
Yeah, yeah.
So, the bottom line is they're going to...
The Senate is going to pass the 64-page bill again, probably around the middle of July,
between July 15th, 20th or so, that they'll pass it and they'll send it on over to the House.
You know, we're focusing on Crenshaw.
Crenshaw, you know, Dan Crenshaw is now the new head of the Intelligence Committee in the House.
And that's where we ran into trouble before.
It was primarily Mike Turner, who was the congressman from Ohio, Wright-Patterson District, you know,
was stopping the full bill from being passed.
Is Crenshaw pro-UFO in transparency?
We don't know yet.
We're trying to get...
But he's certainly not anywhere near as bad as Turner was.
You know, Turner had his own personal agenda because of his constituency there, you know, with the base.
But Crenshaw's a guy that's, you know, been critical of things he doesn't agree with.
He's kind of a bit of a maverick.
He's got a lot of integrity, you know, tough guy, you know, he's a SEAL team dude, you know, but...
Eye-patch.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But he's not just kind of a knee-jerk reactionary.
Yeah.
You know, so there's real promise there.
And so we're going to be meeting with him and his staff to try to get him to see if he can give a leadership
in the Intelligence Committee to greenlight the full bill, you know, or at least a lot more of it.
Yeah.
We've gotten 23 pages of the 64 passed with, unfortunately, some amendments even with that part.
Yep.
But the bottom line, what we're after is the appointment of the board.
That we want to get that portion of the 64-page bill done at least this time around is to get the panel appointed, you know.
Now, one of the challenges is that, well, our new Paradigm Institute is one of the groups that's authorized to make recommendations under the statute.
But the president is the one who ultimately decides who he's going to appoint.
The Congress can mandate that he do it.
They can pass the statute and say the president is to appoint this board, you know, but then he could, you know, he could appoint his daughter, you know, to be on it or whatever he wants to do.
And so we're going to try to appoint, we're trying to recommend a group that is sort of almost beyond criticism, you know, the kind of people you'd really want to have there.
And then hope that that will cause Trump to say, okay, good, that's a good group.
Let's have them do it.
So we're hoping this year, or at least this side of the next election, this side of the election in 2026, to get an additional chunk of the 64-page bill passed, specifically the part having to do with the board, okay?
And we're going to have, you know, it's going to be a dynamic going on with this board.
There are going to be a lot of people inside the national security infrastructure that are going to want to have people in there that are going to continue to keep it as sphinctered as possible, you know?
And then there's going to be lots of people putting pressure on us to try to have it be, you know, here, let's have it all, you know, like, like Bursette, you know, let's just order the president to reveal everything right now.
Just dump it on everybody, you know, that's, so there are extremes all around us here.
But what we're trying to do is kind of navigate our way through to really the dynamic that's going to take place, hopefully, between now and November of 2026, you know?
Now, we've got the end of September coming here in 2025 when that's the extension that the National Archives has given to the military services and the intelligence community to gather together all the information they've got, okay?
And that's a standing order that they've got, you know, it's still got that wiggle language in there saying in there to turn it over to the National Archives as soon as possible.
You know, the Senate bill said immediately and they gave them the drop dead date of October 20th, you know, and now they've managed to get the House to water it down, say, as soon as possible.
So, so my sense is their lawyers are going to push back against us.
But, so I'm not, I'm not, I don't give it more than a 51% chance, you know, that we're going to get any kind of meaningful release of that information at the end of September here.
Well, Danny, you're doing the Lord's work and Godspeed.
I'm excited to see what happens in the next few months and years and you're a really important champion for this whole topic.
And I hope that, you know, as much as I love, you know, my own podcast, I hope that you go on like Tucker Carlson or Joe Rogan or something.
And the JFK thing is so important and I know both are so interested in it.
And I, you know, I, I dabble and like, you know, I've, I've learned, you know, from Oliver Stone and, you know, read, you know, Mark Lane and, and Jim Mars and all these guys.
And like, I think you're the best living reteller of the entire story in a way that is a coherent narrative with all of the players, but you also talk about motives.
And so I think it would be great if you, if that was amplified as much as possible.
No, I'd be happy to do it.
You know, I did the, you know, no, no interview is any better than the interviewer.
Uh-huh.
That's true.
Well, I think they're both great, but I mean, they, more importantly than that, they have much bigger platforms than me.
I mean, I have a big platform, but there's their next level.
So biggest in the world.
Yeah.
They both seem to be sincerely interested, you know, and so that's the key, you know, and they're not particularly biased or prejudiced in any way about it.
No.
And, and, and because they, they straddle different kind of worldviews, you know, and reach out to people that are adherents to different worldviews, it's a valuable forum.
Yep.
Those, both of those guys.
Yeah.
Well, Danny, it's an honor, man.
Appreciate you taking the time.
This is always awesome.
Yeah.
Always learn so much.
Thank you.