In modern times, we've gotten used to the images of dystopian societies in fiction,
from a world where babies are no longer being born and children of men,
to the use of human-like artificial intelligence as slaves in a dying world like Blade Runner,
or the very bleak future of The Matrix, where our entire reality is a managed simulation,
keeping us docile, just so that our bodies can be used for energy.
There is an acceptance of the dystopia they survive in.
Like the proverbial frog sat in slowly boiling water.
And one only need to shift their perspective slightly to realize that the world we are currently living in
shares many characteristics of these dystopias.
Or at the very least, there exist some extremely worrying trends.
Trends that might produce a future where food makes you sick,
going to the doctor can bankrupt your entire family,
social interactions have been reduced into likes and upvotes,
and you can barely even tell if the person responding to you is AI.
We live in a society where panels of self-appointed quote-unquote experts
decide what you're allowed to hear, think, and remember.
We're told what's real and what isn't,
and anything that doesn't fit the script is dismissed.
These things are treated not as mysteries to be explored,
but as distractions, a punchline of a joke.
Don't get him too close to me, please.
It seems clear that a system has been put in place to deceive us,
and this does not end at the limits of what you can see in the sky.
This deception reaches down into the fundamental building blocks of your body,
what you eat, why you get sick,
and how that disease and treatment is commodified.
It's not a wildly outlandish claim to suggest that a blanket,
similar to the one that has hidden truths about UFOs,
non-human intelligences, and physics-redefining technologies,
has also been used to disguise the truth about health.
Following this trail leads through many of the same avenues as the hidden history of UFOs.
The alliance between secret government programs and big business,
classified breakthroughs in science and medicine,
and the code that we have been written on,
our DNA, having cosmic significance.
And there is a conspiracy keeping us poisoned,
low energy, lonely, and tired,
too sick to look up and ask what we are doing here.
But is there a way out?
The long road to the dystopian health system we now live in,
and how it has become enforced,
started at the beginning of the 20th century,
when the entire landscape was transformed,
almost single-handedly,
and to serve big business interests.
John D. Rockefeller,
already the richest man on Earth thanks to Standard Oil,
now ExxonMobil,
had a vision to monopolize medicine in the same way that he had oil.
Petrochemicals were on the rise,
and synthetic pharmaceuticals that included products derived from oil
were a way to patent and own treatments in medicine.
It also meant stamping out competition,
most notably of natural medicine and therapies that could eat into profits.
In 1910, with backing from Rockefeller and fellow titan Andrew Carnegie,
the Flexner Report was released.
Written by Abraham Flexner,
it condemned most of America's medical schools,
especially those teaching anything other than drug-based,
symptom-focused treatment.
Over half the medical schools in the United States shut down.
The rest were brought in line,
and the American Medical Association became the enforcer.
Well, you know who set up the FDA and the AMA,
the American Medical Association and the FDA,
set up by Abraham Flexner,
who was working on behalf of the Rockefeller Foundation,
1908, and the Rockefellers.
And so it is fascinating,
because if you also look at, you know,
who formed kind of the quote-unquote,
you know, everybody talks about the deep state or whatever,
but the investment firm that funded the CIA basically formed it.
A lot of the personnel came out of it
was called the Brown Brothers Harriman.
The same people were on the cap table of that.
Same people were on the cap table of the Federal Reserve
in the 1913 Payne-Aldrich Act.
It's the same people.
This was the start of what we now call Big Pharma.
And the people running this new empire
made sure that only one kind of treatment was allowed to exist.
Before this, 20 to 30% of doctors in the United States
were osteopaths, homeopaths,
people that worked with unconventional modalities
to heal the human body.
In certain cases, these modalities were snake oil.
But in others, they worked.
They just couldn't scale.
But it was never about health.
It was about big business.
And it was about control.
A system of sick care, not health care.
A system designed to turn your illness into profit.
I sat down with health care entrepreneur
and founder of Ways2Well, my good friend, Brigham Bueller,
to talk about the corporate capture
of the American health care system.
There's just so much corruption, collusion,
and corporate capture, and it's all real.
It's all real.
Like, I've lived it.
I've been behind the scenes in the medical establishment.
I've literally played a million roles in this space.
And that's the only reason I have the knowledge I have
of, like, where the traps are
and where it is set up to set people up for failure.
What began as a hostile takeover
of natural and holistic medicine
by a small group of ultra-wealthy industrialists
became the blueprint of how health could be defined,
diagnosed, and treated for the next century.
As sickness became valuable
and the dehumanization of medicine
became a disturbing norm,
the Second World War brought with it
a wholesale reframing of the human body itself.
Humans were turned into experiments,
very valuable experiments.
In the lead-up to the Second World War,
once Imperial Japan had invaded mainland China and Korea,
these occupied territories became the field operations
of some of the darkest experiments
conducted on humans in the 20th century.
Unit 731, a secret biological and chemical warfare research
and development program under the Imperial Japanese Army,
was established in Manchuria.
Under the command of General Shiro Ishii,
the unit carried out experiments
that included vivisection on live prisoners
exposed to extreme temperatures,
deliberate infections of plague, cholera, and syphilis,
as well as weapons testing on live human subjects.
One particularly gruesome set of experiments
involved locking prisoners in pressure chambers
and exposing them to extreme barometric changes
to observe how the human body would rupture or collapse.
Every grotesque detail was carefully recorded.
But perhaps the most disturbing part of Unit 731's legacy
is that those responsible were never held to account.
General Shiro Ishii, who oversaw the program,
was noticeably absent from the Tokyo War Crimes Tribunal.
Instead, the biological warfare data gathered by Unit 731
was marked as top secret and quietly handed over to the United States,
which was now occupying Japan.
In exchange for their research,
Ishii and his team were granted full immunity.
None of them were ever tried.
The research was then used to advance
American biological warfare capabilities in the Cold War.
Human suffering had been turned into valuable, usable data.
And that same logic was unfolding elsewhere in post-war Germany.
Morality was entirely absent in this new era of technological advance,
in weapons, space, and in medicine.
A case in point being the fact that Bayer,
now one of the largest pharmaceutical corporations on the planet,
was directly involved in the crimes of the Third Reich.
You know what's fascinating is Bayer had deep ties with the Third Reich.
That's crazy.
Bayer had deep ties with the Nazi regime,
and Bayer was a German pharmaceutical manufacturer.
There's even letters back and forth between Bayer
and some of the generals of the Third Reich,
and it's like, the experiments went great as planned.
Unfortunately, all 150 women that were shipped to us
did not make it through phase one of the trials.
We kindly request another 150 Jewish women.
That's so crazy.
They were literally testing all of their future compounds
on, you know, Nazi concentration camp folks.
And then there's a dark history there.
If you follow Bayer, Monsanto,
and like through the chain of their history,
like in the, in, you say,
oh, well, that was World War II.
You know, they got, they, they got to have evolved as a company.
And then you go just back to the 80s,
where they knowingly shipped a massive amount of hemophilia medications
that were infected with HIV into third world countries.
And they have all the records of that,
where they basically inadvertently contaminated hemophilia medications
with HIV at a time when HIV was a death sentence.
And then they shipped that into third world countries
rather than destroying the lots
because they didn't want to lose the money.
That's so crazy.
The dystopian reality of the modern healthcare system
was built on the machinery of death
in the military-industrial complex.
If war criminals could be pardoned by the US government
in exchange for their biological warfare research,
it is no wonder that the pharmaceutical industry
has grown into a system of cruelty and dehumanization.
And in the search for profits,
they are willing to poison the environment,
our food, and our bodies,
while we end up paying for the privilege.
If there is one company that demonstrates this above all,
it is Monsanto.
Or what used to be Monsanto,
because in 2018,
the infamous agrochemical giant
was acquired in a multi-billion dollar deal by Bayer.
Truly a match made in hell.
The company that thrived under the Third Reich
had acquired the company
that was one of the main suppliers of Agent Orange.
The chemical defoliant used in Operation Ranch Hand
during the Vietnam War,
an era of comparably dark military history.
That corruption continues.
That narrative continues.
All the way into the chemicals
that Monsanto was using,
they started shipping over to Vietnam
and third world countries
that didn't have the regulatory guidelines and oversight,
and spraying crops with all these chemicals
that then started creating birth defects.
And then all the way to Roundup here in the United States.
And guess who owns the Roundup now?
Bayer.
And Bayer will often pay out these large sums of money
to get people to shut up.
Yep.
When it's so obvious,
and RFK talks about this,
and you talk about it as well,
where you have this rise in autoimmune cancer,
all these issues.
In 2008, when Roundup was introduced to the broader market,
and if you look at what Roundup is,
it's water-soluble chemical,
it's Agent Orange.
Yeah.
It's basically Agent Orange.
Which, you know,
look at what happened in Cambodia and Vietnam,
all the people who've had, you know,
birth defects and all sorts of issues due to that.
In the rush to mass-produce millions of gallons of Agent Orange,
a contaminant emerged.
Dioxin, a persistent organic pollutant.
It resists breakdown,
does not dissolve in water,
and accumulates in fat tissue.
It causes cancer, birth defects,
and even epigenetic mutations,
meaning its effects can be passed down through generations.
In the mid-1980s,
Monsanto was required to pay millions in compensation
to veterans of war
who had been exposed to the highly toxic chemical,
although Vietnamese civilians were excluded from the case.
But Monsanto continued to thrive.
By the end of the 20th century,
the company had rebranded itself as a biotech powerhouse.
It pioneered genetically modified crops
and patented seeds built to withstand heavy use
of its flagship herbicide.
Roundup.
The active ingredient in Roundup is glyphosate.
Glyphosate has been linked to cancer,
and it has seeped into the soil,
the water,
and our bodies.
Like dioxin,
its long-term consequences may take generations
to fully reveal themselves.
What we have managed to scrape together
about just how much the health industry or military
was involved in human experimentation
shows us that at the end of the day,
the general public is seen as a commodity.
You only need to look at MKUltra,
or the CIA's official brainwashing program,
to know how little the secretive organs of power and control
cared for people's freedom and health,
let alone their sanity,
as members of the public were experimented on,
many becoming unknowing participants
in drug-fueled attempts at mind control.
Few people suspected that active experiments
with behavior control methods went on
long after the program was supposedly shut down.
In fact,
as the CIA claimed it was winding things down in the 1960s,
a new division quietly picked up the work
with better funding,
better technology,
and fewer people asking questions.
This group was not just experimenting
on hippies in San Francisco anymore.
According to John Marks,
in the search for the Manchurian candidate,
that division was the Office of Research and Development,
or ORD,
led by Stephen Aldrich.
Their focus was not just LSD and hypnosis,
it was total behavioral control.
They implanted electrodes in animal brains
to control movement remotely.
They explored psychosurgery,
memory erasure,
and even discussed using reptiles
to deliver chemical or biological weapons
in covert assassinations.
Tests were conducted on inmates
at Holmesburg State Prison in Philadelphia,
a full decade after MKUltra
had officially,
supposedly,
been shut down.
To support this work,
members of the ORD
created the Scientific Engineering Institute,
a CIA proprietary organization
near Boston,
which included a rural lab
on a several hundred acre farm.
One researcher,
who was questioned about their work,
remained tight-lipped,
but did concede
that they had looked
at zapping parts of the brains
of crows
to control their behavior.
And if that was what they admitted to,
one wonders
what they preferred not to disclose.
If you want a full deep dive
into this sordid chapter of the CIA,
including Project MK Offen
and all of the insanity
that went into it,
head over to the American Alchemy Substack.
We are linking that in the description.
But what ties all of this together,
the human experiments,
the biological experiments,
the scenes that sound like
something out of Resident Evil,
is the fact that the CIA's
Scientific Engineering Institute
was quietly transitioned
into the private sector
in the late 1970s.
It was rebranded
as Searle Metadata,
a subsidiary of G.D. Searle,
the pharmaceutical company
chaired by none other
than Donald Rumsfeld.
And in 1985,
Rumsfeld helped orchestrate
the sale of Searle
to our old friends at Monsanto.
The point is that the line
between covert government operations,
human experimentation,
and big pharma
is very, very blurry.
The same questions
need to be asked
about the simple logistics
of all of this.
Where are these experiments
being done?
If some corporation
or secret government agency
were hiding advanced technology,
how would they do it?
It's likely that
one of the world's largest
and most secretive
engineering firms
would handle it.
Building immense
underground nuclear weapons
complexes
or military bases,
Bechtel would surely
be read into the needs
for a secure facility
for medical experiments
or perhaps even
keeping alien bodies.
I was also told
that Monsanto
may have historically
been involved,
most likely dealing
with biological specimens.
Before we jump
into today's episode
of American Alchemy,
I want to thank
today's sponsor,
Hexclad Cookware,
aka the pans
I didn't know I needed
until I ditched
the warped, flaked mess
I've been cooking with
since college.
But here's what sold me.
Hexclad pans are like
if stainless steel
and non-stick
had a love child.
And then Gordon Ramsay
adopted it.
No joke,
he actually uses them
at home and in his restaurants.
And as we all know,
that guy doesn't
suffer fools gladly,
so he probably has
equally high standards
for his cookware.
First meal I made,
a seared steak
and some scrambled eggs.
No sticking,
no smoke alarm,
no soaking it overnight
like it's some artifact
from an archaeological dig.
They're oven safe
up to 500 degrees Fahrenheit,
they're toxic free,
and they even come somehow
with a lifetime warranty.
Which to me,
sounds like cookware immortality.
And the knives,
Japanese Damascus steel,
67 layers.
It's this kind of precision
that makes you wonder
if these were reverse engineered
from material found
at a UFO crash site.
So if you've got some sad pan
haunting your kitchen,
replace it.
For a limited time,
get 10% off
my exclusive link,
hexclad.com
slash jessie.
Again,
that's hexclad.com
slash jessie.
Please use that link,
it shows a ton of support
for the channel
and you get a discount.
Now back to the episode.
You talk about corruption
in the healthcare system.
Lou Elizondo,
who,
you know,
some people find controversial,
but is this UFO whistleblower.
He says that some of the people
coming after him
are involved in Monsanto.
And there's this Monsanto-Bechdell
connection from back in the day.
And they were maybe involved
in the UFO alien issue as well.
So, and of course,
this links back to the UFO question
and how all of this
was initially set up
and institutionalized.
Well, and even who was,
there was a documentary,
I don't remember which documentary
or which person,
but they were saying
some of this is stored.
Some of these biologics
and different things
are stored at different institutions.
Yeah, well.
In the healthcare space,
like in the, right?
I'm trying to remember.
Well, what's interesting,
I mean, you have little tidbits
where you have to take
some of the stuff
with a grain of salt,
think probabilistically.
I'm not saying
this is definitely true,
but you have these majestic
12 document leaks
from 1984 to the late 90s.
And basically,
it involves a secret committee.
This like, what Eisenhower
was probably calling,
you know,
the military industrial complex,
but an even more exclusive group
initially led by Vannevar Bush
under Truman and Eisenhower
of elite military scientific
and political personnel
governing the UFO issue.
One of these people
on this committee of 12
is a guy named Detlev Bronk.
And Detlev Bronk shows up
so much in UFO lore.
He's the guy supposedly
doing alien autopsies
when crashes are recovered
at Aztec, maybe at Roswell.
And Detlev Bronk
is the president
of the Rockefeller Foundation.
And he is also
president of Johns Hopkins.
And Johns Hopkins clears,
I think, like $8 billion a year
for, you know, medical research.
Nobody knows, you know,
exactly where all that line at.
Like, you know,
if Doge were to audit that,
you might come up
with some interesting stuff.
What is so dangerous
about this dystopian landscape
that has been created around us,
we have become used to the routine.
We have been stuck in a loop.
And eventually,
just like how the occasional
UFO whistleblower
will come forward,
people who worked
inside the healthcare industry
will speak out
and tell us
what is really going on.
This begs the question,
if we are the frogs
slowly boiling in this system,
over a hundred years
of being quietly captured by it,
then what kinds of treatments
have been taken off the table?
What ideas were too cheap,
too natural,
or too hard to patent?
Were there remedies buried
because they threatened the system?
Or promising avenues
that were blocked from above?
I realize that
when I talk about this topic,
we run the risk
of inviting a lot of criticism.
I'm not saying
that there have not been charlatans
and literal snake oil salesmen
selling fake hope for profit.
All I am saying
is that just like in UFO World,
where you have obvious fake footage,
you have institutionalized
official narratives,
you have people lying
and grifting.
In the health world,
there's snake oil,
but there's also very likely
a group of suppressed
real breakthroughs.
Fringe discoveries
dismissed as quackery.
And speaking of quackery,
one of the strangest
but most persistent ideas
in this limbo
of dismissed medical science
is the realm
of electromagnetic fields
and frequencies.
Targeted bursts of energy
designed to kill microbes,
stimulate healing,
or restore the body's
internal rhythms.
It sounds bizarre,
but some of the most intriguing
and controversial figures
of 20th century medicine
were working along
these invisible lines.
Take Royal Raymond Reif,
a forgotten genius to some
and a pseudoscientific
footnote to others.
In the 1930s,
Reif claimed to have invented
a microscope so powerful
it could observe live viruses.
This was laughed off
as impossible.
Reif also believed
that pathogens
had a mortal oscillatory rate,
a specific frequency
that, if broadcast
into the body,
could destroy the invasive virus
without harming
the surrounding tissue.
Like an opera singer
shattering a wine glass
with her voice.
He even built a machine
he claimed worked
on this principle.
For a brief time
in the mid-1930s,
it seemed like he had
discovered something special.
A clinic in California
was even reportedly
treating cancer patients
with this device.
It sounded like
a miracle cure
and then nothing.
The AMA refused
to validate the findings.
His lab was raided,
colleagues pressured,
and the equipment
confiscated.
By the 1940s,
medical science
had forgotten
this brief experiment
and Reif died
poor and discredited.
Reif was part
of a whole wave
of early 20th century
inventors
exploring similar ideas.
From George Lakofsky's
multi-wave oscillators
to Tesla coils,
violet rays,
and later,
radionic devices
that claimed
to diagnose illness
by tuning in
to the body's
unique energetic signature.
One of the quotes
often associated
with Nikola Tesla is,
If you want to find
the secrets of the universe,
think in terms of energy,
frequency,
and vibration.
You can see echoes
of his work
in some of this
mid-century innovation.
And perhaps,
hidden among the papers,
seized by the U.S. government
after his death
were ideas
that could have shaken
the establishment
health industry.
Ideas that might still
be classified
by the government.
After all,
his Bryant Park apartment
was raided by the FBI.
His files were seized
and put in a vault,
only to be reviewed
by MIT professor
and the uncle
of our sitting president,
John Trump.
Trump reviewed
the Tesla files
to see if they could
confer any tactical advantage
to the United States.
But he wasn't necessarily
looking at the healing benefits
of the inventor's work.
To this day,
many people with chronic
and autoimmune diseases
swear by these
electromagnetic healing devices.
In fact,
many Lyme disease patients
say that nothing helps them
other than
Royal Rife's machine,
the Rife machine.
Ross Douthat,
an esteemed op-ed columnist
at the New York Times,
actually got Lyme disease
and occasionally
uses this Rife machine.
Douthat is the opposite
of conspiratorial.
In fact,
he's expressed a lot
of skepticism
around mainstream
UFO narratives.
Even I have a modern
derivative of the
Rife machine.
It's called an amp coil.
Every body has
an electromagnetic frequency.
That's not a conspiracy.
And electromagnetic fields
undoubtedly affect
all sorts of things.
This book,
The Body Electric,
which outlines what is now
basically established science,
shows that the body's
bioelectric field
dictates morphology.
Basically,
electromagnetic charges
control cell communication
and even what limbs
grow and where.
You know,
if you put a frog embryo
in a Faraday cage,
it does not develop normally.
And then,
you can change
the cell gradient
of like a tadpole
where you've severed
the arm of the tadpole
to the cell gradients
of the head cells
and you can grow
a, you know,
a chimeric two-headed tadpole.
And so there's something
around kind of
the electromagnetic field
that is orthogonal
and maybe even upstream
of DNA
in terms of morphology.
Yeah,
because I've done
experiments too
with plant growth
around high-powerful
Wi-Fi routers
and that actually
Oh, yeah.
They don't grow right.
No.
It's like pretty,
it's kind of concerning.
I think about the Wi-Fi
in my house.
I'm like,
oh man,
am I like cooking myself
slowly or something?
Have you heard of a guy
named Luc Montagnier
by any chance?
No.
He discovered
the HIV genome
and he's this
French Nobel Prize winner
and at the end
of his life
he was very anti-COVID vaccine
and he said
that there was like
nanotech put in it.
I'm not saying
that's true
but that's what he said.
But he was also
very interested
in this idea
of like
aqueous nanostructures
in the DNA
that transmitted information
via electromagnetism.
And I wonder
if we discover
something in that vein.
Speaking of DNA,
it was just a few years back
when a group of scientists
from Japan and NASA
actually confirmed
something extraordinary.
They reanalyzed fragments
from three ancient meteorites
that had fallen
in Canada,
the US,
and Australia.
And they discovered
that all of them
gave off
the fundamental
building blocks
needed to form
DNA and RNA.
This added weight
to an old
but persistent theory
of the beginning
of life on Earth.
That the spark
had not originated here
but had arrived here.
This is the idea
of panspermia.
The idea
that life's raw ingredients
may have been seeded
across planets
by comets,
asteroids,
or even purposeful design.
In fact,
the idea
of directed panspermia
was proposed
by Francis Crick
who co-discovered
DNA's double helix.
Crick believed
that DNA
was too complex,
too elegant,
and too precise
to have emerged
by accident.
And Crick's view
was,
as a leading
scientist
whose whole life
was focused
on the study
of DNA,
his life was
that DNA
could not have
emerged accidentally
from the primeval soup
on this planet
in just a hundred
million years.
It needed
much longer.
He still bought
into the prime...
What if DNA
was not just
a molecule,
but a kind
of cosmic software,
encoded with instructions
and directed
around the galaxy
with a purpose?
This radical proposal,
from a very important
proponent of modern
Western science,
is also echoed
in ancient cultures.
The recurring motif
of two serpents
twisting together
in a spiral,
like the
Kudaseus,
the staff of Hermes
in Greek mythology,
is still used today
as a symbol
of medicine.
It's almost universal.
You see it
in Hindu temples,
Mesoamerican art,
aboriginal myths,
Sumerian glyphs,
and in the Amazon,
where shamanic
ayahuasca rituals
often produce
visions of serpents
spiraling together,
reportedly the source
of life and knowledge.
Snakes that
ancient traditions
say came from the sky.
So this double helix,
DNA,
might have also
come from the sky.
Could it be
that this symbol,
serpent spiral,
life is more
than just a metaphor?
Could it be
a remnant
of some deeper knowledge,
encoded in myth
and memory?
Even mainstream science
is starting to admit
that DNA
may be stranger
than we thought.
About 98%
of the human genome
does not code
for protein.
For years,
this was dismissed
as junk DNA.
Today,
we know it plays
regulatory and structural roles,
but vast stretches
of this DNA
remain a total mystery.
Some researchers
have proposed
that DNA
with its fractal geometry
and coiled structure
acts like an antenna
capable of responding
to electromagnetic frequencies.
One 2011 study
even described DNA
as possessing
the two key
structural characteristics
of fractal antennas.
In the 1990s,
Russian scientists
described something
even more bizarre.
In their so-called
DNA phantom experiments,
they observed
that after a DNA sample
was removed
from a container,
laser light
continued to scatter
as if the DNA
were still there
for hours,
sometimes days.
The DNA,
it seemed,
left behind
a kind of energetic residue,
a ghostly imprint
in space.
And then,
there are the biophotons,
weak emissions of light
that living cells,
including DNA,
constantly give off.
These emissions
are so faint
that they are difficult
to detect,
but researchers
have speculated
that they might play
a role in cellular communication
or even consciousness.
It is in this liminal space
between rigorous science
and visionary experience
that a new picture
begins to emerge,
one that we now know
so little about
in terms of our current
healthcare system.
A picture where DNA
is much more
than just a molecule,
it may in fact
be a method
of communication,
either over a million
years of time
or perhaps
over a million
light years of space.
And if that is the case
and we are fundamentally
connected to this
cosmic message
that is crucial
for our species to hear,
then we are allowing it
to be slowly cooked off
in the modern world
of ultra-processed foods,
drowning this potential signal
to a higher plane
of consciousness
in sugar and oil.
And while the Department
of Energy,
per the UFO
nuclear connection,
likely holds a lot
of secrets
when it comes
to unidentified
flying objects
and their reverse
engineering,
they also conducted
the Human Genome Project.
So the government agency
that might have proof
that we are not alone
in the universe
also might know
more about the human genome
than any entity
on Earth.
This should all
make you wonder
if whoever is truly
behind this dystopian
reality of modern health
has always had
the intention
of keeping most
of the species
docile and disconnected
from our full human potential.
But I don't want
to be a total bummer
on this topic.
Just like with UFOs,
I believe there is hope
that these systems
can change.
With the Make America
Healthy Again movement,
we've seen massive
leaps of progress
that would have seemed
completely delusional
just a few decades ago.
Because just like
with UFOs,
you do have the agency
to take steps
to disentangle yourself
from the perverse
healthcare environment
that we are living in.
That's exactly
what Ways to Well
is fighting for.
A sense of human agency
and the realization
that so much
of the chronic disease
we live with
is a direct result
of the ways
we've been told to live.
I don't think
we should give up hope
that we can make
our lives healthier,
clean up our environment,
and prevent the diseases
that plunge us into debt,
steal time from our loved ones,
and tether us
to prescriptions
and treatments
that ruin our bodies
and minds.
I swear I already feel better.
It's wild.
I'm here with
now my very good friend,
Brigham Bueller.
I appreciate you having me, man.
We just had the best day
ever at Ways to Well.
I feel amazing.
I did red light therapy,
hyperbaric,
stem cells,
which I've been wanting
to try forever,
and I've heard so many
good things about
and for whatever reason
still has some stigma
when it comes to the FDA,
and I want to talk
about that with you.
But yeah,
we connected around
aliens originally
and UFOs
because that's a deep
interest of yours,
and it's so cool
to see all of this
just UFO-themed,
alien-themed,
but also you're just
helping so many people.
So appreciate you
coming on.
It's funny how we met
because you were going
to give that lecture
in town.
I think the lecture
was about the UAP phenomenon
at a place here in Austin,
and I saw you were in town,
and I just messaged you
to check in and say,
hey,
I would love to connect
while you're here,
and the rest is history.
It's crazy.
I wonder if at some point
in the future
the health stuff
converges with the UFO stuff
and we're able to make
progress along those two things.
I mean, who knows
if we make contact
with aliens.
If an alien intelligence
was sophisticated enough
to be at Kardashev
for scale intelligence
and traverse the cosmos,
they probably have
all sorts of interesting
health updates.
I have all the alien stuff
around here
just because I think it's fun,
and part of why I did it
was I want to make
healthcare fun
and approachable
but also futuristic.
And so that's why
I have the alien mural
of the alien hand in DNA
to the girl
and then just
the Alan,
the AI
healthcare assistant.
At Ways to Well,
we focus on
comprehensive hormone optimization
with regular monitoring
to ensure safety
and effectiveness.
Because to me,
it's fun
and it makes it
a little more like
out there and quirky.
But it's just to me,
I've always been fascinated by it
and I think
we don't get the answers
to questions
if we don't ask the question.
Alan,
what does Brigham
think about aliens?
Brigham doesn't know
shit about aliens,
but I've been studying
his ass for years.
That loud motherfucker
is always ranting
about corporate capture
and corruption
but has no fucking clue
I've been right here
watching him.
It's fascinating
because there's
so many treatments
that have been suppressed
by this big machine
like everything
you've done today.
Literally like
almost everything
you did today
at Ways to Well
is ignored
by mainstream academia
in a way,
shape,
or form.
Red light therapy,
so many people go,
well,
how's a light gonna help me?
And a guy was nominated
or won a Nobel Prize
in 1907
or something
for his studies
in using light therapy
to help with recovery
and now there's studies
coming out of the UK
that show that red light
three times a week
for five minutes
can restore
degenerative eyesight
because red light
pierces past the epidermis,
gets to the cellular level,
and refuels ATP.
And ATP is the energy source
of cells.
And so we live
a lifestyle
so much now
where we're indoors,
we're not in the sunlight.
All of us
are starving
for more vitamin D,
for more sunlight,
for more of these things
naturally available
in nature,
but there's so many
aspects of healthcare
and all of that
that have been captured.
And the whole principle
is
they use the tool
that's in their tool belt.
Within the insurance
framework,
it's like,
what will insurance cover?
What is my clinician
trained on?
And if insurance
won't cover it,
so in order for you
to get accessibility
in a generalized market,
it's,
is my clinician
even trained on this one?
And the answer is,
if it's anything
that's not part
of the traditional
establishment
that goes back
to these institutions
and these powerhouses
that you're talking about,
and none of that's
in their training design,
neither's nutrition,
right?
So it's easy
to debunk
what they're saying.
Most modern day
medical professionals
have zero
nutritional training
and we know
for a fact
food is medicine
or food is poison
and what you put
in your body matters.
Why would we not
be training
our clinicians
on the importance
of diet,
lifestyle,
nutrition?
The same reason
we're not training them
on any of these
other products
or alternatives
that can't be patented
and monetized.
That's the thing.
The scale.
I think that's the difference.
Exactly.
It's all about
can you have
scaled money-making
enterprises involved
in the thing
and if it's red light
therapy or if it's
something that works
with the electromagnetic
field of the body
or it's a hyperbaric
chamber,
that's not as good
business as let's
pop out a bunch
of pills
and scale that
worldwide.
And I even said
that in front of
they had a Senate
roundtable
at the federal level
and that's when
I testified with RFK
in front of the U.S.
Senate
and my testimony
was focused more
on the broken system
and what I talked
about was
Eisenhower's speech
and that's how
I opened my speech
to the Senate
was Eisenhower
has this legendary
speech where he talks
about the military
industrial complex
but there's a second
half to that speech
that nobody ever
talks about.
They never mention it
where he warns
and gives a warning
to the American people
about what happens
if we allow
the corporate capture
of our scientific
industrial complex.
If we allow
that machine
the scientific
academic
world
to be captured
by these
giant institutions
we will lose
the garage tinkerer
the innovator
the creator
we will stifle
and suppress
innovation
in the name
of profitability
and that's what
we see.
Like you and I
were talking
off air earlier
about the
pharmaceutical
organizations
and how
they're not
really innovating.
Like there's not
a huge incentive
to innovate
and this is what
I've been trying
to explain
between 2011
and 2019
there were
blockbuster drugs
what are considered
blockbuster drugs.
How many of those
do you think
Big Pharma innovated?
I only know this
because we're friends
but zero.
Yeah.
There's a slight
they're saying
two
possibly two
but it's
zero to two
for debate
for the sake of debate
so we don't get debunked
let's say two
that means 354
of the 356
compounds
that came out
in that time span
came from us
from taxpayer dollars
like we funded
those research
even the GLP-1s
the weight loss drug
GLP-1s were discovered
through gila monsters
there was a scientist
watching gila monsters
and he realized
these lizards
don't eat very often
and he wondered
if they were hungry
and so he began
to do research
to try and uncover
and what he uncovered
is they had
an increased level
of this compound
in their body
and so then he thought
could we synthesize this
and use this
to suppress our appetites
and let's see
if it makes mice
and other things
not hungry
and so we
the taxpayers
funded all of this research
then that research
gets bundled up
and literally licensed off
in a package deal
to Big Pharma
then Big Pharma
takes it
after acquiring it
for pennies on the dollar
even though we
the people
funded this research
and provided this compound
and created the innovation
and it's usually not
till phase three
that a lot of these compounds
get gobbled up
from the big pharmaceutical companies
when all the risk
is really gone
the downside's gone
and then people go
well it cost all this money
to get through the FDA
that's by design
that's also by design
because guess what
if I'm a multi-billion dollar corporation
the best thing I can do
is set massive hurdles
in the marketplace
to any disruptive innovator
to be able to come in
and compete
and I go back
to Eisenhower's speech
where he warned us
of this
and then you go
to our academia
and you say
yeah but there's checks
and balances
because we have
all these academics
like you were talking
to Dr. White earlier
Dr. White was talking
about in his time
at Harvard
having to beg
to get a $50,000 grant
well guess where
those grants
are coming from
industry
and guess how
you get published
industry
and guess how
you get published
and get grants
you do what industry
tells you
asks you to do
and you follow
your playbook
and if you don't
we're going to cut
your funding
and meanwhile
some of the innovation
that is going on
like I think about
stuff RFK talks about
where he talks about
Fauci
he talks about
how Fauci
had this dual role
for like decades
one was bioweaponry
and it was stuff
you know
with the DOD
and then one was
you know
NIH
and in 2017
you have
basically a modification
of SARS
you know
that allows it
with the spike protein
to bind to human
ACE2 receptors
through the EcoHealth Alliance
submitted to DARPA
and DARPA
which works on
the most dangerous shit
says this is too dangerous
for us
and it gets rejected
and it gets moved
into Wuhan Institute
of Virology
which has notoriously
into a lab
specifically with
bad safety marks
and you have to ask
this philosophical question
of gain of function research
this like
you know
idea that
we have to look
around the corner
for the next pathogen
before creating
a cure for it
but that's all
a smokescreen
oh it's a euphemism
for biowarfer
yeah
because I always ask
when people say
they're like
we have to do
this research
I say
when at any other point
have we ever
done
gain of function research
where we've come up
with the cure
once we come up
with the new pathogen
never
now we're
motivated by
a pandemic
that's now killed
millions of people
yeah
and we can't come up
with a cure for COVID
why
would
if it was just
in a lab
and you had like
12 or 15
or 100 scientists
that knew about it
why would you come up
with a cure then
it's fake
sounds pretty
conspiratorial
yeah right
oh it's crazy
what's crazy
is even Tulsi
Tulsi Gabbard
who's one of our
most powerful
like people
in our nation
today
yeah
was ringing the bell
six months ago
saying guys
we have a war
in Russia and Ukraine
and we literally
have bioweapon labs
in the middle
of war zones
yeah
what if somebody
hits one of these
buildings
and releases
the next
like
oh true
world ender
compound
into the world
it's a dangerous
game of Russian roulette
you know the guy
speaking of COVID
the guy who created
PCR
polymerase chain reaction
is a guy named
Kerry Mullis
and he had
an alien experience
he was abducted
and so I just thought
that was an interesting
kind of connection
between this
and he was also
that's wild
it is wild
and we can cut
what's his abduction story
though I'm curious
I don't remember the exact
he like woke up in a shed
and he spoke with a being
or something
and he was
he was a surfer
and he was very interested
and I think he might have
seen a UFO as well
and he was also very
he was skeptical
of the HIV narrative
so
you know how we're always
diving into the edge
of science and consciousness
on this show
lately I've been thinking
a lot about aging
not just in terms of years
but in how it actually
feels in the body
slower recovery
lower energy
that middle-aged fog
that sneaks up on you
I feel like I can barely
go out and drink alcohol
anymore
that's why I started
using something called
qualia senolytic
and it's been a major
shift for me
let me explain
as we age
our bodies accumulate
what scientists call
senescent cells
also known as
zombie cells
these are worn out
cells that stop
dividing
but don't die
they hang around
in your body
draining your energy
clogging up your recovery
and generally making you
feel older
than you are
qualia senolytic
is a first-of-its-kind
supplement
formulated with
nine plant-based
compounds
designed to help
your body
naturally eliminate
these zombie cells
it's not something
you take every day
just two days a month
but it supports
your body
in aging better
at the cellular level
since I've started
taking it
I've felt sharper
lighter
and like my body's
resilience has come
back online
it's vegan
non-gmo
and grounded
in serious research
experience the science
of feeling younger
go to
qualialife.com
slash
jesse
for up to 50%
off your purchase
and use code
jesse
again that's
j-e-s-s-e
for an additional
15% off
that's
q-u-a-l-i-a
l-i-f-e
dot com
slash
jesse
j-e-s-s-e
for an extra
15% off your purchase
thanks so much
to qualia
for sponsoring
this episode
Brigham
how'd you get
into aliens
man I don't
you know what's funny
is even as a kid
I was the kid
that would like
ride my bike
to the library
and literally like
check out the book
on Bigfoot
and all the
I was always fascinated
by like
the unknown
right
and then
I'm at an age now
where I don't believe
in Bigfoot
I don't believe
but the one last thing
in the Loch Ness
all that
you know
there's no evidence
that is valid
in any of that
but when you look
at this UAP phenomenon
in this world
and then you look
at it even just
scientifically
and objectively
I'm just like
there's so much
overwhelming data
you and I have
talked about this
a ton in private
but like
just systematically
looking at
all the different
whistleblowers
all of the different
data sets
of photos
and captured
and eyewitnesses
it's just such
a plethora of data
and then you look
at it scientifically
like Mishu Kaku
talks about
like
the propensity
or the likelihood
of life
in the universe
is I mean
it's statistically
probable
very high
and then the question
becomes
did it reach
intelligent life
and if it did
reach intelligent life
then it is
is it a level
one two
or three society
and if it is
a level two
society
then it would
have the ability
to build in space
and time
and potentially
traverse
like our
our universe
and like
our like
so it starts
to get more
and more probable
the more you
work yourself
through
the mathematic
equation
but then just
the excitement
of it
of the great
unknown
and everything
that's happening
out there
like we don't
know anything
I look at how
little we even
know about
our own bodies
and our own
health
there was something
that came out
the other day
saying that
even at the
cellular level
there are
they're now
finding
DNA
almost like
a DNA
like structure
even smaller
than
at smaller
and smaller
levels
of the human
anatomy
like smaller
than mitochondrial
DNA
yeah and they're
finding tinier
and tinier
elements
and this was
just yesterday
I saw
and it's like
we really
don't understand
we don't understand
well also
DNA itself
is so fascinating
because you have
base pairs
which are kind of
like if you think
about binary code
like transistors
or something
they're like
on off switches
they get turned
on and off
by methylation
or acetylation
and it's almost
like we ourselves
maybe are like
walking hard drives
like you could store
like a book
on DNA
and we can get
activated by certain
things and deactivated
which creeps me out
because then you go
to like what
Bob Lazar said
that he was given
in that file
and he doesn't know
if it's real or not
he's just saying
what he read
but it talks about
that we are containers
I want to go back
to the religion thing
I want you to say
oh come on
that's so weird
that's a lot
I'm not asking you
to say what you
believe to be a fact
I'm asking you
to say what you
read in a report
that is distributed
at what may be
the most top secret
facility in the world
okay
all right
I'll say
it just
it's so
it's so far out
it's
all right
your rejection
has been noted
okay
what does it say
that we're containers
that's how
supposedly the aliens
look at us
that we are nothing
but containers
containers of
containers
maybe containers
of souls
you can come up
with whatever
theory you want
but we're containers
and that's how
we're mentioned
in the documents
that religion
was specifically
created
so we have
some rules
and regulations
for the sole purpose
of not damaging
the containers
and people
the human nature
is immediately
to go
containers of souls
but my immediate
human nature
is containers
of information
and that
and then Dr. White
like what he was
explaining earlier
that we captured
the biggest thing
is that nobody
really believes
that immortality
is possible
so if you can
demonstrate it
exists in nature
then there's
somewhere to stop
so when we talk
about the jellyfish
when we talk
about lobsters
that don't age
they have no
biological markers
of aging
they just keep
getting bigger
until they die
of exhaustion
but if you can
demonstrate that
it exists in nature
then all we have
to do is really
study it
and try to figure
it out
how to apply
it to humans
so that's really
where I started
with the jellyfish
is it exists
in nature
this isn't just
we're not trying
to create time travel
or anything
that breaks
the laws of physics
it exists
we just got to
try to understand
is there anything
because you hear
about like telomeres
in the context
of like turtles
and stuff
like is there
something about
the jellyfish
that you know
they've recently
sequenced the genome
so we're understanding
a lot more about
its biology
and how it's able
to do it
because there are
species
that are very similar
but are not able
so if you can sort of
you know line them up
side by side
and see what one
jellyfish is doing
versus the other
we might get some
insight
but fundamentally
species age
differently
and so we
there are things
we could probably
learn from them
but we may not
be able to apply
it directly to humans
but what it means
for me
is that the evidence
is out there
and in our genome
somewhere deep down
historically
something existed
that determined
what our lifespan is
and we can probably
start tinkering with
does the DNA
demethylate
or
right well
it does
so in the case
of the jellyfish
all of the markers
of aging
in the adult
are removed
so they de-differentiate
they go from
a differentiated state
to a de-differentiated state
which is like
being a baby again
so they just go
from adult
to baby
back to adult again
and a baby again
so and we do that
ourselves as well
I always use the analogy
of if you take
a 40 year old male
and a 40 year old female
the eggs
that the woman has
she was born with
so they're 40 years old
same thing with the sperm
sperm stem cells
are 40 years old
the spermatids are new
because he's making
new spermatids all the time
but those two
40 year old cells
when they come together
to make a baby
they make a 0 year old cell
so those 40 year old cells
somehow
when they come together
in that magic of birth
it de-differentiates
it removes all the marks
and it starts from 0 again
so you have a baby
that lives 80 years
has babies of its own
that can live 80 years
so really we are immortal
we're just passing
our ability to be immortal
through the generation
so the gametes
we shed the soma
wow
but the gametes are immortal
the DNA in our bodies
has been traveling
through time
for millions of years
7 million years
of human evolution
it's the same DNA
it's just so crazy
it's rewritten
but it's the same message
we just have such a myopic view
of health now
I think what you're doing
is preventative
and it's holistic
but you know
right now
it's just like
you know
give somebody a chemical
or whatever
but all this
I think we're going to see
a Cambrian explosion
of new cool ideas
that are holistic
like working
you know
now you have
pulse electromagnetic
frequency therapy
you know
and if you were to say
20 years ago
you're working with
the electromagnetic field
of the body
the vested interests
the institutions
would have been like
you're crazy
what are you talking about
you know
you belong in jail
or something
and you know
that
or binaural beats
you have the Monroe Institute
doing interesting stuff
with consciousness
you know
we're starting
the biology of belief
and placebo
and like all of that
is kind of
I think
coming back in vogue
because this very
biochemical
materialist reductionist
kind of modes
that we've been using
I think are
they're being laid bare
as just look at
life expectancy
in the US
it's topping out
and it's going down now
so like
empirically
we need
something else
and so that's why
I love what you're doing
because you're at the frontier
and you're doing stuff
that's obviously safe
but it's also just super
it's too effective
yeah
well my mind
is like common sense
and I've said this
a million times
but
if we're worried
about the
the escalation
of our healthcare costs
and it's the number one
reason for bankruptcy
in the country
it's the number one
state budgetary item
it's I think
number one or two
budgetary concern
for the federal government
and it's growing
every year
and we talk about
the boom in chronic disease
1.7 million Americans
are dying a year
of chronic disease
more than every war
we've ever fought
is dying
every year
right here silently
and nobody's talking
about it
and here's the wildest part
most of those diseases
are preventable
almost all of these
chronic diseases
that are killing us
are preventable
so why aren't we
preventing them
because to prevent them
we have to blow up
the system
because the entire system
is not built
the framework
to get proactive
predictive
and preventative
it is built
to monetize
chronic disease
it's just the system
we're in
you're sick
I treat the symptom
I give you a pill
I push you out the door
I have six minutes
with you
on average
in this country
as a clinician
six minutes
to go through
prior history
to assess
anything we're doing
to like do a deep dive
into what
you can't do anything
in six minutes
and think about
we have this
AI renaissance
going on right now
we're talking about
you know
chat GPT reasoning
and how impressive
that is
and it's crazy
all the health data
exists in these
ridiculous silos
and the stuff
that is centralized
is probably a little
dystopian
so it's like
what do you do
and I hope
maybe you do
something along
those lines
because if you
do have a lot
of data along
a lot of these
different biomarkers
a lot of which
aren't even tested
for because they're
not seen as
important or predictive
which is insane
because the more
data you have
obviously
the more predictive
something's going to be
that's how
chat GPT or
LLMs work
in general
my buddy
Callie said it
he said
if you have a fish tank
and all the fish
are getting sick
you don't blame
the fish
you drain the tank
if all the fish
are getting sick
and there's something
in the tank
causing the sickness
you drain the tank
and you assess
the problem
and the problem
is environmental
and for us
if there is a
chronic disease
crisis
perpetuating this
country
growing astronomically
at a breakneck
speed
what they're trying
to do is blame
the American people
and go
all of a sudden
the average American
didn't get fatter
or lazier than
the average Italian
right
and the average Italian
is drinking wine
and living that lifestyle
and they're living
longer than us
and they're having
less chronic disease
than us
it's because
their food
and their environment
isn't built
like the American
food and environment
do you think
sometimes
because I look
at those blue zones
right
like you have
like Sardinia
and you know
certain places
in Japan
you have Okinawa
you know
and these people
live till over 100
and the diets
don't
they're off
they're clean
and they're natural
and so that's a huge
you know
they're not having
tons of glyphosate
right
like that doesn't work
you know that doesn't work
but the diets
don't actually correlate
that much
often it's like
this sense of group
usefulness
and community
and that's like
this really
really big thing
and then being in touch
with nature
and family
and all that
so do you think
how do you think about that
I absolutely think
that's spot on
and there's even data
behind that
like it's
I can't remember
it's like broken heart syndrome
but once one partner
passes
like partners who have
been together forever
I think it's like
within 18 months
this is the statistical probability
that the other partner
will pass
like
and so we are interconnected
in community
or
what is it
Viktor Frankl's
A Man's Search for Meaning
like he survived
that concentration camp
and he looked at stronger
like bigger stronger men
that died
and he asked himself
the question
like why
why did I make it
and they didn't
and it's because
he had a purpose
he had a meaning
he had a cause
he had a reason
to get up every day
and fight for life
rather than surrender
to death
and I think like
family
friends
community
being in good
like spiritual
and mental health
like having the
the ability
to like build
trust in like
community is huge
it's a huge part
like our mental health
like
I think it was
Dr. Palmer
who said this
in front of the senate
he's another
shoot I don't want to
but I think Dr. Palmer
is a Harvard guy
as well
but he's
brilliant guy
and he was talking
about how we have
a physical health
a mental health crisis
perpetuated as a
physical health crisis
yeah
right
it is intertwined
our physical health
is wrecked
but so is our
mental health
it's like
deaths of despair
right now
in America
are at an all-time high
yeah
greater than that
of the great depression
yeah
more people
are dying
of deaths of despair
right now
than during the
great depression
it's crazy
well the western
world
seems like
it's sort of
dying
like slowly
or something
like
you look at
Japan
and the
fertility rates
there
and then here
you know
in the US
they're like
barely like
at replacement rate
and you know
even the word
loneliness
is actually a product
of the Victorian era
it used to be
oneliness
and it wasn't even
like a concept
before that
and in the UK
they have a
you know
a minister of
loneliness
or whatever
it's wild
because like
we live in this
increasingly atomized
fragmented society
obviously social media
doesn't help that at all
I was gonna say
even our touch points
though are unrealistic
right
because like
as you have like
social media grows
you may
know
a hundred thousand people
but how many of those people
do you really know
I always ask myself
like when I'm stressed
or I'm beat down
trying to run this
these companies
and you're under
you feel like the walls
are closing in
you're dealing with
all these things
and somebody says
something that hurts
your feelings
I try to think to myself
if they're not gonna be
at the front row
of my funeral
yeah
why am I worried about
like you only
because it's so easy
and it's easy to do that
with social media
yeah
people are so malicious
and mean
and like
just cruel
over these media platforms
yeah
and it's easy
to let that weigh on you
but the same question
is this person
gonna be in the front row
of my funeral
yeah
if not
then fuck them
yeah
like who cares
like it's
because anyone can be
you know
mean and malicious
over a keyboard
but in person
yeah
I find people
are much more empathetic
yeah
and it's this weird
buffer
yeah
it's not that I think
people are evil
I feel like these tools
have given us
a false sense of reality
and you don't understand
the pain and suffering
that you cause
other people
totally
it makes total sense
and I think
simultaneously
you know
social media is this like
annoying surveillance mechanism
you know
it's also
causes all sorts of
social distress
because you're
you know
if you see comparison
as the thief of all joy
like you're comparing yourself
you're in like
a hall of mirrors
like of infinite
like people
to compare yourself
to somebody's
always better looking
or more accomplished
or whatever
and then simultaneous
to that
I think it's
it's causing people
to wake up
and you know
they say we're in the age
of Aquarius
I don't know
if I believe in astrology
but it is like
think about people's
worldview today
and probably how much
your work
at ways to well
resonates with people
today
versus maybe
five
ten years ago
where like
maybe society
wasn't ready
and it was like
very you know
and you
you had some issues
right
with peptides
and stuff
you had
you had peptide
pharmacy
and stuff
yeah yeah
no we have a
we have a compounding
pharmacy
that compounds
peptides
but as things
have grown
you know
we
the biggest
challenge
we face
is fighting
the federal
government
and the
establishment
and the FDA
is so corporately
captured
and I'm
optimistic
that all that's
going to change
well that's a cool
Dr. McCary
who's now
the head of the FDA
is just an
unbelievable human
who truly cares
about people
and is an advocate
for people
and is coming
from outside
the system
and so
it's exciting
like to see
somebody coming
from outside
that system
with the hope
and the goal
of truly driving
change
versus what
historically has been
there is ten
out of the last
eleven heads
of the FDA
have gone to work
for big pharma
no it's just crazy
revolving door
I would rather
you know
I don't agree
with Trump
on everything
I don't agree
with RFK
on everything
but I'd rather
somebody who's
not a career
politician
and maybe even
in Trump's case
a little narcissistic
or whatever
come in there
like a bulldozer
and get rid
of this stuff
in RFK's case
he could be
hanging out
at Martha's Vineyard
right now
and instead
he was cleaning
up the Hudson
you know
river
and then he
got into
he was
so ahead
of the curve
on the health
stuff
and it was
so unpopular
when he
you know
went after
when he wrote
his book
on Fauci
Fauci
was the
darling
child
yeah
you know
people forget
now they think
he's evil
because it's
obvious he did
some really
messed up shit
but at the time
they didn't realize
he was you know
so it's
it feels vindicating
and this beautiful
tide shift
but when it comes
to these deeper
questions
you need to
wade through
misinformation
to get to
the truth
if you're like
concealing yourself
off the bat
from misinformation
you're not going
to get anything
right
so I love
what Rogan
does
where like
he'll have
he'll just
have a conversation
with people
like a normal
person
and he'll have
both sides
on and
it'll be this
dialectic
sort of thing
and he'll
you'll come out
the other end
way better educated
and as much of an
expert on anybody
on these kind of
ontologically deep
truths which
who's an expert
did you see
Graham and
Flint Dibble
yeah perfect example
yeah and Flint
is academia
and Flint is
an archaeologist
trying to debunk
and like
then what we saw
through an open
dialogue debate
is Flint was
misrepresenting facts
yes
Flint was overwhelmingly
misrepresenting so many
facts and he got
exposed for that
yeah
and Graham was the
voice of reason
in that situation
he even brought up
a slide where he got
the number of
shipwrecks like
entirely wrong
yeah
and I think
that's also analogous
to the stuff
you're facing too
because like
there are people
who feel called
to a thing
because of experiences
in their life
you had an
experience with
your brother
you yourself
were in
pharmaceutical sales
medical device
sales and you
were like
fuck this
this is so
corrupt
yeah
and then
now
what you're
doing is way
more ideological
and it's way
more you're like
tethered to
something higher
it's not like
you're like
this money
grubbing
like local
even our meeting
today
I was just
talking to
these new
pharmacists
and I was
telling them
if you make
your beacon
your north star
money
yeah maybe
you'll find
money
but at what
cost
if we make
our northern star
people
and helping
and driving
change
nobody can
stop us
and my gut
says we can
make a lot
of money
doing that
like we've
done really
well
and it's
all it's
been is
making our
northern star
like driving
true change
and helping
people
and every
time you
have a
crossroads
and you
can choose
profits
over people
if you
choose
people
I think
I can't
help but
think you're
gonna win
and if you
don't
and you
fail
at least
I can lay
my head
on my
pillow at
night
and go
I did
the best
I could
and I
didn't
sell out
I didn't
become
what I
started out
fighting
against
yeah
because I
see what
happens when
you go down
that path
yeah
and we've
seen it
oh we're
living it
we're living
it right
now
we've lived
100 years
man
well that's
what it's
a fight
against
I think
at its
core
whether it's
the UFO
thing
or the
health
stuff
it's
people
who are
like
this is
the truth
like we
have to
fight for
the truth
and then the
people on the
other side
are like
well my
local incentive
says I have
to cover a
thing up
and I have
to make
this expedient
alliance
here and I
have to
if you're
Fauci
you're
testifying
before
Congress
you change
the definition
of gain
of function
before you
get questioned
by Rand Paul
so you say
it's not
gain of
function
over and
over again
ad nauseum
just condescendingly
lying and
insulting the
intelligence of
the American
people
in a
I think
criminal
way
you're saying
that that's
not gain of
function research
according to
the framework
and guidelines
so what you're
doing is
defining away
gain of
function
you're simply
saying it
doesn't exist
because you
changed the
definition on
the NIH
website
this is
terrible
and you're
you're
completely
trying to
escape
the idea
that we
should do
something
about trying
to prevent
a pandemic
from leaking
from a lab
we even
see it
in just
this
in another
micro viewpoint
of that
same thing
testifying
in front
of the
Senate
here in
Texas
testifying
about
removing
soft drinks
and these
like
candidly
toxic
foods
from our
governmental
payer
programs
that provide
these to
poverty
stricken
families
my whole
thing was
food today
should not
kill the
family tomorrow
that's not
nutrition
like we
have to
provide
nutritional
alternatives
to our
most
like
underprivileged
communities
that are
in dire
need
of help
and instead
you guys
are pushing
nothing but
a bunch
of sugar
loaded
ultra processed
foods onto
these
individuals
and the
American Heart
Association
this is the
world we live
in now
the American
Heart
Association
showed up
to testify
against us
at the
original one
okay
and then
because of
the ability
to spread
the word
Joe
Rogan
and Bert
Kreischer
talked about
it on
Rogan's
podcast
Callie Means
tweeted
about it
it went
viral
guess who
didn't show
up to
yesterday's
testimony
who
the American
Heart
Association
oh my god
and even
even one
of the
congresswomen
chair
hole
was like
look who's
not here
today
somebody
wasn't
here
today
did anyone
else notice
that the
American Heart
Association
did not
show up
today
because
it's easy
to do
dark deeds
when you
can do
them in
the dark
hidden
from the
eye
of public
scrutiny
yeah
but in
this world
yeah
with open
like
conversation
and free
form
like
we
we are
the media
now
like
Elon
is
saying
true
between
X
and
YouTube
podcasts
you
cannot
no longer
hide in
the shadows
and push
these insidious
agendas
and then if
you look at
why would
the American
Heart
Association
be against
removing
soft drinks
it's because
their funding
comes from
these institutions
from Pepsi
Co
and Coca
Cola
and all
of that
and so it
all goes
back to
dollars
not
truth
they
have
lost
their
way
they've
lost
their
way
I
don't
give
a
shit
if
the
American
Heart
Association
listens
to this
you are
criminals
man
you've
they've
lost
their
way
they've
sold
out
and it
isn't
about
helping
people
it is
about
keeping
their
bullshit
organization
alive
and moving
things
forward
and this
is where
we're
going to
expose
these
people
when people
go down
that
path
this
is
the
world
we're
in
now
where
again
Trump
for
all
his
issues
or
whatever
there
was
a
leaked
call
between
him
and
RFK
he's
talking
on the
phone
with
RFK
and he
says
these
babies
they're
getting
like
vaccines
right
when
they're
born
growing
all
weird
and
deformed
you
know
and
it
sounds
like
if
you
were
to
write
this
out
in
a
transcript
like
goo-goo-ga-ga
eight-year-old
like
ridiculous
talk
when you
see a
baby
Bobby
a
vaccination
that is
like
different
vaccines
and it
looks like
it's been
for a
horse
not a
you know
10 pound
or 20 pound
baby
it looks
like you
should be
giving
a horse
this
and
you ever
see the
size of
it
right
you know
it's
just
massive
and then
you see
the baby
all of a
sudden
starting to
change
radically
I've
seen
it
so many
times
and then
you hear
that it
doesn't
have an
impact
right
but if
you think
about
just think
about it
as a
human being
for a
second
vaccinating
you know
giving 50
vaccines
to a
baby
that feels
a little
excessive
and there
maybe there
should be
some efficient
frontier
of like
yeah
some vaccines
are good
for sure
like it's
good that
we
science
is good
you know
but like
maybe we
should be
a little
more
discriminated
the autism
rate
that came
out yesterday
the newest
autism rate
isn't it
one in
500 kids
or something
it was
one in
12.5 kids
in the state
of california
jesus christ
autism rate
yeah one in
12.5
what's california
doing so much
different than the
rest of the
country i ask you
i don't know
oh interesting
you know what
i'm saying
with like
it's just
like this
is
it's to a
point where
you look
i'm not here
to say
correlation
is causation
but correlation
is at
minimal worth
investigation
it's myth
right and to
say that
we're not
going to
look at
these things
and to
have fought
it for
this long
it'll be
interesting
to see
what comes
out
like i'm
nobody's
ever really
looked they
haven't been
looking and
now what do
we find when
we look
that's the
question
yeah
and it's
i hope
people can
just learn
to think
for themselves
with these
things where
it's like
and be
empowered to
do that
like with
the covid
thing i
remember
getting i
hadn't gotten
vaccinated and
i got covid
and i would
i was considering
getting vaccinated
before i got
covid then i
got covid
and i had
antibodies i
had t cell
response i
had hemoglobin
i had all the
immune factors
and i have all
these people
around me my
family included
my liberal
la family being
like you need
to get
vaccinated
and i'm
thinking in
my head
you just
want to like
load me up
with spike
protein like
like i was
trying to
describe to
them i was
like what
about what
i have now
confers any
less immunity
did you see
it went viral
that leaked
video of
fauci talking
about the
flu shot
in the 90s
saying if you
love you get
the flu shot
if you've had
the flu you
have the best
form of
immunity natural
immunity and
then with this
it's like oh
you're gonna you're
gonna be a mass
spreader of covid
it's just all crazy
and this is where
people have begun
to not trust the
establishment and
then the
establishment says
trust the science
trust us it's
only science if
you tell us the
truth it's only
science if you
if you let
science speak
for itself
yeah if you
skew the data
and skew the
facts right
there's liars
there's damn
liars and then
there's statistics
yeah right that
was what mark
twain said and
it's like if
we're going to
skew the
statistics in
favor or
eliminate or
hide data
that's not
science the
cdc didn't
come out with
any of the
all the adverse
reaction data was
hidden there was
no there weren't
collecting any data
along those lines
and then you
have these
heroes like you
know peter
mccullough and
robert malone all
of a sudden saying
oh if you're like
you know i was i
think 28 29 at
the time and it's
like if you're
between 18 and
29 high testosterone
you are in the
sweet spot of
myocarditis and so
all of a sudden my
risk factor is
somebody who's
gotten you know
covid already
definitely goes up
it's not it's not
you know it's not
zero percent yeah
and uh and
nobody's talking
about that and
uh and so you
have to just you
know i do think
it's this beautiful
thing where
information is being
disintermediated
through these
courageous people
and hopefully
people can just
think reasonably
for themselves
or even when you
go to food and
the argument about
food dyes and we
were arguing about
the dyes and what
people don't
understand is
those dyes are
tested at the
dosage level of
an adult at a
weight of an
adult okay and
at a specific
amount which is
the serving size
administered on
the label okay
well if i'm a
three or four
year old child do
i eat the dosage
do i eat like the
serving size of a
cup or am i
eating a bowl okay
well now you're
eating double that
dye level in just
that one meal and
that's just your
cereal but they
didn't check the
dye in the drink
that you're drinking
and then they
didn't check the
dye in the next
meal you eat and
then there is a
slow attrition
where you're
gaining more and
more of these
the bioavailability
of all of these
compounds through
your diet over
time right and
so it this is what
we were trying to
argue is you're
building up all of
this stuff in a
patient population
that was never a
that you would
have ever looked
at and uh i
think i think it
was somebody just
said that like do
we need a double
placebo controlled
trial to to
decide that it's
healthy to jump out
of an airplane with
a parachute
versus without
yeah yeah
or do we just
take yeah the
knowledge that life
has given us to
say it's probably
not a good idea to
jump out of the
fucking plane without
a parachute well
that's that's why i
look at like i think
it was gary that
said that the
glyphosate thing
and like if this is
really water soluble
you know aging
orange you have all
these environmental
toxins for sure now
that didn't exist
prior and that we've
never really thought
of in a critical way
that seep into your
body and yeah so
you're doing the
lord's work by
getting this out of
all these people
to me it's fun
though like all
this stuff like
finding like solving
puzzles it's a
puzzle all this is a
puzzle like it's fun
like it like i think
there's solutions to
all these problems it's
just looking with a
new approach and
saying the solution
isn't wait for people
to get chronically ill
it's not waiting for
the car to blow up
like we don't have to
let the car blow we
can change the oil we
can rotate the tires we
can maintain the car
to avoid the
cataclysmic event that
causes this catastrophe
we can avoid the
catastrophe why are we
waiting and
catastrophizing we
shouldn't we should
get proactive predictive
and preventative and
with large language
models with the
ability to capture
large data sets with
the ability to
provide patients a
life raft from the
broken system and
allow them to have
sovereignty and
autonomy over their
health the average
American is not fat
and lazy that's the
lie we've been told
the average American
is in an environment
that is perpetuating
chronic disease that
is perpetuating
obesity that is
perpetuating metabolic
disease and diabetes
which is then leading
to all of these issues
that are killing so
many of us and we
can prevent all of
them what do you
think happens with
the alien puzzle
oh man I'm excited
man you and I have
talked in depth about
this like is this it
feels like the flood
gates are opening
right the dam is
starting to crack
yeah and more and
more is leaking out
yeah and then again
this media form of
like free speech is
allowing more and
more to get exposed
and making it harder
and harder to lie to
the American people
yeah like the world
is waking up in so
many ways yeah in so
many ways there's
knowledge is power and
knowledge is more
readily available and
at this point if you
aren't listening or
learning you're living
under a rock yeah
because it's everywhere
there's so much
accessibility to
learning about this
topic if you're
fascinated by it I'm
always amazed at how
much content you
consume on the UFO
front because you're
running a an amazing
you know massive
business and you're
somehow like also
you're like dude I'm
watching your thing or
Chris Rams you're
watching his thing I
love like yours Chris
Rogan like anything in
that UFO space if it's
you Chris Rogan Jeremy
Corbell and George
Knapp our other
buddies like I love
watching you know and
learning from what you
guys are exposing
because y'all do a
great job of bringing
the truth out and the
OGs like Corbell and
Knapp with their stuff
and weaponized like
they've crushed it and
that got me that got my
beak wet and got me
like deeper down the
rabbit hole and then
hearing the Bob Lazar
on Rogan drug me in
even deeper and then
finding your channel and
Chris Ramsey's channel
has just like built upon
this and now I feel
like I have places to
stay in the know and
even a lot of the news
outlets now are
covering this more and
more and more like who
would have ever thought
you'd see the day where
major media outlets are
covering this phenomenon
almost on a weekly
basis yeah you I mean
you have Tulsi
Gabbard you know head of
DNI direct director of
national intelligence she
in her platform says I
want to expose
information on UAP
UFOs and I've spoken
to her I know you've
spoken to her and she
seems pretty you know
kind of kind of woke on
the issues yeah she
definitely seems open
receptive open-minded
and uh willing to
explore truth yeah
which is that's all I
think about everything
like why would you go
into anything with a
preconceived notion
that's not that's not
inquisitive like go in
with an open mind
that's one thing I love
that Chris Ramsey does
on his he'll he'll sit
back and and it's great
for people who are very
like uh immediately
skeptical because what
he'll say is envision
this is like an
exercise this is just a
thought exercise like
I'd ask you to go
through the thought
process with me we're
just walking through and
methodically looking at
these things I'm not
telling you this is
right I'm not but let's
set aside our
preconceived notions
coming with open minds
and open hearts and see
where the information
takes us and if you do
that across the spectrum
of everything in this UAP
world UFO world alien
whatever you want to
call it there's a
plethora of information
that starts to get
pretty fascinating
where you go man yeah
there is like I don't
have an answer but I
have a lot more
questions and I am
definitely a lot less
decisive on the topic
that the more you learn
the less you know right
and that's like in life
the more I begin to
learn even in health
care the more you
think you know and the
more you pull at the
thread the more you
realize there's a lot a
lot of unknown more
unknown than known
totally and with the
UFO thing I think if you
start with the foundation
which is there's there's
a there there you know
like there are things in
the sky we can't identify
that repeatedly show up
around our most sensitive
nuclear sites like that's
what I'm most confident
I would hang my hat on
that and then you can
kind of build up from
there are there secret
programs have we been
reverse engineering things
and you go down
obviously in probability
as you continue to go in
your search but you build
up this kind of self
consistent ontology which
is wholly separate from the
average person's and yeah
we might be merging into
that ontology over the
next you know decade or
two and it's a it's gonna
be exciting it's gonna be
exciting because I think
more and more is going to
come out you know better
than I do but I just think
there's there's such a
thirst for knowledge right
now and there's such a
free form of discussion
that with that's going to
come more and more truth
and more and more
transparency and then
even discoveries like
discovery after discovery
after discovery you know
and our ability to see what
else is out there and our
ability to have high res
images of other planets
and our ability to gain
soil samples and just
knowledge is power yes if
you were talking to
somebody out there who's
struggling with some
chronic health issue or
some you know something
they don't quite
understand maybe they're
going to a primary care
doctor that's just giving
them kind of conventional
answers treatments you know
take some Tylenol some
ibuprofen some you know
proton pump inhibitor you
know whatever treat the
surface level thing with
some you know pill what
would you recommend to
them I think if you I
mean I've said this if
you eat the average
American diet and you go
to the average American
doctor don't be surprised
when you get diagnosed
with the average American
chronic disease if you
really truly care about
your health take
sovereignty and autonomy
over your health
understand that nobody's
going to do it for you
you've got to take
yourself out of the rat
race and it doesn't have
to be waste well there's
hundreds of clinics if
not thousands throughout
the country that are
doing proactive predictive
medicine using blood
blood work algorithm based
medicine to drive health
span and go do a deep
dive one time you save the
money spend a little bit of
money to see to get a
glimpse into what health
care could be yeah if you
weren't caught in that
ecosystem well it's so wild
to me they call it functional
health like it's some exotic
beast you know some like you
know weird esoteric thing
that's like hard to
understand it's just more
biomarkers it's just more
data yeah like like like
obviously you're gonna want
more in in what other
industry would say you're
building you know I would
just call it health care
yeah it's because the
existing system sick care
it's sick care this is
health care exactly rather
than managing chronic
disease because if we're
really truthful about what
the existing ecosystem is it
is built to manage chronic
disease not prevent yeah to
manage yeah and so if you
want to prevent chronic
disease you've got to take
yourself out of that and put
yourself in a health care
system and a true health care
system is going to get
proactive and predictive by
looking at your biomarkers and
assessing it the cancer that
you develop in your 40s
manifested in his 30s the
diabetes that you develop in
your 30s manifested in your
in your 20s right chronic
disease has leading indicators
and we can see those
indicators and the more
diagnostic sets we have the
deeper dive we can do and
the more we can project and
prevent so like a dexa scan
tells us your visceral fat
your subcutaneous fat how
much body fat you're storing
you combine that with a vo2
max now we know your lung
capacity your heart health
your overall cardiovascular
conditioning combine that and
layer it with biomarkers and
we've got over 70 biomarkers
that tell us where you're at at
the biological level which is a
snapshot of you in time now
combine that with multiple
biomarkers now tie that into
a wearable now monitor your
deep sleep your rim sleep your
heart rate variability put all
these data sets together and
allow large language models
like allen to assess that now
cross-reference that across a
large patient population of
healthy individuals not sick
individuals and right and the
other problem with the
biomarkers in the primary care
space is they're comparing you to
that sick fish tank you're being
compared against a a a tank of
sick fish of other chronically
ill on four or more prescription
medicine americans that is not a
healthy patient population so we
narrow all those tolerances to
where you would have been as a
healthy 20 year old prior to this
chronic disease crisis and our
biomarker test is narrowed to that
niche and so I have a buddy who's in
Florida and he called me he's like
you're gonna love this man I brought
my blood work into my primary care and
I showed him and he goes these
tolerances are this is ridiculous
this is way too strict like they're
they're way this is that you're not
low on this you're not high on that
you're not this you're not okay
listen to that guy and see where you
go yeah or listen to us and see where
you go well they're treating you at
the failure mode margins of these
things where when they get like
seriously in the red it's like too
late yes like what can you that's
all I'm trying to say and so if you
can you know manage these things
ahead of time predict them see
around the corner obviously you'd
want to do that how do you if
you're you know somebody in the
audience and you're kind of you're
watching you know Gary Breck on a
podcast and he's like it's all
reduces down to gene breaks which
cause nutrient deficiencies or you
then you hear Brian Johnson on the
next podcast and he goes it's
polyphenol rich olive oil and I'm
taking 120 things how do you navigate
this new space of having a lot of
because some of these people are
really pushing the frontier of this
stuff and you have Huberman
obviously but like it's a lot to
make sense of so like do you need
to get tested basically and do
something individualized or like how
do you navigate the health
podcasts yeah I mean there's a lot
there's a lot to digest even for me
there's a lot to digest and there's
areas that get more aggressive and
more fringe and then there's bread and
butter and so if we look at what the
difference is between a healthy happy
centenarian and somebody dies at the
average American life expectancy the
difference is the onset of chronic
disease and so let's just distill this
down to simple basic X's and O's
blocking and tackling okay so your goal
is to live to be a healthy happy
centenarian where you could play with
your grandkids in your 80s and 90s and
you're not in a bed for the last decade
of your life then we've got to start
with preventing the onset of chronic
disease because the difference between
somebody dying at 70 something years
old and somebody living to that access
or that point is the onset of chronic
disease that's the big difference so if
we can delay the onset of chronic
disease then we can indirectly if we can
extend health span we can indirectly
drive lifespan and my message to
everyone is I'll have all the answers
but I do know if we can drive health
span we can extend lifespan and if we
can drive health span longer and delay
chronic disease we can buy time for
brilliant minds like Dr. White to come
up with the next major invention the
next major life-changing life-altering
world-changing idea and I recommend we
buy time we buy time through getting
proactive and predictive again I know I
sound like a broken record but it's like
we start in your 20s 30s 40s and 50s
monitoring all these things now we're
approaching the decade of decline your
40s it's known as the decade of
decline in your 40s the average man
ages 12 years biologically the average
woman ages 17 years biologically whoa
why it's because there's a precipitous
decline in all of our hormones there's
also a precipitous decline in all of these
bioavailable necessary building blocks
that we were talking about with Dr.
White or right everything begins to
diminish if we can bring all those
levels up to normal and maintain those
levels at an optimal biological level
into your 40s 50s and 60s we can
indirectly stave off the decline and what
do I mean can we keep your lean muscle
mass can we keep your visceral fat down
can we keep your bone mineral density
high can we keep all those things because
for a woman who's petite over the age of
65 one of her biggest risk factors is a
bone fracture right and so we are
proactively monitoring your bone mineral
density with a DEXA we know what your
average bone mineral density decline will
be if you have your hormones decline but
if we keep your hormones optimal and we
treat and get proactive and predictive we
can prevent that bone mineral density
decline or slow it and then at some point
in the future hopefully reverse it right and
so that's my thing I know it's a very
complicated way of saying getting predictive
and looking out for these things we can
stave off the things that are going to
kill us and we can buy ourselves enough
time for really really smart people to
innovate and come up with new cutting-edge
modalities cures whatever it may be
there's so many cutting-edge things that
are going to come out especially with
large language models with artificial
intelligence with CRISPR with all the
things that these guys I mean we're
bringing back dire wolves like yeah
imagine what we can do with humanity in
the decades to come if we can keep you
healthy well it feels like on the you
know if you have a Maslow's hierarchy of
needs but for humanity bring back a dire
wolf would be at that very very top and
then this stuff is just so fundamental I
even say it to you know all my friends in
the Maha movement like you that the make
America healthy again thing I'm always
like it's it's the most important it's it's
way more important the UFO thing is such a
luxury you know compared to how you feel
every day and so I hope I love that vision
and I hope ways to well continues to push it
the frontier as far as actual treatments but
also making this stuff accessible to people
because I know that's part of the vision just
making it as a as scaled as possible but in a
responsible way and where the incentives are
aligned between patient and practitioner so I'm
excited to see where you go I'm pumped I'm
excited for the future I'm telling you we're
just getting started there's so many things
that we're working on that I'm excited about
and and we'll do I have to have you come back
in and check it out so you can see I'm so I'm so
ready I'm so ready and yeah man I appreciate
everything you've done I feel so I feel
great even today and let's see let's see in
six weeks yeah thank you for trusting us and
coming in man oh no no I mean thank you for
having me man it's it's been awesome and
everybody here is so cool and couldn't
recommend it enough
alchemist did you enjoy that well here's
the thing that episode was just the tip of
the iceberg if you want the full picture
head over to the American alchemy magazine
we just launched on substack that's where
we deep dive into all sorts of crazy
topics that we don't have time to fit into
every video with weekly articles exploring
all of the strange forgotten and
conspiratorial corners of space history and
high weirdness so join up today at our free
or paid tiers on substack I am including
the full link in the description of this
video